<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- MARKET -- Real Estate Video Blog with -- CLIENT NAME --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Doug Cary Team is to be your best resource for Wasatch Front real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Doug Cary Team, your professional Wasatch Front Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 14:30:27 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 14:30:27 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways to Sell Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NE5NMVvQSe8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Time to move or cash in on your investment property? Now is a great time to sell, the question is, how to go about it? Today we'll go over the pro's and con's of a home owner's three major options. To learn more, watch this video.%20localhost:4000/3-ways-to-sell-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Time to move or cash in on your investment property? Now is a great time to sell, the question is, how to go about it? Today we’ll go over the pro’s and con’s of a home owner’s three major options. To learn more, watch this video.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-ways-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-ways-to-sell-your-home.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Look for in a Real Estate Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/99Ha7s0xCqI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of real estate agents out there, but that doesn’t mean they’re all able to serve your needs effectively. In fact, there are some key differences that set the best agents apart from the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The average real estate agent with the Salt Lake Board of Realtors only sells four homes per year.&lt;/strong&gt; 50% of agents sold no homes in 2018. It’s very important to make sure the agent you choose isn’t one of these low producers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=To find out how good of an agent they are, you need to look at their track record.%20localhost:4000/what-to-look-for-in-a-real-estate-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“To find out how good of an agent they are, you need to look at their track record.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out how good of an agent they are, you need to look at their track record. Don’t just focus on years of experience—you need to know how many homes they sell in a year. Here are a few questions you can ask in order to gain a better understanding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. “How many homes did you sell last year?”&lt;/strong&gt; This shows how productive and experienced they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. “What is your list-to-sale price ratio?”&lt;/strong&gt; For example, if they list a $300,000 home and sell it for $300,000, they have a 100% list-to-sale price ratio. However, the average agent only has a 95% ratio, so it’s important to know your agent’s ratio. Mine, for example, is 99.3%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. “Do you work alone or with a team?”&lt;/strong&gt; If they’re a solo agent, they have to manage everything on their own. There’s so much to keep track of, so it’s much better to have an entire real estate team at your service. However, you may not want to work with a very large team that may not give you personalized service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 13:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-to-look-for-in-a-real-estate-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-to-look-for-in-a-real-estate-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Going on in the Wasatch Front Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wW9_KBW2cqQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of this year, economists predicted that, along the Wasatch Front, we were going to see a very flat or even a declining market. Interest rates were predicted to go up a couple times this year, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, those predictions have been called off. In fact, in February, when interest rates were expected to go up, they actually came down. &lt;strong&gt;Due to our economy, interest rates for a 30-year fixed mortgage are currently at 4.25%, which is quite a drop from the 4.75% to 5% range they were in.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only can owner-occupied buyers afford more, but investors can also buy now. Doing so makes better sense financially, even with the home prices going up as they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That spurred the market on—&lt;strong&gt;not only are we seeing far more competitive offers in the market, but we’re also seeing properties in the lower price points sell above list price!&lt;/strong&gt; Overall, the market for homes under $500,000 has been seeing a lot of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’re thinking of selling a home, I encourage you to act before June, just in case the market does flatten out.%20localhost:4000/whats-going-on-in-the-wasatch-front-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re thinking of selling a home, I encourage you to act before June, just in case the market does flatten out.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above the $500,000 price point, homes that are properly marketed, fairly priced, and that are in great condition are selling as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, &lt;strong&gt;inventory along the Wasatch Front is again going down, reaching an all-time low in all price ranges.&lt;/strong&gt; There are currently 1.5 months of supply, meaning that if no other homes came on the market today, it would take 1.5 months to sell all the homes currently available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that an inventory of four to five months is a balanced market and an inventory of six months or more constitutes a buyer’s market, &lt;strong&gt;we can clearly see that this is a fantastic seller’s market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spring of 2018, we noticed these trends occurring, as well. We were in a great seller’s market until June came along, when things flattened out. We can reasonably expect something similar to happen again in 2019, but who really knows what the future will bring?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of selling a home, I encourage you to act before that time, just in case the market does flatten out. For specific questions related to your property, feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 14:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-going-on-in-the-wasatch-front-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/whats-going-on-in-the-wasatch-front-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A New Loan Program for You to Know About</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/A8O08SzasAo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today we’re excited to talk about a brand-new loan program that allows buyers to use the rent on an investment property to help them qualify for more home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This program lets you buy and invest at the same time.%20localhost:4000/a-new-loan-program-for-you-to-know-about.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This program lets you buy and invest at the same time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utah Housing has been around for a long time. They have a ton of different loan programs, from the traditional 20% down mortgage loans to zero-down loan programs. Recently, they’ve introduced a new program that allows buyers to purchase different kinds of properties, such as a duplex or a home with a mother-in-law apartment, and use the projected rent from those accessory dwellings to add into their income in order to purchase more real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a great opportunity for a buyer to buy a new home while also getting a great asset.&lt;/strong&gt; If you or someone you know is interested in this brand-new program, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 12:42:41 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-new-loan-program-for-you-to-know-about.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/a-new-loan-program-for-you-to-know-about.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>National Radon Prevention Month</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DYUjQzf04MI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radon is a colorless, odorless gas that rises from the ground, enters our home through the foundation and, right now, is the No. 2 leading cause of lung cancer in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between the months of October and March, Davis County actually provides free radon testing for residents. You can file a request for this test &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.co.davis.ut.us/health/environmental-health-services/environmental_testing/radon/radon-form&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some startling numbers: &lt;strong&gt;56% of homes in Centerville, 42% of homes in Bountiful, and 20% of homes in North Salt Lake City tested above the healthy EPA levels for radon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Radon is the second leading cause of this kind of lung cancer in the United States.%20localhost:4000/national-radon-prevention-month.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Radon is the second leading cause of this kind of lung cancer in the United States.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re buying a home, I highly recommend having a radon test performed. I also recommend having your home tested whenever you make significant changes or remodels, especially to the lower level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your home tests high or positive, you can purchase a radon mitigation system.&lt;/strong&gt; This system uses a fan to pump air through the house to eliminate radon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/national-radon-prevention-month.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/national-radon-prevention-month.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Market Recap to Close Out 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1ZizejhwWAI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that 2018 is in the books, what should buyers and sellers know about this past year’s market? What do the market trends from 2018 tell us about 2019?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final numbers aren’t out yet, but we estimate that &lt;strong&gt;homes appreciated by 8% over the course of the entire year.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of that increase happened during the first half of the year; after that, prices generally flattened out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates started the year at 4%, but now they’re around 4.75%, and we expect them to continue to rise in 2019. Of course, the higher interest rates rise, the more expensive homes become for buyers. For example, getting a $300,000 mortgage would cost $133 per month more at today’s rate than it would have a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As inventory levels have risen, homes have stayed on the market longer.%20localhost:4000/a-market-recap-to-close-out-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“As inventory levels have risen, homes have stayed on the market longer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building costs are extremely high right now, but that’s not stopping builders from building and buyers from buying.&lt;/strong&gt; There are some fabulous communities being built right now along the Wasatch Front, so make sure you contact a knowledgeable local agent before you walk into any of these properties so you know what you’re getting into and you get the best deal possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nationwide, we’ve seen a general market slowdown. As interest rates have risen, inventory has increased as well. In many places, inventory is at a five-year high. Here in Utah, we’re starting to see this same trend. As inventory levels have risen, homes have stayed on the market longer. This is good news for buyers, who now have more homes to pick from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking forward to a fantastic 2019, so if you have any other questions about our market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 14:15:27 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-market-recap-to-close-out-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/a-market-recap-to-close-out-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Opportunity Zones for Real Estate Investors</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jWZTQLnEX-A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are new and not very well known opportunities in the market called Opportunity Zones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were created by Congress last year and put into place beginning this year. There are certain census tracts in every state in the U.S.—46 in Utah, in fact—that are lower income areas in need of redevelopment. &lt;strong&gt;Opportunity Zones allow for states to nominate the areas as they would like to see increased investing in real estate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you invest in these Opportunity Zones, you are allowed to defer, reduce, or eliminate your capital gains entirely. This includes single-family homes and commercial real estate. &lt;strong&gt;If you hold the property for five to seven years, you’ll get a 10% reduction on your federal capital gains; for seven to 10 years, you’ll get a 15% reduction; and if you hold it longer than 10 years, you’ll pay no capital gains tax on the gains of this property.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, there are 46 Opportunity Zones here in Utah right now, including 15 in Salt Lake County, three in Davis County, and five in Weber County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you invest in these Opportunity Zones, you are allowed to defer, reduce, or eliminate entirely your capital gains.%20localhost:4000/opportunity-zones-for-real-estate-investors.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you invest in these Opportunity Zones, you are allowed to defer, reduce, or eliminate entirely your capital gains.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works: Imagine that you have enough savings to allow you to invest in real estate; maybe you’ll end up selling another investment property of yours specifically so that you can invest in this Opportunity Zone. &lt;strong&gt;If there’s a capital gain from that previous sale, you can defer those gains, reinvest into this property, and then look to pay zero capital gains later on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big key is that you have to hold it for 10 years or more to be able to eliminate these capital gains altogether. Hypothetically, if you were to normally pay 25% in federal capital gains tax, &lt;strong&gt;eliminating the capital gains would allow you to have a 25% gain compared to investing in areas outside of an Opportunity Zone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is interested in investing in an Opportunity Zone, I’ve created automated emails that alert me and my clients about opportunities in these areas. Simply reach out to me and let me know in which areas you’re interested in searching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind you, I’m a licensed real estate agent, NOT an accountant or a financial planner, so &lt;strong&gt;it is very important to consult those people on your team as you look at these opportunities.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 16:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/opportunity-zones-for-real-estate-investors.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/opportunity-zones-for-real-estate-investors.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Get Rid of Your Mortgage Insurance</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rBdofAEAbmw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Doug Cary, Real Estate Agent with Century 21 Everest. I’m going to tell you how to get rid of mortgage insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve bought a home and put less than a 20% down payment down, you’re familiar with mortgage insurance.  It’s that added amount on your statement every month you wish you could get rid of. The good news is you might be able to.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homes with less than 20% equity in it are more risky for lenders and the lender requires that you pay for insurance. This goes to another company that will pay back the lender if you were to foreclose on the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consumerfinance.gov/owning-a-home/loan-options/conventional-loans/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;conventional loan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, your lender will set up what is called &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consumerfinance.gov/ask-cfpb/what-is-private-mortgage-insurance-en-122/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Private mortgage insurance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (PMI) and the rates vary by down payment and credit score but are generally cheaper than FHA rates for borrowers with good credit. Private mortgage insurance is typically paid monthly with your principal and interest payment. Once you hit 20% equity in your home you can request an appraisal from your mortgage company and drop this payment altogether. This will naturally drop off when you’ve made enough payments and it get’s to 78% loan-to-value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Once you have at least 20% equity on the property, you can also request that your lender drop that mortgage insurance altogether.%20localhost:4000/how-to-get-rid-of-your-mortgage-insurance.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Once you have at least 20% equity on the property, you can also request that your lender drop that mortgage insurance altogether.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get an FHA loan now the mortgage insurance cost is the same no matter your credit score and you are not allowed to drop the mortgage insurance premium when you hit 20% equity. You will either stick with it or refinance to a conventional loan. It wasn’t always this way. If you got your FHA loan before June 2, 2013, you can drop it at 20% just like a conventional loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VA loans have the VA guarantee which replaces mortgage insurance and works the same. There is an up-front funding fee that varies based on many things that your lender can go over with you. Sometimes this is all paid up front and sometimes it’s calculated into the monthly payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people are in a much stronger equity position today with prices having increased so much over the last few years. You might be surprised to find out that you could drop your mortgage insurance and save all that money every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m offering a free mortgage insurance review to see if you should request from your lender to drop mortgage insurance from your payment. Just call me and have your monthly mortgage statement available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m here to help you with anything regarding real estate. &lt;strong&gt;Forward this to others making real estate decisions so they can be the best informed. Thanks for watching, I’m Doug Cary, your Utah Real Estate agent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 14:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-get-rid-of-your-mortgage-insurance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-get-rid-of-your-mortgage-insurance.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in our Wasatch Front Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DtihSaVnq8o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been paying any attention to the Wasatch Front market lately, you’ve probably noticed that it’s been undergoing some changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparing this year’s statistics to those from last year, we can see that &lt;strong&gt;there has only been an 8% year-over-year rise in the number of homes for sale.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, while year-over-year changes may not indicate much change, the shift we’ve seen over the past few months has been comparatively quite dramatic. In the time between June of this year and the present moment, there has been a 56% increase in our market’s available inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is the time to sell.%20localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-wasatch-front-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is the time to sell.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;strong&gt;the number of homes that have gone under contract in the last 30 days has decreased 20% since this time last year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do these statistics mean, exactly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it’s hard to say what the future holds. But while I may not have a crystal ball,  I can tell you that if you or anyone you know of are looking to sell, now is the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 10:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-wasatch-front-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-wasatch-front-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Won’t Want to Miss This Halloween Client Appreciation Event</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tpymFod8EFs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m excited to invite you to our Client Appreciation Pumpkin Patch Event coming up on &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, October 10, 4:30-7:30pm.&lt;/strong&gt; We’ll be transforming the parking lot outside our office into an amazing pumpkin patch featuring a hay maze, face painting, balloon animals, family photos, and free pumpkins for all! We plan on having a lot of fun and making this a great place for you to make some memories with your family. I’ll be dressed up, and if you can find me there, you’ll have the chance to guess which superhero I am. To see my full invite with all the details, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/you-wont-want-to-miss-this-halloween-client-appreciation-event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/you-wont-want-to-miss-this-halloween-client-appreciation-event.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
