<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dave Friedman Team</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 15:57:05 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 15:57:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’ve Got $1,000,000 With YOUR Name On It</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rtWIaTNrrG8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about all of the expenses that you incur in your business today - when we team up all of those costs DISAPPEAR. At Dave Friedman Team you’ll get over $1,000,000 (annually) worth of technology, tools, systems, and models for you to use in your business. Reach out to us today to discuss how you can leverage our resources to maximize your income.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 15:03:06 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/weve-got-1000000-with-your-name-on-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/weve-got-1000000-with-your-name-on-it.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who's Got Your Back in These Uncertain Times?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C_JBUi2-knU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a  prospecting-based, marketing-enhanced Real Estate Team, we have no shortage of opportunity right now. That means that while most real estate agents are in basic survival mode, we are overwhelmed with folks that need to buy and sell. When the dust settles and all of this is over, Dave Friedman Team will be right where we were before, still serving the community and leaders in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be a part of a team that will continue to prosper in even the toughest of times then we need to talk RIGHT NOW.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 14:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whos-got-your-back-in-these-uncertain-times.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whos-got-your-back-in-these-uncertain-times.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Wondering What You Can Be Doing Right Now to Move Your Business Forward In These Crazy Times?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RwvNZUjvx3Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave Friedman Team is built for crazy times like this. Our collective successes and failures have uniquely prepared us for exactly this type of situation. If you are concerned about how your business will survive then we need to talk! Call us to learn more about how you can thrive while other agents merely hope to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 14:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-wondering-what-you-can-be-doing-right-now-to-move-your-business-forward-in-these-crazy-times.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-wondering-what-you-can-be-doing-right-now-to-move-your-business-forward-in-these-crazy-times.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Freaking Out?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zTAY1VgXO3k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know that the most important quality of a real estate agent is the ability to deliver the best experience to her/his clients. &lt;strong&gt;Well we are inundated with opportunities right now - last week alone we set &lt;em&gt;30 consultations&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a great chance to continue growing your business while we do all the heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 14:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-freaking-out.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-freaking-out.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Afraid of How the Coronavirus Is Going to Affect Your Long Term Business?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LJ_5tTojz-s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you worry that the current crisis will hurt your business? Are you thinking about leaving real estate and the career you love? If you answered “yes” to any of the above questions then it is time for us to have a serious conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation is real and your concerns are valid. Let’s talk about how you can be a part of a Team that will allow your business to prosper in even the most difficult of times. &lt;strong&gt;We are still selling a home every single day! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a confidential conversation about business growth opportunities, please reach out (see contact info below) or visit us at &lt;a href=&quot;http://davefriedmancoaching.com&quot;&gt;DaveFriedmanCoaching.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 12:52:57 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-afraid-of-how-the-coronavirus-is-going-to-affect-your-long-term-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-afraid-of-how-the-coronavirus-is-going-to-affect-your-long-term-business.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Story Behind Building Our Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ola_0999bCA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting as a solo agent, I was eventually able to make real estate a lucrative business. However by the end of my first breakout year, I was isolated from friends and family and enjoyed life less than when I was only making $40,000; something had to change. In today’s interview with Lars Hedenborg, I share my journey of building the Dave Friedman Team, and explain the world-class model I built it around that affords agents real opportunities for growth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:23—Dave reflects on his breakout year in real estate, going from 30 to 60 transactions &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:42—The problems with success: How Dave sought to revolutionize the industry model &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:40—Explaining the Dave Friedman Team mantra and structure &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:57—How the Friedman Team culture and the ‘seven Fs’ compare to other real estate teams that are disorganized and loose-knit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:50—The opportunities available for those interested in joining the Friedman Team &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15:00—The ‘why’ behind the Dave Friedman vision; helping others succeed and manage life with work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18:24—How to handle growth on your team and elevate team members &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:10—What the training process looks like on the Dave Friedman Team &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24:30—Anecdotes of success; wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have real estate-related questions for me, or you’re interested in buying or selling a home, please reach out by phone or email. My team and I are always happy to hear from you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 11:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-story-behind-building-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-story-behind-building-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking to Grow Your Real Estate Career?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8u7ftuU0Doo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got an exciting announcement to make. &lt;strong&gt;This month, we are looking for two special people to join us on The Dave Friedman Team.&lt;/strong&gt; A real estate license is required, but the opportunity here is huge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first open position we have is for a buyer’s specialist. The total target income is a minimum of $100,000 and easily over $200,000 for those who want to get after it. It’s an exciting opportunity where you can generate new business every day, meet with buyers, and gain their trust to work with you. Our team structure will also help you get more free time in your schedule. &lt;strong&gt;You’ll make more money by working less than you would as a solo agent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A real estate license is required, but the opportunity is huge.%20http://localhost:4000/looking-to-grow-your-real-estate-career.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A real estate license is required, but the opportunity is huge.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second open position is for a market specialist. This person works with our buyer’s specialist and the buyer. They show the buyers all the homes they want to take a look at, which allows the specialist to spend more time generating business or just relaxing. &lt;strong&gt;The target income here is between $75,000 and $85,000.&lt;/strong&gt; This position will also attend closings and inspections while showing homes to all of our buyers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re interested in either of these positions or know someone who might be, reach out ASAP.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re making our selections over the next few weeks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 11:03:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/looking-to-grow-your-real-estate-career.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/looking-to-grow-your-real-estate-career.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interested in Joining One of Charleston’s Top Real Estate Teams?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hDQM78Y7cxg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dave Friedman Team has continued to grow, and because of that, we’re looking to make a few more key hires to help us maintain that growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m also excited to announce that I’m personally going to be training these new hires to make sure that they are rockstars in the industry and have the right skills, knowledge, habits, and attitude in order to be successful.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason that so many of our clients have been so satisfied with our level of service is that that’s a big focus of ours. We’re looking for folks who align with that customer-first mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re looking for folks who align with our customer-first mindset.%20http://localhost:4000/interested-in-joining-one-of-charlestons-top-real-estate-teams.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re looking for folks who align with our customer-first mindset.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right now, we’re looking to hire a lead listing specialist and two buyer’s agents.&lt;/strong&gt; There is an opportunity right now for a new hire to serve 126 new clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’ve ever thought about joining a team or wondered about what joining a team can do for you, we’d love to chat with you and get to know you.&lt;/strong&gt; Feel free to reach out to us on our website &lt;a href=&quot;https://davefriedmancoaching.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, where you can learn more about our open positions, or reach out to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Christina@davefriedmanteam.com&quot;&gt;Christina@davefriedmanteam.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 11:55:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/interested-in-joining-one-of-charlestons-top-real-estate-teams.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/interested-in-joining-one-of-charlestons-top-real-estate-teams.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Expanding Our Team, and We Want You!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/koqS73MHZFY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our goal for 2019 is to achieve a 50% growth in our business, &lt;strong&gt;we need to find some great, motivated agents and staff to help bolster our ranks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agents have reached out to us, speaking of how they were unable to reach their goals in 2018. No matter how experienced in real estate you are, you can always use a helping hand. We’d like to offer one to you through a variety of new positions we have open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A listing agent.&lt;/strong&gt; The listing agent’s primary role is to go out into the market and meet with sellers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A licensed closing coordinator.&lt;/strong&gt; The closing coordinator helps agents from contract to close. We prefer our coordinators to be licensed so they can help with repair negotiations, post-occupancy agreements, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Four inside sales staff.&lt;/strong&gt; In this new role that we’re currently developing, we’re looking to coach four individuals into becoming professional sales consultants who can help to further grow our business.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A director of lead generation.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re looking for someone to replace me in this role so I can better focus on coaching the new department.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know would be interested in any of these positions, feel free to reach out to us to learn more. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/were-expanding-our-team-and-we-want-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/were-expanding-our-team-and-we-want-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Hosting a Mastermind and Helping With Hurricane Relief</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LHtiegJYbfY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got two different things to share with you today. &lt;strong&gt;The first is how you can personally sell 100 listings in one year.&lt;/strong&gt; We have two agents on our team who will sell just about 200 listings between them, so we are hosting a FREE agent mastermind to share how they are able to do that with our team’s leads, leverage, and systems. This mastermind will take place on September 28 from 11 a.m. until 2 p.m. All agents from all brokerages are invited to join us at this free mastermind. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/charleston-agent-mastermind-how-to-focus-on-listings-in-a-shift-tickets-50232513801&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RSVP here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second thing I wanted to talk about was our Hurricane Florence relief efforts.&lt;/strong&gt; Some of us stayed around after the evacuation and bought a lot of water, supplies, and more that we don’t need right now but others do. We’ll be donating those, and we invite you to donate any supplies you might have to our office. We’re going to get a truck together to ship those items to North Carolina to people in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The mastermind is on September 28 from 11 a.m. until 2 p.m.%20http://localhost:4000/were-hosting-a-mastermind-and-helping-with-hurricane-relief.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The mastermind is on September 28 from 11 a.m. until 2 p.m.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you know anyone who might be interested in the mastermind or in dropping some supplies off at our office, please feel free to share this with them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 12:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/were-hosting-a-mastermind-and-helping-with-hurricane-relief.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/were-hosting-a-mastermind-and-helping-with-hurricane-relief.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
