<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- MARKET -- Real Estate Video Blog with -- CLIENT NAME --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Colemere Realty Associates, LLC is to be your best resource for Wasatch Front real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Colemere Realty Associates, LLC, your professional Wasatch Front Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 14:20:43 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 14:20:43 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Is a Pre-Listing Walkthrough Important?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ivaYubQIshA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before you sell your home, make sure you have a pre-listing walkthrough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A pre-listing walkthrough is essentially an opportunity for you to look at your home in detail, point out the pros and cons of the property, and uncover any necessary repairs. A lot can be missed if you don’t schedule one, and that could affect your final sale price drastically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Missing this step puts you at a disadvantage to sellers who don’t.%20http://localhost:4000/why-is-a-pre-listing-walkthrough-important.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Missing this step puts you at a disadvantage to sellers who don’t.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like creating a game plan for your house. We’re setting the timelines, expectations, etc., for your home sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The pre-listing walkthrough is also key in terms of staging&lt;/strong&gt;. Walking through the home helps us get a much better understanding of the home. This step often gets missed in this market, and that’s a disadvantage to homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When we are physically in a home and can analyze it this way, we can get a much better idea of the home’s value&lt;/strong&gt; and what we can do to maximize the sale price. Agents who miss this step suffer in negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-is-a-pre-listing-walkthrough-important.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-is-a-pre-listing-walkthrough-important.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Real Estate Videos Get More Money For Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I1F80N-Hx28?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much of a difference can listing videos make? A lot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Can videos really help sell your home? The short answer is yes, and we have the statistics to back that up. In fact, 85% of clients want an agent who uses video tools as part of their marketing package. What’s more, homes presented with a video tend to receive 403% more attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But making a real estate video isn’t as easy as using your cellphone camera—&lt;strong&gt;a high-quality video requires specialized equipment&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ve invested in a very expensive camera that will allow the consumer to virtually walk through the home and look around almost as though they were there in person. To make a really effective real estate video, you’ll also need drone footage. It adds a wow factor to the presentation, showing the home itself and the surrounding areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the pandemic changing people’s habits so drastically, this kind of technology has really helped keep home sales moving along. It’s the next best thing to actually viewing a home in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Not all platforms can fully capture the richness that listing videos can create.%20http://localhost:4000/how-real-estate-videos-get-more-money-for-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Not all platforms can fully capture the richness that listing videos can create.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from high-quality technology, &lt;strong&gt;you’ll also need a high-quality editing and production team&lt;/strong&gt; to help put the video together. This might sound expensive, but at Colemere Realty, we’ve tailored the process down to capture listings of any price range to help them sell for more money in a shorter amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you can’t have all this great equipment and editing technology without having the right platform to share the videos on. Not all platforms can fully capture the richness that listing videos can create; Zillow, for example, has specific requirements in terms of video resolution that don’t really work for the process. There are many options out there, so working with an experienced real estate marketer is key to helping you find the right ones so that you can get your listing in front of as many potential buyers as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about today’s topic or anything to do with real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-real-estate-videos-get-more-money-for-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-real-estate-videos-get-more-money-for-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the Absorption Rate and Daily Snapshot</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7X-YVMDhi2Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are the two statistics you need to know before entering the market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’ve been sitting on the fence, now is the time to make a move in the real estate market. There are two statistics, in particular, that you need to understand before making any real estate decision that will also prove why it’s such a great time to buy or sell right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our favorite stat in real estate is the absorption rate. &lt;strong&gt;When we discuss inventory, we talk about it in terms of time&lt;/strong&gt;. When homes sell, they’re taken out of the inventory count, and this affects the number of houses for sale and how much time it would take to sell them. A balanced market has four to six months’ worth of inventory, meaning that if no other properties came onto the market, it would take four to six months to sell them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the Salt Lake City market has only two weeks of inventory—well below that equilibrium of four to six months’ worth. If all listing activity ceased today, there would be no more homes to purchase after just two weeks. &lt;strong&gt;We’ve never seen inventory this low&lt;/strong&gt;. Properties are selling very, very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second stat to know is the daily snapshot. This shows us a comparison of real estate activity today versus the same day last year. The numbers included in the snapshot are active listings, pending listings, properties under contract, and the number of properties sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Currently, the Salt Lake City market has only two weeks of inventory.%20http://localhost:4000/understanding-the-absorption-rate-and-daily-snapshot.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Currently, the Salt Lake City market has only two weeks of inventory.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, there are a little over 1,200 active listings on the market right now, while that number was over 2,400 at the same time last year. Inventory has decreased by 50% in a year. Interestingly, &lt;strong&gt;the number of homes under contract has increased by 37%&lt;/strong&gt;, which means demand has risen. This is the perfect storm, especially for sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we love stats—they equip us as real estate professionals to help you position your offer well and succeed in this hyper-competitive market. We’re seeing multiple offers on every house, sometimes more than 10! If you’re well-positioned, you get the best shot of winning the property you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some would think that in this type of market a seller can price their home however they like, or just sell it themselves. However, buyers use professional real estate agents, so sellers who overprice will end up selling for less. &lt;strong&gt;Use a professional agent&lt;/strong&gt; as a seller to help you maximize the value of your property and avoid mistakes, such as simply taking the highest-priced offer that may not be supported by an appraisal. An agent can help you make the best decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would love to go to work for you. If you’re sitting on the fence and unsure what to do, reach out to us via phone or email. We’ll show you how we’ll add more value to your transaction and reach or exceed your real estate goals. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/understanding-the-absorption-rate-and-daily-snapshot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/understanding-the-absorption-rate-and-daily-snapshot.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>‘Tis the Season for Holiday Home Selling Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/snnNYniNCKo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;These five tips will help you sell your home during the holidays.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’re looking to sell your home during the holidays, which is actually a viable time to list (despite all the misconceptions to the contrary), here are five tips to help you find success:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Tastefully decorate your home for the holidays&lt;/strong&gt;. What better time to accentuate the emotional appeal of your home to potential buyers than the holidays?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Deep clean before you decorate&lt;/strong&gt;. Make sure that every nook and cranny is white-glove clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Keep the home warm&lt;/strong&gt;. Don’t turn down the heat; in fact, turn it up a little bit. Turn on all your lights, and if you have a fireplace, light it or turn it on to help bring in some emotion. Another good idea is to light some holiday-scented candles to keep your home smelling fresh and cozy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Price your house properly&lt;/strong&gt;. Traditionally, real estate moves a bit slower during the holidays, so pricing your home correctly is critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Be patient during the process&lt;/strong&gt;. Showings may come at inconvenient times, especially during the holidays, when you’ll likely have your own plans to contend with. Just try to be patient with the process. If the home doesn’t sell during the holiday season, it’ll sell eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Light some holiday-scented candles to keep your home smelling fresh.%20http://localhost:4000/tis-the-season-for-holiday-home-selling-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Light some holiday-scented candles to keep your home smelling fresh.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have further questions about real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out to your Colemere Realty specialists. We’d love to answer them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tis-the-season-for-holiday-home-selling-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tis-the-season-for-holiday-home-selling-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Which 7 Mistakes Will Hurt Your Home Sale?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UlMXicxnuzc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sellers: Be proactive and avoid these huge home seller mistakes!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you want to sell quickly and for top dollar, there are seven critical mistakes you must avoid:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Picking the wrong agent&lt;/strong&gt;. Pick someone who’s experienced and has sold a lot of properties. If you need heart surgery, you’ll probably want to pick a heart surgeon who’s performed a lot of surgeries, right? Your agent needs to have their finger on the pulse of your specific market and offer a solid, customized marketing plan for your home. Make sure your agent actually walks through your home; believe it or not, some agents won’t even do this, and it should be a huge red flag for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Overpricing your property&lt;/strong&gt;. Even though it’s a seller’s market, it’s all too possible to price yourself out of the market. Consumers are well-educated these days and can find out everything they need to know online—including the price at which a given property &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be listed. Today’s homebuyers won’t even bother seeing your home in person if they believe it to be overpriced, and remember: The longer your property sits on the market, the staler it becomes. If you do get an offer on your overpriced listing, appraisal problems will more than likely come back to bite you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Only considering the highest priced offer&lt;/strong&gt;. There’s more to an offer than just price, so you’ll need the help of your agent to interpret the &lt;em&gt;overall&lt;/em&gt; strength of each offer you receive. Obsessing over price alone will cause you to neglect other key elements, like the buyer’s financing (e.g., earnest money, down payment, lender credibility).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is money your only priority? Perhaps you’re like the many other sellers we’ve worked with who needed time to find their next property and move. If so, the strongest offer may actually be one where the buyer agrees to an ample rent-back period and throws in two additional weeks rent-free. That’s exactly the offer that one of our sellers recently accepted, and it worked out well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buyers can’t make an offer on a home they can’t see.%20http://localhost:4000/which-7-mistakes-will-hurt-your-home-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buyers can’t make an offer on a home they can’t see.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Not preparing your home for the market&lt;/strong&gt;. We understand the temptation to leave things as they are—we are in a hot seller’s market, right? Yes, there will be a lot of buyers walking through your home, but they’ll also be seeing a ton of different homes. Yours needs to stand out from the crowd. In &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/how-do-i-prepare-my-home-for-the-market.html&quot;&gt;a previous video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, we explored all of the steps for getting your home market-ready and offered advice on how to prioritize repairs; we advise you to go back and check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Not allowing showings&lt;/strong&gt;.  Let’s say you go on the market on a Thursday but decline showings that following Saturday. That’s a colossal mistake! Those weekend showings are critical because that’s when most buyers are off work and viewing properties with their agents. Buyers can’t make an offer on a home they can’t see. Yes, it will be inconvenient and frustrating at times, but be proactive and designate a spot where you can go at a moment’s notice should a buyer request a showing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Getting too emotional&lt;/strong&gt;. Stressed and tired sellers are more likely to decline showings, which is never in their interest. Sometimes, buyers love to come in with their guns blazing and tell you everything they think is wrong with your house to get a better deal on it. It’s easy to get offended by that, but let cooler heads prevail; the better offer may come from a buyer who is quite particular. Try to remember that, at the end of the day, your home sale is just a business transaction—the calmer and more focused you are, the better your outcome will be. Listen to the advice of your agent because they are not nearly as emotionally involved as you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Not decluttering&lt;/strong&gt;. You’re moving anyway, so why not begin boxing up your belongings now? A clutter-free home helps buyers to better envision themselves living in that space. In a cluttered home, all buyers see is &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; stuff. Your agent has seen countless homes, and they will be a fresh pair of eyes for yours; listen to their feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have further questions on how to sell your home quickly and for top dollar, or want more personalized solutions for your selling situation, don’t hesitate to reach out to us via phone or email. We’re more than happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/which-7-mistakes-will-hurt-your-home-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/which-7-mistakes-will-hurt-your-home-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do I Prepare My Home for the Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NFG1GVWUh8I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are tips to help sellers prime for a swift and profitable home sale.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What goes into preparing a home for the market? First things first, you need to &lt;strong&gt;create a home selling plan with an emphasis on properly staging your house&lt;/strong&gt;. Staging simply refers to the work that goes into transforming your home as you know it (comfortable, highly personalized, reflective of your specific lifestyle) into a property that’s show-ready (depersonalized, clutter-free, minimally furnished). It’s all about removing unnecessary items, finding the most aesthetically pleasing arrangement for furnishings, and maximizing your home’s space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Statistics have shown that a staged home will sell faster and for more money than its unstaged competition. If you don’t have a professional stager on speed dial, reach out to us and we’d be glad to help you with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should also start decluttering your home as soon as possible&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether you’ve been in the home for three, five, or 30 years, you’ve likely accumulated stuff that you don’t need or seldom use. Pack up seasonal items, donate usable stuff you no longer need, and throw away junk. Again, the goal is to make your home look as clean and open as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps what’s even more pressing than clearing the inside of your home is updating its curb appeal. The exterior of the home is obviously what buyers will see first, and if that first impression doesn’t reel them in, your home selling journey will be a rough one. Make sure your lawn is mowed, the flower beds are weeded (and there’s actually flowers in there), and the shrubbery is trimmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you can repair something in the home yourself before you list it, always do so.%20http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-prepare-my-home-for-the-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you can repair something in the home yourself before you list it, always do so.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’ve cleaned your home’s siding and improved your landscaping, head back inside, roll up your sleeves, and &lt;strong&gt;do a &lt;em&gt;deep&lt;/em&gt; clean of every room&lt;/strong&gt;. This would include getting the carpets cleaned, wiping down the baseboards, tackling dust in every nook and cranny, clearing out the filter vents, and addressing any small stains or spots on walls. Make sure you also clean out the grout between your tiles, too! If your carpet is in pretty rough shape, either have it professionally cleaned or replace it altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noticing way too many little stains on the walls? The best way to make them vanish is to add a fresh coat of paint! Painting is something you should be doing anyway if your walls aren’t already neutrally colored (e.g., whites, off-whites, beiges, grays, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, it’s time to finally tackle that ever-growing to-do list that we all keep as homeowners—fixes or replacements around the house we’ve been meaning to do. If you can repair something in the home yourself before you list it, always do so; it will save you some headaches down the road when your property undergoes an inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, these tips provided a good roadmap for you to get started on your home selling journey. If you have questions about anything mentioned in this blog or other real estate topics, please feel free to reach out to us via phone or email. We’re always happy to help in any way we can!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-prepare-my-home-for-the-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-prepare-my-home-for-the-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can a “Love Letter” Help You Win the Home You Want?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pej1hDyun_A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Writing a buyer &amp;ldquo;love letter&amp;rdquo; will help get your offer accepted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When submitting an offer on a home, a great way to get an edge over any competition is to write a buyer “love letter.” There are a few reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;it allows you to thank the seller for letting you into their home and considering your offer&lt;/strong&gt;. It also gives you the chance to ask them to take a closer look at why you’re making an offer. Additionally, it shows genuine sincerity and enthusiasm for their home. Everyone loves to hear how great their home is, and you can tell them what you love about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, it allows you to personally connect with the seller. If the seller is receiving multiple offers, this connection can make all the difference because they’ll be able to see the person behind the offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;writing a letter lets you tell your story and talk about your family&lt;/strong&gt;. You can elaborate on how you’ll love the home as much as they did. Everyone has a story to tell, and everyone’s situation is different. Many of our clients have entered into multiple-offer situations without being able to submit the highest offer and still won because of writing this letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If the seller is receiving multiple offers, this connection can make all the difference.%20http://localhost:4000/how-can-a-love-letter-help-you-win-the-home-you-want.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If the seller is receiving multiple offers, this connection can make all the difference.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-a-love-letter-help-you-win-the-home-you-want.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-can-a-love-letter-help-you-win-the-home-you-want.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can Homebuyers Stay Competitive in Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H2vl3kreviE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are a few tips to help get your offer accepted in our competitive real estate market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To have any chance of being a competitive homebuyer in our market, there are some key tips you should follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Write a strong offer with tight deadlines and few (if any) contingencies&lt;/strong&gt;. One of those contingencies is the inspection contingency, which gives the buyer the right to cancel the transaction if they don’t like what they see during the inspection. We encourage you to communicate with the inspector through your agent before writing your offer so that you can have the inspection take place in a timely manner. This will give the seller peace of mind knowing that you’re not going to waste their time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Communicate well with the listing agent&lt;/strong&gt;. An open line of communication with the listing agent about the offer will show the seller that your agent is knowledgeable and experienced, as well as demonstrate that they can make the transaction move forward smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Ensure that all the financial aspects of your offer are strong&lt;/strong&gt;. Your sales price, earnest money, and deposit need to be strong to entice the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Be straightforward and don’t play games&lt;/strong&gt;. Don’t write unrealistic offers that the home couldn’t appraise for. Unfortunately, many agents like to play games by going under contract at a high price and then trying to get a bunch of concessions from the seller later. This tactic just muddies the water and has the potential to cause the seller to pass over your offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Make sure your lender is ready to contact the seller’s agent early&lt;/strong&gt; so they can present the pre-qualification letter with the offer before it’s accepted. If the lender contacts the seller’s agent as you submit the offer, that will make your offer stronger, since it will tell the seller that you’re ready to go and willing to move the transaction along without hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about this or any other topic, reach out to your Colemere Realty associate. We’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-homebuyers-stay-competitive-in-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-can-homebuyers-stay-competitive-in-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Do You Need Representation When Buying New Construction?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-8qpEYKjt-s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking of buying new construction, you need to hire an agent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When buying a new construction home, you absolutely need an agent on your side representing your interests. There are a few key reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, while the builder’s agent may be friendly and helpful, &lt;strong&gt;they still represent the builder&lt;/strong&gt;. They have a fiduciary responsibility to represent their interests, and if you enter into the transaction and give them more information about yourself, they can use it against you. Their incentive is to get you to pay more for the property so they make more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads us to our next point: Without representation, the builder’s agent will be the one helping you pick out all of your upgrades, and &lt;strong&gt;they’ll inevitably suggest making every upgrade possible&lt;/strong&gt;. Having an agent working for you provides a voice of temperament when it comes to choosing upgrades. They’ll help you be smarter about where to spend your hard-earned money and avoid expensive, unnecessary upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Having representation when building a new home doesn’t cost you anything.%20http://localhost:4000/why-do-you-need-representation-when-buying-new-construction.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Having representation when building a new home doesn’t cost you anything.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, having representation means &lt;strong&gt;having a second set of eyes to look over the builder’s purchase agreement&lt;/strong&gt;. Most builders have their own purchase agreement, and these are usually lengthy documents. Your agent can identify any mistakes, keep the builder honest, and make sure all contractual items are in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, having representation when building a new home doesn’t cost you anything. Contrary to what some may think, in this market, builders usually won’t give you a discount if you don’t have your own representative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about how an agent can help you when buying new construction or have any other real estate questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-do-you-need-representation-when-buying-new-construction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-do-you-need-representation-when-buying-new-construction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can Sellers Expect in the New Normal?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZlajAHn1qu0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;For home sellers, there&amp;rsquo;s a new normal in the market. Here&amp;rsquo;s what it looks like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a home seller, it’s wise to minimize the physical contact that potential buyers have with the stuff in your home as they walk through to view it. Leave the doors and drawers open so that buyers can visually access your home without having to touch anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing you can do is leave hand sanitizer along with instructions at your home’s entrance. &lt;strong&gt;Visitors should be instructed to use the hand sanitizer before coming in and after walking through your home&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also encourage you to discuss your comfort levels with your Colemere Realty associate regarding how many showings you want to have, how many people you want to enter your house, etc. If you’d rather keep your home’s exposure to others to a minimum, you can always pursue virtual showings and open houses instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once showings are over, be sure to turn all the lights off and &lt;strong&gt;take disinfectant wipes to all the surfaces in your house that people are likely to touch&lt;/strong&gt;, like light switches and doorknobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’d rather keep your home’s exposure to others to a minimum, you can always pursue virtual showings and open houses instead.%20http://localhost:4000/what-can-sellers-expect-in-the-new-normal.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’d rather keep your home’s exposure to others to a minimum, you can always pursue virtual showings and open houses instead.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ll let buyers know that they need to stay home if they’re not feeling well to reduce the risk of spread. If you, the seller, feel like you’re coming down with something, &lt;strong&gt;don’t be afraid to put showings on hold&lt;/strong&gt;. There are plenty of virtual options out there for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what safety precautions are being implemented to keep buyers and sellers safe during the pandemic, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to provide you with more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-can-sellers-expect-in-the-new-normal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-can-sellers-expect-in-the-new-normal.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
