<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philadelphia Real Estate Video Blog with The Salas Team</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Salas Team is to be your best resource for Philadelphia real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Salas Team, your professional Philadelphia Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://salasteamrealestate.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 15:46:15 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 15:46:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>9 Silly Things That Could be Sabotaging Your Home Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AFjdum6AmCA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you are preparing to list your home for sale or already have it on the market, you should know about the things that may be sabotaging your home sale. These are the nine silly things that I am going to share with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.  Cords hanging from your mounted television.&lt;/strong&gt; Putting the cords behind the wall is a small expense but it makes a room look cleaner and brighter. Buyers want the ideal home and if they see cords along the wall it breaks the fantasy in their minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Unkempt yard&lt;/strong&gt;. First impressions are lasting impressions. The first thing someone sees when they drive up to your home is your yard, so you want to make sure it looks tidy and maintained to make the best impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Dingy front door.&lt;/strong&gt; On the same note as before, painting or power washing your front door can make all the difference to a buyer’s first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Animals.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people have pets that they love, but a buyer might have a sensitive nose. They may smell a dog and not want to come into the house. Sellers must also be very cautious of pet odors because although we may be unable to smell it, other people can. You can eliminate pet odors with plug-in filters, just make sure you do not make it too overpowering for the same reasons. I recommend storing all pet toys and beds while showing a home, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Sellers must be very cautious of pet smells because although we may be unable to smell it, other people can.%20http://salasteamrealestate.org/9-silly-things-that-could-be-sabotaging-your-home-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Sellers must be very cautious of pet smells because although we may be unable to smell it, other people can.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Cobwebs.&lt;/strong&gt; I know that it’s silly to think about, but if your house has a bunch of cobwebs or dust lying around, someone may think you are not there often, which puts you at a disadvantage. Some people may think that they can negotiate because you are a desperate seller. Have someone come through your home occasionally to remove the cobwebs and give you the best chance of a full-priced sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Poor furniture arrangement.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers want to imagine where they are going to put their furniture. If you have bigger pieces, consider minimizing the furniture in the room to make that room appear bigger and streamlined. Don’t be afraid to rearrange a room to look more organized. The new arrangement may not be functional for your family but if it’s a standard arrangement, buyers will be open to imagining their own arrangements. We can also help with staging if you prefer to use staged pieces rather than your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Junk drawers and crammed cabinets.&lt;/strong&gt; I feel it’s acceptable to have one junk drawer, but any more and people will wonder if the house is going to be big enough for them. Cleaning out clutter and keeping drawers and cabinets tidy opens space in your home, making it spacious for buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Overfilled closets.&lt;/strong&gt; Anything that is out of season can be stored away so that the closet is not as stuffed. Remove any excess hangers and clear the bottom of the shelves because buyers always look in the closets. They want to make sure they have enough room for their shoes and other items and having a tidy space for them that is functioning but not over-filled is the perfect way to grab their attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Cluttered countertops.&lt;/strong&gt; We all love our coffee or tea in the morning, so keeping out a kettle or a coffee pot is okay but storing away any extra appliances and knick-knacks creates extra space. The buyer can see how much counter space they can potentially have to prepare food and entertain. It’s all about playing into the buyer’s fantasy home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions or are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 09:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/9-silly-things-that-could-be-sabotaging-your-home-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://salasteamrealestate.org/9-silly-things-that-could-be-sabotaging-your-home-sale.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Costs Can You Expect When Selling a Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/od8ZOBYu3fM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to go into the details of the costs of selling your home. If you’re ready to get your property out there, &lt;strong&gt;these are some of the costs you can expect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Paying for upfront repairs.&lt;/strong&gt; This isn’t always the case for home sellers, but more often than not, it is. When I visit a home for the first time, I look for any glaring repairs that need to be done before listing. This will ensure the home is shown in its best light. I’ll make recommendations for staging as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Commissions.&lt;/strong&gt; You can anticipate an average commision rate of 6% to 8% depending on the type of service you opt for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt; Depending on the state you’re in, closing costs may vary. In Pennsylvania, these costs are split 50/50 with the buyer. That would include a transfer tax, a mortgage and deed recording tax, etc. If you’re in New Jersey, the seller typically pays that transfer tax on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You may incur additional repair costs after the buyer inspects the home.%20http://salasteamrealestate.org/what-costs-can-you-expect-when-selling-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You may incur additional repair costs after the buyer inspects the home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. HOA fees.&lt;/strong&gt; If your home is a condo or part of an HOA, you are going to have to order a resale certificate and association documents for the buyer prior to closing. This is an upfront cost you’ll have to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. After-repair costs.&lt;/strong&gt; After the buyer has had their home inspection, it’s possible they might ask you to repair certain items or ask for a credit for those repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Payoffs.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a mortgage, any kind of lien, or utility balances, you’ll need to pay those off at closing as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Moving expenses.&lt;/strong&gt; You might have to pay for some storage as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Cleaning expenses.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the basic costs of selling your home. If you have any questions or want to discuss any of these things further, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email anytime. I look forward to working with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 13:15:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/what-costs-can-you-expect-when-selling-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://salasteamrealestate.org/what-costs-can-you-expect-when-selling-a-home.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Things You Should Know as a First-Time Homebuyer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B5DHrEWbUz0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you want to buy your first home and you’re ready to get out there and start looking at properties. I’m excited for you! I love working with first-time homebuyers. It’s a fun experience, but sometimes it can be a little stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to share five tips that will help you during the process of buying your first home.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Pick a great agent.&lt;/strong&gt; You want to work with somebody who takes the time to understand what it is that you are looking for. It is important for them to know your needs and wants. You need to have a great working relationship since you are going to be working with this person for potentially several months.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;You will also need that person to be someone who listens to you. While Realtors know what you want, they still need to be willing to listen, so don’t work with someone who is pushing you.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Establish a plan.&lt;/strong&gt; You need to know where you want to be. Other important factors to consider are what kinds of things you want in your home, your commute time to work, or even schools in the area. You should have somebody who understands the areas you’re looking to buy.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3. Determine your financing.&lt;/strong&gt; How are you going to pay for this house? A Realtor’s job is not to know about your personal financial situation, but a good agent will have great lending firms they can introduce you to and who you can work with directly. The lender can help you understand the different packages and products to help you pick the right product for you. Then the agent will work with the lender to help you find the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=While Realtors know what you want, they still need to be willing to listen.%20http://salasteamrealestate.org/5-things-you-should-know-as-a-first-time-homebuyer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“While Realtors know what you want, they still need to be willing to listen.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Get to know the neighborhood.&lt;/strong&gt; Go out and find what neighborhood you want to be in. While I can give you an idea of the neighborhoods, it is still up to you to decide if you can live in a particular area.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;I recommend that you walk around at different times of the day and see if a neighborhood is comfortable to you. You should also schedule a visit with the schools, check out the shops, and go to the parks. It will give you a good idea of the community.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Understand the pricing and the seller.&lt;/strong&gt; A good agent is going to know the pricing in different areas. It can vary greatly, especially in cities. So, you want to make sure that you have an agent that understands the differences between the neighborhoods and how to come up with a comp plan on a particular home.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Finally, you want them to understand the seller. Once you find a house, you want to make sure your agent understands the seller’s perspective. What do they want from the house to make sure that we are giving you the best negotiating techniques and tips possible to get you the home that you really want?&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions or would like to sit down and go through a buyer’s consultation, please contact me by phone or email. I would be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 10:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/5-things-you-should-know-as-a-first-time-homebuyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://salasteamrealestate.org/5-things-you-should-know-as-a-first-time-homebuyer.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Let a Bad Credit Score Stop You From Buying a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pCigM-xPV5k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on buying a home but you’re not sure whether your credit score is high enough to qualify for a loan, don’t worry. Here are a few tips that can help you still become a homeowner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, try utilizing these credit repair strategies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lower your credit utilization rate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Request a credit limit increase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Become an authorized user for someone with good credit history&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consolidate your debt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also several government loan products, such as a VA or FHA loan, that require a FICO score as low as 300.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t let a bad credit score stop you from buying a home%20http://salasteamrealestate.org/dont-let-a-bad-credit-score-stop-you-from-buying-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Don’t let a bad credit score stop you from buying a home”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re having trouble with your down payment, there are several city and state programs that can help you, including the Homestead Down Payment and Closing Cost Assistance Loan, the Keystone Advantage Assistance Loan Program, the First Front Door Program, and the Settlement Assistance Grant from the Division of Housing and Community Development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or you’d like to know more about any of these programs, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 17:42:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/dont-let-a-bad-credit-score-stop-you-from-buying-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://salasteamrealestate.org/dont-let-a-bad-credit-score-stop-you-from-buying-a-home.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Upgrade Your Home’s Exterior With These Quick Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OqZFPWHSwYQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have a few tips to share with you that will help you upgrade the outside of your home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re selling your home or making sure it’s well-maintained heading into spring, here are a few tips that will help you upgrade its exterior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, replace or clean the siding. Take a look around the outside of your home and search for any damaged siding that needs to be replaced. Also, spray off any dirt or mold or consider hiring a professional to power-wash your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, keep an eye out for any dry rot, especially around door and window frames. Scrape off any peeling materials, sand, and/or paint to make your home more attractive to buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you have any roof damage, have it repaired before putting your home on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; If your concrete is in disrepair, that could become a hazard, so consider having any broken or uneven concrete fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A fresh coat of stain can go a long way.%20http://salasteamrealestate.org/upgrade-your-homes-exterior-with-these-quick-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A fresh coat of stain can go a long way.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a deck or patio, keep that clear of any debris. A great way to give these areas a great new look is to have them power-washed. If they’re made of wood, a fresh coat of stain can also go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fences can sometimes fall into disrepair and give your home a shabby look, so make sure you have any missing boards replaced and painted or stained to match the rest of the fencing. Your gates should also open and close smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t kept up your home’s maintenance or you have doubts about its condition, you can always &lt;strong&gt;get a home inspection done before listing&lt;/strong&gt; to give yourself peace of mind knowing it will sell without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like more tips on how to upgrade your home’s exterior or you have any other real estate questions I can help you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to assist you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/upgrade-your-homes-exterior-with-these-quick-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://salasteamrealestate.org/upgrade-your-homes-exterior-with-these-quick-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Expect From Your First Meeting With Us</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yFc36SIEOJo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s it like to meet with the Salas Team? Whatever your real estate needs, we are here to help. Today, I’d like to go over what you can expect when you start working with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are looking to purchase a property, your first meeting with us will be a buyer’s consultation.&lt;/strong&gt; During this consultation, we’ll discuss your wants and needs. We’ll go over where you’d like to live, what kind of property you’re looking for, and other specifics. Next, we’ll explain the entire process of purchasing a home using what we call our “homebuyer roadmap.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are looking to sell a home, the process will also begin with us meeting for a consultation.&lt;/strong&gt; We will visit your property, discuss your intentions for the sale, and talk about price and value. We’ll also point out any areas in your home that might benefit from repairs or updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Understanding your preferences, needs, and intentions will help us best serve you.%20http://salasteamrealestate.org/what-to-expect-from-your-first-meeting-with-us.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Understanding your preferences, needs, and intentions will help us best serve you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to know what your expectations are for us, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re looking to invest in real estate, we will meet to discuss your intentions.&lt;/strong&gt; We can’t help you unless we know what it is that you want. Understanding your preferences will help us best serve you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what your real estate needs, the last step of our meeting will be to explain all of our services to you. Because we’re a team, many different people will be assisting you throughout the process. We really want you to feel that we’re on your side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 12:05:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/what-to-expect-from-your-first-meeting-with-us.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://salasteamrealestate.org/what-to-expect-from-your-first-meeting-with-us.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Tips to Drive Your Home Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tSzLDEAxVJ8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are six tips I always share with my clients that can help you drive your home sale to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Price it right.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want to overprice your home, because you won’t attract enough buyers to actually show up and look at the property. Most buyers have search ranges, and if your home is over their range, they won’t even take a look at it. It will also hurt you in the long run because if you price the home too high initially and you have to keep reducing that price while the home sits on the market, buyers will be suspicious of it and wonder what’s wrong with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Understand buyer preferences.&lt;/strong&gt; If your house has multi-colored bedrooms with many different types of furniture, that might not be very popular among the buyers of today. You might be better off switching things to a more neutral color. Your agent can certainly help you with this kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Stage and declutter.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure someone walking into your home can envision it as their home. If you have lots of clutter and personal items lying around, that will make doing that hard for them. Don’t forget to declutter your closets too, because buyers always check those to make sure there’s enough room for their stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure someone walking into your home can envision it as their home.%20http://salasteamrealestate.org/6-tips-to-drive-your-home-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure someone walking into your home can envision it as their home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Repair any pet damage.&lt;/strong&gt;Oftentimes, dogs and cats can leave scratch marks around doors and door frames, so make sure that kind of thing is repaired. You also want to check for smells. It’s hard to notice your own house’s pet odor, but buyers will definitely notice if a house has a dog or cat smell. That being said, don’t overpower the house with potpourri, because that can give off the wrong impression as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Enhance the home’s curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt;This can be tougher in wintertime, but you want to make sure anyone approaching your house sees a clean driveway and walkway and a sharp exterior. In springtime, it’s a good idea to plant some flowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Focus on marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; Roughly 99% of all buyers today look online when searching for a home, which means the first thing they see are photos. You want to make sure those photos pop and impress them enough to want to see your property in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about how to drive your home sale or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 14:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/6-tips-to-drive-your-home-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://salasteamrealestate.org/6-tips-to-drive-your-home-sale.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Questions to Ask a Potential Real Estate Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/77X_16jYEHg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should never ask a magician their secrets, but I don’t feel the same way about real estate. Today, I’m going to clue you into a couple “magician’s secrets” of real estate by providing you with insider questions you should ask a potential listing agent when making your decision about who to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What is your average sales-to-list price ratio?&lt;/strong&gt; When you sell your home, you’ll decide on a price for it. Ultimately, you want your home to sell for at least that price, but it could also sell for less. The market average right now is about 92%, but here at the Salas Team, we actually sell with a 96% sales-to-list price ratio. But not every agent is built the same, and some agents will only sell the home for 80% to 85% of the original list price. Ask this question to make sure that your agent meets the industry standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What is your marketing strategy?&lt;/strong&gt; For instance, do they stage the homes they’re trying to sell? You want an agent who is experienced and can tell you what a potential buyer will want to see so that you can prepare your home to sell for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do they use professional photography?&lt;/strong&gt; Never settle for an agent who uses their iPhone or Android to take pictures of your home. A good agent should have someone on staff with professional equipment and and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Look for key indicators of success, such as how many houses they’ve sold.%20http://salasteamrealestate.org/4-questions-to-ask-a-potential-real-estate-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Look for key indicators of success, such as how many houses they’ve sold.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do they have a strong social media presence and knowledge of online advertisement?&lt;/strong&gt; In our social media-driven society, it is so important to be up to date on the latest internet technologies. You can access demographic information to predict who is most likely to be looking for a house. They should have a properly segmented database, and use Facebook and Google advertising to their best advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do they do circle prospecting?&lt;/strong&gt; Your agent and their team should be calling around the neighborhood to ask if anyone is thinking of buying a house. This is critically important in a market with tight inventory. You want an agent who will proactively market on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What is your success rate?&lt;/strong&gt; Look for key indicators of success, such as how many houses they’ve sold. The average agent sells about three homes a year. The Salas Team, however, has repeatedly sold 150 homes a year. An agent who sells many homes has the experience to be able to advise their client in the best way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Are you part-time or full-time?&lt;/strong&gt;The popularity of real estate shows like those on HGTV has brought a lot of people into the market thinking that it’s a flexible career. But a part-time agent isn’t good enough for you. This is, in many cases, the biggest financial transaction in your lifetime, and you’ll want someone who knows what they’re doing and can devote their full attention to your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking these questions is a great way to get a look at how experienced the agent is and whether or not they have the level of expertise you need in order to satisfy your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us, we’ll be more than happy to give you answer. Feel free to reach out to us by phone or email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 04:38:14 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/4-questions-to-ask-a-potential-real-estate-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://salasteamrealestate.org/4-questions-to-ask-a-potential-real-estate-agent.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Tips for a Successful Home Buying Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MGLf2qZsRnA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the seven habits of highly effective homebuyers? If you’re ready to enter the market and start looking for your new home, here are some great tips to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Get pre-qualified.&lt;/strong&gt; Be ready to buy as soon as you find the right home. Sellers are going to want to see a pre-qualification letter to know that you are truly capable of purchasing the property. You should become pre-qualified before even beginning your search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Define your “must-haves,” your “like-to-haves,” and your “don’t-wants.”&lt;/strong&gt; At our buyer’s consultation, my team and I will go over these things with you. It’s important to determine what you’re really looking for in a home. Once you do, you can break down those desires into the categories I mentioned earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Be realistic.&lt;/strong&gt; Today’s market is short on inventory. With that being the case, buyers simply won’t be able to lowball sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Be open and flexible.&lt;/strong&gt; As a buyer, you won’t always get everything you want. It’s certainly good to focus on what you want and don’t want from a property during your search, but try not to expect the perfect house. Remember that you can always change things after you move in. Don’t get caught up in trying to find a home that’s already perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t get caught up in trying to find a home that’s already perfect.%20http://salasteamrealestate.org/7-tips-for-a-successful-home-buying-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Don’t get caught up in trying to find a home that’s already perfect.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Understand the home buying process.&lt;/strong&gt; Our team wants to help you understand what you can expect. When you meet with us for a consultation, we will walk you through every step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Be responsible and maintain your credit.&lt;/strong&gt; I can’t tell you how many times I’ve had issues with buyers paying off some major debt right before closing. It might sound counterintuitive, but paying off a loan or a credit card right before you close can actually sink your credit. Also, hold off any major purchases until after closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Have fun with the process.&lt;/strong&gt; My entire team and I truly want you to have the best home buying experience possible. If you let us help, we will make sure the process is as smooth and as enjoyable as it can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 03:47:19 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/7-tips-for-a-successful-home-buying-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://salasteamrealestate.org/7-tips-for-a-successful-home-buying-process.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Easy Steps for Selling Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_zqIGulibKs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to share three easy steps for selling your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first step I recommend is planning.&lt;/strong&gt; When it comes to selling, a lot of mistakes can come from a lack of preparation. If you take the time to plan things out, you will be more successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goes for selling a home, as well. One thing to consider is when and where you move. If you have children in school, you may want to think about which point during the school year you want to make your move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the planning process means having your real estate with you for at least 30 to 60 days before you plan to sell. &lt;strong&gt;In this current climate, it could take 30 to 45 days to find the right buyer.&lt;/strong&gt; And even once you’ve found a buyer, it could take an additional 30, 40, or even 60 days to actually close. You really need to plan for this amount of time in order to be successful with your home sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Taking the time to plan things out will greatly benefit your listing.%20http://salasteamrealestate.org/3-easy-steps-for-selling-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Taking the time to plan things out will greatly benefit your listing.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second step has to do with first impressions.&lt;/strong&gt; When it comes to selling houses, first impressions matter. The first 30 days of the process are especially important. Some of the ways you can make sure your home gives off the right impression to buyers are by neutralizing and decluttering. Also, be sure to have a professional take the photos for your listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third and final step is to make sure you price it right.&lt;/strong&gt; I know you probably hear this tip over and over again, but it is so critical in today’s market. The strategy of pricing a home high and waiting to negotiate down simply isn’t a good idea. All that does is lead to more haggling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to price your home right, you should take the time to do a comparative market analysis. My team will perform this for you by sitting down to really examine your home and the competitive landscape around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 07:06:48 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/3-easy-steps-for-selling-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://salasteamrealestate.org/3-easy-steps-for-selling-your-home.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
