<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Utah's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Joshua Stern, a top Real Estate Agent in Salt Lake City, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 15:35:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 15:35:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Focus Your Business on the 3 L’s: Leads, Listings, and Leverage</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ejmMbU3gwwA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create the foundation of a successful real estate business, you need to focus on the three L’s: leads, listings, and leverage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My original mentor in real estate, Gary Keller, wrote a book called “The Millionaire Real Estate Agent,” in which he describes a triangle of success. In that triangle, each side represents one of the three L’s: leads, listings, and leverage. At the center of this triangle is your value proposition. Once you find your value proposition, your next step is to build your business around the three L’s, and here’s how. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leads:&lt;/strong&gt; As Gary said, “Lead generation comes first, it comes last, and it comes always.” Gary also said that real estate is a contact sport, so agents should be prospecting-based and marketing-enhanced. Protect your daily lead generation time blocks—I recommend no less than three hours a day. I also recommend lead generating first thing in the morning while your willpower is still on will call. Also, try using scripts—I recommend role-playing scripts or real-playing scripts each day, every day, for the rest of your career. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, learn to make effective offers for immediate response. On the Stern Team, we call these “MOFIRs” (make offer for immediate response). They’re great for following up and getting an appointment. Start tracking your lead sources and your conversion rates and be sure to hold actions accountable to your results. Goals are dictators of actions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Find your value proposition and build your business around it.%20http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/why-you-should-focus-your-business-on-the-3-ls-leads-listings-and-leverage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Find your value proposition and build your business around it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listings:&lt;/strong&gt; Setting serious goals for listing appointments and being accountable to these goals is paramount. For example, setting two to two-and-a-half appointments per day, five days a week, with a 75% conversion rate puts an agent on the path toward earning $1 million. Know the minimum number of listings you’ll need to hit your income goals you set forth in the one-page business strategy coaching video. Be accountable for hitting your minimum goals; raise your sales price if you need to be more effective. Implement a systematic marketing and servicing plan for your listings and consistently market seller leads for more listings. Get sellers to accept the specialist concept for those who are running teams now or in the future. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage:&lt;/strong&gt; There are two types of leverage—systems leverage and people leverage. To create people leverage, hire the right people the first time around. At Keller Williams, they teach a career visioning class that I think should be taken at least twice a year, every year, for the rest of your career. Learning to hire the right person and place them on the right seat on the right bus going in the right direction is something you need help with, so follow a lead generation plan and a follow-up recruiting process. Use compensation and opportunity as a competitive weapon. Hire unproven or emerging talent. Implement a 90-day action-and-results training program for your new hires. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many agents are ill-equipped for this that they tend to hire and let the talent learn for themselves. Well, guess what? World-class onboarding and training processes is a must for talent if you want that talent to stay with you. Use the 1-3-5 (or GPS) plan and then use the 411 plan to create accountability with your new team member on a weekly basis. Finally, remember to topgrade and build a bench as you go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle around the triangle is service, and &lt;strong&gt;service is key if you want to stay in business for the long haul.&lt;/strong&gt; Exceptional service should be a given in this day and age. You should be servicing your clients to the point where they heartily refer you to everyone they know. When you close a transaction, remember—you don’t run away from your client, you run toward them. If you turn this triangle upside down with creativity, you’ll only get instability. This model will absolutely stand the test of time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this topic or there’s anything I can help you with, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/why-you-should-focus-your-business-on-the-3-ls-leads-listings-and-leverage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/why-you-should-focus-your-business-on-the-3-ls-leads-listings-and-leverage.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Me Teach You How To Master Success</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YV0NJJfkFo4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a millionaire agent seeking to help others achieve their greatness potential, I’m going to be teaching a live class on September 18th from 4-5 pm. There is no cost to attend and there are no strings attached, which is pretty rare in today’s time. I’ll teach you about the six paths to personal mastery and the science of success. By mastering each of these six perspectives, you will begin to see the subtle, then sudden, aggregation of these traits in your personal and professional success. If you’d like to start on this path, join us at 2121 S. McClelland St., Suite 201 in Salt Lake City, just above the Habit Burger. Space is limited, so RSVP today. I look forward to seeing you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/let-me-teach-you-how-to-master-success.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/let-me-teach-you-how-to-master-success.html</guid>
        
        <category>Reviews and Referrals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Science of Success and the 6 Steps of Mastery</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UFbq0WdBvm4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had the opportunity to act as a guest speaker on the Salt Lake Community College program “Bruin Voices.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps which will direct you to various subjects I go over in the video above. Feel free to watch my full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;00:13 - Introduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;00:51 - Creating a personal mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:39 - The science of success and the six paths to mastery: Self-mastery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:44 - The science of success and the six paths to mastery: Implementation of 80/20 rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:30 - The science of success and the six paths to mastery: Moving from “E” to “P”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:12 - The science of success and the six paths to mastery: Having a learning-based mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:34 - The science of success and the six paths to mastery: Remove limiting beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:59 - The science of success and the six paths to mastery: Accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:49 - Review and demonstration of the science of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/the-science-of-success-and-the-6-steps-of-mastery.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/the-science-of-success-and-the-6-steps-of-mastery.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Me Teach You How to Build Your Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/akqJbV1GdIk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a millionaire agent seeking to help others achieve their greatness potential, I’m going to be teaching &lt;strong&gt;a live class on August 21 from 4 p.m. to 5 p.m&lt;/strong&gt; at our office (2121 S. McClelland St., Suite 201, Salt Lake City, Utah). There is no cost to attend and there are no strings attached, which is pretty rare in today’s time. I’ll teach you how to build a massive real estate business through talent and the new seven levels to a million dollar, passive income real estate business. You’ll also learn who to hire, when to hire, and where to find the talent. We’ll be at 2121 S. McClelland St., Suite 201 in Salt Lake City, just above the Habit Burger. &lt;strong&gt;Space is limited, so &lt;a href=&quot;http://realestatecareersinutah.com/register/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RSVP today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; I look forward to seeing you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/let-me-teach-you-how-to-build-your-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/let-me-teach-you-how-to-build-your-business.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gaining and Understanding the Power of the 4-1-1 Calendar</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C7z3rgPl4l8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s next millionaire mindset tip, I will talk about how to use the 4-1-1 calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our last millionaire mindset coaching tip, we talked about the GPS plan, also known as the 1-3-5 plan. As you may remember, this is a simple one-page business plan to help you achieve your goals. If you do not have your plan in place, you can rewatch the video &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a data-cms-editor-link-style=&quot;undefined&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://realestatecareersinutah.com/a-one-page-business-plan-to-achieve-your-goals.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal now is to turn your to-do list into a success list. &lt;strong&gt;This simple template for weekly, monthly, and annual planning turns your “one thing” intentions into actions. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Begin with your annual goal in mind and then drill down into the monthly and weekly milestones you must achieve to hit that goal. I look at monthly goals as my parking lot. This is where I put the strategies for my 4-1-1 that I intend to work on for the month. I then begin the process of unpacking these items from the monthly goals into the weekly goals. The weekly goals are a must-do list, not a task list. Goals, after all, are a dictator of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The 1-3-5 plan combined with the 4-1-1 calendar will create the success you deserve.%20http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/gaining-and-understanding-the-power-of-the-4-1-1-calendar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The 1-3-5 plan combined with the 4-1-1 calendar will create the success you deserve.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the goal is unpacked into weekly must-do items, the next step is to calendar those items to actually get them done. Each weekend, I create my 4-1-1 success list and calendar the most important things I need to get done. When adding must-do’s to your calendar, remember to leave plenty of white space, because real estate is a business that is expandable. You will need time to take care of working in your business as well as working on your business, so it is important not to have a schedule that is overfilled.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am usually able to finish between three and five must-do’s per week from each of the four categories in the 4-1-1. Do not try to do more than seven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I show up to the office, I have my must-do calendar set, which helps bulletproof myself from myself. I simply show up and follow what is on my calendar. Like I require of all my coaching clients, &lt;strong&gt;review and update your 4-1-1 on a weekly business and do it away from the office before the week starts to amplify your success. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1-3-5 plan combined with the 4-1-1 calendar and a disciplined approach to that calendar will create the success you deserve. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about today’s topic, please feel free to reach out to me. I would love to discuss the 4-1-1 calendar with you further.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/gaining-and-understanding-the-power-of-the-4-1-1-calendar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/gaining-and-understanding-the-power-of-the-4-1-1-calendar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Systematizing and Creating a Referral Machine</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HBJRhQ19gHM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m back to share another great tip in the Millionaire Agent Mindset series. This time, our conversation will focus on referrals from current clients, as these are our very best lead source. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, ask yourself this: &lt;strong&gt;What is your system for servicing clients at the highest level in this industry?&lt;/strong&gt; Do you run away after settlement or do you lean in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our team, we set up an expectation of excellence. Our clients know to expect the best from us. Simultaneously, we also set up an expectation that they will refer us to people they know. This is a staple of low-cost and repeat, or referral, business. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I once learned a script from an agent named Mike Hicks in the small, 70,000-person town of Idaho Falls. Mike does nearly 500 transaction sides per year, with most of his business coming from current client referrals. Upon finding this out, I wanted to know his secret for success. According to Mike, it starts with the script I mentioned earlier, which he calls the “Promise Script.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend implementing this script into your own business. Start by reciting it verbatim, and then, once you’ve internalized it, you can personalize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So imagine that you’ve just signed a listing with a client. At this point, &lt;strong&gt;it’s time to implement the Promise Script, which I’ve included for you here: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, before you go, there’s one more thing. Do you have just another minute? Okay. Let’s talk about our promise. You see, our group has this promise—this goal—to create an experience that you, honestly, really cannot imagine being any better. Our systems and everything we do are designed around delivering on this promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everyone in our group is focused on what it is you want and what it is that you need. We make every effort to be out in front of everything—to stop surprises, and keep it as good as it can be. Now, there will be challenges. We know that there will be. It’s real estate, and it’s people. But just know that our group is focused on creating that 10+ experience, if you will. Does that sound okay? Great. So there’s something that I want. Just to say it, we have another goal. And that is, some time from right now until the day that we close on your home, that you’re going to feel so great about what we’re doing for you that you’re going to call me, text me, or email me with the name of somebody who needs help in real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“See, they might just have a general question, they might need to buy or sell a home, they might need to refinance, or just need some help in real estate. So while we’re working together, you’re hopefully going to be giving my name out, which I truly appreciate because word of mouth is our lifeblood. Yet I need you to take it to the next step. To make sure I have a chance to help, in addition giving out my name, I want you to call, email, or text us their information so there’s a 100% chance I can get in touch with them. Okay. That’ll be great. So you’re going to call right? That going to be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now, if we get to the day of closing, we’ve sat down at the closing table, and we’ve signed all the paperwork, and you haven’t got in touch with me with the name of somebody that we can help, I’m going to have to assume that our group didn’t deliver on the promise—that we could’ve done something better. So I’m going to have to ask you the hard question, and that is what we could have, or should have, done differently in order to have earned that referral. Will that be okay? Great. Well, listen: I’m going to count on it. And I’m going to count on you sending that referral to me, okay?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The byproduct of excellent service and asking for business is referrals.%20http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/systematizing-and-creating-a-referral-machine.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The byproduct of excellent service and asking for business is referrals.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, go ahead and shake the clients hand or make a physical connection like placing a hand on their shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This script is the start of our team’s high-level service, and it sets the expectations for what we will deliver throughout the transaction.&lt;/strong&gt; As a service provider, you’re going to be graded on your systems by your clientele. With our clients, our goal is to communicate early and often over the course of transactions. There should never be a week that goes by where our clients don’t hear from us, even after settlement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use a system of good news in making these communications. So, for example, after we begin working with sellers we send them a copy of documents they’ve signed and a short video thanking them for their trust and confidence. It is at this point where we will call them to confirm information like our photography date, as well as our first open house. During this phone call, we’ll also deliver the Reticular Activating System (or RAS) Script. This neurological system is responsible for behavioral alertness, which will come to be important in gaining referrals. &lt;strong&gt;We’ve already delivered the Promise Script, so here’s what the RAS Script looks like: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hi [Client Name], it’s Joshua Stern calling. Just wanted to make sure that you received an email with a copy of the signed paperwork. Fabulous. Did you get a chance to watch the short video? No? Okay well, briefly, it’s a RAS video. You do know what RAS is, right? Well, the RAS is the reticular activating system within our brain, and the easiest way for me to explain this to you is: Do you remember the last time you bought your car? All of a sudden you notice all the other folks driving that same car. You hadn’t noticed them prior to buying your car. Well, that’s the RAS. And now that we’re working together, I wanted to let you know that you’re going to run into between one and three people who are thinking of buying or selling a home. And I just wanted to remind you to call, email, or text me their information so there’s a 100% chance that we can get ahold of them. And I promise that I’ll make you look good.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take these servicing touches very seriously. We have an entire series of emails, calls, and videos using scripts we follow up with throughout the transaction, including after closing. &lt;strong&gt;Our post-closing plan is actually where 80% of our client referrals come from.&lt;/strong&gt; Imagine if you had a systematic servicing plan for all of your clients. The byproduct of excellent service and asking for business is referrals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/systematizing-and-creating-a-referral-machine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/systematizing-and-creating-a-referral-machine.html</guid>
        
        <category>Reviews and Referrals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A One-Page Business Plan to Achieve Your Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cTWFV_A3QGA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a millionaire agent mindset tip for you today: how to create a one-page business plan to move your career forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think the No. 1 thing that prevents people from reaching their goals is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is clarity. See, in real estate, we must start out by asking ourselves, “What’s the math that I need to do?” For instance, your units multiplied by the average home price will equal your sales volume. Your volume multiplied by your average commission equals your net income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this going to take care of your big dreams? That’s the question you should ask yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you have the numbers nailed down, here’s what your 1-3-5, or your GPS plan (goals, priorities, and strategies), will look like:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three priorities necessary to achieve your one goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Five strategies under each priority to help  you reach the goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the basic format—&lt;strong&gt;here are the rules:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your plan must fit on a single sheet of paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your whole team needs to use the same format that you do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone must follow the template.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share it with others, or you won’t be held accountable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose the the real estate professional’s GPS goal is: I will close X number of homes, equaling X in volume, equaling X in GCI. With that, your No. 1 goal will be a dollar amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Priority No. 1: Number of buyers closed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll need to decide on what percentage of that GCI will actually be buyers closing. Underneath that priority, your strategies could be :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sphere of influence: what percentage of your buyers will you have to close via your sphere to hit your number?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open houses: what percentage of the buyers will come from open houses?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet leads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signs and flyers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First-time and move-up homebuyer classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as all the strategies added up are greater than your priority, then you know you’ll hit it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you really want to put the 1-3-5 business plan on steroids, you can create a separate page for each strategy, outlining five more strategy to accomplish each main one.%20http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/a-one-page-business-plan-to-achieve-your-goals.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you really want to put the 1-3-5 business plan on steroids, you can create a separate page for each strategy, outlining five more strategy to accomplish each main one.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Priority No. 2: Number of sellers closed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decide on a percentage and put in a number based on your goal. If you’re newer to the business, I find that 30% sellers and 70% buyers seems to be fairly normal, but as you age into the business, you’ll probably want to start focusing on the selling side. For the listing side, some of your strategies might be similar to the buyer side:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sphere of influence: what percentage of your buyers will you have to close via your sphere to hit your number?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open houses: what percentage of the buyers will come from open houses?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet leads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expired/FSBO listings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Farming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Priority No. 3: “Who-Have-Know-Be”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to get different results, you need to know different things, have different tools, know different people, and be in business with talent. Here are the strategies you might use to achieve success here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a coach.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hire an assistant.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hire a showing agent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get your systems in place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Educate yourself on leadership.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you really want to put the 1-3-5 business plan on steroids, you can create a separate page for each strategy, outlining five more strategies to accomplish each main one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The GPS plan is your roadmap. If you do it, you’ll find the holes in your business. If you share it, you’ll get results. If you unpack each strategy with further strategies, you’ll have a manual for how to run your business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next video, I’ll talk about how you can execute your GPS plan by using a document called a 4-1-1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about today’s topic, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to discuss the GPS plan with you further.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/a-one-page-business-plan-to-achieve-your-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/a-one-page-business-plan-to-achieve-your-goals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can Understanding the 80/20 Rule Help You Succeed?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PP_msCvmGK0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding and applying the 80/20 rule can help you tremendously with your success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the 80/20 rule? The 80/20 rule, also known as “Pareto’s principle,” was conceptualized by Italian economist Vilfredo Pareto. In 1906, he discovered that 80% of the wealth in Italy was owned by 20% of the population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;80/20 distribution of cause and effect occurs frequently.&lt;/strong&gt; In the real estate world, 80% of the homes are sold by 20% of the real estate agents. Actually, in any professional occupation, you’ll discover that 80% of the results (e.g. productivity and profitability) come from 20% of your (or the company’s) effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to real estate sales, we know there are five income-producing activities: &lt;strong&gt;scripts and role play, lead generation, lead follow-up, appointments, and negotiating contracts.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important to understand that not everything matters equally. You must focus your efforts on the 20% that matters most. We don’t need to master everything—we simply need to master the 20% that produces the 80%. Your goal in real estate sales should be to spend 80% of your own time in the 20% of those five activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does this work? If you have a list of 10 items to accomplish, two of those items will be worth more than the other eight items put together. The sad fact is, most people procrastinate on the top 10% or 20% of the items that are the most valuable and busy themselves instead with the more trivial 80%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What is the one thing you can do that, just by doing it, will make everything else easier or unnecessary?%20http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/how-can-understanding-the-8020-rule-help-you-succeed.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What is the one thing you can do that, just by doing it, will make everything else easier or unnecessary?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you apply the 80/20 rule to goal-setting and your overall productivity? First, take a piece of paper and write down 10 goals. Then, &lt;strong&gt;ask yourself if you could only accomplish one goal today, which one would have the greatest impact on your life? &lt;/strong&gt;After that, pick the second-most important goal. After you finish this exercise, you’ll have predetermined the most important 20% of your goals that will help you more than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, success is sequential. It’s not simultaneous. It’s like a geometric progression in life that’s set up like a row of dominos. If you focus on knocking down that first domino, you can rest assured that the rest will fall. This sounds simple, but it’s not easy. In real estate, easy is being distracted and focusing on urgent things that are cleverly disguised as important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, ask yourself, what is the one thing you can do that, just by doing it, will make everything else easier or unnecessary?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about applying the 80/20 rule to your goal-setting or there’s anything else I can help you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, good luck with your focus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/how-can-understanding-the-8020-rule-help-you-succeed.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://RealEstateCareersInUtah.com/how-can-understanding-the-8020-rule-help-you-succeed.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
