<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>davefriedmantv.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="davefriedmantv.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 13:54:20 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 13:54:20 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking Back on the 2018 Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JA5eGxvhDsM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we come closer to the end of the year, we’d like to wish you all a happy holiday season. Thank you so much for all of your support throughout the year; we’ve grown by 50% in our number of units sold in 2018!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we enter the new year, we’d like to do a quick recap of what we saw in our market throughout 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first half of the year was extremely strong and on track to exceed the units sold in 2017’s market. However, the second half slowed down a bit, &lt;strong&gt;meaning we’ll end up with about 1.7% fewer homes sold compared to last year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ve seen excess appreciation over the last several years, but now it’s beginning to normalize.%20davefriedmantv.com/looking-back-on-the-2018-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve seen excess appreciation over the last several years, but now it’s beginning to normalize.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have been asking me if we’re seeing a correction in our market—we are! We’ve seen excess appreciation over the last several years, but now it’s beginning to normalize. This isn’t a bad thing. We’re not seeing prices decrease or anything—we actually anticipate a 4% to 6% increase in appreciation over the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People have been seeing their homes stay on the market for longer, and some homes aren’t selling at all. &lt;strong&gt;This has been the case in our market as a whole.&lt;/strong&gt; However, our team’s average days on market remains at 10, and our listing-to-sale price ratio is still at 100%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need any real estate advice, have questions, or would like some more information, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to helping you! In the meantime, Happy Holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 12:41:21 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/looking-back-on-the-2018-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/looking-back-on-the-2018-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reserve Your Free Pie Today</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LPjuju3IZr8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the season for being thankful and this year we couldn’t be more thankful for you. It’s your referrals and your continued support of our team that allows us to help families year after year. This year we want to pay you back in some small way by giving you a free pie! We would love to have you come out, visit us, and pick up a pie on Monday, November 19 and Tuesday, November 20. With no strings attached and no cost to you, we just want to say thanks. RSVP to reserve your pie &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeCKsW3Lqx7cu2dbFGArdvh_HwFUD9wvXtERdP_KAz8ZQuD6w/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=%20davefriedmantv.com/reserve-your-free-pie-today.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 10:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/reserve-your-free-pie-today.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/reserve-your-free-pie-today.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Great Pumpkin Giveaway</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jx4Czcv4fq0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s message will be twofold. First, we would like to remind you of our upcoming second annual pumpkin giveaway, and second, we’d like to encourage you to help support Hurricane Florence relief efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the recent tropical storm, we could all use a bit of levity—so let’s begin with the lighter of these two subjects: Our pumpkin giveaway. This event will take place on Saturday, October 14 from 10 a.m. to 2 p.m. at Riverfront Park in Mount Pleasant, and we hope to see you there. We gave away over 1,000 pumpkins last year, and we have just as many to offer this year. &lt;strong&gt;To reserve your place, and your chance to snag one of these pumpkins, go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davesevents.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.davesevents.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; The giveaway will be first come first serve, so don’t delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there will be a lot of other things to enjoy at the event, as well. There will be a professional photographer offering family photos, a number of food trucks, and a face painter for the kids. Best of all, our team will also be using this event as an opportunity to give back. We’ve partnered once again with Lifeline, a great organization that places foster children into homes, to raise money for that cause. &lt;strong&gt;We raised more than $11,000 at last year’s event, and we hope to raise at least that much again this time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is going to be a great event. You won’t want to miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, let’s move on to the more essential of today’s two topics: The relief efforts for Hurricane Florence. We in Charleston are very fortunate that the storm didn’t hit us, but many other areas along the Carolina Coastline were impacted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We in Charleston are very fortunate that the storm didn’t hit us, but many other areas along the Carolina Coastline were impacted.%20davefriedmantv.com/the-great-pumpkin-giveaway.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We in Charleston are very fortunate that the storm didn’t hit us, but many other areas along the Carolina Coastline were impacted.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, many of us stocked up on toiletries, nonperishable food items, and other essentials in anticipation of the storm. Now that the potential for danger has passed, though, many are wondering what to do with these things. Our team would like to recommend that instead of leaving them to sit in storage, you donate them to those who were affected by the storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re taking donations at our office (located at 496 Bramson Court, Mount Pleasant), so we encourage you and anyone you know who has items to spare to join us in making a difference for those in need. &lt;strong&gt;We’re accepting over-the-counter medicine, canned food, bottled water, pet food, paper goods, construction tools, toiletries, and other such essential items&lt;/strong&gt;. Our hope is that, after collecting these items, we will be able to take an 18-wheeler full of them up to North Carolina where we will distribute the goods. If you’re able to contribute, we would highly appreciate your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 10:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/the-great-pumpkin-giveaway.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/the-great-pumpkin-giveaway.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Has Our Market Been Doing?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MQfEA9far10?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to cover two topics: First, a recap of a special event we recently participated in, and second, an update on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We just wrapped up our fifth annual community appreciation event and fundraiser for the MUSC Burned Children’s Fund&lt;/strong&gt;, and it was a blast. A ton of people came out to support the cause, and we met our goal of personally donating $5,000 to the fundraiser, and we raised a total of $22,000 for the 22nd anniversary of the MUSC Burned Children’s Fund and for Camp “Can Do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had an opportunity to go down to the camp and visit the kids there. It turned out to be a life-changing event for me. We learned what kind of an impact this camp has had on the kids and how it has shaped and changed their lives. To learn more about this organization and the awesome cause they serve, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.musckids.org/patients-and-visitors/patient-and-family-resources/community-resources-and-support-groups/burned-childrens-fund&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, on to our market update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market has been great this year. As a whole, &lt;strong&gt;the market has appreciated about 6%, which is a little bit higher than what you’d typically see&lt;/strong&gt;; usually we see gains of around 3% to 4%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some areas that have reached double digits, and much of Charleston is in the high single digits—around 8% or 9%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This increase in the median sales price is likely due to the amount of new construction in the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other areas like Goose Creek and Summerville have seen value appreciation of around 5% to 6%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Those with realistic expectations of their home’s value are going under contract, while those who overestimate aren’t having as much success.%20davefriedmantv.com/how-has-our-market-been-doing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Those with realistic expectations of their home’s value are going under contract, while those who overestimate aren’t having as much success.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the market is healthy. Year over year, we haven’t seen any increase in sales; this is because we don’t have as much inventory on the market as we did last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I’ve noticed is that &lt;strong&gt;some sellers have the perception that their home is worth way more than it really is.&lt;/strong&gt; If you look at active listings in the MLS, on average, they’re priced 11% higher per square foot than the homes that are actually selling. Those with realistic expectations of their home’s value are going under contract, while those who overestimate aren’t having as much success. &lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hose sellers might feel like there’s a market bubble that has burst, but really, they’re just forced to be more realistic about their home’s value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the market or our fundraising events, please reach out to me. I hope to hear from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 13:39:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/how-has-our-market-been-doing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/how-has-our-market-been-doing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vote for Us by July 25 and Join Us at the Park on August 8</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8hAp-OUb-cw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got two very exciting things to talk to you about today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, we have been nominated as the best real estate company in Charleston for the Post &amp;amp; Courier. They have a “Best of” competition each year and we were nominated once again. However, we really need your votes to follow through and win.&lt;a href=&quot;http://pnccontests.secondstreetapp.com/2018-Charlestons-Choice/gallery/109633660/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; You can click the link here, which will take you to the voting page.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;We need your vote by July 25!&lt;/strong&gt; Every single vote counts, so we appreciate all of your support.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We need your vote by July 25!%20davefriedmantv.com/vote-for-us-by-july-25-and-join-us-at-the-park-on-august-8.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We need your vote by July 25!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I wanted to tell you about our upcoming client and community appreciation event. &lt;strong&gt;On August 8 at Joe Riley Stadium, we’re giving away free tickets to you, your friends, and your family for the RiverDogs game.&lt;/strong&gt; All you have to do is RSVP at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davesevents.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Davesevents.org&lt;/a&gt; to make sure that we get enough tickets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll have your tickets out in front at the game, and &lt;strong&gt;f&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;or every ticket that you guys redeem through us, we’ll donate $5 to the MUSC Children’s Burn Fund.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re really trying to level up our game by setting a goal of $22,000 in donations. I’ll be donating a large portion of that, but additional donations are always appreciated (but not required).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I look forward to seeing you on August 8, and I look forward to our team winning the Post &amp;amp; Courier “Best of” competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the meantime about the real estate market or about anything else, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 14:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/vote-for-us-by-july-25-and-join-us-at-the-park-on-august-8.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/vote-for-us-by-july-25-and-join-us-at-the-park-on-august-8.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Coming Soon Program Explained</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yu8Kg8kdxEc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team’s “Coming Soon” program, which we do for our sellers, is absolutely phenomenal. In the last 12 months, we have sold every single listing we’ve taken on in just seven days, on average, and for 100% of the asking price. A lot of these sales can be attributed to our Coming Soon program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This program attracts buyers to your listing before we ever actually put it on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; By the time we put it on the market, we inundate our sellers with showings. This results in multiple offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the ways that we achieve these results is through extensive marketing. &lt;strong&gt;We post your home on over 400 different websites and advertise that it is “Coming Soon.”&lt;/strong&gt; Since there is such an inventory shortage, the anticipation we build around your listing gets buyers excited and allows your home to gain traction. And when your listing does hit the market, we end up scheduling many different appointments for showings from the very first day that it’s active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, I have a massive database of buyers that are currently looking for homes. So, I go through every single one of those buyers and call them to let them know about your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We also do a lot of social media marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; Social media has a massive influence in today’s world. So if you want to get your listing in front of people, you have to do marketing on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=By the time we put it on the market, we inundate our sellers with a lot of showings which results in multiple offers.%20davefriedmantv.com/our-coming-soon-program-explained.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“By the time we put it on the market, we inundate our sellers with a lot of showings which results in multiple offers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our client development team also helps by making phone calls. They call up and down the streets of your neighborhood to see if anyone wants to move. Some people may need a larger home but still want to stay in the same neighborhood, so we want to make sure they’re aware that your property will soon be available. Those people may even know someone who wants to move into the neighborhood as well. They provide us with referrals for us to contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;we advertise for a mega open house.&lt;/strong&gt; For the very first few days that your home is on the market, we will do this and drive a ton of attention to it. Once your home is on the market and interested buyers see it, a sense of urgency and excitement builds. As a result, we often see multiple offers and we’re able to get our buyers under contract usually within seven days for 100% of the asking price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions about our coming coon program or are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 10:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/our-coming-soon-program-explained.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/our-coming-soon-program-explained.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Charleston Market Update and Some Great Summer Events</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ey5ni9VylCk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to give you a quick market update for Charleston as well as a few great events that are going on around Charleston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few recent events just occurred here in Charleston, including the James Beard Awards. &lt;strong&gt;Rodney Scott of Rodney Scott BBQ actually won Best Chef in the Southeast.&lt;/strong&gt; I live right down the street from his restaurant and it’s fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, FIG won the award for the best wine program in the country and The Charleston School of Business won an award for their MBA program. They were voted the top MBA program for post-graduates in the country as it related to post-graduation job placement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as some other things that are coming up, there is the &lt;strong&gt;13th Annual Sweetgrass Festival, 2nd Sunday on King is back in town, and the Charleston Rum Fest and Charleston Beer Mile are also coming up soon.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dave+Friedman/June.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;You can learn more about these and all the other events going on in the area by checking out this document.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Real estate is still a great investment in our market and I don’t think we’re heading toward a bubble.%20davefriedmantv.com/a-charleston-market-update-and-some-great-summer-events.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Real estate is still a great investment in our market and I don’t think we’re heading toward a bubble.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As far as real estate goes in the Charleston market, we are up 7.2% in terms of home value in the last year.&lt;/strong&gt; The last two years, we averaged around a 4% increase, so this is a big jump. We’ve actually seen the same number of home sales this year as last, so the increasing prices are a result of low inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still a lot of buyers out there and a lot fewer homes for sale, and as you can see, this is forcing prices up. &lt;strong&gt;That’s not going to be sustainable in the long run, but does it mean we are in a housing bubble?&lt;/strong&gt; Not in my opinion. I think we’ll continue to see great appreciation for at least two more years. After that, I don’t think we’ll see a dip. The research I’ve done has shown that we’ve only seen a massive decrease in home values since 1991 during the 2008 market crash. &lt;strong&gt;When markets shift normally, they tend to just flatten out for a few years as opposed to crashing and falling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate is still a great investment in our market and it’s a great time to buy or sell a home right now. &lt;strong&gt;Our team is seeing record-breaking sales numbers and homebuyers are still going to be able to take advantage of the great appreciation we’ll see in the next few years.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any questions about buying or selling a home in Charleston or about anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 14:40:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/a-charleston-market-update-and-some-great-summer-events.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/a-charleston-market-update-and-some-great-summer-events.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Market Update and an Introduction Some Great Goal-Setting Workbooks</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vDjqfXQzYgk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the latest news from our market, today I want to talk about a great workbook and planner written by Lars Hedenborg that can help you reach the goals you’ve set for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Below, I’ve sectioned off the highlights from today’s video:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:24 - What our market’s inventory crisis and rising interest rates mean for buyers and sellers.&lt;br /&gt;2:30 - Introducing the “Intensive Workshop” workbook.&lt;br /&gt;3:49 - Session 1: Putting your life first.&lt;br /&gt;4:32 - Questions what will help you understand your “why.”&lt;br /&gt;9:23 - Exercises to help you identify what you don’t want in your life and what you do want in your life.&lt;br /&gt;11:13 - Writing your purpose statement and your personal goals.&lt;br /&gt;12:09 - Switching over to “The Business Freedom Planner.”&lt;br /&gt;14:45 - The Business Freedom Planner’s five P’s: planning, priorities, projects, potential, and positive focus.&lt;br /&gt;15:15 - Bridging the gap between the results you’re committed to creating and the results you’ve produced in the past.&lt;br /&gt;19:14 - Organizing and scheduling your five P’s for the entire 13 weeks of your quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This workbook and planner are a great way to stay on top of your goals.%20davefriedmantv.com/a-market-update-and-an-introduction-some-great-goal-setting-workbooks.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This workbook and planner are a great way to stay on top of your goals.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re interested in using this workbook and planner, just get in touch with me and I’ll send them to you.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 10:10:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/a-market-update-and-an-introduction-some-great-goal-setting-workbooks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/a-market-update-and-an-introduction-some-great-goal-setting-workbooks.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everything You Need to Know About Commission Splits</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VH1BnDSRCYY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of sellers have been asking how commission splits work in the real estate business. It’s actually pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a 50% commission, for example, half goes to the buyer’s agent and half goes to the listing agent. Listing agents can use this money to attract buyers’ agents to your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A listing agent’s commission is used in the marketing of the property. &lt;strong&gt;93% of buyers last year found their homes on the internet and through other advertising, as opposed to through the recommendation of a buyer’s agent. &lt;/strong&gt;This goes to show the importance of allocating funds to these marketing resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A portion of the listing agent’s commission is allocated to marketing resources.%20davefriedmantv.com/everything-you-need-to-know-about-commission-splits.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A portion of the listing agent’s commission is allocated to marketing resources.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big portion of funds on the listing side also go to the brokerage and to the government. Whatever is leftover becomes income for the listing agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you list with my team and I bring you a buyer, myself, we will only charge you half of the commission fee since there was no buyer’s agent involved.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 10:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/everything-you-need-to-know-about-commission-splits.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/everything-you-need-to-know-about-commission-splits.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is an Escrow Account and How Does It Work?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D3avVTIMkik?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is an escrow account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An escrow account is essentially a holding tank for money that’s held by a third party.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s used in several different capacities, but here are a couple examples to help you understand how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first is when you make an earnest money deposit on a home purchase.&lt;/strong&gt; That earnest money is then held in an escrow account by an attorney or title company (or a real estate broker in some cases) and not released until the terms of the contract are complete. If the contract releases, the escrow officer has to release that money to either the buyer or the seller. Whoever the terms of the contract say the money should be released to, the escrow officer has to fulfill that obligation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the home closes successfully, that money usually goes toward the proceeds of the transaction. That way, it’s not held by the buyer or seller, but rather a third-party who’s just fulfilling the terms of the contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=An escrow account is essentially a holding tank for money that’s held by a third party.%20davefriedmantv.com/what-is-an-escrow-account-and-how-does-it-work.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“An escrow account is essentially a holding tank for money that’s held by a third party.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another example of how it’s held is with your mortgage.&lt;/strong&gt; Your mortgage is more than likely escrowing your taxes and insurance. They take a small piece of your monthly payment and put it into your escrow account. The goal for them is to build that account up until it has enough money to satisfy your tax bill at the end of the year and your insurance bill whenever that’s due.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, for whatever reason, your payment changes, it’s likely because your loan officer miscalculated the estimated taxes and insurance due. In that case, they could actually request more money. If they’re taking too much money and there’s too much money building in that account, you can adjust it. In this example, the escrow account provides protection for the bank to ensure you’re paying your insurance and your taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about how escrow accounts are used or you have any other real estate topics you’d like to bring to my attention, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 03:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>davefriedmantv.com/what-is-an-escrow-account-and-how-does-it-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">davefriedmantv.com/what-is-an-escrow-account-and-how-does-it-work.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
