<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tulsa Real Estate Video Blog with Jennie Wolek</title>
    <description>Our mission at Keller Williams Realty Advantage is to be your best resource for Tulsa real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Keller Williams Realty Advantage, your professional Tulsa Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:48:55 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:48:55 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons to Hire a Real Estate Professional When Buying</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zi6xcyn_-v0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that it’s important for a homebuyer to use a licensed real estate agent when buying a home. But do you know why? Today I will share three of the top reasons. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. We have the inventory.&lt;/strong&gt; As real estate professionals, we have access to the multiple listing service (MLS), which is a database for Realtors. Of course, there are other websites out there that list houses for sale, but we all know that the MLS is the most up-to-date database for listings. Buyers who look for homes on other websites will only to be disappointed to find out they’re not available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, if we do not have the inventory, we have the tools and technologies and databases to help find you a home that fits all of your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When a seller lists their home on the market, they have already agreed to pay the buyer agent’s compensation.%20localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-hire-a-real-estate-professional-when-buying.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When a seller lists their home on the market, they have already agreed to pay the buyer agent’s compensation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. We have the negotiation skills.&lt;/strong&gt; As a homebuyer, you may be hesitant to speak your mind on certain points, for fear of offending the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an agent on your side, you will get the best deal and terms, you will know what is normal, and you will know what to expect. We will keep you up to date on timelines to make sure that you do not miss out on an opportunity for inspections or appraisals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. A buyer agent is free.&lt;/strong&gt; When a seller lists their home on the market, they have already agreed to pay the buyer agent’s compensation. There is no reason for you to do all of the work when you can use us. We can help you negotiate your best terms, hold the deal together to get you to closing on time, and provide you with all of our years of experience for free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions or are interested in buying, please feel free to call me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 16:34:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-hire-a-real-estate-professional-when-buying.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-hire-a-real-estate-professional-when-buying.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What 1 Organization Is Doing to Address Childhood Hunger</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MICgZZbH7B4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am excited to bring you some important information about a great local organization: the Community Food Bank of Eastern Oklahoma. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eileen Bradshaw, the executive director of the Community Food Bank, joined me to explain a little bit about what they do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With approximately 450 partner programs, this organization helps to distribute food throughout the state. According to Eileen, about one in every four children goes to bed hungry at night. And, as we can all agree, this is unacceptable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“It’s part of our job just to make sure [these children] get what they need,” says Eileen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was truly amazing to get a behind-the-scenes look at operations here at the Community Food Bank. Especially because at the time of my visit, they were preparing for “Summer Feeding.” The Summer Feeding program is one way that they are able to continue providing for kids who rely on school meals at other times of the year. On day one of this program, they fed an estimated 1,100 children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Approximately one in every four children goes to bed hungry at night, so the work the Community Food Bank is doing is critical.%20localhost:4000/what-1-organization-is-doing-to-address-childhood-hunger.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Approximately one in every four children goes to bed hungry at night, so the work the Community Food Bank is doing is critical.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workers at the Food Bank are also delegating more resources to their partner programs, as they know that their lines grow longer in the summer months, as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with as much as this organization does for our community, how can we give back and help them make a difference? Well, for every dollar donated, the Food Bank is able to produce four meals. Obviously, financial gifts are always welcomed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, volunteering your time and donating food are also great ways to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you want to get in touch with Eileen, you can give her a call at (918) 585-2800, or visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://okfoodbank.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;www.okfoodbank.org. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:36:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-1-organization-is-doing-to-address-childhood-hunger.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-1-organization-is-doing-to-address-childhood-hunger.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Get a Raised Garden Bed This Season?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2Ib5_lKL7Is?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s spring and that means it’s time to get our hands dirty in the garden. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, today I’d like to discuss some pros and cons of a common gardening option: raised beds. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One benefit of raised garden beds is simply that they’re nice to look at. Beyond that, raised beds also keep animals from getting to your garden. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They also allow you to plant earlier, since the loose soil you fill the bed with will be warmer than the ground itself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The decision as to whether a raised bed is right for you depends on your preferences and circumstances.%20localhost:4000/should-you-get-a-raised-garden-bed-this-season.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The decision as to whether a raised bed is right for you depends on your preferences and circumstances.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s take a look at some of the downsides. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, they’re pricey. You’re going to have to invest in the bed, the materials, soil, and fertilizer to get started. &lt;strong&gt;Raised beds also aren’t as sustainable as simply planting your garden in the ground.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the decision as to whether a raised bed is right for you depends on your preferences and circumstances. And if you’re unsure, my friends over at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.groggsgreenbarn.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Grogg’s Green Barn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can help you decide what gardening solutions may work best for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other questions for me or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:31:14 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-you-get-a-raised-garden-bed-this-season.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/should-you-get-a-raised-garden-bed-this-season.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emergency Infant Services: Where Struggling Tulsa Families Can Find Help</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ylt9CUAyghY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m coming to you live from the downtown office of Emergency Infant Services (EIS) here in Tulsa to tell you a little bit about this great organization and what they do for our community. Joining me is EIS Executive Director Bill Andoe. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 40 years, the mission of EIS has been &lt;strong&gt;to serve families who are experiencing financial hardship and have children under the age of five.&lt;/strong&gt; They provide clothing, diapers, groceries, formula, and other essential needs these families have. All these families have to do is meet with an EIS interviewer to assess their needs so they can determine which services they can provide and which community services might be available to them—even if their children are over five. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from their downtown location, they also have a location on the east side of Tulsa and two satellite locations on the north and south sides of town. Right now they’re in the middle of a capital campaign, so a year from this summer, they’ll be moving to 11th and Denver. This move will help them provide more resources for families, centralize their warehouse, and stockpile more supplies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Anyone is welcome at EIS.%20localhost:4000/emergency-infant-services-where-struggling-tulsa-families-can-find-help.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Anyone is welcome at EIS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing in particular I love to share about EIS is anyone is welcome there. &lt;strong&gt;They provide their services with love and without judgement—it’s one of their founding principles.&lt;/strong&gt; According to Bill, they average about 18,000 visits per year, and they expect that number to reach 20,000 in the near future. To help carry the loan, they have church groups, school groups, and a number of other regular volunteers who help them on a weekly basis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re in this because we want to help,” Bill says. “That’s what attracts employees and volunteers to EIS. We often talk about the people who come in—we talk about professionally mentioning them statistically as clients, but they’re really more than just clients. They’re members of our community. They go to our churches. We see them at public events. They’re Tulsans just like us. We’re here to help them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EIS relies on the generosity of donors and the Tulsa community at large, so if you’d like to help them in their mission, they always welcome financial donations. They also accept diapers, wipes, car seats, strollers, and anything else a family with a young child might need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’d like to get in touch with EIS or you’d like more information on how to donate, you can visit their website at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eistulsa.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.EISTulsa.org.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions for me or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:25:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/emergency-infant-services-where-struggling-tulsa-families-can-find-help.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/emergency-infant-services-where-struggling-tulsa-families-can-find-help.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Tips for Decluttering Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nhsX1pb5_OU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decluttering is so important in getting your home ready to sell as well as just cleaning up for spring. Whatever your motivation, thinning out your home is a great way to feel good. Today let’s go through the seven steps it takes to declutter your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Make sure the front of your home is welcoming and encourages buyers to come inside.&lt;/strong&gt; First impressions are everything. Buyers are probably going to find your home online first, and then they might even drive around the neighborhood to check it out. You’ll want to clear out any dead leaves and put some fresh mulch down. Be sure that there are no mud daubers or bird’s nests in your eaves. Pretend you’re a buyer and walk up to your front porch. What would you think? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Take it one room at a time.&lt;/strong&gt; Decluttering can be really overwhelming, so just start small. Thin out the things in your room and closet; think about what your room would look like in a photograph. What isn’t needed? Pictures will amplify those extra things on countertops and other areas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Decide what furniture you really need in the home.&lt;/strong&gt; To make your property look like a model home, get rid of extra furniture and end tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Clean off countertops.&lt;/strong&gt; These are common places for us to pile things up, but kitchens are very important rooms to make a good impression with. Put your toaster, blender, and other similar appliances away in a cabinet, and clear away other extraneous papers and tidbits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Think about what your room would look like in a photograph. What isn’t needed?%20localhost:4000/7-tips-for-decluttering-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Think about what your room would look like in a photograph. What isn’t needed?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Clean your shower.&lt;/strong&gt; When we come to preview your home, we’re going to pull back the shower curtain. Be sure the grout is clean and that tiles or paint aren’t peeling. Your shower will tell buyers a lot about how you take care of your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Take away your collectibles.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s great that you care about and collect things that are dear to your heart, but that can become a distraction to buyers. Go ahead and box it up and put it away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Declutter the garage and storage sheds.&lt;/strong&gt; If there are things in there that you need to keep on hand, put them in boxes or storage bins that are neat and organized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these things sound crazy, however, they make a lot of difference. A decluttered home will help you get the most money for your home in the shortest amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need any help with decluttering your home or have other questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you however I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:20:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/7-tips-for-decluttering-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/7-tips-for-decluttering-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Are Looking for Homes to Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ayzba1I0UvQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring has sprung for us here in the Tulsa market. We’re very busy this time of year, so I wanted to take a short minute to talk about our listing shortage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need good, ready-to-move-in homes in the $150,000 to $250,000 price range. If you have a home that would match this criteria, please let us know so that we can help all of our buyers. &lt;strong&gt;We have more buyers than we have homes for sale that match their criteria.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We need good, ready-to-move-in homes in the $150,000 to $250,000 price range.%20localhost:4000/we-are-looking-for-homes-to-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We need good, ready-to-move-in homes in the $150,000 to $250,000 price range.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another tool that we use is called “My Buyer Listings,” a website just for buyer listings. That means we’ve met with our buyers, we’ve qualified them, and they’re ready to go buy a home. They’re just not finding homes that match what they’re looking for. Be sure to check out our listings that we already have with buyers and let us know if this is the perfect time to put your home on the market in this price range. That way, you get to take advantage of the market by moving up—and &lt;strong&gt;that’s always a win.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a home in this price range that you’d consider selling or if you have any other questions, please reach out to us and let us know how we can help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/we-are-looking-for-homes-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/we-are-looking-for-homes-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Kids About Science and Teamwork Through Global Gardens </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zKhzubP828Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maryann Donahue from Global Gardens is here today to share how this wonderful organization helps empower children in high-poverty areas of Tulsa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that’s really important to us as a real estate team is giving back to our community, which is why we like to spotlight our local nonprofits that are doing great things in the Tulsa area. Today, I’m talking to Maryann Donahue from Global Gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global Gardens was created by a teacher from Tulsa named Heather Oakley [spelling?] in 2007. Heather had a background in urban science education and peace education. She also had a bachelors degree in botany. She combined all of those things to create Global Gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The purpose of Global Gardens is to help fight the cycle of poverty and empower kids&lt;/strong&gt; from high-poverty communities to be agents of change in their own lives and in their communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Heather came back to Tulsa in 2007, she started the first program at Eugene Field. She offered during and after-school programs. At that time, there was an empty lot next to Eugene Field that was bare, empty, and forgotten. She and that first group of students turned it into a beautiful, bountiful garden, and that’s what Global Gardens has done ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since then, Global Gardens has added three more sites in addition to Eugene Field, including the one Maryann and I are filming from today.&lt;/strong&gt; This field services Union Middle School and Union High School. There are two other elementary schools in the program as well: Rosa Parks Elementary and McAuliffe Elementary in East Tulsa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE PURPOSE OF GLOBAL GARDENS IS TO HELP FIGHT THE CYCLE OF POVERTY AND EMPOWER KIDS.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-community-spotlight-global-gardens.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE PURPOSE OF GLOBAL GARDENS IS TO HELP FIGHT THE CYCLE OF POVERTY AND EMPOWER KIDS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We serve over 1,800 kids every week in this program,” says Maryann. “We’re helping about 2,500 people a year.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global Gardens uses gardening as a vehicle for empowerment. They also use gardening to teach science and how to be peaceful. “In the during-school program, they have a class garden. They get to decide what to plant, and they have a harvest party at the end of the year,” says Maryann. “They do all of that together. It’s very intentional.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These programs teach science that addresses state science standards while also teaching teamwork. The students don’t have many opportunities outside of Global Gardens to do hands-on, real-world things and have to do them as a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We really believe that Global Gardens is doing a great thing.&lt;/strong&gt; How can you help? Go to Global-Gardens.org to make an online donation. All of their funding is raised from community donations; they don’t have state contracts or charge fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maryann says that Global Gardens hopes to add a fifth site at Jackson Elementary School in North Tulsa by 2019. This has been in the works for a while, so please consider helping them reach their goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank Maryann for taking the time to talk to me today. You can learn more details about Global Gardens at Global-Gardens.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate questions or know another local nonprofit you think we should spotlight, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-community-spotlight-global-gardens.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-community-spotlight-global-gardens.html</guid>
        
        <category>The Wolek Group</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can Cleansing Rain Help You Clean and Organize Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lDahCYGy7HE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk about Cleansing Rain, which is an incredible home cleaning business here in our town.To learn more about the business and how it began, I spoke with the owner, Lacie Partney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk about an incredible home cleaning business here in our town: Cleansing Rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I asked how she got the idea to begin her business, owner Lacie Partney told me she wasn’t always such a neat and organized person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Lacie, it all began when she returned to Tulsa after two years on the mission field. At that point in time, she was searching for something to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, she’s found cleaning homes to be very fulfilling. She says it really helps her build relationships. On top of that, &lt;strong&gt;Lacie herself makes all of the natural cleaning products she uses.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=FROM YOUR ATTIC TO YOUR JUNK DRAWER, LACIE IS HAPPY TO HELP ANYONE DECLUTTER.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-clean-your-home-with-cleansing-rain.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“FROM YOUR ATTIC TO YOUR JUNK DRAWER, LACIE IS HAPPY TO HELP ANYONE DECLUTTER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one of the things that help her stand out from other cleaning companies in town. She also loves to help people get more organized. From your attic to your junk drawer, Lacie is happy to help anyone declutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, it doesn’t stop there. Once she helps her clients declutter their spaces, &lt;strong&gt;Lacie also helps them develop an organizational system that can be implemented into their specific lifestyle.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing Lacie highly recommends is to make use of vertical space. Instead of buying new furniture that takes up floor space, she suggests that people try to utilize their walls for storage, instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Lacie and her business, you can visit her website at www.CleansingRain918.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-clean-your-home-with-cleansing-rain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-clean-your-home-with-cleansing-rain.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How John Carter Bathrooms Can Help You </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LodG7j_AEbg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Carter from John Carter Bathrooms is here today to answer a few questions about his business and some of the latest trends in bathroom remodels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m here with John Carter from John Carter Bathrooms. John has graciously agreed to answer some questions about his business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you get into this business?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started way back. I’m from Namibia and my father did remodeling. He taught me everything I know. I learned everything from scratch and got to love remodeling, which made me decide to make it a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to the United States a couple of years ago and got a job like everybody else. Then I realized that I wouldn’t be able to work on my dreams, so I decided to start a remodeling business. I can do kitchens, bathrooms, and even build homes, but I wanted to focus on something special, so I learned how to specialize in bathrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I love your story and that you are doing something you are passionate about, which is important to me as well. What makes you stand out from the competition?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of things that make us different. First, we complete all projects on time and on budget. It is a top priority for us to work around your schedule and your finances. Second, all of our projects are designed to fit your size and your style. We don’t ask you to cut corners on the perfect remodel. Finally, we are the most available and we provide daily progress reports on what’s done, so you’re never left wondering what we did all day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU WILL GET DAILY PROGRESS REPORTS SO YOU KNOW EXACTLY HOW MUCH WORK HAS BEEN DONE.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-favorite-bathroom-remodel-specialist.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU WILL GET DAILY PROGRESS REPORTS SO YOU KNOW EXACTLY HOW MUCH WORK HAS BEEN DONE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s a new style or trend that you have noticed lately?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In kitchens, soapstone has been popular lately. We’ve been using it in bathrooms for a little bit. People do want to use quartz for their surfaces these days. There are a lot of new materials out there. People like wooden countertops as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For bathrooms, people stick to light, neutral colors. Those will last a long time. Back in the 80s, people made pink, green, and purple bathrooms. That doesn’t work. My job is to come into somebody’s home and put something in there with tile that will last. Technology has improved with tile and cement, so we can build up bathrooms that are mold-free and 100% waterproof, which is great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can someone get in touch with you about a remodel or to ask any questions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My phone number is 918-574-4610 or look at my website, JohnCarterBathrooms.com. You can enter your information and get a free 3-D model of what your bathroom could look like at no cost to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to John for answering my questions. As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-favorite-bathroom-remodel-specialist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-favorite-bathroom-remodel-specialist.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Does Luxe Furniture and Design Have to Offer?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pLgQqROEbLI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here with Tamara Noel, owner of Luxe Furniture and Design, to discuss the products and services her company provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tulsahomevalue.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thewolekgroup.com/search-for-homes/#/-1451235678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here with Tamara Noel, owner of Luxe Furniture and Design, and I’m so excited for her to share with you all the great things they have here at Luxe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with beautiful furniture and decor, &lt;strong&gt;Luxe also offers a great design service&lt;/strong&gt; that’s complimentary with purchase. When you shop there, you get to work with a qualified, educated, and talented interior designer to help you every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re not just salespeople who are knowledgeable about all the products Luxe offers; they are honestly legitimate design experts. The designers went to school to learn the skill and have spent their entire career honing the craft. They love what they do, and they’re very good at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When somebody walks through the door with a need, what does the process of helping them look like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be anything from one of the designers helping the client navigate the store to identify their wants and needs to schedule a house call where someone isn’t quite sure what they’re looking for or they have a larger project they don’t know how to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=THE HELP OF A DESIGNER CAN MAKE ALL THE DIFFERENCE.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-luxe-is-great-for-products-and-design.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“THE HELP OF A DESIGNER CAN MAKE ALL THE DIFFERENCE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our designers make &lt;strong&gt;complimentary house calls&lt;/strong&gt; out to your home. They’ll do all the measuring, look at your paint colors, work with what pieces you already have, give guidance on space planning, give direction for new pieces, and more. It could be something as simple as window treatments, but whatever it is, the help of &lt;strong&gt;a designer can make all the difference.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do a lot in stages. It may just be planning for the big picture—doing a few changes now and a little bit more down the road to ultimately get the look that you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you seeing in terms of design trends?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clean lines are still key here in Tulsa. It’s becoming a transitional market, but neutrals are still very popular, and a lot of the taupes of years past are coming back. Adding in a little bit of fun with texture or a pop of color is a good way to brighten up your space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can people get in touch with you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find us in our showroom at 9922 Riverside Parkway in Tulsa, Oklahoma, in the King’s Landing Shopping Center. You can also visit our website www.luxetulsa.com, give us a call at (918) 459-8950, or like us on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you need anything in terms of real estate from the Wolek Group, please feel free to reach out to us. Have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 11:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-luxe-is-great-for-products-and-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-luxe-is-great-for-products-and-design.html</guid>
        
        <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
