<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dallas Mortgage Lender – The Betz Team</title>
    <description>The Betz Team are your local Dallas mortgage lenders. There’s more to a mortgage than the close. Request your consultation today.</description>
    <link>https://winningwithwade.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://winningwithwade.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 13:50:10 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 13:50:10 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buyers: How Much of Your Closing Costs Can Sellers Pay?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ndcfGeDY9WU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are the limits of seller concessions? As a buyer, the answer depends on your loan program.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the limits of seller concessions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My homebuyer clients often ask me whether the seller can pay for some or all of their closing costs, and the reality is, different loan programs have &lt;strong&gt;different limits for what a seller can and can’t do. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FHA and USDA programs cap the maximum contribution at 6% of the sales price. Very rarely do the closing costs amount to 6%, but they allow it if those closing costs are there to be paid. VA programs, on the other hand, allow 4% plus closing costs. This is a broad generalization of what can and can’t be done, but if the amounts are large enough, the buyer can pay off their funding fee, non-mortgage debt, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventional loan limits are capped based on your down payment. If you put down 10% or less, the maximum is 3% of the sales price. If you put down anywhere from 10% to 25%, the limit is 6%. If you put down more than 25%, the limit is 9%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’d like to talk more about how these limits affect your home buying prospects, give me a call and I’d be happy to run the numbers for you.%20https://winningwithwade.com/buyers-how-much-of-your-closing-costs-can-sellers-pay.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’d like to talk more about how these limits affect your home buying prospects, give me a call and I’d be happy to run the numbers for you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re thinking of making an offer on a property and using seller contributions as part of your strategy, let your Realtor know up front&lt;/strong&gt; so they can include that in their negotiating strategy. If you’d like to talk more about how these limits affect your home buying prospects, give me a call and I’d be happy to run the numbers for you.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, though, let’s say you make an offer of $200,000, wherein your actual price is $205,000 but you also ask for $5,000 worth of seller contributions, the seller would usually be OK with this because they net the same amount. As long as the property appraises, that’s a good way to keep a large chunk of money in your pocket. Technically the mortgage payment is slightly higher because you’re borrowing more money, but it’s usually a good tradeoff. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/buyers-how-much-of-your-closing-costs-can-sellers-pay.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/buyers-how-much-of-your-closing-costs-can-sellers-pay.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Listing Incentive Helps Buyers, Sellers, and Agents</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K5ID4rbUvjA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I just wanted to take a moment to outline our newest listing incentive plan. Here’s what you need to know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, we hear from our listing agents that one of their biggest concerns when listing homes is that it’s hard to know the quality of the lender who will represent the buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help combat this uncertainty, we’ve created a listing incentive: &lt;strong&gt;giving the buyer a credit.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll be able to include this in your listing presentations with sellers and your advertisements on the MLS as well as other marketing materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, &lt;strong&gt;the amount of the credit depends on the loan amount.&lt;/strong&gt; If it’s a jumbo mortgage, the credit will be capped at $3,000. If the loan amount is lower than the conforming loan limit, the buyer will be able to get a credit equal to 1% of the loan amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This listing incentive is a way for you to obtain certainty in your process.%20https://winningwithwade.com/this-listing-incentive-helps-buyers-sellers-and-agents.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This listing incentive is a way for you to obtain certainty in your process.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if the loan amount is $400,000, the credit would equal $4,000. If it’s a $100,000 loan, they’d get a $1,000 credit. Basically, one point of credit equals about a 0.25% interest rate, so they’d be able to get very good mortgage terms, but only by partnering with us on your listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This listing incentive is a way for you to obtain certainty in your process and ensure that you’ll be able to close the contract on the closing date. It gives you more control over the process, and the buyer gets terms that they wouldn’t have been able to qualify for otherwise. &lt;strong&gt;It’s truly a win-win situation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we are realists—we know that we’re not going to get a whole bunch of participants in this program because buyer’s agents aren’t going to be too excited about using a listing agent’s recommended lender. We get that, but &lt;strong&gt;we just wanted a way to add value to our listing partners so we can help you sell more homes and help buyers build more wealth and memories with real estate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to sit down in person or speak over the phone about this incentive program, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d be honored to visit with you. Thanks so much for your business and trust! I truly appreciate it, and I can’t wait for what the future holds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 14:00:36 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/this-listing-incentive-helps-buyers-sellers-and-agents.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/this-listing-incentive-helps-buyers-sellers-and-agents.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Minimum Down Payment You Should Expect to Make?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5S5A2dHKGG0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unless you’re using a USDA or VA loan, you’ll always have a minimum down payment to make.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the minimum down payment needed to purchase a home? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is that unless it’s two specific loan programs, there’s always a down payment required. Those two loan programs are the USDA loan (for rural properties) and the VA loan (for veterans and active military personal). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because you have to make a down payment doesn’t mean you have to put down at least 20%, though. &lt;strong&gt;Depending on the loan program, the minimum is actually 3% to 5%.&lt;/strong&gt; Many times, it makes sense to put this amount down even if you can put more down because then you can keep assets in your account for other investments that will yield a higher interest rate than the one on your mortgage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When in doubt, give me a call so we can have a conversation about the best use of your funds.%20https://winningwithwade.com/whats-the-minimum-down-payment-you-should-expect-to-make.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When in doubt, give me a call so we can have a conversation about the best use of your funds.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in doubt, give me a call so we can have a conversation about the best use of your funds. Sometimes you’re better off investing in other areas instead of putting more down than you need to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any more questions about this or any other mortgage topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 15:09:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/whats-the-minimum-down-payment-you-should-expect-to-make.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/whats-the-minimum-down-payment-you-should-expect-to-make.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Convert a Primary Residence Into an Investment Property</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TzNGb1vKER8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many people are curious about what it takes to convert a primary residence into a rental, so today we’ll get to the bottom of this common question.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often ask us whether they can convert their current residence into an investment property after they buy their next home, so let’s get to the bottom of this question today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, keeping a property to use as a rental instead of selling it when you move can be a great way to generate extra income. However, &lt;strong&gt;there are certain standards you’ll need to meet. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Keeping a property to use as a rental instead of selling it when you move can be a great way to generate extra income.%20https://winningwithwade.com/how-to-convert-a-primary-residence-into-an-investment-property.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Keeping a property to use as a rental instead of selling it when you move can be a great way to generate extra income.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, you must rent out the property using at least a 12-month lease. Also, when you take on a tenant, your lender will need to verify that their security deposit has cleared and is in your account. This helps them to ensure that the lease is legitimate—not just an under-the-table arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you’ve met these two qualifications, you’re all set to start reaping the benefits of your new rental property.&lt;/strong&gt; When executed correctly, this strategy can not only help you to qualify for your next home purchase, but can also eliminate any remaining debt you owe toward your first home’s mortgage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/how-to-convert-a-primary-residence-into-an-investment-property.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/how-to-convert-a-primary-residence-into-an-investment-property.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Strategies to Save Money on Credit Card Debt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you charge $2,000 and the interest on your credit card is 12%.  If you only make the minimum payment, it will take you approximately 16 years (yes, years) to pay it off.   Getting rid of credit card debt not only increases your credit score, it’s a big relief to eliminate a payment, giving you extra money to spend or save.  Here are 3 strategies to help you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Pick just one credit card to pay off first&lt;/strong&gt; – If you have several credit cards, consider throwing as much money as you can to pay off one of them. There are two options to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Credit Card with the lowest balance – Choosing this option will help boost your credit score because credit bureaus determine scores by the number of outstanding credit cards and the ratio of balances owed to your maximum loan limit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Credit Card with the highest interest rate – Choosing this option will save you money in the long term. Review how much interest you have paid over the last 12 months compared to your other credit cards and see if this option makes more sense to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Call your credit card company&lt;/strong&gt; – Sometimes a simple phone call is all it takes to get a lower interest rate. If you are a long-term customer with a good credit score (in the 700 range), and have made your payments on time, you can usually get a couple of percentage points knocked off the rate.  If you’ve gotten an offer of a lower rate from a competitor, mention that to the customer-service rep and there’s a chance they will match their offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Consider Transferring Your Balances &lt;/strong&gt;– You can save hundreds of dollars by transferring credit card balances from a higher interest rate to a lower one—you can save a lot of money that way. However, it might just be a low, introductory rate that will only last for 12 to 18 months.  Be cautious:  Transfer your balance only if you are committed to paying off that credit card within the “low-rate window”; otherwise you may find yourself paying a higher rate than the one you paid on your old credit card.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/3-strategies-to-save-money-on-credit-card-debt.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/3-strategies-to-save-money-on-credit-card-debt.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Entitled to Claim Money from the Equifax Settlement Agreement?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In September of 2017, Equifax announced a data breach that exposed the personal information of 147 million people. The company has agreed to a global settlement with the Federal Trade Commission, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, and 50 U.S. states and territories. The settlement includes up to $425 million to help people affected by the data breach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what you need to do to determine whether your credit data has been compromised and the options that you have if your social security number appears as one of the 147 million credit records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use this link to the FTC and enter in the last 6 digits of your social security number. (WARNING:  there are other websites out there that are asking for your information.  Don’t use them—use this one – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/cases-proceedings/refunds/equifax-data-breach-settlement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/cases-proceedings/refunds/equifax-data-breach-settlement&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The website will tell you whether you are eligible to file a claim.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 4 claim options:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cash or Pre-paid credit card of $125&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Or, Free credit monitoring for 4 years and $1 million dollars of identity theft insurance&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Or, free credit monitoring for 6 years (no insurance)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Or, You incurred loss of money and time due to identity theft. If you claim less than 10 hours, you must describe the actions that you took to fix the issues. If you claim 10 hours or more, you must provide documentation.  Maximum claim is $20,000.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your claim must be filed by January 22, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claims will be reviewed starting January 23, 2020 but no date has been set when the money will be sent or the credit monitoring option will begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more thing…It used to be that you could ask for one free credit report per year.  Now as part of the settlement, consumers can get up to 6 credit reports per year from Equifax for up to 7 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/are-you-entitled-to-claim-money-from-the-equifax-settlement-agreement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/are-you-entitled-to-claim-money-from-the-equifax-settlement-agreement.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Max Number of Homes You Can Finance?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NuEg0K1o37w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is the maximum number of properties you can finance? Find out today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked with a lot of investors over the years, and they always ask me how many properties they’re allowed to buy using financing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the answer to that is, “However many you qualify for.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;different investors in the secondary mortgage market will have different limits on how much exposure they’ll have to a single investor client.&lt;/strong&gt; That said, the traditional investors will build their rental portfolio using Fannie Mae financing: Fannie Mae allows up to 10 financed properties at once. If you own 15 and eight of them are free and clear, you haven’t yet reached the 10-property limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need to partner with a lender who can grow with you as your investment plans grow and lay out a strategy to help you accomplish your goals.%20https://winningwithwade.com/what-is-the-max-number-of-homes-you-can-finance.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You need to partner with a lender who can grow with you as your investment plans grow and lay out a strategy to help you accomplish your goals.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fannie Mae is used on the first go-around because they have the best pricing for your real estate investors, but &lt;strong&gt;once you get to that tenth financed property, we need to go to a different strategy.&lt;/strong&gt; Typically, this comes in the form of commercial financing, but even those commercial financiers will have limits to how much exposure they’re going to have to a single individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, you need to partner with a lender who can grow with you as your investment plans grow and lay out a strategy to help you accomplish your goals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is looking to grow your investment portfolio and build wealth through real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be honored to take great care of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/what-is-the-max-number-of-homes-you-can-finance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/what-is-the-max-number-of-homes-you-can-finance.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thinking of Remodeling? Read 2019 Cost vs. Value Report</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, remodelers and real estate agents are surveyed to determine the cost of making improvements to your home versus the dollar amount it adds to the value of your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sharing the stats based on the national average, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.remodeling.hw.net/cost-vs-value/2019/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here’s the link&lt;/a&gt; if you’d like to check it out yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remodel Job                                  Mid-Range Cost                             Resale Value&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bathroom Remodel                      $20,420                                           $13,717&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bathroom Addition                       $47,427                                           $28,726&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wood Deck                                     $13,333                                           $10,083&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entry Door Replacement             $ 1,876                                            $ 1,368&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garage Door Replacement          $ 3,611                                            $ 3,520&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major Kitchen Remodel               $66,196                                           $41,133&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minor Kitchen Remodel               $22,507                                           $18,123&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asphalt Roof Replacement          $22,636                                           $15,427&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siding Replacement                      $16,036                                           $12,119&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vinyl Window Replacement        $16,802                                           $12,332&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backyard Patio Addition              $56,906                                           $31,430&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are thinking of remodeling, contact me because we may be able to use the equity in your home to help you spruce it up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/thinking-of-remodeling-read-2019-cost-vs-value-report.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/thinking-of-remodeling-read-2019-cost-vs-value-report.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Credit Scores Are Different Between Different Credit Reporting Companies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Credit scores are one of those things that has consumers (and sometimes lenders) scratching their heads and saying, “How did they come up with THAT credit score?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one you hear about the most are FICO scores (acronym for the Fair Isaac Corporation, the creators of the FICO score). It’s the one that most mortgage lenders use as one of the benchmarks to see if you qualify to refinance or purchase another home.  Usually 3 scores are provided, and the lender uses the middle score as the basis for granting (or denying) a loan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing about FICO scores is that the credit score may vary from lender to lender.  Why?  Because over the years, Fair Isaac has updated their credit scoring model software (best estimate, about 85 times), but the credit bureaus who buy the software from Fair Isaac do not always update their own software.  One lender could be using the latest version while another lender’s model is several years old. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, not everyone uses FICO scores as a guide.  Here are some other credit scoring models that are used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto Loans&lt;/strong&gt; – If you apply for an auto loan through a dealer, they have developed their own credit scoring models, which are completely different from those used by lenders. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insurance Companies&lt;/strong&gt; – Your insurance premium you pay for homeowners or car insurance also depends upon the credit scoring model that insurance companies use.  Oh, and it will vary with different insurance companies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vantage Scores&lt;/strong&gt; – If your occupation/employment requires you to be “licensed” (especially in the financial services industry) and to obtain (or maintain) your professional license, Vantage Scoring model software is used. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free Credit Reports&lt;/strong&gt; – According to law, you are entitled to one free credit report (per bureau) every year.  While it won’t be exactly what lenders see when they order a credit report on your behalf, it will be “in the range” and is a good indicator of what to expect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, you are entitled to one free credit report—PER BUREAU.  Go to &lt;a href=&quot;AnnualCreditReport.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AnnualCreditReport.com&lt;/a&gt; and you can request one credit report from EACH of the bureaus listed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A word of caution!  Be careful when signing up for offers to provide you with a FREE credit report.  If you are asked to enter your credit card number, what you are really signing up for is a credit monitoring service—that may cost you over $300 per year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if you’d like me to review your credit report.  I can make suggestions on how to increase your credit score.  Sometimes it just takes a little tweaking to increase it by 25 to 50 points. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/why-credit-scores-are-different-between-different-credit-reporting-companies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/why-credit-scores-are-different-between-different-credit-reporting-companies.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Wait Any Longer to Have Your Home Inventoried</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dGbcvrlL_Wg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taking an inventory of your home is vitally important, and TakeStock Inventory can help you with this task.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is a home inventory important? Today I’m joined by Alison Wood of TakeStock Inventory to answer that question for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was born and raised in New Orleans, so I’ve had quite a few friends and family members who have been affected by natural disasters. As a company that specializes in helping people inventory their possessions, TakeStock Inventory’s services fit very well with what my life experience has been, and I want to share this information with you because &lt;strong&gt;I think it’s vital for you to have your possessions cataloged and accounted for in case something happens.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, what TakeStock Inventory does is take pictures of your stuff. They can get in and out of your home in a few hours, and in terms of a price estimate, a 3,000 square foot home would cost around $595 to photograph. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to photographing those things that are within their general line of sight, they also photograph the insides of drawers, cabinets, and closets. People tend to forget about what’s in their storage boxes until they’re faced with a crisis (death, divorce, falling into debt, etc.), and they can help you prove your assets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Basically, what TakeStock Inventory does is take pictures of your stuff.%20https://winningwithwade.com/dont-wait-any-longer-to-have-your-home-inventoried.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Basically, what TakeStock Inventory does is take pictures of your stuff.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ve used TakeStock Inventory for years, and I think every business owner/homeowner should have a conversation with them&lt;/strong&gt; so that you’re prepared and your family is protected in case of a life-changing event. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to schedule a free, no-obligation consultation, you can email Alison at &lt;a href=&quot;alison@takestockinventory.com&quot;&gt;alison@takestockinventory.com&lt;/a&gt;, visit their website &lt;a href=&quot;www.takestockinventory.com&quot;&gt;www.takestockinventory.com&lt;/a&gt;, or give them a call at (214) 908-9838. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any mortgage needs from me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/dont-wait-any-longer-to-have-your-home-inventoried.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/dont-wait-any-longer-to-have-your-home-inventoried.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
