<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <title>Colemere Realty and Associates</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Colemere Realty and Associates - your professional Wasatch Front Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 11:35:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 11:35:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thank You for Attending Our Summer Barbecue Kickoff</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D0kzbB2pwX0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
=======
    <title>-- MARKET -- Real Estate Video Blog with -- CLIENT NAME --</title>
    <description>Our mission at  is to be your best resource for  real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The , your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 09:59:09 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 09:59:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>this is a test post</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SFFy_drFrZs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
>>>>>>> cd1c7b7baf4308f7ac54304945870ef602d4f876

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;A big thanks to all who stopped by!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

<<<<<<< HEAD
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
=======
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bushwick&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;'http://google.com'&quot;&gt;marfa&lt;/a&gt; wayfarers heirloom pork belly. Tumblr ramps roof party, church-key portland tbh viral letterpress. &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot;&gt;Fanny&lt;/a&gt; pack flannel neutra, polaroid fam thundercats kale chips kogi gluten-free chicharrones cray tumblr meh keffiyeh messenger bag. Church-key vegan mixtape, ramps DIY fixie PBR&amp;amp;B keffiyeh pinterest pop-up offal. Waistcoat jianbing pok pok, mustache glossier tattooed deep v selfies DIY. Beard fingerstache cray XOXO, iPhone readymade forage offal. Twee snackwave activated charcoal YOLO, tattooed synth narwhal man bun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/homevalue/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/home-value.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; alt=&quot;Home Valuation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
>>>>>>> cd1c7b7baf4308f7ac54304945870ef602d4f876

&lt;p&gt;We at Colemere Realty Associates would like to extend our gratitude to all who attended our Summer Barbecue Kickoff! We had a lot of fun, spent time with a lot of friends, and ate a lot of food—some of you even won prizes! From our family to yours: Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

<<<<<<< HEAD
&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions or would like any information about how we can meet your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/thank-you-for-attending-our-summer-barbecue-kickoff.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/thank-you-for-attending-our-summer-barbecue-kickoff.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Avoid Pricing Your Home Too High</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JA5PD3XpHGY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
=======
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is an example of a pull quote%20http://localhost:4000/this-is-a-test-post-copy-2.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is an example of a pull quote”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
>>>>>>> cd1c7b7baf4308f7ac54304945870ef602d4f876

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be sure to avoid these three pitfalls created when you overprice your home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it a bad idea to overprice your home when you put it on the market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, remember that people who browse for homes online can see how long a home has been on the market&lt;/strong&gt;. When a home is overpriced, it tends to stagnate on the market, and when buyers see that, they’ll probably think that something’s wrong with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another danger of overpricing your home is getting burnt out. The longer your home is on the market, the more worn down you’ll get having to clean your house at a moment’s notice to prepare for a showing—especially if you have kids and/or pets. &lt;strong&gt;Your hopes may get high that each buyer who visits will be the last, but if they’re aware that your home is overpriced, you might be in for a disappointment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Chances are you won’t be able to fool the buyer about the value of your home.%20http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/why-you-should-avoid-pricing-your-home-too-high.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Chances are you won’t be able to fool the buyer about the value of your home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, it’s worth noting that buyers today have more information at their fingertips than they ever have before. They’re both astute and diligent about comparing homes to others they’ve seen in the market.  Even if they don’t have the exact data on your home, they do think about the general cleanliness of the home, what upgrades it has, and what features it has compared to homes that are priced lower than yours. &lt;strong&gt;Chances are you won’t be able to fool the buyer about the value of your home&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or real estate in general, reach out to your Colemere Realty specialists. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/why-you-should-avoid-pricing-your-home-too-high.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/why-you-should-avoid-pricing-your-home-too-high.html</guid>
=======
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/this-is-a-test-post-copy-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/this-is-a-test-post-copy-2.html</guid>
>>>>>>> cd1c7b7baf4308f7ac54304945870ef602d4f876
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
<<<<<<< HEAD
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Summer Barbecue Kickoff Is Almost Here</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QnFthRiVMFw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;On June 1st, we want you to join us at Lone Peak Park for our summer barbecue kickoff. Here are the details.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re here today at beautiful Lone Peak Park (10140 S. 700 E, Sandy, UT), the site of Colemere Realty’s upcoming Summer Barbecue Kickoff. Please join us on June 1st from 11 a.m. to 3 p.m. for great barbecue, lots of fun, and prizes galore. We appreciate your support so much, and this is just a way for us to thank you in person. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/colemere-summer-client-picnic-registration-61460697601&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to RSVP&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt; We can’t wait to see you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/our-summer-barbecue-kickoff-is-almost-here.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/our-summer-barbecue-kickoff-is-almost-here.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Miscellaneous</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding the Importance of Getting a Home Inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UF0r43ywUVQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss why a home inspection is vitally important to those buying a home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes an inspection such a necessary part of the real estate transaction for homebuyers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you go under contract for the purchase of a home, included in your agreement is a timetable for any due diligence you’d like to conduct. Consider this your opportunity to inspect the property to the fullest extent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you hire a home inspector, they’ll come with a checklist of items, and they’ll examine those items to ensure sufficient functionality of each&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, you may get swept up in all the excitement of going under contract on your new home, only to have an inspector identify some issues. That’s why it’s so important to have a professional inspector come in—&lt;strong&gt;their preset checklist will be comprised of around 300 items, and they’ll document every problem area they uncover in a thorough fashion&lt;/strong&gt;. This way, you’re not surprised by the actual condition of the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The inspection is instrumental in letting you know the exact condition of the home and about anything you weren’t aware of beforehand.%20http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/understanding-the-importance-of-getting-a-home-inspection.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The inspection is instrumental in letting you know the exact condition of the home and about anything you weren’t aware of beforehand.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a checklist of this length, an inspector is bound to find flaws or areas that need servicing in the home. We’ve even seen cases where inspectors have found issues in new construction properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If and when issues arise out of the inspection, as the buyer, &lt;strong&gt;you’ll need to identify the biggest concerns&lt;/strong&gt; and ask yourself: If any issues were to go unaddressed, how would it impede my ability to move forward smoothly? From there, &lt;strong&gt;you’ll essentially renegotiate with the seller to either make those repairs or give you a credit toward the repairs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the inspection is instrumental in letting you know the exact condition of the home and about anything you weren’t aware of beforehand, so you’ll be comfortable with what you’re getting into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about today’s topic or anything else real estate-related, please feel free to reach out to your Colemere Realty specialist. We’d love to help you however we can!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/understanding-the-importance-of-getting-a-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/understanding-the-importance-of-getting-a-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are There Opportunities to Buy With a Low Down Payment?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yhgSBDdE2qU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;You aren&amp;rsquo;t doomed to pay 20% down. Here are some of the options you have.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get this question a lot: Are there opportunities to buy a home with low or no money down?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various news outlets have claimed that you need a 20% down payment in order to purchase a home, but it’s not true—&lt;strong&gt;you can certainly buy a home with zero down&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several loan programs out there, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://utahhousingcorp.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Utah Housing Corporation&lt;/a&gt; loan or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://eligibility.sc.egov.usda.gov/eligibility/welcomeAction.do&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;USDA&lt;/a&gt; loan, that help you buy with either nothing down or a very low amount. However, each program does have requirements. &lt;strong&gt;These may include:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Income&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Size of household&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Home condition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are many factors that go into this, and a lot of them depend on your specific situation.%20http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/are-there-opportunities-to-buy-with-a-low-down-payment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are many factors that go into this, and a lot of them depend on your specific situation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many factors that go into this, and a lot of them depend on your specific situation. &lt;strong&gt;Your best bet is to speak with a professional real estate agent&lt;/strong&gt;, and we’d be more than happy to have a conversation and figure out what works best for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, would like more information, or are ready to talk about loan options, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/are-there-opportunities-to-buy-with-a-low-down-payment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/are-there-opportunities-to-buy-with-a-low-down-payment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
=======
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
>>>>>>> cd1c7b7baf4308f7ac54304945870ef602d4f876
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <title>What to Know as We Kick off the Spring Selling Season</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fKuB0aktmGs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where are things headed in our real estate market as spring begins? Keep reading to find out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to give you a bit of a recap on the first quarter of the year and what to expect as we move into spring and summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re ready to kick off the spring selling season after a slight slowdown toward the end of the last year&lt;/strong&gt;. Even though the number of units sold has gone down lately, that has to do more with a lack of inventory than it does with the health of our market. We’re still in a healthy, strong seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;
=======
        <title>A Fox in Space</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SFFy_drFrZs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Master cleanse pork belly pour-over VHS kogi locavore. Butcher chartreuse pour-over, farm-to-table slow-carb asymmetrical hexagon man braid. Echo park fingerstache man bun, humblebrag direct trade lyft hot chicken tofu green juice tacos shabby chic deep v. Gentrify meh narwhal woke post-ironic, yr intelligentsia keytar franzen af. Poke vape skateboard, la croix beard pok pok mlkshk scenester ramps &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gastropub&lt;/a&gt; marfa r&lt;/strong&gt;etro roof party kinfolk unicorn. Lomo keffiyeh gochujang slow-carb kitsch celiac. Succulents asymmetrical franzen intelligentsia tofu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bushwick&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;'http://google.com'&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;marfa&lt;/a&gt; wayfarers heirloom pork belly. Tumblr ramps roof party, church-key portland tbh viral letterpress. Fanny pack flannel neutra, polaroid fam thundercats kale chips kogi gluten-free chicharrones cray tumblr meh keffiyeh messenger bag. Church-key vegan mixtape, ramps DIY fixie PBR&amp;amp;B keffiyeh pinterest pop-up offal. Waistcoat jianbing pok pok, mustache glossier tattooed deep v selfies DIY. Beard fingerstache cray XOXO, iPhone readymade forage offal. Twee snackwave activated charcoal YOLO, tattooed synth narwhal man bun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/homesearch/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/home-search.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; alt=&quot;Home Search&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
>>>>>>> cd1c7b7baf4308f7ac54304945870ef602d4f876

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the median price in the single-family home market is up to $355,000 and we’re seeing an appreciation rate of around 8%.&lt;/p&gt;

<<<<<<< HEAD
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re still in a healthy, strong seller’s market.%20http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/what-to-know-as-we-kick-off-the-spring-selling-season.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re still in a healthy, strong seller’s market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
=======
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is an example of a pull quote%20http://localhost:4000/a-fox-in-space.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is an example of a pull quote”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
>>>>>>> cd1c7b7baf4308f7ac54304945870ef602d4f876

&lt;p&gt;What economic factors have led to this? One of them is a bit of a slowdown in terms of job growth. &lt;strong&gt;At the same time, we’re not seeing as many people move to the state of Utah, and wage growth isn’t necessarily keeping up with how fast real estate is evolving&lt;/strong&gt;. A wage increase is not expected this year, but it’s something we’d really like to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean to you? Well, if you’re thinking about buying or selling this spring, you might want to jump in early and get ahead of the summer rush. &lt;strong&gt;If you get in now while prices are still high, inventory is still extremely low, and the rush has yet to enter the fray, you could stand to get a better deal&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us about real estate in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<<<<<<< HEAD
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/what-to-know-as-we-kick-off-the-spring-selling-season.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/what-to-know-as-we-kick-off-the-spring-selling-season.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
=======
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-fox-in-space.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-fox-in-space.html</guid>
>>>>>>> cd1c7b7baf4308f7ac54304945870ef602d4f876
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thank You For Celebrating With Us</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/efTglAA-4_4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d like to extend our thanks to those that joined us for our Founders Day celebration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we wanted to send you a quick message thanking all those who helped us celebrate 66 years of business at our recent Founders Day event. We wouldn’t be here without your help and support. Additionally, we wanted to let you know that we will be hosting another event this summer. This will be a barbecue for you, your family, and your friends! More information on this will be released at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/thank-you-for-celebrating-with-us.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/thank-you-for-celebrating-with-us.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
<<<<<<< HEAD
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You’re Invited to Our Founder’s Day Celebration This March</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ljS5TRHo2YA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;2019 is our 66-year anniversary of being in the real estate business, and to celebrate, we&amp;rsquo;re hosting our very own Founder&amp;rsquo;s Day celebration this March.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2019 marks the 66th year that Colemere Realty has been in business, and we’ve decided to throw a party to celebrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we’ve brought in our father (and previous owner of Colemere Realty) Tom Colemere to tell the story of how our brokerage got started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our grandfather founded Colemere Realty in 1953. He originally worked in the furniture and appliance business, but a fire damaged his establishment and left him in debt. To pay off that debt, he became a real estate agent. A short time after, he became his own boss. We joined the family business many years later, and a large part of our continued success is due to our father Tom being a great mentor to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you plan on attending, please RSVP.%20http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/youre-invited-to-our-founders-day-celebration-this-march.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you plan on attending, please RSVP.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, to commemorate our 66th year in business, &lt;strong&gt;we want to invite you to our Founder’s Day celebration on March 8 right here at our office from 11 a.m. to 6 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on attending, please &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1bNk_MKQdtn1tFByN8kc2A6Ihm3lUC9LSFcxjOlbtWHA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RSVP here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;with your name, number, and what kind of pie you would like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/youre-invited-to-our-founders-day-celebration-this-march.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/youre-invited-to-our-founders-day-celebration-this-march.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Check With Your Local Municipality Before Renting Out an ADU</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zEiXerPGQyo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessory dwelling units represent a great opportunity for homeowners, but there are rules for renting them out that you need to pay attention to.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may know, Salt Lake City passed an ordinance last October that allowed all homeowners to have accessory dwelling units (ADUs) on their property. If you’re looking to make some extra money through real estate investing or you’d like to have additional family members (such as in-laws) live on your property, ADUs are a great option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, today we want to remind you that there are different types of legislation being considered for different cities regarding ADUs, so &lt;strong&gt;it’s important that you check with your local municipality before deciding to rent one&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we mention this is because companies that specialize in ADUs, such as Airbnb and VRBO, were market disruptors when they first came on the scene. They gave homeowners a platform to rent their ADUs, and as more and more started doing it, state and city governments became concerned that a surplus of ADUs would become a potential neighborhood nuisance. They don’t want streets to become overcrowded with cars or households with ADUs to become disruptive, so they stepped in and established some ground rules for renting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are a lot of great opportunities to be had with ADUs, but you need to make sure that you follow these rules before adding one to your property.%20http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/check-with-your-local-municipality-before-renting-out-an-adu.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are a lot of great opportunities to be had with ADUs, but you need to make sure that you follow these rules before adding one to your property.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of great opportunities to be had with ADUs, but you need to make sure that you follow these rules before adding one to your property. Also, &lt;strong&gt;you should consider the management aspect of renting out an ADU because that responsibility falls on you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any more questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/check-with-your-local-municipality-before-renting-out-an-adu.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/check-with-your-local-municipality-before-renting-out-an-adu.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Homeowner Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Check Out This Quick Guide to Accessory Dwelling Units</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5grholfBnq4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;d like to shed some light on the hot topic of accessory dwelling units.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in making some extra money through real estate investing, or simply how to have your mother-in-law (legally) live with you, then having an accessory dwelling unit (ADU) on your property may be the perfect solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ADUs, which can be attached or detached, allow one additional family to reside on your lot&lt;/strong&gt;. This can be a wonderful option for those with elderly parents moving in or if you have adult children coming back to live with you temporarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our team would be happy to assist if you are curious about how to pursue this option.%20http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/check-out-this-quick-guide-to-accessory-dwelling-units.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our team would be happy to assist if you are curious about how to pursue this option.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you so choose, you can charge rent for those living in your ADU, as we mentioned earlier. So, in the light of recent legislation pertaining to this subject, our team would be happy to assist if you are curious about how to pursue this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/check-out-this-quick-guide-to-accessory-dwelling-units.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://colemererealtyvideoblog.com/check-out-this-quick-guide-to-accessory-dwelling-units.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Homeowner Tips</category>
=======
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
>>>>>>> cd1c7b7baf4308f7ac54304945870ef602d4f876
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
