<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dallas Mortgage Lender – The Betz Team</title>
    <description>The Betz Team are your local Dallas mortgage lenders. There’s more to a mortgage than the close. Request your consultation today.</description>
    <link>https://winningwithwade.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://winningwithwade.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 10:12:44 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 10:12:44 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Get Rid of “You Are Pre-Approved” Phone Calls &amp; Junk Mail Using Pre-Screened Opt Out!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you get junk mail from other mortgage companies, insurance agents, credit card companies and car dealers with ads telling you that you have already been pre-approved to do business with them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, let me tell you why!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit bureaus make a ton of money selling “credit profiles” to companies that are looking for a certain type of financial history. While they don’t know your social security number, the company sending you the pre-approved offer goes to the credit bureau and pays for a list based on certain criteria—criteria like minimum credit scores, geographic areas, mortgage or car loans, or outstanding credit card balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read the tiny, tiny print, they must also disclose that you were “pre-screened” and that’s why you were sent the marketing solicitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in the tiny, tiny print (that you can barely read), they must disclose how to Opt Out so your name and address are not sold, which also eliminates some of your junk mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of reading the fine print, I want to tell you how to opt out of receiving the pre-screened offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the website to visit is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.optoutprescreen.com/selection&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OptOutPrescreen.com/selection&lt;/a&gt;. You have a couple of options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can opt out from receiving offers for five years. This can be done online but you’ll have to renew every five years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can opt out permanently. However, you must download a form and MAIL it to the address provided.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can also opt back in if you opted out previously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s another link to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.optoutprescreen.com/faq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/a&gt; that describes what happens when you opt out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help opting out, please feel free to call me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/how-to-get-rid-of-you-are-pre-approved-phone-calls-junk-mail-using-pre-screened-opt-out.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/how-to-get-rid-of-you-are-pre-approved-phone-calls-junk-mail-using-pre-screened-opt-out.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Important Announcement About My Future</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/152cRSkQVJ0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m here to announce a transition in my career. I’m leaving Guardian Mortgage, but I’m staying in the business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got some huge news to share with you today. After 14 wonderful years with Guardian Mortgage, I have decided to pursue a different opportunity. I can’t thank Guardian enough for thirty years of support in my career, and I will forever be in their debt. I’m not getting out of the business, however, so if I can help you going forward, I would love to do so. &lt;strong&gt;My number isn’t changing, but my new team email is &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#084;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#066;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#122;&amp;#084;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#064;&amp;#087;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#087;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#087;&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#084;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#066;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#122;&amp;#084;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#064;&amp;#087;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#087;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#087;&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and personal email is &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#087;&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#087;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#087;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#087;&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#087;&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#087;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#087;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#087;&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions for me about this transition or about anything related to the mortgage world, always feel free to reach out via phone or email. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 12:35:50 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/an-important-announcement-about-my-future.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/an-important-announcement-about-my-future.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nine Things You May Not Have Thought About When Buying Your Next Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You may not be in the market (yet) to buy another home, but when you do, here are nine things to consider.  And if you are selling your home, these things also apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Good View = Higher Price:&lt;/strong&gt; The view really doesn’t matter. It could be a pond. A view of a mountain or valley.  The rule of thumb is that you can expect to pay a higher price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Sold AS IS&lt;/strong&gt;: Sellers will sometimes negotiate the price or give a dollar concession rather than put the home back on the market and start all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Gated community:&lt;/strong&gt; It might have a gate—but what does that really mean?  Can anyone push a button to open the gate?  Or is there a special card or access code to gain entry?  If security is an issue, it pays to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Curb appeal:&lt;/strong&gt; If the yard is neglected, the weeds are taking over or the outside paint job is fading, the inside is usually neglected too.  Get a home inspection and be especially careful to look for hidden maintenance items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Check the area for crime&lt;/strong&gt;: It’s still about location, location, location!  You can get crime stats from your local police or sheriff’s department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Check out the school system:&lt;/strong&gt; Same as above.  In addition, use the Internet to do some of your own research to compare it to other schools in your area (including private schools).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Don’t buy into the “marketing” fluff:&lt;/strong&gt; Beware of descriptions such as “cozy, cute, fixer-upper, charming,” etc.  Pay more attention to the “facts”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Lowest price in the neighborhood:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a red flag because people usually don’t sell at a lower price because they don’t need the money.  It’s priced low because of some other issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Don’t believe what you read:&lt;/strong&gt; Remember that the real estate agent is the one who creates the marketing strategies – and it’s all in the way they “perceive” it.  So if you are interested in the home, go ahead and view it, but make your own decision.  (If you are selling, ask to review the listing information before it is published.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/nine-things-you-may-not-have-thought-about-when-buying-your-next-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/nine-things-you-may-not-have-thought-about-when-buying-your-next-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tweak Your Withholding Taxes – Filing a New W-4 Form with Your Employer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Remember filling out a W-4 form when you were first hired?  It’s the form that determines how much money your employer withholds from your paycheck to pay federal and state taxes—based upon the number of “allowances” that you claimed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But have you checked to see if it’s still applicable?  Consider adjusting your W-4 form if the following applies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You owed the IRS money – You may want to have more money withheld from your paycheck. In fact, if you owed too much, the IRS can assess you and add a penalty for not depositing enough money into your account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve experienced a “life change” like
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Marriage&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Divorce&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Birth or adoption of a child&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Purchase of home&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Refinance of mortgage&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Retirement&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You expect to earn money from your home-based business or other source that does not withhold income taxes from the check.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve had a change in itemized deductions
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medical expenses&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gifts to charity&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dependent care expenses&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Education credits&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Child tax credit&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To INCREASE the amount of taxes from your paycheck, you will need to DECREASE the number of dependents.  You can also specify a dollar amount—like $50 per pay period.  Likewise, to have LESS money deducted, INCREASE that number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend that you check your withholding every year—right after you’ve filed your income tax return.  The IRS offers a withholding calculator at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irs.gov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IRS.gov&lt;/a&gt; and you’ll need your most recent tax return and current paycheck stub. Or, ask your tax preparer to help you adjust your withholding so you don’t owe too much—or get a large refund from the IRS—at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/tweak-your-withholding-taxes-filing-a-new-w-4-form-with-your-employer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/tweak-your-withholding-taxes-filing-a-new-w-4-form-with-your-employer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Derogatory Credit Items and Their Effect on Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BC8jNpUld8o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’ve had credit issues such as a foreclosure, short sale, or bankruptcy, you can buy a home again in the future. However, you might not be able to for seven years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people understand that a negative life event, such as a short sale or foreclosure, affects your credit. &lt;strong&gt;It will also have some repercussions for mortgage qualifying purposes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different loan programs have different time frame requirements for the different events. It can take anywhere from one to seven years for you to be able to buy a home again, depending on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Different loan programs have different time frame requirements.%20https://winningwithwade.com/derogatory-credit-items-and-their-effect-on-homebuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Different loan programs have different time frame requirements.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These days, I’m seeing a lot of Chapter 7 and Chapter 13 bankruptcies.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s a pretty wide gap for what the different programs allow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is contemplating one of these actions it’s important that we have a conversation up front so that we can lay out a roadmap for what happened and what we can do to get you back into homeownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is looking to buy a home, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:07:32 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/derogatory-credit-items-and-their-effect-on-homebuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/derogatory-credit-items-and-their-effect-on-homebuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Avoid Paying These Bills Using Your Autopay Account</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Paying your installment loans, your mortgage and car payment via auto-pay is a simple way to make sure that the critical bills get paid every month.  It helps you avoid late fees.  The payments are secure.  It helps reduce paper invoices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before you AUTO-PAY all of your bills, there are some that may not make sense to streamline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, use the automatic payment option only if you are positive that you will have enough money in the account to pay that bill on the due date.  Otherwise, you may have overdraft charges and the bank may charge you interest on the overdraft (because basically it’s a loan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some bills that you should avoid putting on auto-pay:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annual subscriptions, annual memberships, or semi-annual insurance premiums. &lt;/strong&gt;You are more likely to forget about them and you may end up overdrawing your account or are getting charged without realizing it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utility, Telephone and Cable Bills.&lt;/strong&gt; Those bills fluctuate from month to month and could be a different total each time. As a result, you might either overpay or underpay.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credit Card Bills. &lt;/strong&gt;A minimum payment is usually required and it could change month to month based upon your credit card balance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trial Services.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s tempting to sign up for a free trial but, when you do, read the fine print.  Most trial services ask you to enter your credit card information and ask you to check a box that you authorize auto-pay—UNLESS YOU CANCEL the service before the first charge.  Put the expiration date of the trial service on your calendar and determine if you will continue to use the service or cancel it before the expiration date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more thing—most auto-pay bank accounts have check boxes where you can request both a notification 5 days BEFORE a bill will be paid and an ALERT checkbox when the money has been taken out of your account.  It’s a great heads-up service to ensure that your account is never overdrawn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 13:48:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/why-you-should-avoid-paying-these-bills-using-your-autopay-account.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/why-you-should-avoid-paying-these-bills-using-your-autopay-account.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8 Mistakes to Avoid If You Are Thinking Of Building or Remodeling a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever walked into a home (either a brand new one or one that’s been around for 25 years or more) and said to yourself, “I wonder what the builder was thinking when they built this house?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you are thinking of finally building your dream home. Or considering downsizing the one you currently own. Or need to remodel the one you currently live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 8 things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a vision of what you want your home to look like.&lt;/strong&gt; The floor plan is just the first step in the process. There a hundreds of thousands of decisions you will need to make. Take just the bathroom – &lt;em&gt;what color tile? What pattern? Will the cabinets match? Faucets? Countertops? The floor? And that’s just one bathroom!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find the right people&lt;/strong&gt; – By people, I mean an architect, a builder, sub-contractors, suppliers. Are they licensed and bonded? More importantly, can you get along with them? Do they offer suggestions? Are they difficult to deal with?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visit the construction site often&lt;/strong&gt; – Be sure that the home/remodeling is being built to your expectations. Ask questions. Make suggestions. Visiting your home every other day is recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building too big of a home&lt;/strong&gt; – Don’t think about what size you need right now—but what you will need 7 to 10 years from now. A well-designed 3,000 sq. ft. home may work just as well as an ill-designed 5,000 sq. ft. home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work that you can do to reduce costs&lt;/strong&gt; – Ask the builder what sweat equity he/she will allow you to do to help reduce costs. Painting the walls or staining the trim. Maybe you have a friend who is a licensed electrician who would charge you less.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think about the upgrades&lt;/strong&gt; – When a builder provides you with a price to build your home/remodeling, it’s usually based on “medium grade” materials. Take kitchen cabinets for example. What type, color and grade are included? Or should you pay $8,000 extra for solid maple cabinets instead? It depends on your budget and if you can find something that you like in the medium grade so you can use the money for something else. Other than you loving maple wood, there is very little resale value in upgraded cabinets when it comes time to sell. Consider only adding your MUST HAVE upgrades.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think about selling your home in the future&lt;/strong&gt; – Even if you never plan to sell your home, your descendants may have to do so. Build your home so it’s not a nightmare to sell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think about monthly mortgage payments&lt;/strong&gt; – When you have been pre-approved for your mortgage amount there are a few things to consider.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What will the interest rate be when the home is completed?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How much will extra upgrades add to the monthly payment?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How much money will you need after the closing (window coverings, furniture, landscaping)?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/8-mistakes-to-avoid-if-you-are-thinking-of-building-or-remodeling-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/8-mistakes-to-avoid-if-you-are-thinking-of-building-or-remodeling-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do you think you are paying too much in property taxes?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the National Taxpayers Union, roughly 60% of the nation’s taxable property may be over-assessed.  Taxpayers are paying hundreds of thousands of dollars more than they need to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NTU also states that 30% of all people who appeal their property assessments end up with lower taxes.  Your chances are especially good in a time of declining property values.  Assessors use data from the Multiple Listing Service (just like real estate agents do) to determine assessed values.  However, in a slow market, sales data is simply not available and there is a good chance that the assessment is faulty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what you need to do if you decide to appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Delay – &lt;/strong&gt;When you receive your assessment notice, you usually have only 30 to 60 days (sometimes an actual date is stated in the fine print) to let city hall know that you plan to appeal.  At this point, it’s ONLY a “notification” that you don’t agree with the dollar amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will then provide you with a hearing date, which will give you time to gather your evidence as to why you think the assessment is too high.  They should also provide you with a list of “allowed” documents that you can bring to the hearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gather the Evidence – &lt;/strong&gt;First, go to the assessor’s office to check out the data they have on your property.  There may be mistakes in square footage or lot size, or other data may be inaccurate.  Write down the addresses of homes similar to yours (in the neighborhood) and ask to see their information, too.  Don’t worry, the information is public and others can see what YOUR property taxes are, too.  Next, get sales data from a real estate agent and find out what homes are selling for—both listed and sold transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look for Unique Factors That Could Make a Difference –&lt;/strong&gt; Are you next to high-tension electrical wires? A drainage ditch?  On an extremely busy street versus your neighbor who lives on a cul-de-sac?  Check to make sure the assessor made adjustments for negative factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hire an Appraiser –&lt;/strong&gt; Refer back to the list of documents that you might be required to present when your hearing is held. You may need an appraisal, which could run $300 or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Word of Caution – &lt;/strong&gt;If the appraisal or the comparable sales from the real estate agent comes back HIGHER, cancel your hearing appointment.  They also have the ability to RAISE your property taxes at that hearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a link to a handy homeowner’s checklist, “Steps to Take in Appealing Your Assessment”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ntu.org/publications/detail/ntu-in-the-news-kiplinger-how-to-appeal-property-taxes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.ntu.org/publications/detail/ntu-in-the-news-kiplinger-how-to-appeal-property-taxes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/do-you-think-you-are-paying-too-much-in-property-taxes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/do-you-think-you-are-paying-too-much-in-property-taxes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Power of Attorney – The Good, the Bad and the Ugly!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you know the story of Brooke Astor? She was one of the richest women in the world.  She gave her son power of attorney (when she became incapacitated) and he proceeded to spend hundreds of millions of dollars of her money for his personal benefit! When you give someone a Durable Power of Attorney, you are literally giving them total access to your bank accounts, your retirement, and the ability to sell your home, your jewelry and any other assets you might have.  It’s like giving them a &lt;em&gt;second set of keys to your car and saying, “here, take my car whenever you want to.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a Power of Attorney is a good thing, here are some safeguards to put in place and other things to consider when choosing someone to act on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know what you are giving away.  &lt;/strong&gt;The designated person you choose is known as an “agent”, and will have control over your finances and assets.  They can write checks against your bank account, sell your stocks, and dip into your retirement account.  You can modify your power of attorney to exclude certain accounts or limit them from certain powers (like selling your house).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose your agent carefully.  &lt;/strong&gt;The majority of legal issues that go to court are power of attorney crimes involving family members or close friends.  Only appoint someone as your agent if you can thoroughly trust them and they are keenly aware of what you want them to do in case you are not able to act on your own behalf.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider an ‘oversight agent’.  &lt;/strong&gt; Creating a plan for your agent to “report” to a third party doesn’t mean that you distrust them.  It means that you want them to keep good records, seek advice, and share them with someone else.  It could be your attorney or banker.  You may also want to share information about your power of attorney with other family members so your agent knows that other people &lt;em&gt;know (about the existence of the power of attorney)&lt;/em&gt; and might be watching for any misconduct!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get legal advice.   &lt;/strong&gt;While you can create a do-it-yourself power of attorney, you might want to use an attorney if your finances are complicated.  Also, your power of attorney is not written in stone, and can be changed at any time.  As long as you are mentally capable, you can remove or change agents or revoke the power of attorney and start over.  When this happens, it’s best to get legal advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you should become incapacitated for any reason, your family will probably have to go to court to get the authority to manage your affairs.  It’s costly and time consuming, and the person the court appoints may not be your first choice.  But by acting now, you can avoid family feuds and have the peace of mind that your financial affairs will be handled in the best interest of your family!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/a-power-of-attorney-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/a-power-of-attorney-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Does Delayed Financing Work and Will It Benefit You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mSBOP9OGrFo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is delayed financing and how can you benefit from it? Let’s discuss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every now and then, I meet with a homeowner who chose to make an all-cash purchase on their home. While there’s nothing wrong with buying your home this way, if you ever want to accrue debt on the property, my opinion is &lt;strong&gt;it’s best to start at the original point of purchase.&lt;/strong&gt; Today I’ll tell you why, but I’ll also explain an alternative option: &lt;strong&gt;delayed financing&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, subsequent to your all-cash purchase, you go to a lender to take cash out of the property, your cash-out refinance rate will be a little higher than the original purchase-money rates. What’s more, the IRS will only give you a 90-day window to close on a cash-out refinance from your original purchase and reclassify the debt from equity indebtedness to acquisition indebtedness. The significance of which is &lt;strong&gt;your mortgage interest can’t be written off on an equity indebtedness loan.   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a conversation worth having with your CPA, but I’ll give you the gist: If you ever want to have mortgage debt on your property, start by financing your home from the get-go. However, if you’ve already bought your home in cash, it’s not necessarily too late. &lt;strong&gt;Your next best option is to do it immediately thereafter through a delayed financing mortgage&lt;/strong&gt;, so you have the ability to deduct your mortgage interest come tax time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The way you structure financing on the front end correlates with your likelihood for success on the back end.%20https://winningwithwade.com/how-does-delayed-financing-work-and-will-it-benefit-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The way you structure financing on the front end correlates with your likelihood for success on the back end.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I should point out that delayed financing loans can be tricky. For one thing, &lt;strong&gt;lenders have to source the funds from the original cash purchase&lt;/strong&gt;—by far the most common issue that arises. In other words, the way we handle financing in a specific situation will depend on the source of the funds used to buy the home. For example, say the source was a secured asset like a brokerage line of credit or a home equity line of credit. In that case, the cash-out proceeds for the delayed financing loan must go directly to that particular creditor to pay back what was borrowed.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also fairly common for us to see situations where a third-party person has gifted the money to the original purchaser. Unfortunately, this will disqualify you from receiving a delayed financing loan. Based on Freddie Mac and Fannie Mae’s regulatory rules, it’ll be six months before you’re eligible for a cash-out refinance, which is, of course, problematic since you have just 90 days to receive the tax writeoff associated with acquisition indebtedness.     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is the way you structure financing on the front end correlates with your likelihood for success on the back end. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or you’re considering delayed financing for your situation, don’t hesitate to reach out to us first. We’d be happy to help you navigate through the complexities inherent in this type of loan. Talk to you soon! &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 14:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://winningwithwade.com/how-does-delayed-financing-work-and-will-it-benefit-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://winningwithwade.com/how-does-delayed-financing-work-and-will-it-benefit-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
