<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Your Key To Memphis - your professional Memphis Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.weknowmemphis.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 12:31:03 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 12:31:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Real Estate Terms You Should Know</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D-W6ES7riNU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to explain a few different real estate terms in detail. Oftentimes, we use a lot of shorthand or abbreviated words without realizing it, and I wanted to make sure you’re clear on what some of these terms mean when you hear them come up in conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Comps.&lt;/strong&gt; This is short for “comparables.” It’s just a word that we use to refer to homes that are comparable to yours when we’re getting ready to buy or sell a home. They help us know whether or not a home’s value is in the right range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=PMI is required for homebuyers that are putting down less than 20% on their home purchase.%20http://www.weknowmemphis.com/3-real-estate-terms-you-should-know.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“PMI is required for homebuyers that are putting down less than 20% on their home purchase.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. PMI.&lt;/strong&gt; This stands for private mortgage insurance. It’s required for homebuyers that are putting down less than 20% on their home purchase. This insurance insures the lender, but it doesn’t have to last forever. Once you have 20% equity in your home, you can get a re-appraisal and get it removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt; They refer to all the additional fees it takes to finalize a home closing. They include things like escrow fees, lender fees, and attorney fees. It doesn’t include inspection costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are just a few terms that I wanted to make sure you were aware of. If you have any questions about the Memphis real estate market or anything else, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 11:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/3-real-estate-terms-you-should-know.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.weknowmemphis.com/3-real-estate-terms-you-should-know.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Things You Should Not Compromise on as a Buyer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x6anp7sZmoE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to talk about five things that you should never compromise on as a buyer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The floor plan.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure that it fits your needs now and in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The school district.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if your kids are out of the house, this matters for resale value.  You can find out about the different municipalities online to see what school system the home you are looking at is in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It is important not to overextend yourself financially.%20http://www.weknowmemphis.com/5-things-you-should-not-compromise-on-as-a-buyer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It is important not to overextend yourself financially.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The neighbors.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are interested in a house in a neighborhood you are unfamiliar with, drive around during different times during the day to make sure you will be happy and comfortable there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Your budget.&lt;/strong&gt; It is important not to overextend yourself financially. You want to be comfortable with what you are buying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The commute.&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe take a test drive of the commute before you decide to pull the trigger. This is another important factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or you are interested in buying or selling a home here in Memphis, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 11:23:13 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/5-things-you-should-not-compromise-on-as-a-buyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.weknowmemphis.com/5-things-you-should-not-compromise-on-as-a-buyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Ways to Compete Against Cash Buyers and Win Your Dream Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zJM9q3P_zvM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you make a competitive offer when you are going against cash buyers? While a lot of the market is not paying cash, there are some people who are. You’re not out of luck, though. I have a few options for you that will help you be competitive and win your dream home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Provide a level of comfort to the seller.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are comfortable with it, show them your bank statements and credit scores to prove that you have your finances in order. They will know you have quite a bit of cash if you are putting 20% down on a loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Consider not doing an inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; You always have the right to an inspection. But, if you are comfortable with not doing an inspection because you are buying as-is anyway, it could be huge for the seller to not have to deal with that. Inspections are a source of contention which could be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you are comfortable not having an inspection, you may be more appealing to a seller since they can avoid that possible contention.%20http://www.weknowmemphis.com/6-ways-to-compete-against-cash-buyers-and-win-your-dream-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you are comfortable not having an inspection, you may be more appealing to a seller since they can avoid that possible contention.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Have all the documentation ready for your lender.&lt;/strong&gt; This way, all they need is a contract from you and an appraisal. This will cut down the process tremendously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Expedite the appraisal process.&lt;/strong&gt; When you are supplying the documentation, ask the lender if they can order an appraisal the day they have the address. Let the seller know this so they can have a quicker closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Cash buyers think they should get a discount since they are spending cash.&lt;/strong&gt; This is not necessarily true. You could finance a little more to pay the seller more and the difference could only be $15 to $20 per month. The seller will choose you because you are providing more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Provide a letter about yourself.&lt;/strong&gt; If you write a personal letter about your family, it touches the seller’s heart. They know they are selling the home to someone who will love it as opposed to an investor, which means a lot to a seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about any of this or about buying or selling, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 09:38:56 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/6-ways-to-compete-against-cash-buyers-and-win-your-dream-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.weknowmemphis.com/6-ways-to-compete-against-cash-buyers-and-win-your-dream-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Numbers Are in for Memphis Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qQcaPjqVXVg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today I just wanted to give you a quick update on the Memphis real estate market.&lt;/strong&gt; We took a look at the numbers for April and wanted to share them with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw 1,664 home sales recorded in the month of April. That figure is up 13% from this time last year. At the same time, the average sale price was up by 7%. We usually see around 5% appreciation on average, but the jump to 7% is great news for homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=36% of all purchases during this time were from investors.%20http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-latest-numbers-are-in-for-memphis-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“36% of all purchases during this time were from investors.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;36% of all purchases during this time were from investors, for what it’s worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The average list price is up 26% from this time last year, and the average sale price for new construction homes is up to $394,000.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s just a quick overview of some of the general numbers in the Memphis market. If you want some more specific numbers for the area you’re in, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email and I’d be happy to discuss them with you. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 15:07:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-latest-numbers-are-in-for-memphis-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-latest-numbers-are-in-for-memphis-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Interview Questions to Ask Your Realtor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FuAu1-6v_Mc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to give you some tips on how to interview agents before you hire them to help you sell your home. Here are seven questions you need to ask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. How long have you been in the business? &lt;/strong&gt;A good way to gauge an agent’s experience and productivity is to ask them about their designation. A good designation for an agent to have is the CRS, or certified residential specialist, which requires you to have a certain level of production and work a certain number of hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What is your list-to-sale price ratio?&lt;/strong&gt; Your Realtor should know their average list price to sales price. If they listed a home for $100,000 and sold it for $95,000, then their list price to sales price would be 95%. Seeing the averages can show you how much more they can get you. And, how much more money in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What’s our best marketing plan or strategy?&lt;/strong&gt; Are they online? How do they take their pictures? Are they on Zillow? Whatever you would like to know about that, feel free to ask. They should even have some samples for you to see, or different sites to go to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Whatever you would like to know about that, feel free to ask.%20http://www.weknowmemphis.com/7-interview-questions-to-ask-your-realtor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Whatever you would like to know about that, feel free to ask.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Do they have references that you can talk to?&lt;/strong&gt; You should look for someone that can point you to references. You should be able to call them if you wanted. Zillow is huge right now for reviews, so we try to get a lot of reviews on Zillow. You can see if a Realtor that you are looking at has their reviews on Zillow and what they say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Can you review the documents ahead of time?&lt;/strong&gt; Some people may send pre-listing documents that you may want to look at before they come back. There is nothing wrong with looking at that and asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. How much do you charge and what kind of guarantee do you offer?&lt;/strong&gt; Since commissions are not a set amount, this can range. Nobody can set these fees for you as they do depend on different companies and agents. Is there a satisfaction guarantee included as well, or some other kind of guarantee?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. What have I not asked that I need to know about?&lt;/strong&gt; See if there are any common questions that slipped your mind or you didn’t even think to ask about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this list or anything else related to selling your home, please contact me by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 15:34:57 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/7-interview-questions-to-ask-your-realtor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.weknowmemphis.com/7-interview-questions-to-ask-your-realtor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest From Our Memphis Area Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bna0uYle7Zo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest numbers from our real estate market have just come in, so I’d like to share a quick update with you today. Let’s take a look at how our market fared this February and March compared to what we saw during the same time in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, sales and average home prices have both risen year over year. Year-to-date, prices have actually risen 8% so far. This is a decent improvement upon the 5% average increase we typically see over this period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This lack of inventory is great for sellers but can make it difficult for buyers to find the right property.%20http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-latest-from-our-memphis-area-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This lack of inventory is great for sellers but can make it difficult for buyers to find the right property.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While sales volume is up, we are still experiencing a shortage of inventory.&lt;/strong&gt; As of the end of March, we recorded just 3,883 units on the market. In March of 2017, there were 4,464 units on the market. This lack of inventory is great for sellers but can make it difficult for buyers to find the right property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they are able to find a home, buyers currently have the opportunity to take advantage of today’s low interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what your real estate goals may be, I would be happy to help you discover the best way to navigate these current market conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:44:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-latest-from-our-memphis-area-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-latest-from-our-memphis-area-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Repairs to Make Before a Home Inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3yV4aVGmIRg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to share with you 10 observations I received from an inspector that he sees during every home inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Windows often need to be replaced or resealed.&lt;/strong&gt; In terms of cost, it’s not as big of a deal as you would think to fix those issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Check to make sure the chimney is cleaned and well-maintained.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a good idea to have the chimney checked every two years. Almost nobody does that, but we have people we can refer you to if you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Make sure doors seal and shut properly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Take care of the heating and air conditioning system.&lt;/strong&gt; If you haven’t changed the filter recently, it’s a good thing to do. It’s cheap and a great thing to do ahead of time so that you can provide the letter of service when it’s time for the inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Provide and change the lightbulbs. &lt;/strong&gt;I know it sounds silly, but you would not believe how many times we see in inspection reports that a certain number of lights don’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Move or pack away any items that will prevent an inspector from accessing areas they’ll need to in order to do their jobs.%20http://www.weknowmemphis.com/10-repairs-to-make-before-a-home-inspection.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Move or pack away any items that will prevent an inspector from accessing areas they’ll need to in order to do their jobs.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Check for rotten wood around the home. &lt;/strong&gt;That includes walking around the exterior, looking behind the gutters, and under the eaves and soffits. Home inspectors will be looking for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Buyers want a roof that is in great shape.&lt;/strong&gt; We have a roofer who can come out and inspect yours to see if there are any issues or leaks. For $75, he can give us a roofing letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Tighten your plumbing fixtures. &lt;/strong&gt;Make sure there aren’t any drips or cracks that could cause water- or mold-related damages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Make sure there is no furniture in the inspector’s way. &lt;/strong&gt;Move or pack away any items that will prevent an inspector from accessing areas they’ll need to in order to do their jobs. Panel boxes, water heaters, furnaces, and other such key areas are especially important to keep clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Know your home.&lt;/strong&gt; We always put things off until we get ready to list, but if you take the time to familiarize yourself with the workings and condition of your home, the easy it will be for you to address any problems before it comes to inspect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need any resources or have any questions, please feel free to reach out to us. We’re always happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 10:09:19 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/10-repairs-to-make-before-a-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.weknowmemphis.com/10-repairs-to-make-before-a-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Additional Home Buying Costs You Need to Look Out for</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/11Ll0f6k-Sc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buying a home, there are a few costs you need to look for besides PITI (principal, interest, taxes, insurance) to get an idea of what you can really afford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Utility bills.&lt;/strong&gt; You can get an estimate of this cost from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mlgw.com&quot;&gt;www.mlgw.com&lt;/a&gt;, and you also have to take into consideration who will be living in the home to get a better idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Commuting costs.&lt;/strong&gt; What’s the difference, location-wise, between where you want to live and where you work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HOA fees can really affect your monthly mortgage payment.%20http://www.weknowmemphis.com/4-additional-home-buying-costs-you-need-to-look-out-for.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HOA fees can really affect your monthly mortgage payment.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Homeowners association fees.&lt;/strong&gt; We have many HOA neighborhoods here in Memphis, and HOA fees aren’t considered part of the payment your lender provides you. These fees can vary quite a bit and can really affect your monthly mortgage payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Different credit cards.&lt;/strong&gt; When you move in, you’ll receive a lot of different credit cards in the mail from Home Depot, Lowe’s, Sears, and other places, so be careful about signing up for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re saving for a home, here’s a list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Blog+Attachments/Screen+Shot+2018-03-02+at+12.35.38+PM.png&quot;&gt;ways you can conserve your money&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about additional costs to look out for when buying a home or you have any other real estate needs I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 13:13:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/4-additional-home-buying-costs-you-need-to-look-out-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.weknowmemphis.com/4-additional-home-buying-costs-you-need-to-look-out-for.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do Rising Interest Rates Mean for Buyers and Sellers Right Now?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/63afHHjxLZ4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are interest rates impacting our current market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ve been increasing slowly lately, and we’re above the 4% mark now. It’s hard to complain, though, since they were so low for such a long time, and it’s predicted that they won’t be that low again for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Inventory is low and it’s a strong seller’s market.%20http://www.weknowmemphis.com/what-do-rising-interest-rates-mean-for-buyers-and-sellers-right-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Inventory is low and it’s a strong seller’s market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of 2018, rates are expected to rise even further into the high 4% range. This means a lot of sellers have been looking at their current interest rate and thinking about refinancing. Any seller who’s considering refinancing is probably staying where they’re at, and &lt;strong&gt;this trend has created a shortage of inventory in our market, both locally and nationwide.&lt;/strong&gt; As you can see in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis_Year_to_Dat_Home_Sales_Active_Inventory-1.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;graph in the video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, our year-to-date inventory is the lowest it’s been in the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a buyer, the current situation might be a bit of a struggle.&lt;/strong&gt; There aren’t very many homes to choose from, and in some price points, multiple offer situations are common. If you’re a seller, you might be able to get more money that you thought you could for your home sale right now.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As spring progresses,  the inventory situation will hopefully get better. In the meantime, if you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 13:38:10 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/what-do-rising-interest-rates-mean-for-buyers-and-sellers-right-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.weknowmemphis.com/what-do-rising-interest-rates-mean-for-buyers-and-sellers-right-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Get a Pre-Home Inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/R9soScfn7mA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to talk to you about what you need to know, as a future home seller, about pre-home inspections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re getting ready to list your property, we can give you a list of home inspectors who we know and like. The cost will be in the $300 to $400 range. They’ll come out to look at everything to make sure there aren’t any surprises that buyers may come across. That way, &lt;strong&gt;the buyer won’t come back asking for a discounted price&lt;/strong&gt; for some malfunction they discovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you take care of the inspection ahead of time, you won’t have to rush through to get things done.%20http://www.weknowmemphis.com/why-you-should-get-a-pre-home-inspection.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you take care of the inspection ahead of time, you won’t have to rush through to get things done.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason to get a pre-home inspection is that when you go under contract, there are only so many days to negotiate the home inspections and the resolution period. As a seller, you may only have three to five days to get estimates. If you take care of it ahead of time, you won’t have to rush through to get things done. Additionally, &lt;strong&gt;it helps you get a good price for your home&lt;/strong&gt; to make any repairs that come up during the inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The buyer may still do their own inspection, but with a pre-home inspection, &lt;strong&gt;you can say that you’ve already disclosed everything.&lt;/strong&gt; It will make the buyer feel better about your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need a list of trusted inspectors or have any further questions, feel free to reach out anytime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 08:20:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/why-you-should-get-a-pre-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.weknowmemphis.com/why-you-should-get-a-pre-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
