<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SoCal Real Estate Video Blog with Tim Majka</title>
    <description>Our mission at Imagine Realty is to be your best resource for SoCal real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Imagine Realty, your professional SoCal Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://socalrealestatetips.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 13:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 13:26:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Incentives to Owning Investment Property?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rRZ_GGwwaiw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, many of my clients have made home purchases and are beginning to turn their attention to what’s next: saving for retirement, contributing to their kids’ college fund, or taking steps to reduce their taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Give it some time, and you’ll reap the benefits of great cash flow from your property.%20http://socalrealestatetips.com/what-are-the-incentives-to-owning-investment-property.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Give it some time, and you’ll reap the benefits of great cash flow from your property.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t considered owning investment property as an option, maybe now is the time—&lt;strong&gt;doing so comes with some major benefits that can be a driver for a strong financial well-being for you and your family.&lt;/strong&gt; There are four benefits, in particular, that I’d like to go over with you now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wealth.&lt;/strong&gt; Purchasing an investment property is great for wealth accumulation over time. Ultimately, you’ll own that property, and it’ll be an asset to your financial security.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appreciation.&lt;/strong&gt; Though market fluctuation is a factor, the appreciation rate we tend to see year over year in California is 5%. Putting 20% down on, say, a $500,000 investment will actually yield a much higher ROI than that 5% appreciate rate would suggest.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cash flow.&lt;/strong&gt; Like property values, the cost of rent steadily rises at a rate of about 5% each year. As you’re charging that additional 5% from your tenants from one year to the next, the cash flow you’re collecting will also continue to grow. Give it some time, and you’ll reap the benefits of great cash flow from your property.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tax benefits.&lt;/strong&gt; Often overlooked, an important thing to consider is that you’re able to write off depreciation—the physical attributes and structure of the property. By the time you own the property, this comes out to be about half of its value.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about what I’ve discussed in this video or about any other real estate-related questions, please reach out to me. We’d love the opportunity to assist you!    &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 12:36:28 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/what-are-the-incentives-to-owning-investment-property.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://socalrealestatetips.com/what-are-the-incentives-to-owning-investment-property.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Cost of Waiting to Buy Later Vs. Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XrhpneRvtfw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you buy now or wait? I have been asked this by potential buyers a lot recently because of how home prices have increased over the last 10 years. To help me answer this question, I have invited Steve Hankla of Doorway Home Loans to talk about what it costs today to buy a home versus what it may cost a year from now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Steve Hankla joins me to talk about what a home would cost you today versus what it would to wait a year.%20http://socalrealestatetips.com/the-cost-of-waiting-to-buy-later-vs-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Steve Hankla joins me to talk about what a home would cost you today versus what it would to wait a year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have provided timestamps so that you can jump to the section(s) that are of most interest to you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:45 – A background on our current market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:05 – The factors you need to consider&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:40 – Looking at past rates and our potential correction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:50 – The affordability investment analysis chart&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:20 – Why borrowing from your 401(k) could be a good option&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:05 – The tax benefits of buying instead of renting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions for Steve, you can reach out to him at (714) 470-5626 or email him at steve@gotoloanpro.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as always, if you have any buying or selling questions, please feel free to call or email me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 14:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/the-cost-of-waiting-to-buy-later-vs-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://socalrealestatetips.com/the-cost-of-waiting-to-buy-later-vs-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Miss Out on These Great Holiday Events</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4tP1Brq4MxE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your favorite holiday traditions? My family and I love to go and see The Young Americans perform at La Mirada Theatre; it really helps to put us in the Christmas spirit each year. If you’re looking for some great festivities to enjoy this winter season, check out our list or follow us on our social media pages for upcoming events that are guaranteed to put you in the holiday spirit throughout December. Maybe you’ll find a new tradition you can look forward to every year like we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitlongbeach.com/blog/ring-in-the-holidays-in-long-beach/&quot;&gt;Long Beach Holiday Events:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rancho Los Alamitos Open House - December 12-14&lt;br /&gt;Bixby Knolls Holiday Party - December 14&lt;br /&gt;Retro Row Open House&lt;br /&gt;Rose Park Tree Lighting&lt;br /&gt;A Baroque Christmas - December 8-9&lt;br /&gt;David Benoit’s Charlie Brown Christmas at the Carpenter Center - December 15&lt;br /&gt;Long Beach Ballet Presents “The Nutcracker” - December 15, 16&lt;br /&gt;Naples Holiday Boat Parade - December 8&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitlongbeach.com/blog/ring-in-the-holidays-in-long-beach/&quot;&gt;Click here for more holiday events in the Long Beach area!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discoverlosangeles.com/blog/los-angeles-holiday-events-and-activities&quot;&gt;LA Holiday Events:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;CHILL At The Queen Mary - Open now-January 7th.&lt;br /&gt;Holidays at Disneyland&lt;br /&gt;Drive Through Christmas Tree Lane!&lt;br /&gt;58th Annual L.A. County Holiday Celebration - December 24th, 2018&lt;br /&gt;Holiday Light Festival Train Ride - Now through December 23, 2017, and from December 26 – December 28, 2017.&lt;br /&gt;WINTER WONDERLAND &amp;amp; SANTA HOUSE - THE GROVE - Now through Dec. 24&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discoverlosangeles.com/blog/los-angeles-holiday-events-and-activities&quot;&gt;Click here for more holiday events in LA!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.orangecounty.net/html/Weekend_winter.html#losalamitos&quot;&gt;Orange County Holiday Events:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Annual Holiday Tree Lighting Ceremony - December 5, 2018&lt;br /&gt;Winter Wonderland - December 1, 2018&lt;br /&gt;Annual Newport Beach Christmas Boat Parade - December 19-23, 2018&lt;br /&gt;Crystal Cove Tree Lighting &amp;amp; Holiday Bazaar - December 1, 2018&lt;br /&gt;Moreno’s Restaurant 6th Annual Christmas Boutique - Sunday, December 2, 2018&lt;br /&gt;Annual Holiday Wassail Concert  - December 7 &amp;amp; 8&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.orangecounty.net/html/Weekend_winter.html#losalamitos&quot;&gt;Click here for more holiday events in Orange County!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 12:20:58 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/dont-miss-out-on-these-great-holiday-events.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://socalrealestatetips.com/dont-miss-out-on-these-great-holiday-events.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wishing you a happy Thanksgiving</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PmUsT0yiw_A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2018 holiday season has officially begun! We hope you are as excited as we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to take a moment to express our gratitude to all of you this Thanksgiving. We have met some truly wonderful people, and we’re proud to have helped so many reach their real estate goals over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wouldn’t be where we are today without all of your support. Enjoy your Thanksgiving dinner with all of your family and friends—that’s what we plan to do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us if you have any real estate questions. We would be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Majka&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imagine Realty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serving the greater Los Angeles, Orange County, and Long Beach area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1-800-309-1528&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim@ImagineRealty.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 16:57:04 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/wishing-you-a-happy-thanksgiving.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://socalrealestatetips.com/wishing-you-a-happy-thanksgiving.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join Us at Our October Seller’s Seminar</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rgohf2d2OUg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To RSVP visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/how-to-sell-your-home-for-top-dollar-free-event-wcomplimentary-wine-tasting-tickets-50712982897&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.imaginerealty.com/events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of possibly selling or making a move, I have an exciting announcement to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of selling your home and navigating today’s changing real estate market can be challenging, so if you’re thinking of selling your home or investment property now or in the future, we have an upcoming home seller seminar that’s just for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This seminar is happening on October 24 at the Seal Beach Winery from 6:30 p.m. to 8:00 p.m&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s free to attend, and you’ll also have the opportunity to sample some great complimentary wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’ll give you the tools, tips, and information you need to make the best decision with one of your biggest investments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’ve been considering selling your home or investment property, now is a great time.%20http://socalrealestatetips.com/join-us-at-our-october-sellers-seminar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’ve been considering selling your home or investment property, now is a great time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll also share the steps you need to take to sell your home for the most money and talk about you and your agent’s role in making the sale happen. Additionally, we’ll discuss the current market, share our marketing strategies, and show you how to outshine the competition and make your home look its best before listing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seal Beach Winery is located at 3387 West Cerritos Avenue, Los Alamitos, California. We look forward to seeing you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To RSVP visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/how-to-sell-your-home-for-top-dollar-free-event-wcomplimentary-wine-tasting-tickets-50712982897&quot;&gt;www.imaginerealty.com/events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions in the meantime, please feel free to reach out to us. We’d be happy to speak to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 11:12:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/join-us-at-our-october-sellers-seminar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://socalrealestatetips.com/join-us-at-our-october-sellers-seminar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's the First Step in Buying a Home? Meeting With a Lender</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vkvvgHUHtJ0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things we recommend when you’re considering a real estate purchase is to get in touch with a lender. Doing so will be a critical first step in ensuring your success throughout the rest of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate why, I recently brought on Steve Hankla from Doorway Home Loans—a mortgage expert with 34 years of experience—to discuss some tips for people about to embark on a home buying journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve’s first tip to all homebuyers was to get pre-approved early on. This will set you up with a clear understanding of your financial circumstances and allow you to proceed with confidence in your home search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Lenders like Steve can identify and resolve certain details of your financial health that may otherwise go unnoticed.%20http://socalrealestatetips.com/whats-the-first-step-in-buying-a-home-meeting-with-a-lender.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Lenders like Steve can identify and resolve certain details of your financial health that may otherwise go unnoticed.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;During the pre-approval process, lenders like Steve look at three key areas of your finances: credit, income, and assets.&lt;/strong&gt; When Steve receives these components from clients, he is able to give them a fully-underwritten pre-approval letter. Being pre-approved allows you to assert offers that are extremely solid, which, in turn, allows you to compete with cash buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, top lenders like Steve can also work with you to improve certain aspects of your financial situation in order to boost your chances as a buyer. Polishing up your credit, for example, can significantly impact your success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trying to make such improvements without professional guidance, meanwhile, could actually damage your chances as a buyer&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, did you know that paying off collection accounts may actually lower your score? This and other factors can take the average buyer by surprise, so it’s no wonder why an early pre-approval is so crucial to your overall success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lenders like Steve can identify and resolve certain details of your financial health that may otherwise go unnoticed. Earning the best deal during your home purchase requires a lot of intricate strategizing, and &lt;strong&gt;this is exactly why working with a professional lender is a must.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reach Steve directly and find out more about today’s topic, you can give him a call at (714) 470-5626 or by emailing him at steve@gotoloanpro.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://socalrealestatetips.com/#contact&quot;&gt;give me a call or send me an email&lt;/a&gt;. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 16:56:53 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/whats-the-first-step-in-buying-a-home-meeting-with-a-lender.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://socalrealestatetips.com/whats-the-first-step-in-buying-a-home-meeting-with-a-lender.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another Update on the Path to Repealing The Costa-Hawkins Act</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4IVSGlcTl9w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following our blog, you’re already aware of the efforts underway to impose rent control in California. Since our previous update, there have been some major new developments that I wanted to share with you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The California ballot initiative has received enough signatures to get on the November ballot&lt;/strong&gt;. It will be called Proposition 10, and if passed, it will repeal the Costa-Hawkins Act, which limits the kind of rent control policies that cities can impose. If Proposition 10 is passed, cities will be permitted to enact their own rent control initiatives. Currently, the law makes it illegal for cities to impose rent control ordinances on properties built after 1995. In addition, the Costa-Hawkins Act prohibits cities from imposing rent control on single-family homes, condos, and from regulating how much a landlord can charge in rent after a tenant moves out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It doesn’t look like rent control will be on the ballot in Long Beach this year.%20http://socalrealestatetips.com/another-update-on-the-path-to-repealing-the-costa-hawkins-act.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It doesn’t look like rent control will be on the ballot in Long Beach this year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Backers of a rent control ordinance in the city of Long Beach have suspended their plans&lt;/strong&gt; and are refocusing on a ballot initiative in 2020. It doesn’t look like rent control will be on the ballot in Long Beach this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own an investment property and would like to know how Proposition 10 may impact you, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 13:42:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/another-update-on-the-path-to-repealing-the-costa-hawkins-act.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://socalrealestatetips.com/another-update-on-the-path-to-repealing-the-costa-hawkins-act.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>California Cities May Soon Find It Easier to Implement Rent Control</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C0sNo_aeFpQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the cost of rent in many cities across California at an all-time high, efforts have been made to support ballot initiatives that would make it easier for cities to implement some form of rent control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a real estate investor, a homeowner, or a renter, these ballot initiatives will have a major impact on housing, if passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the state level, supporters have gathered a sufficient number of signatures for the initiative to be placed on the ballot this November. &lt;strong&gt;This initiative would repeal the 1985 Costa-Hawkins Rental Housing Act,&lt;/strong&gt; which makes it illegal for cities to set rent caps on properties built after the year during which their respective city rent control laws were passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Los Angeles, for example, the main rent control law is the Rent Stabilization Ordinance. This law, passed in 1979, restricts rent control on units built prior to October of 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=At least 15 California cities have rent control policies right now.%20http://socalrealestatetips.com/california-cities-may-soon-find-it-easier-to-implement-rent-control.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“At least 15 California cities have rent control policies right now.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Costa-Hawkins also bars cities from passing rent control ordinances on condominiums and single-family homes. &lt;strong&gt;It also prohibits cities from reckoning how much a landlord can raise the rent after a tenant moves out, under a policy known as vacancy control.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, at least 15 California cities have rent control policies. In the Los Angeles area, this includes the City of Los Angeles, West Hollywood, Beverly Hills, Thousand Oaks, and Santa Monica.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are also efforts underway to implement some form of rent control in other cities throughout the state,&lt;/strong&gt; including Long Beach, Inglewood, and Pasadena. In Long Beach, for example, the proposed initiative would cap rent hikes for most apartments built before 1995 at 5% or lower. It would also establish a citywide Rental Housing Board, which would be funded through fees charged to landlords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like more information about how these ballot initiatives may affect you, please reach out through our website at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imcd.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.imcd.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, give us a call, or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 16:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/california-cities-may-soon-find-it-easier-to-implement-rent-control.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://socalrealestatetips.com/california-cities-may-soon-find-it-easier-to-implement-rent-control.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Maintain Your Current Property Taxes When You Move?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m-m2LT4Jgbs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you or someone you know thinking of downsizing? If this is the case, but you are putting off the transaction because you are afraid your property taxes may go up, I have some important information to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that &lt;strong&gt;under California Proposition 60, homeowners age 55 and over may be eligible to transfer their property tax base to their new home after the sale of their current property&lt;/strong&gt;, so long as the move is within the same county?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And under California Proposition 90, homeowners may transfer their property taxes to a home in a different county, provided that that county is eligible. This is a great opportunity for those who are looking to downsize. Transferring your property tax base to a new home can also help you extract equity without losing money in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Transferring your property tax base to a new home can also help you extract equity without losing money in the long run.%20http://socalrealestatetips.com/can-you-maintain-your-current-property-taxes-when-you-move.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Transferring your property tax base to a new home can also help you extract equity without losing money in the long run.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, though, there are some requirements a homeowner must meet to be eligible. First, the homeowner or their spouse must be 55 or older at the time they sell their current home. Next, the replacement property must serve as a principal residence and be of equal or lesser market value to their current home. And finally, &lt;strong&gt;the replacement property must be purchased or built within two years of the sale of the original home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it is important to keep in mind that this is a one-time use policy. But there is an exception. If you were to become seriously disabled after taking advantage of this opportunity, you may be eligible to utilize it a second time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To learn more about this opportunity, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boe.ca.gov/&quot;&gt;http://www.boe.ca.gov/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 14:36:38 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/can-you-maintain-your-current-property-taxes-when-you-move.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://socalrealestatetips.com/can-you-maintain-your-current-property-taxes-when-you-move.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You're Invited to Our Upcoming Shredding Day</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PAkpdM6B1qA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any documents, paperwork, or mail you need shredded, you’re in luck. You’re invited to our upcoming shredding day on July 14. &lt;strong&gt;The event will run from 9 a.m. until 1 p.m., so be sure to drop by our office (located at 3030 Old Ranch Parkway in Seal Beach).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be three shredding trucks in our parking lot, and this event is absolutely free. &lt;strong&gt;You’re certainly welcome to make a donation to KW Cares, but there’s no obligation to do so.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You’re invited to our upcoming shredding day on July 14.%20http://socalrealestatetips.com/youre-invited-to-our-upcoming-shredding-day.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You’re invited to our upcoming shredding day on July 14.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year this event was a big success. We filled up three shredding trucks and actually had to close up early. There’s no need to RSVP, but you may want to show up toward the beginning of the event to ensure you’re able to get in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 10:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://socalrealestatetips.com/youre-invited-to-our-upcoming-shredding-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://socalrealestatetips.com/youre-invited-to-our-upcoming-shredding-day.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
