<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dan Jones Group - your professional Charlotte Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 15:50:25 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 15:50:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Questions Should You Ask an Agent or Team Before You Hire Them?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gy_t86WVvig?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before you hire any agent or team to assist in the sale of your home, there are certain questions you must ask them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you hire an agent or team of agents to assist you with your home selling experience, you’ll need to make sure they’re the right fit for the job. The best way to determine this is by simply asking the right questions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you do this, &lt;strong&gt;our team recently put together a guide on the top 10 questions you must ask before hiring a listing agent to sell your home.&lt;/strong&gt; We would be happy to send you a free copy of this guide by mail or email, but, for now, we’d like to give you a preview of just a couple of these questions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first (and potentially most important) question you should ask any agent before you hire them is: &lt;strong&gt;“Can I fire you if I’m not satisfied?”&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one wants to be stuck working with a professional who they aren’t happy with. Any listing agent you work with should be willing to let you walk away if they aren’t delivering the results you want and deserve. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second question in this guide is: &lt;strong&gt;“Do you have actual results?” &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The best way to determine if an agent or a team of agents is right for you is by asking a few key questions%20https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/what-questions-should-you-ask-an-agent-or-team-before-you-hire-them.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The best way to determine if an agent or a team of agents is right for you is by asking a few key questions”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone can talk the talk, but only truly qualified agents will be able to back their claims up with a proven track record of success. Our team, for example, has a full list of statistics pertaining to our past and current success in the industry. 96% of our team’s listings are successful. The average success rate of other agents in our market, meanwhile, is just 61.6%. Our team also maintains a 98% list-to-sales price ratio. This is 4% higher than the 94% list-to-sales price ratio held by the average agent in our market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason for our success is our team structure, which brings me to another important question: &lt;strong&gt;Is the agent you’re thinking about working with part of a team or are they working alone? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas a team structure allows each of its agents to focus their energy into specialized tasks, solo agents are left to handle everything on their own. As the old saying goes, “A Jack of all trades is a master of none.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The questions and tips we’ve shared today are just a small preview of the wealth of information that’s available in our full guide. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or want a copy of this guide for yourself, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 08:50:59 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/what-questions-should-you-ask-an-agent-or-team-before-you-hire-them.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/what-questions-should-you-ask-an-agent-or-team-before-you-hire-them.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Tip to Buyers and Sellers Entering the Market This Year</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HSKIS6qr228?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I’m answering a question that’s probably on every buyer and seller’s mind: When is it too early to take action?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real estate market can be likened to Black Friday pandemonium: You want to beat the rush. We’re approaching that time of year when leases will be ending, and people will be looking and relocating in every area of our market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when is the best time to beat the real estate rush? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can count on both the buyer and seller crowd storming onto the market in April and May, and even as early as March, but that doesn’t mean there will be a lack of activity in January and February. &lt;strong&gt;Actually, people are buying and selling in the winter months. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a buyer, being early will help you avoid multiple-offer scenarios that you may have encountered in last year’s market.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re tied to a lease for a little longer, pay your two months and close on the first of the month so you can stay in front of the busy season. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come April and May, the market will be inevitably flooded with thousands of properties. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re a seller, listing now will give you a decisive advantage and ensure that your home stands out.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As a buyer, being early will help you avoid multiple-offer scenarios that you may have encountered in last year’s market.%20https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/a-quick-tip-to-buyers-and-sellers-entering-the-market-this-year.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“As a buyer, being early will help you avoid multiple-offer scenarios that you may have encountered in last year’s market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we can assist you with your real estate needs in any way, please reach out and give us a call. We’re never too busy for you. We look forward to meeting you at the closing table!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 09:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/a-quick-tip-to-buyers-and-sellers-entering-the-market-this-year.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/a-quick-tip-to-buyers-and-sellers-entering-the-market-this-year.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Represent the Dan Jones Group With This Great New Apparel</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JDgDtYbLE5Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Will you be among the lucky few who receive some Dan Jones Team apparel? Email us and see!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have some new apparel we’ll be giving away for clients’ home closings, but we’d love to give you the chance to get some of these great clothing items in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 10 people to email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sold@myhomecarolinas.com?subject=I love Carolina Real Estate Experts&quot;&gt;Sold@MyHomeCarolinas.com&lt;/a&gt; with the subject line “I love Carolina Real Estate Experts” will receive their choice of a red or blue hat (one size fits all) or a grey or blue t-shirt (tell us your preferred size).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:43:22 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/represent-the-dan-jones-group-with-these-great-clothing-items.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/represent-the-dan-jones-group-with-these-great-clothing-items.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>May the Merry Bells Keep Ringing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yr0WZ5YF0Zk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Merry Christmas to you!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The holiday season has officially arrived. We hope you enjoy this wonderful time of year and make some fantastic memories with your family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just wanted to take a moment to thank you for your continued support. We love helping people make their real estate dreams come true, so thank you for working with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be a busy time of year, but we are always here to help you and answer any questions you may have. Just give us a call or reply to this email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case we don’t hear from you, have a happy New Year as well!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 10:49:57 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/may-the-merry-bells-keep-ringing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/may-the-merry-bells-keep-ringing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Best Way to Present an Offer? Follow These Steps</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8qWUKRE-hlk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s the best way to present an offer? Let’s discuss this crucial question.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’ve found the perfect home, what’s the best way to present an offer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to consider is the price. If the list price is appropriate from the get-go, then some of the work has already been done for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people want to submit offers below what the seller is asking, but proceeding this way doesn’t give you any leverage as a buyer. If the home is priced at $400,000, why not appease the seller and offer $395,000? Many other buyers will be making offers around $380,000 and $385,000, so submitting an offer that comes close to what the seller wants will make you stand out. &lt;strong&gt;Coming in strong is key—even if you eventually negotiate a higher price as the result of a bidding war.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve submitted an offer with a competitive price and made a substantial earnest money deposit, ask the seller to cover closing costs. This isn’t necessary, but they may agree to handle this expense given the strength of your offer. Make sure, though, that your offer comes with an expiration date. You want the seller to realize that you won’t wait around forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In addition to asking for the seller to pay the closing costs, you may also choose to ask for some personal property, like the refrigerator.&lt;/strong&gt; People tend to assume that appliances like this come with the home, but this isn’t always the case. If the home was shown with patio furniture, you could ask for that to be included as well. Sellers will occasionally be willing to part with large furniture items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your price, terms, and conditions must be attractive to the seller, but they should also help you secure a great deal.%20https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/whats-the-best-way-to-present-an-offer-follow-these-steps.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your price, terms, and conditions must be attractive to the seller, but they should also help you secure a great deal.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, don’t forget about home warranties. &lt;strong&gt;Many sellers will be willing to pay for a one-year home warranty policy to give their buyer peace of mind&lt;/strong&gt; about proceeding with the purchase. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The items we’ve covered are just a few of the things you can and should ask for when presenting an offer. Your price, terms, and conditions must be attractive to the seller, but they should also help you secure a great deal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have any other questions, would like more information, or are curious how we can help you succeed with your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 15:34:03 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/whats-the-best-way-to-present-an-offer-follow-these-steps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/whats-the-best-way-to-present-an-offer-follow-these-steps.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Agent Marketing Your Home Correctly?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3e5iTHPcCvk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today, I’ll go over three important marketing strategies to help you sell your home for top dollar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on selling your home, it’s very important that it’s marketed correctly. There are three ways to market your home: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Agent networking.&lt;/strong&gt; There are 27,000 properties on the MLS. It’s impossible for agents to keep up with every single one of them. That’s why it’s your agent’s job to let other buyer agents know that your property is available. Your agent needs to have a networking system in place to tell 13,000 agents in the area about your new listing. Agents have to know about your house; that’s 70% of the reason your home will or will not sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Paid advertising. &lt;/strong&gt;When you put your home on the market, it automatically goes on Realtor.com and Zillow. However, they will be on the last page. It costs a lot of money to have your home featured on those websites. Your agent needs to spend a couple thousand dollars a month on marketing on those websites, or your listing will live on the last page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Agents have to know about your house; that’s 70% of the reason your home will or will not sell.%20https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/is-your-agent-marketing-your-home-correctly.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Agents have to know about your house; that’s 70% of the reason your home will or will not sell.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Yard marketing. &lt;/strong&gt;We don’t just stick a For Sale sign in the yard and call it a day. We provide four ways for a buyer to contact us about your house. We have the traditional yard sign, an information sign, an “Open House Every Day, Call for Times” sign, and a “Buy This House and We’ll Sell Yours for Free.” We have 24-hour tracking so we can capitalize on every buyer who called one of those four numbers. We also have a team of agents to capture, return, and answer those calls at a high level so that you get maximum exposure for your property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about marketing your home in today’s market, just give us a call or send us an email. My team and I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 15:18:16 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/is-your-agent-marketing-your-home-correctly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/is-your-agent-marketing-your-home-correctly.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2018 Real Estate Market Review and Predictions for 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PlopNxqepqw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’re still in a seller’s market, but there are signs out there that we could be seeing a shift soon. Here’s what you need to know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have been asking me about the market lately. The one question I keep hearing constantly is, “Was 2018 a seller’s market or a buyer’s market?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When looking at all the numbers across the board, I lean toward saying 2018 was more of a seller’s market.&lt;/strong&gt; Although interest rates have been creeping up and we have a feeling we are going to start seeing a shift in the market, I don’t think it will be anything crazy. At the same time, things will certainly change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 2008 and 2009 we saw the bottom of our market in the Charlotte area. This is also when we saw a huge increase in short sales and foreclosures. After that, we saw a steady increase that takes us to where we are today. We’re on about a nine to 10-year increase in home prices right now. &lt;strong&gt;As most people know, real estate tends to operate in cycles that are usually about this long.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some signs out there of this shift? For starters, we’ve seen about double the amount of expired listings compared to last year. Home sales are still about equal and pricing has continued to go up for the time being, but in some areas, days on market are starting to creep up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our expired listings have nearly doubled this year.%20https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/2018-real-estate-market-review-and-predictions-for-2019.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our expired listings have nearly doubled this year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With homes staying on the market a little bit longer and expired listings on the rise, it doesn’t necessarily mean we’ll see a heavy shift.&lt;/strong&gt; 2018 was and is still a fantastic seller’s market with fantastic interest rates and continually increasing home prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the market or about how you can take advantage of the current conditions before they possibly shift, give me a call or send me an email today. I would love to hear from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 11:18:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/2018-real-estate-market-review-and-predictions-for-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/2018-real-estate-market-review-and-predictions-for-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seasons Are Uncertain: Follow the Market to Sell Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jbJElOJxxkM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t look to the seasons for when to sell—look to the market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the best season for selling your house? The quick answer is: &lt;strong&gt;none of them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best time could be &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; time of year, but it’s always when &lt;strong&gt;inventory is low and there is still a high demand from buyers. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping up with the current market is vital. If you’re in a price range with 100 comparable homes for sale in your area when there are usually around 50, it might be best to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seasons do have &lt;strong&gt;some&lt;/strong&gt; influence—buyers are looking around in the summer and spring while in the fall, people are looking for a new-year home. The good thing is, people are moving to the Carolinas all year long. People often wait to sell in the spring, meaning lower inventory during other seasons. This is when we sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other companies often slow down during the winter months, while we speed up and sell many homes in the fall and winter seasons. We find that a lot of buyers say the same thing: “There’s no inventory, I’m just going to wait until spring.” There’s no need to wait, as we can connect those buyers directly to the sellers. All it takes is putting homes up for sale in the late fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The good thing is, people are moving to the Carolinas all year long.%20https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/seasons-are-uncertain-follow-the-market-to-sell-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The good thing is, people are moving to the Carolinas all year long.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve helped countless homeowners take advantage of these opportune times, and I’m more than happy to help you as well with the home selling process. Please contact me if you would like my guidance, have any questions, or would simply like some information. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 14:13:08 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/seasons-are-uncertain-follow-the-market-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/seasons-are-uncertain-follow-the-market-to-sell-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sellers: Stay Far Away From Companies Offering to Pay Cash for Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fm_69A9FVcM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of you have probably seen advertisements for companies claiming they’ll buy your home for cash. They make it sound so easy, but is it really? Are the results worth it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s the truth: If it sounds too good to be true, it probably is.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our clients recently met with one such company. Over the phone, they had priced her home at $308,000—but this client’s home is actually worth about $330,000. When they visited her property, they started making price reductions based on things like the fact that she didn’t have granite countertops. And these deductions made no sense. Even though it only would have cost this client about $2,800 to install granite countertops, the company chopped $4,000 off of their offer because her home lacked them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The company made deduction after deduction like this until she was left with an offer of about $290,000—$18,000 less than what they had originally said they’d pay.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In addition to making such low offers, companies like these also charge a fee that knocks the price down even further.%20https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/sellers-stay-far-away-from-companies-offering-to-pay-cash-for-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In addition to making such low offers, companies like these also charge a fee that knocks the price down even further.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of working with this company, this seller decided to come to us. Within the first week of having her home on the market with our team, she received an offer of $327,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If our client would have proceeded with the company she’d been speaking to before, she would have been in for yet another nasty surprise. In addition to making such low offers, companies like these also charge a fee that knocks the price down even further. In the case of our client, &lt;strong&gt;she would have been asked to pay a 7% fee to sell her home to this company and ultimately earn less than she could (and did) on the open market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have $60,000 or $70,000 to lose to a dishonest company, by all means reach out to them. But if you want to sell your home quickly and for top dollar, call us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 16:50:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/sellers-stay-far-away-from-companies-offering-to-pay-cash-for-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/sellers-stay-far-away-from-companies-offering-to-pay-cash-for-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Questions Should You Ask an Agent Before Hiring Them?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/w4T3qoCX1Vs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are a few key questions you should be asking any potential agent before you hire them. Here are just three of them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to hire the best agent to help you with your real estate transaction, there are a few questions you need to be asking before you hire one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Ask how many homes they’ve sold this year.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s good to be even more specific by asking how many homes they sold in a particular area, or how many homes they didn’t sell. If you hire someone with a track record of 10 listings in which only three sold, that’s a problem.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Ask about their list-to-sales ratio.&lt;/strong&gt; If an agent is consistently selling houses for less than what they’re listed for, you may want to reconsider hiring that agent. You want to get the most money that you can for your house, don’t you?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Ask about their marketing plan.&lt;/strong&gt; The average agent in the area spends a maximum of $300 per month on true marketing systems to get homes sold. However, $300 doesn’t get you very much exposure for your listing—the Dan Jones Group spends over $20,000 a month in marketing to generate buyers for our listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If an agent is consistently selling houses for less than what they’re listed for, you may want to reconsider hiring that agent.%20https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/what-questions-should-you-ask-an-agent-before-hiring-them.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If an agent is consistently selling houses for less than what they’re listed for, you may want to reconsider hiring that agent.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the market to buy or sell a home, please reach out to us. We’re prepared to answer these questions and more if you consider hiring us for your transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:12:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/what-questions-should-you-ask-an-agent-before-hiring-them.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.listwithdanjonesblog.com/what-questions-should-you-ask-an-agent-before-hiring-them.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
