<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Charleston Real Estate Video Blog with Mikki Ramey</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Mikki Ramey Team is to be your best resource for Charleston real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Mikki Ramey Team, your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 11:09:03 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 11:09:03 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Come See the Beauty of Del Webb in Nexton</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/e5wF5oRQl_k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s a quick tour of the stunning community of Del Webb in Nexton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at Del Webb in Nexton—Somerville’s Premier 55-plus community! With a neighborhood of about 500 residents, this piece of paradise has it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It has the most amazing amenities center in the greater Charleston area,&lt;/strong&gt; where the residents can enjoy a clubhouse with game rooms for laid-back time and a ballroom for nice social events. They also enjoy a state-of-the-art fitness center offering yoga and other aerobic activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, they have an indoor lap lane pool, an area to drive your golf cart, outdoor areas for lounging, and a stunning resort-style pool that is next to the tennis courts, pickleball courts, and bocce ball courts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s always something to do in Del Webb; when you’re not busy, you can relax in your gorgeous semi-custom home. Come and visit the amazing Somerville community of Del Webb. If you want to learn more about Del Webb or have any real estate questions, call or email me. I’m always happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 01:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/come-see-the-beauty-of-del-webb-in-nexton.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/come-see-the-beauty-of-del-webb-in-nexton.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Catch a Glimpse of This Charleston Golf Club</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8LqFPB7DAG4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Take a tour of the stunning Yeamans Hall Club in the Charleston area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m taking you for an exciting jet ski tour of one of Charleston’s most private areas. It’s a property that is exclusive to members and can be seen by water. If you’re thinking it’s downtown, Kiawah, or Daniel Island, you couldn’t be more wrong—we’ll be looking at Yeamans Hall Country Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This members-only golf course runs along a branch of the Cooper River known as Goose Creek, which is a brackish waterway that’s home to a ton of wildlife and serves as a great spot for fishing. Animals ranging from alligators and dolphins to catfish can be seen here. &lt;strong&gt;The golf course was built on a plantation that was originally owned by Lady Margaret and Sir John Yeamans in the 1700s.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1924, the owners transformed the plantation into an unbelievable golf course. The club was designed to attract wealthy financiers from the north, offering two to 300 home sites with stunning colonial architecture. The beautiful Southern style architecture became so popular, you had to be invited to become a member.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get a chance, check out Yeamans Hall Country Club. As always, if you have questions about this piece of paradise or anything real estate related, call or email me. I’m always here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 01:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/catch-a-glimpse-of-this-charleston-golf-club.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/catch-a-glimpse-of-this-charleston-golf-club.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Appraisal Is Lower Than Contract: What Now?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-isEYFDYV9A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;There are three options to choose from if the appraisal came in low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re under contract, but there’s an issue—the appraisal came in lower than the contract price. In this situation, what do you do? There are some options you can take if this happens to you, and today I’m sharing them with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first option is: You are going to talk to the other parties, and find out if &lt;strong&gt;you can buy the home for the lower appraised value.&lt;/strong&gt; All buyers want to buy homes for less money. This is a good opportunity to get in there and get the home for a reduced price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the seller refuses, the second thing you can do is negotiate with the seller. You’re at the low end, and they’re at the high end; try to meet somewhere in the middle. Keep in mind that anything over and above the appraised price is going to &lt;strong&gt;require you to bring cash to closing.&lt;/strong&gt; So if you are around $2,000 off the appraisal, you would have to bring $2,000 to closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is a good opportunity to get the home for a reduced price.%20http://localhost:4000/the-appraisal-is-lower-than-contract-what-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is a good opportunity to get the home for a reduced price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third item is that you can be released from the contract if you’re not comfortable, and you cannot reach a happy medium ground with the seller about a new price. You are in no way responsible for moving forward if there is an appraisal issue, and you don’t feel comfortable with the new price terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about appraisals or anything real estate related, please reach out to me and my team. We’d love to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-appraisal-is-lower-than-contract-what-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-appraisal-is-lower-than-contract-what-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Old Village Mt. Pleasant: A Slice of Heaven</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yy1fTSQ2YgA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;A quick tour of Old Village Mt. Pleasant in Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m going to &lt;strong&gt;take you on a tour of Old Village Mt. Pleasant&lt;/strong&gt;. One of my favorite things about Old Village is the architecture. At 0:15 in the video, you can see that there are newly designed homes right next to some old brick ranches. There’s a gorgeous new custom house right next to this brick ranch that was just purchased for $850,000, and is currently being remodeled. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest parts of Old Village is the Pit Street Bridge. It has beautiful views of Charleston Harbor, and people love to take walks and enjoy this great space. Downtown Old Village is also home to the renowned Post House restaurant, which has amazing food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Old Village has Alhambra Hall, where great events are held. It’s right across the street from Alhambra Park, where I used to bring my kids to play when they were little. &lt;strong&gt;This is a gorgeous area&lt;/strong&gt;. I hope you get a chance to come and check out what Old Village has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this location or have any real estate-related concerns, call or email me. I’m always happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/old-village-mt-pleasant-a-slice-of-heaven.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/old-village-mt-pleasant-a-slice-of-heaven.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ongoing Assessments Can Appreciate in Value</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TCXiVaaagh4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;What to think about when buying a condo with an ongoing assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking about buying a condo that has an assessment coming? If you are, don’t just discount it. Here are four things you’ll want to investigate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What caused the issue?&lt;/strong&gt; Is it water intrusion? Are there structural issues? Just figure out what’s going on. We have properties all throughout Charleston that have been through this. It just means there’s some issue with the exterior, usually where there’s been water intrusion or a structural issue. If that’s the situation, just learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Is there ongoing litigation?&lt;/strong&gt; Is there a current lawsuit? Or maybe everything is resolved. Just look into it to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Can you live in the condo while the work is being done?&lt;/strong&gt; Or do you have to move out of the property?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. How much will it cost you?&lt;/strong&gt; Is it going to be a fee to you as a buyer or to the seller? Condos with assessments aren’t a horrible situation because at the end of it you’re going to get a great new product that usually will appreciate in value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re thinking about buying a condo, learn about all of the details of any ongoing assessment. If you have questions about this, please reach out to me and my real estate team. We look forward to helping you with any real estate concerns you have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/ongoing-assessments-can-appreciate-in-value.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/ongoing-assessments-can-appreciate-in-value.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Makes This the Coolest Home in Town?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WPXYmbaLYGg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Taking a detailed tour of the most beautiful house in Charleston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m showing you &lt;strong&gt;the coolest house in Charleston&lt;/strong&gt;, 521 Cypress Point Drive. Its outdoor living space truly has it all: a built-in brick pizza oven, a breathtaking grilling station, a dining area, a big-screen TV, and even a bar. The home also has an outdoor spa with a hot tub and a gorgeous fireplace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beautiful master bedroom and bathroom are spacious and come with tons of storage space. Everything from the window bench to the closets offers plenty of room for jewelry, linens, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kitchen is an absolute dream. The sink is actually a complete workstation with cutting boards, knife storage, and a gas-burning stove. There’s also a coffee maker, a warming drawer for your mugs, two ovens, and even a steamer. &lt;strong&gt;This kitchen has so much to offer&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This home truly has it all.%20http://localhost:4000/what-makes-this-the-coolest-home-in-town.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This home truly has it all.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moms will love the easy-access, well-hidden Christmas tree closet—it’s absolutely amazing. One of this home’s most pristine qualities is its saltwater pool, which comes with an ANA filtration system and stunning travertine tile. If you enjoy fishing, this home also comes with a fully stocked pool, so you can fish from the comfort of your backyard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This incredible home at &lt;strong&gt;521 Cypress Point Drive is readily available for private tours&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want to see it or have any questions, please reach out to me via phone or email. I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-makes-this-the-coolest-home-in-town.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-makes-this-the-coolest-home-in-town.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways To Get Your Home Ready for Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TLdxhLQE60A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Home improvements that will help you sell quickly and for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes time to show your home to potential buyers, it pays to have your house ready for the market. Keeping your property in top condition will ensure you sell for top dollar. Here are three simple but effective ways to prepare your home for sale:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Fresh paint.&lt;/strong&gt; As the market’s most popular color, white paint makes rooms look larger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Flooring.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s worth it to invest in a nice hardwood flooring. For a smaller budget, carpet or tile are great options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. New appliances.&lt;/strong&gt; New means the best and most reliable functionality, which buyers love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, reach out to me by phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you. You can also download the Charleston Properties App to look for properties in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 04:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-ways-to-get-your-home-ready-for-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-ways-to-get-your-home-ready-for-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our List of Affordable Places in Charleston</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pi0Zg6aPHWE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s a list of the top three most affordable places in Charleston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people assume that Charleston, South Carolina, is one of the most expensive cities in the state. If you plan on living here, I have good news. There are some very affordable areas in Charleston you can move to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. North Charleston.&lt;/strong&gt; In terms of employment, North Charleston offers an easy commute to the other areas in the city. If you plan on living here, I have good news: There are some very affordable areas in Charleston. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Summerville.&lt;/strong&gt; Summerville has an average sale price of $383,000 for a single-family detached home. Many families who live here consider it to be a friendly neighborhood. People also choose to retire in Summerville because of its affordability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=North Charleston is a walkable community where you can enjoy fun activities with family and friends. %20http://localhost:4000/our-list-of-affordable-places-in-charleston.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“North Charleston is a walkable community where you can enjoy fun activities with family and friends. ”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Goose Creek.&lt;/strong&gt; Goose Creek offers an average sales price of $391,000 for single-family detached homes. The area has plenty of construction developments, great restaurants, and nice shops. It also offers an easy commute if you work in other areas of the city. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to hear more details about these areas, or have any questions about real estate, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I’ll be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 06:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-list-of-affordable-places-in-charleston.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/our-list-of-affordable-places-in-charleston.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons to Move to Charleston</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/COqPJ4jXQig?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Five things that I really love about Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love Charleston, South Carolina, and there are many reasons you might want to move here. Here are the top five reasons to move to this great city:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The people.&lt;/strong&gt; Southern charm is real here. All the people are so generous, kind, and helpful. This is a great place to make long-lasting friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The food.&lt;/strong&gt; Foodies love the low country where you can find amazing restaurants like High Cotton, Halls, Husks, and Magnolia. You can eat your way through the city and be happy as a clam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The history.&lt;/strong&gt; Charleston is a great place to enjoy walking tours, carriage tours, and plantation tours. You can even visit the first settlement at Charlestown landing. There’s so much rich history to learn about here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The beaches.&lt;/strong&gt; We have gorgeous beach areas with wonderful communities and amenities. You can enjoy a great family vacation as a tourist in your own town. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The architecture.&lt;/strong&gt; As a real estate agent, I love seeing the various types of architecture in Charleston. We have everything from full front porches to Charleston singles, traditional brick homes, and colorful houses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the five top reasons you should consider moving to Charleston. If you have any questions, reach out to me by phone or email. I would love to be of assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 05:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-benefits-of-moving-to-charleston.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-benefits-of-moving-to-charleston.html</guid>
        
        <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Might Not Want To Move to Charleston</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/O2darQ81860?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Three things that I wish were absent from Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love Charleston, South Carolina, and as a Realtor, it’s my job to convince people to move here. However, there are three things that I absolutely could do without in Charleston, and they could be reasons why you wouldn’t want to move here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Alligators.&lt;/strong&gt; They live in the ponds and are particularly active during their mating season. You don’t want to stand too close to the bank of a pond. However, they won’t bother you if you don’t bother them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Bugs.&lt;/strong&gt; Mosquitoes and no-see-‘ums can drive you crazy. They’re not out all the time, and if you go to the beach where there’s a nice breeze, you can avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Traffic.&lt;/strong&gt; During peak rush hour, getting from one side of the city to the other can take a lot longer than you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all that said, I hope you move to Charleston because there are also a lot of great things about this city. If you have any questions, reach out to me by phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-might-not-want-to-move-to-charleston.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-you-might-not-want-to-move-to-charleston.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
