<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What's Working Now!</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from 240-731-8079 - your professional Cleveland Park Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:10:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:10:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Great Example of How We Are Able to Help Buyers in Any Situation</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pf_NVocO14A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently met a buyer who wanted to look at a co-op apartment with a friend of hers. They were waiting for me in the lobby, and right before I arrived I got a text message that said, &lt;strong&gt;“Hey Marjorie, do you know what’s going on on the eighth floor? We overheard that someone is waiting for a photographer to take pictures of the property. Are they getting it ready to go on the market?”&lt;/strong&gt; I told her that we could check it out once I got there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got to the building, I picked up the keys to the apartment we were going to look at and took a peek at the eighth floor on our way up. I ran down, knocked on the door, and saw an agent that I knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She let me know the place was going on the market next week. I asked her if I could bring my buyers up to take a peek at it. She said sure,  but she also said that we couldn’t write an offer on it right now because it wasn’t going on the market until the next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Even though the agent said we couldn’t make an offer on the property, we made one anyway and it got accepted.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/a-great-example-of-how-we-are-able-to-help-buyers-in-any-situation.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Even though the agent said we couldn’t make an offer on the property, we made one anyway and it got accepted.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brought the buyers down, we saw the property, and they fell in love with it. After we left the building, we decided to go ahead and write an offer on it anyway. I know the agent told us not to, but I also knew that everybody has a price. &lt;strong&gt;I told the buyer that we could make an offer, but it would have to wow the seller and their agent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went back to the office and wrote a big, fat offer. The price was well above what they were asking and, although &lt;strong&gt;I apologized to the agent in advance, they ended up calling the owner and we ratified the contract shortly thereafter.&lt;/strong&gt; All in all, it was a great success and we found the buyers their perfect home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for our next video, which will give you the three keys to my buyer’s success in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions in the meantime about buying a home, selling a home, or the real estate market in general, don’t hesitate to contact me by phone at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:240-731-8079&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;240-731-8079&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or write to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#077;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#106;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#077;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#106;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#068;&amp;#105;&amp;#099;&amp;#107;&amp;#083;&amp;#116;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#077;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#106;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#077;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#106;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#068;&amp;#105;&amp;#099;&amp;#107;&amp;#083;&amp;#116;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;We have the hottest new video strategy on the planet for buyers and sellers!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-button&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;ctalink&quot; href=&quot;http://dchomeblog.com/videos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Watch Now&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 16:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/a-great-example-of-how-we-are-able-to-help-buyers-in-any-situation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/a-great-example-of-how-we-are-able-to-help-buyers-in-any-situation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Stage Without Breaking the Bank</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iw7SkEa62xk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another episode of &lt;strong&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I want to talk to you about staging…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I want to talk about how to stage your home…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without breaking the bank…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So you can make more money when you sell…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I met with the owners of a new listing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who were concerned with the expenses of staging…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed how staging their space…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Could put an extra $40,000 to $50,000 in their pocket…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to change the look of the place…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make it less colorful &amp;amp; dated to more neutral &amp;amp; current…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s the difference between having potential buyers…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being confronted with the impression of the need for…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overwhelming remodeling and redecoration versus…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feeling comfortable that they can move right in…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With simply paint, cleaning, new carpeting…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some furnishings &amp;amp; dressing up the kitchen cabinets…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s the difference between having potential buyers confronted with the impression of the need for overwhelming remodeling &amp;amp; redecoration versus feeling comfortable that they can move right in!%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/how-to-stage-without-breaking-the-bank.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s the difference between having potential buyers confronted with the impression of the need for overwhelming remodeling &amp;amp; redecoration versus feeling comfortable that they can move right in!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quote from the contractor and stager was $8,700…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The owners did not feel the need to make the changes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guess why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found out…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was more than their budget allowed…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not, just something that they just didn’t want to do…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I knew the budget…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We adjusted…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only painted one room and changed some materials…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And still achieved the look we needed… &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get an extra $40,000 to $50,000…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when you are talking with your agent…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is vital to be upfront &amp;amp; let them know your budget…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any questions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just give me a call at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:240-731-8079&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;240-731-8079&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or write to…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#077;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#106;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#077;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#106;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#068;&amp;#105;&amp;#099;&amp;#107;&amp;#083;&amp;#116;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marjorie@MarjorieDickStuart.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. If you would like to be invited to my next decluttering workshop, please visit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dchomeblog.com/declutter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://dchomeblog.com/declutter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 14:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/how-to-stage-without-breaking-the-bank.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/how-to-stage-without-breaking-the-bank.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What 3 Questions Do Homeowners Ask the Most?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4u2rkEstJxY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the latest episode of “What’s Working Now!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m going to answer three of the most frequently asked questions that I hear from homeowners who are thinking about moving in the next two to five years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.  What do I need to do to get my house ready?&lt;/strong&gt; Step one is always to declutter. Start doing it now. Hire helpers and recruit your friends and family. At the same time, keep your eye on the housing market. Make sure to get signed up for automatic updates on what’s coming up for sale in your neighborhood. Visit retirement communities and get on waiting lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What improvements will get me the most return?&lt;/strong&gt; Should I change my kitchen, my bathrooms, or make repairs? Look at all of these things and spruce them up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’d like to learn even more tips, sign up for my upcoming seminar on decluttering.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/what-3-questions-do-homeowners-ask-the-most.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’d like to learn even more tips, sign up for my upcoming seminar on decluttering.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What do I need to do to get ready to sell?&lt;/strong&gt; You should finish decluttering. Make those repairs. Then focus on getting the home camera-ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to come learn even more decluttering tips and secrets, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dchomeblog.com/declutter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sign up for my upcoming decluttering seminar.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any question for me or need any advice about getting your home decluttered, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/what-3-questions-do-homeowners-ask-the-most.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/what-3-questions-do-homeowners-ask-the-most.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Home Staging Works For Savvy Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H27lZhj6Vn0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another episode of “What’s Working Now!”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today, I’m reporting to you live from my listing at 3201 Garfield Street NW…&lt;br /&gt;On the edge of Cleveland Park…&lt;br /&gt;Last summer, we sold this house for over $1,600,000…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But the story began 3 years earlier…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The owners hired another agent…&lt;br /&gt;Who failed to sell their house in 3 months…&lt;br /&gt;Frustrated, they took it off the market…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then, three years later…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A mutual friend referred them to me…&lt;br /&gt;That was last August…&lt;br /&gt;You all know how I feel about staging…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And something shocking happened at the Garfield house…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That demonstrates exactly how important staging is…&lt;br /&gt;In many cases, home staging has helped my sellers net an extra $100,000…&lt;br /&gt;Or even more…&lt;br /&gt;Sometimes, though, a motivated buyer will get a sneak preview…&lt;br /&gt;Before the house is ready…&lt;br /&gt;I invited an agent and her prospective buyers over to the Garfield house…&lt;br /&gt;She was working with a family of four…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They came into the dining room…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The sellers had their wedding guest list on the wall…&lt;br /&gt;The agent noticed it…&lt;br /&gt;She couldn’t take her eyes off of it…&lt;br /&gt;And she told her buyers…&lt;br /&gt;“Come over here and see who’s invited to the wedding.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure you pack away personal items Before listing your home for sale.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/how-home-staging-works-for-savvy-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure you pack away personal items Before listing your home for sale.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were also a number of personal photos…&lt;br /&gt;And other wedding memorabilia in the dining room…&lt;br /&gt;It turns out that the buyers were so distracted by all of these personal items…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They never really looked at the house…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After that…&lt;br /&gt;We came in and made sure to pack away all personal photos that were in that dining room…&lt;br /&gt;The kitchen walls were brown and covered in pictures as well…&lt;br /&gt;So we cleared everything away…&lt;br /&gt;Opened up the windows, and…&lt;br /&gt;Made the house clean and shiny…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It sold right away…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As you can see…&lt;br /&gt;Staging your home makes a huge difference…&lt;br /&gt;See for yourself at…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://spws.homevisit.com/hvid/202813&quot;&gt;www.3201Garfield.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To learn more about the value of preparing your home for the market…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dchomeblog.com/staging&quot;&gt;sign up here&lt;/a&gt; for my next Staging Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’ll let you know about the next one…&lt;br /&gt;Thank you for watching “What’s Working Now!”&lt;br /&gt;Be sure to tune in next time…&lt;br /&gt;For more on decluttering…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the meantime…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have any other questions about real estate…&lt;br /&gt;Or our current market…&lt;br /&gt;Just give me a call at…&lt;br /&gt;240-731-8079.&lt;br /&gt;Or send me an email…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(77,97,114,106,111,114,105,101,64,77,97,114,106,111,114,105,101,68,105,99,107,83,116,117,97,114,116,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;Marjorie@MarjorieDickStuart.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’m here to help!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S. Watch something really cool my seller did…&lt;br /&gt;It helped sell her home… &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ZIUTSpSaAE&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;CLICK HERE!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 09:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/how-home-staging-works-for-savvy-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/how-home-staging-works-for-savvy-sellers.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Declutter Your Home in 8 Steps</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JdqqLpaUSGs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the latest episode of “What’s Working Now!” In our last video, we talked about decluttering. What is it, why do it, and what’s holding you back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’ll go over eight steps on how to actually declutter your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Find your “why.”&lt;/strong&gt; Why do you want to declutter? Are you making more room for yourself or a family member? What is your “why”? Are you moving? That’s my favorite one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Decide to start.&lt;/strong&gt; Pick a date and give yourself a deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. If you’re decluttering because you plan on selling&lt;/strong&gt;, call me at (240) 731-8079 or email me at marjorie@marjoriedickstuart.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Get your supplies ready.&lt;/strong&gt; Get some boxes, trash bags, sticky notes, and colored dots. You should also look for helpers. You can do this yourself, or you can ask a friend or family member to help. You can even hire a professional organizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.Make your to-do list.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re using an actual organizer, they can help you with this step. Get a pad and pencil and start making your list. Figure out how you are going to sort everything. What will you keep, throw away, or donate? How will you get rid of your trash? Do you need a dumpster? How will you donate items and which organization will you donate to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also make a list of what items you will sell. You can use a yard sale, a neighborhood listserv, or call an auction house. If you’re getting ready to sell, your to-do list should include repairs. Do you need to fix the refrigerator, paint a bedroom, or change a countertop? Even if you’re not going to move, you may notice cracks on the walls behind bookcases or beds. Make a list of those items that need to be repaired and things that need to be cleaned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to sell your property, you also need to make a list of upgrades. Do you need to replace the carpet? Do you need to paint or do some landscaping? Get your list together before you start step six.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Pick a start date and give yourself a deadline.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/how-to-declutter-your-home-in-8-steps.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Pick a start date and give yourself a deadline.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Begin sorting.&lt;/strong&gt; Some people say that you need to go room by room and organize each room. The problem with that is you’ll go into the first room, find something you can’t part with, and get stuck. I suggest going by category. Organize your dishes, then your clothes, then your books. Start with a few easy decisions to get the ball rolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Use your sticky notes. &lt;/strong&gt;You’ve made a few easy decisions on things you want to get rid of. Put a sticky dot or label on these items so you know which ones you want to throw away, sell, or donate. Use a different colored sticky note for items you want to keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. You’re ready to advertise and get rid of all that stuff.&lt;/strong&gt; Check out resources like neighborhood lists for estate sales, movers, and decorators. If you live in my neck of the woods, you can call me and I’ll put you in touch with my resources. If you don’t live near me, call another real estate agent in your area—they should be able to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching “What’s Working Now!” and going through the steps on how to declutter your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to attend my next decluttering seminar, just let me know at &lt;a href=&quot;http://dchomeblog.com/declutter&quot;&gt;DCHomeBlog.com/declutter&lt;/a&gt; or give me a call.  I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/how-to-declutter-your-home-in-8-steps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/how-to-declutter-your-home-in-8-steps.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - Going Under the Radar to Find Homes for Buyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i35REu7lJ5U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the latest episode of &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to share a successful under-the-radar strategy for buyers frustrated by the lack of homes for sale. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I worked with some buyers who made an offer on a home. Unfortunately, there were two other buyers and my people didn’t win. They just weren’t ready. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after that, they became ready to make a purchase. The problem was that at that point, there was nothing to buy. I said, &lt;strong&gt;“Don’t worry about it. I’ll go find you a house.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I put my sneakers on and went out to knock on some doors. I started calling expired listings and agents of properties that were under contract, hoping one would fall through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what? &lt;strong&gt;I found an agent who had a contract that was about to settle, and the sale was falling through.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I showed the house to my people, they made an offer, and they got it. Now they are getting ready to go to settlement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, remember when I put on my sneakers to go knock on doors? When I knocked on the very first door, I met some people who were not ready to sell their house, but they sent me a client. Their friend wanted to buy a house in a nice, big, fat price range, and there was not a house for her on the market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said, “Don’t worry about it. I’ll go find you a house!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking through expired listings, withdrawn listings, houses that were temporarily off the market, and houses that became rentals. &lt;strong&gt;I found three houses that were expired listings that were about to come back on the market. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made appointments for all three of those houses, and now we are negotiating on one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I knocked on doors and called expired listings to find a home for my buyers.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-going-under-the-radar-to-find-homes-for-buyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I knocked on doors and called expired listings to find a home for my buyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of buying in 2018 but you’re frustrated by the lack of homes for sale, just give me a call. I know how to uncover hidden gems for you in our market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of selling a house in 2018, I have something for you. It’s my new book, “Selling Secrets You Can’t Afford to Miss.” To get your free copy, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://dchomeblog.com/freebook&quot;&gt;DCHomeBlog.com/FreeBook&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be on the lookout for my next video to find out &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, just give me a call or send me an email with any questions you may have. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 07:40:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-going-under-the-radar-to-find-homes-for-buyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-going-under-the-radar-to-find-homes-for-buyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - What Happened in the 2017 Market and What to Expect in 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aDgIvAJeDYg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another episode of &lt;em&gt;What’s Working Now!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to look back on what happened in the 2017 real estate market and talk about what to expect in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some homeowners don’t realize how strong the market is or how much equity they have, so they’re not selling.&lt;/strong&gt; Others think the market is so crazy that they can ask any price they want, so they’re on the market but not selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most buyers don’t want to believe how competitive the market is and are frustrated by failed offers until they finally get one accepted. Others think that it’s impossible to buy in our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There is no need to wait to sell your home—the market is hot now.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-what-happened-in-the-2017-market-and-what-to-expect-in-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There is no need to wait to sell your home—the market is hot now.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some facts about our market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017, the average sales price increased by 4%. Inventory over $1 million is down almost 15%, and the number of home sales is up almost 22%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does all of this mean for 2018?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s all about supply and demand, so here’s what I see happening.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Record-low inventory combined with continuing low interest rates and increasing demand means more competition among buyers, frequently resulting in multiple contracts above list price and a seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of selling in 2018, there is no need to wait until the azaleas are in bloom. The market is hot right now and inventory is low, which means there is almost no competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find an agent who will take advantage of current market conditions to make it easy for you to get top dollar, fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer, hire an agent who knows how to uncover hidden gems and win the negotiation for your next home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching &lt;em&gt;What’s Working Now! &lt;/em&gt;If you are thinking of selling your home in 2018, I have something for you: my new book, “Selling Secrets You Can’t Afford to Miss.” To get your free copy, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://dchomeblog.com/freebook&quot;&gt;DCHomeblog.com/FreeBook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for our next video, where I’ll talk to an expert about how the new tax law may affect you and the real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, if you have any questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 05:41:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-what-happened-in-the-2017-market-and-what-to-expect-in-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-what-happened-in-the-2017-market-and-what-to-expect-in-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - How an Under-the-Radar Strategy Can Sell Your Home Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OeE5upoA5cM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Welcome to the latest episode of “What’s Working Now!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Today, I want to share a successful under-the-radar strategy for selling a home that worked in the middle of the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Plus, if you are thinking of selling your home in 2018, I have something special to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Now, we recently sold a home about a week before Christmas. When I met with the homeowner to talk about cleaning, sorting, staging, and making the house market-ready, she looked like she was going to cry. So, we decided on a different strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We decided to show the home before it was ready for the market.&lt;/strong&gt; The market is full of buyers, interest rates are low, and inventory is so low that there is practically nothing for sale. In the last couple of weeks, we’ve had eight buyers that wanted to buy two houses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Inventory is incredibly low right now, which means there is almost no competition for sellers.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-an-under-the-radar-strategy-can-sell-your-home-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Inventory is incredibly low right now, which means there is almost no competition for sellers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;We went ahead and advertised this particular property under the radar to my network of prospects, agents, and the neighborhood. One of the neighbors had a friend who wanted to look at the house. This was the only person we showed the property to, and they turned out to be the right buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you are thinking of selling your home in 2018, there is no need to wait for the azaleas to be in bloom. The seller I just told you about entered the market in the middle of the holiday season. The market is hot right now. &lt;strong&gt;Inventory is incredibly low, so there is almost no competition.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Find an agent who can take advantage of current market conditions to make it easy for you to get top dollar fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you plan on selling your house in 2018, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dchomeblog.com/freebook&quot;&gt;check out my new book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, “Selling Secrets You Can’t Afford to Miss.” To get your free copy, visit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dchomeblog.com/freebook&quot;&gt;DCHomeblog.com/FreeBook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Thank you for watching &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; Be on the lookout for our next video, where I’ll look back on the 2017 market and go over what you can expect in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Of course, if you have any other questions in the meantime, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 07:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-an-under-the-radar-strategy-can-sell-your-home-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-how-an-under-the-radar-strategy-can-sell-your-home-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now! - Hire a Real Estate Agent With Negotiating Expertise</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H_19mDnLENE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another episode of &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about the value of negotiating experience and expertise, especially when sellers get multiple offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me give you an example. We recently put a house on the market on a Friday. By Sunday, it had five offers, and we sold the house Sunday evening. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your agent needs to be able to talk to the buyer agents about how to write a good offer in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt; Once the house is on the market and has had a couple of showings, the agents start calling me and asking, “When are you presenting offers? How are you doing this or that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time, I take the opportunity to discuss with those agents how I would like them to write their offer. I say, “The seller would really appreciate a settlement date of X. The seller would really appreciate a short home inspection contingency or none at all. If your offer is going to have a financing contingency, the seller would appreciate seeing a financial information sheet, not just a lender letter.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I give the agents instructions to bring us what we want: a big number, a short settlement date, and a big, fat deposit from a well-qualified buyer. If possible, we want that from five different buyers if we can get it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So last weekend, I put the word out to these agents and told them exactly what we wanted. I even said, “I know there will be other offers on this property. Rather than doing an escalation clause, which says ‘If someone makes me pay more, I’ll pay more,’ just come in and say ‘I will pay more. I will give you this and take out that contingency.’ That way, your buyer will have a better chance of winning the home, so please make your offer like that.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I talked to these five agents, I got two offers that were really low and had all kinds of contingencies. Those two offers were no good. I got three offers with really big numbers, so I called those three agents and coached them on how to make their offers better while I was sitting with the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I reach out and coach the agents on what the seller wants in an offer.%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-hire-a-real-estate-agent-with-negotiating-expertise.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I reach out and coach the agents on what the seller wants in an offer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any other real estate agent might have looked at those three offers, picked the best one, and sent it over for you to sign. They would probably say something like, “We got five offers! Look at what someone was willing to pay for your home! Here, sign this one.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me and my clients, that’s not good enough. I take it the extra step. Once I get the offers, I take the best ones and &lt;strong&gt;have a conversation with the agents about how they can improve the offers if they want a better chance at winning.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, two of the buyers increased their price, while the other took out the financing contingency and the appraisal contingency. I was able to get one buyer and one back-up buyer for my seller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first buyer called their home inspector, came into the property, and immediately got cold feet. That buyer wound up walking away from the transaction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we had a backup buyer in place. I didn’t have to change the status of the property and say, “This deal fell apart and the house is now back on the market.” Instead, the home remained under contract, and the second buyer got the chance to slip in and get the house without renegotiating. It was a win-win for that buyer and for my seller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just had the inspection today, and everything looks good so far. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sell your home, make sure that you work with a listing agent who will price the home correctly and make it look good enough to get all those people in the door. That agent will be able to create the opportunity for multiple offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your agent also needs to be good enough to coach the buyer agents on how to make those offers into something that will get a better outcome for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your home is priced well, looks good, and you have an agent who is an excellent negotiator, &lt;strong&gt;you will end up with a win.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about selling your home, make sure to watch the Home Seller Half Hour this week. &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.webinarjam.net/register/40860/ffb94e1c2b&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Sign up here&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to learn everything you need to know in less than 30 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; Next time, I’ll cover some of the coolest things happening in our red-hot real estate market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, if you have any other real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 09:59:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-hire-a-real-estate-agent-with-negotiating-expertise.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-hire-a-real-estate-agent-with-negotiating-expertise.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Working Now - Creative Ways to Generate More Interest in Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mKfjXQ5VbT0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the latest episode of &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to talk to you about &lt;strong&gt;an innovative way to generate additional buyer activity when selling your home.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we have a new listing that is getting market-ready. The seller is moving boxes around, packing, cleaning, and gardening so that the house is ready to hit the market in the next couple of weeks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seller had the idea that they would like to invite their friends over to say goodbye to the house. We picked a day on the weekend and invited them over in the middle of the day while the sun was out and the friends all got to take a look at the house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it was a really good idea. Then we started talking about other ideas we’ve used on past properties to market the home to the seller’s community. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes time to market your home, I have a network of 3,500 real estate agents, 2,000 prospects, and a neighborhood listserv of 20,000 of my closest friends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I’ve also had the sellers send my ad with the video tour of their home out to their own listservs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it. You may have a network of fellow college alumni, other parents from your kid’s high school, or you may belong to a church, synagogue, or music group. You may have your own “listserv” right on your own street. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Do you know anyone who might have a buyer for your house?%20http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-creative-ways-to-generate-more-interest-in-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Do you know anyone who might have a buyer for your house?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take this ad and send it out to your friends, &lt;strong&gt;you can tap into a whole new pool of people.&lt;/strong&gt; As a seller, your friends might know someone who would be interested in purchasing your house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also had past sellers send the ad to their Facebook friends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, I show my sellers the examples of the ad and tell them about the networks and publications that I will send the ad to. Then, I say, “If you have a group of people or friends who might know someone interested in your property, why don’t we tap into those people as well? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the seller isn’t sure, then I let it go. If they think it’s a great idea, we talk about their Facebook, their neighborhood listserv, or any newsletters they may send out as part of their job or other organizations they may belong to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By sending out the ad to the seller’s network, we are tapping into even more people than I would ever have access to, which is great. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I also have the seller make a video showing off their home.&lt;/strong&gt; The seller walks around and talks about family dinners, the wedding in the front yard, and the attic the kids used to play hide and seek in. I make the video look like a really nice home video. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, before I could even offer, the owner said to me, “How about I send this video to my friends?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought, what a great idea! We are doing just that with a new listing this week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When getting ready to sell your house, make sure that you work with an agent who has some of these creative ideas. Think about who you know who may know a buyer for your house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the value of getting your home ready for the real estate market. Be sure to watch the Home Seller Half Hour this week. &lt;u&gt;Sign up here&lt;/u&gt; to learn everything you need to know about selling your home in less than 30 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for watching &lt;em&gt;“What’s Working Now!”&lt;/em&gt; In my next video, I’ll talk about some of the coolest things that are happening in our red-hot real estate market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any other questions about real estate, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 05:13:43 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-creative-ways-to-generate-more-interest-in-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://marjoriedickstuart.tv/whats-working-now-creative-ways-to-generate-more-interest-in-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
