<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KW Utah</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Savvy Agent - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.savvyagent.biz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 10:09:47 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 10:09:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Work Hard and Work Smart to Hit Your 2019 Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XgFZtA_cR4w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s crazy to think about, but we’re already about 8% done with 2019. Are you making significant progress with your 2019 goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had the opportunity to speak with many agents over the past few days, and I’m impressed with the energy and commitment they’ve demonstrated in accomplishing their goals. This experience also made me think of a personal story I want to share with you that relates to today’s topic: &lt;strong&gt;How we apply our energy toward our goals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back when I was 16 years old, I worked for my dad’s construction company. One day he asked me to deliver a dump truck to a job site in Nevada. I’d only recently learned how to drive a stick shift, but I agreed to it. During the drive, though, as I worked the truck into fifth gear, it would only go as fast as 45 miles per hour. At the same time, I noticed the RPM gauge redlining. We were putting a huge amount of stress on the engine, but we were barely making 45 miles per hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, I pulled over at a gas station and called my dad (remember—this was before everyone had cell phones). When I explained the situation, I heard him laugh on the other end of the line. As it turned out, that particular truck was a split transmission. Basically, there was a switch on the stick shift that allowed you to switch over to another transmission with higher gears, but I completely missed it. All those other gears were available to me the whole time I was overheating the engine just to get to 45 miles per hour, and I had no idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Realistically, all some agents need is a small tweak in their energy and focus to really hit all of their goals for 2019.%20http://blog.savvyagent.biz/work-hard-and-work-smart-to-hit-your-2019-goals.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Realistically, all some agents need is a small tweak in their energy and focus to really hit all of their goals for 2019.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see a lot of agents putting a ton of time and energy into accomplishing their goals, which is great, but I’m also worried that some of them will burn out because they’re not putting their energy into the right activities that will produce optimum results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me to get into sixth, seventh, eight, and ninth gear in that truck, all it took was noticing a minor detail on the stick shift. Realistically, all some agents need is a small tweak in their energy and focus to really hit all of their goals for 2019. &lt;strong&gt;You don’t need to apply twice the amount of energy to duplicate your goals—you only need to change how you apply your energy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think you need to change how you apply your energy in accomplishing your goals, there are a couple of questions you need to ask yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, is your time blocking designed to match your goals in 2019? You need to commit to protecting your time—both your business time and your personal time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, are you spending enough time on dollar-producing activities? You don’t want to be maxing out your RPMs while only going 45 miles per hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the best way to apply your energy toward your 2019 goals, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you achieve your greatest success this year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 14:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/work-hard-and-work-smart-to-hit-your-2019-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/work-hard-and-work-smart-to-hit-your-2019-goals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coaching Strategies and Closing Techniques</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZE29Yd1MLrc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part 13 of our real estate fundamentals series, we’ll be taking a look at communication strategies and, more specifically, closing techniques. &lt;strong&gt;These are areas we should always be focusing on as real estate agents,&lt;/strong&gt; as a strong understanding of these tactics can mean the difference between making a deal and losing it. This section will be building off what we learned about &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.savvyagent.biz/why-communication-and-problem-solving-are-critical.html&quot;&gt;communication and problem solving in the previous webinar.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s an outline of the discussion we had, with timestamps, so you can skip around to the part(s) that interest you the most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;00:46 — An introduction to today’s topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;02:54 — Mirror and match strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;05:05 — Building rapport and using it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;05:28 — Using connectivity points&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;06:16 — Identifying and using emotion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;07:08 — Using tie-down questions and presuppositions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;07:53 — Examples of tie-down questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:12 — Examples of presuppositions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:21 — How presuppositions work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17:03 — Why these strategies help you close&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17:30 — How to deal with objections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21:47 — Handling the close&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23:48 — The Columbo tactic for closing the deal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24:40 — The assumptive close&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25:54 — The take away close&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;27:08 — The hard close&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28:30 — The leading close&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;29:40 — Why no doesn’t mean no forever&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30:43 — What to take away from the webinar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 11:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/coaching-strategies-and-closing-techniques.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/coaching-strategies-and-closing-techniques.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Communication and Problem Solving Are Critical</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pZFSnhKXMxI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve said before, the agents who are listing-focused and have a strategy for taking listings are dominating the market right now. Today we’re going to talk about a few things that are very critical in preparation for your listing presentation: &lt;strong&gt;communication and problem-solving.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To me, these are the two most critical skills you can learn whether you’re a real estate agent or not.&lt;/strong&gt; If you can be a great communicator and problem solver, you have the ability to make a huge impact on the world and the people around you. Here’s an outline of the discussion we had, with timestamps, so you can skip around to the part(s) that interest you the most:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:30- An intro to communication and problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:00- The business of relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:15- Tips for building rapport and being aware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30- The 5-step process of communication and how it relates to receiving a present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:50- How to use communication strategies to solve problems in your business and in your life in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21:20- The “Three P” approach to negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23:00- How my daughter used the “Three P” approach to come up with an agreement when she wanted to make an Instagram account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25:50- Additional negotiation tips to help you have success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;26:30- How rapport comes in handy when dealing with “Chicken Littles.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;29:00- Final thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for joining us yet again. Next time, we’ll talk about some closing strategies. If you have any questions for me in the meantime about this topic or about your business in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 16:20:40 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/why-communication-and-problem-solving-are-critical.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/why-communication-and-problem-solving-are-critical.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Does a Great Listing Presentation Entail?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FVkvAgzILaA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to our series on the real estate fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve covered before, running a great real estate business isn’t just about being creative. It’s also about knowing, and closely following, the basics of the industry. You need to know the fundamentals before you can put your own spin on things. This time, we’ll be discussing buyer and listing consultations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the interview. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:26 - An introduction to today’s topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:26 - The importance of knowing a buyer or seller’s motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:00 - How to prepare for buyer and listing consultations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:57 - Why listing presentations matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15:27 - Important aspects of a listing presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:40 - How to use eEdge to create and edit a listing presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28:10 - Selling yourself during the listing presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30:34 - How to incite immediate action after a listing presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reviewing today’s video, I encourage you to check out this &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;listing presentation example&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 11:54:08 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/what-does-a-great-listing-presentation-entail.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/what-does-a-great-listing-presentation-entail.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Utilize List Reports to Set Yourselves Apart</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SUU_uZv-W34?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My conversations the past several weeks have focused on listing: In this market, an agent that can control the listings and have more listing conversations is going to win more easily. Given that, it’s critical for us to be utilizing any tools we have available to us to set us apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I asked James and Mark Western from CityWide Home Loans to join us for today’s conversation. I’m very particular about my partnerships, and the reason I decided to bring them on as our mortgage partners is that they’re incredible businessmen—their ethics, culture, and quality of service are very much in line with our standards, and they constantly bring value to the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to introducing James and Mark to you, I wanted to also discuss a particular tool that will set our agents apart when they’re speaking to their clients about their listings: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://welcome.listreports.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ListReports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Though it’s been available to our agents for a while, they’re not plugging into it the way I’d like to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Utilizing this tool will set you apart from what other agents are doing, and it can help you secure more listings.%20http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-utilize-list-reports-to-set-yourselves-apart.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Utilizing this tool will set you apart from what other agents are doing, and it can help you secure more listings.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the timestamps below, feel free to navigate the conversation we had at your leisure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2:30—Introducing James and Mark and their journey in the real estate industry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4:00—Diving into ListReports: James and Mark show us what it is and how it. works, as well as highlight the power of the tool and give recommendations for using it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10:40—Intuitive marketing elements: The marketing materials ListReports provides for an agent’s listings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;14:40—ListReports is formatted for both desktop and phone browsers, giving it on the go convenience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;16:45—Open houses are made easier with ListReports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;18:25—Need promotional flyers? ListReports can do that, too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;19:35—Showing your clients how you’ll be marketing their listings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;20:05—The School Report.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;22:15—Who has access to the listings on ListReports?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;23:10—ListReports can help buyers’ agents and their clients, as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;25:00—Making the most of ListReports’s sign-writing service.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;27:55—Summarizing the benefits of using ListReports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my actionable recommendation to anyone who is looking for tools and resources to enhance your control of your listings: Partner with a CityWide Representative and ask them to help you implement the ListReports tool; they’ll help you set up your account. Then, pull up and look at every report and make a system out of them. Decide what reports you’ll use on which listings, but don’t use all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to thank James and Mark for joining me today, and especially for being such a phenomenal resource and partner for our team. They’re truly an asset for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to us. Until then, make it a great week! Get out there and crush it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 16:06:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-utilize-list-reports-to-set-yourselves-apart.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-utilize-list-reports-to-set-yourselves-apart.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Use Your Website to Leverage Your Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v-tNgcTR1mE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to our webinar series on real estate fundamentals. For part nine of our series, I wanted to touch on &lt;strong&gt;one of the pieces of technology that is underutilized in many of our agents’ businesses: websites.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In no way do I think it’s critical that our agents become web developers, but at the very least, they should know what the tools that are available to them can do to increase their business. Keller Williams invests $1 million per week in technology and that technology is available for us to use to leverage our businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps so that you can jump around to whatever part of the discussion interests you most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:20- A few helpful tips for getting started with setting up your own website through KW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:30- What setting up your own site outside of KW will cost you and why it’s silly to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:20- How to customize your domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:45- How to add branding to your site and the benefits of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:20- Launching your site and what a live website looks like from the front end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:30- How to update your “Featured Listings” page on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17:30- The two options for capturing leads through your site and the benefits and drawbacks of each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:30- How changing the overall look of your site through theme selection can help set you apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:35- Tips for customizing the slideshow pictures that appear on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22:30- How to integrate blogs and testimonials into your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25:00- A few additional tips and tricks to help you maximize the value of your site, including social media and KW app integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about your website or about anything else we touched on in this webinar, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 14:57:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-use-your-website-to-leverage-your-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-use-your-website-to-leverage-your-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Use the KW Mobile Search App</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/30aLrJU2SQU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keller Williams invests $1,000,000 per week into technology for us to use. This shows not only the significance of the technology, but also the company’s awareness of its agent’s needs. One form of technology that they have invested money into is the KW Mobile Search App. This app can be personalized to have your information linked to it automatically for each user. I recently held a webinar on setting up and using the KW Mobile Search App to help you with lead generation that I want to share with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have included timestamps below so that you can jump to the sections that most interest you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:30 – A tool to help walk you through how to use the KW app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:55 – Where to download and brand the app to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:55 – The importance of sharing your app information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:40 – How the app can help your client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The KW Search App can be personalized, when set up, to have your information linked to it automatically for each user.%20http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-use-the-kw-mobile-search-app.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The KW Search App can be personalized, when set up, to have your information linked to it automatically for each user.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:40 – How the app can help you nationally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:35 – Adding a link to your email signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:05 – Scripts to share your app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:00 – Who you can give your app to first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:05 – Run a contest to get more engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16:30 – A crash course to the KW app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:25 – Who else should have your app and give it away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21:40 – How KW video can help you with distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25:00 – The trick to letting the tools work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;27:00 – Next week’s topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this, please let me know. I would be happy to help you in any way that I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 14:46:07 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-use-the-kw-mobile-search-app.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-use-the-kw-mobile-search-app.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using the Final 2 Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rsklnqznN7A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently held a webinar for part seven of Real Estate: The Fundamentals that I would like to share with you. These recent weeks have been a lot of fun for me, personally, because it has given me the opportunity to reanalyze how the fundamentals are being run on my own team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have timestamped the conversation to make it easier for you to jump to the sections most interesting to you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:20 – A quick recap of the career growth initiative tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:50 – An overview of the last two tools: The Agent Language of Real Estate (LORE) and the Local Expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:55 – What should you compare your business against?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:20 – How the LORE and Local Expert tools work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:50 – Where you find the LORE report on kwconnect.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:50 – What the LORE spreadsheet looks like and how we use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:20 – Where the numbers are coming from and how they get compared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:40 – Where the story starts showing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:45 – Why does the data tell this particular story?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:15 – Comparing your business to your board, market center, region, and KWRI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:50 – Developing your value statements and choosing the right ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17:00 – What you do with your value statements after you have them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17:30 – How we compare each category and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18:55 – Tell the story with the Local Expert tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:05 – Why this tool is cool and where you can use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21:20 – The benefits of adding a video to your flier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23:20 – Why you need to do this for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25:35 – What is coming up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions about this, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 15:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/using-the-final-2-tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/using-the-final-2-tools.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Fundamentals, Part 6</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JuLwpl0Y-aE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you be purposeful and strategic in how you make changes to your business? You look at the numbers and adjust accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today in the sixth installment of my webinar series about the fundamentals of real estate, I’ll show you how to utilize your multi-year trend report and look at it in relation to the business plan you’ve put together so you examine the right numbers and make the right adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are timestamped sections of the video above so you can jump ahead to certain points at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:40 - A quick review of what we’ve learned from previous videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:11 - Explaining the CGI tools of the Career Growth Initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:51 - The agent trend report—where you can find it and how it can help you stay on track with your listing goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If your business plan isn’t working, you alter it based on the numbers.%20http://blog.savvyagent.biz/real-estate-fundamentals-part-6.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If your business plan isn’t working, you alter it based on the numbers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15:10 - Why you need to ask “Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:10 - The numbers that can and can’t be tracked in the multi-year trend report and where you can go to find the numbers that aren’t tracked:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://Daily104.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Daily104.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:04 - The activities that are tracked on &lt;a href=&quot;http://Daily104.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Daily104.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23:34 - The final piece of analyzing your multi-year trend report and how it breaks down where you’re at with your four conversations: appointments, listings taken, closed units, and GCI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;27:20 - How focusing on two conversations, your number of appointments, and the number of listings taken can tell you what activities need to change in your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the same playbook that the best agents in the country are running; it’s just a matter of modifying the effort and activity within that model. If you haven’t already done this with your first quarter numbers of 2018, I encourage you to download your multi-year trend report today and use the second quarter to get back on track. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 12:10:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/real-estate-fundamentals-part-6.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/real-estate-fundamentals-part-6.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Fundamentals, Week 5: Capitalizing on Your Pipeline</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uZpzDrm69Gs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Thus far in my webinar series, I’ve discussed how mastering just one of the fundamentals in a given area isn’t enough—you need to master many of them so that your basic skills can fuel and support each other. Fundamentals are all just pieces of one big puzzle without which you cannot see the full picture. To see in detail all of what we’ve discussed so far, visit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://savvyagent.biz/fundamentals/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.savvyagent.biz/fundamentals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Today’s installment begins our journey into week five of my seminar. To those who have been following along, &lt;strong&gt;have you taken specific action in relation to every one of these fundamentals that we’ve covered to turn them into habits?&lt;/strong&gt; For example, have you take action to better time block your calendar? Are you better utilizing your lead generation time? Are you now making an effort to utilize your CRM and systematically follow up with your people? I hope that you are.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today I want to focus on capitalizing on your pipeline, which is a representation of how much business you can expect to close in a given timeframe. &lt;strong&gt;We have a pipeline tool that is sure to help you visually organize your appointments and transactions,&lt;/strong&gt; as well as a means of setting and tracking the goals you set for yourself in terms of appointments set and met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps so that you can jump around to whatever topic interests you most:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;0:00-4:10—An overview of our previous topics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;4:10—Our weekly WIG meetings (&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;ildly &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;mportant &lt;strong&gt;G&lt;/strong&gt;oal) and the &lt;u&gt;four conversations&lt;/u&gt; we have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listing Appointments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listings Taken&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Closings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;6:10—Your CGI (career growth initiative) tools are all interconnected—their power is maximized when each one is used to build upon, support, and strengthen the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8:12—My modified KWRI pipeline sheet: who is most likely to give me business within the next several months?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;12:15—The different ways people get into your pipeline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;21:50—What if your pipeline doesn’t match your goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22:55—My challenges for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;26:15—Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;I’ll return next time to continue this discussion on mastering the fundamentals. Until then, be sure that you’re implementing all these ideas and working to build yourself a better process. If you have any further questions, feel free to reach out to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 16:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/real-estate-fundamentals-week-5-capitalizing-on-your-pipeline.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.savvyagent.biz/real-estate-fundamentals-week-5-capitalizing-on-your-pipeline.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
