<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Video Blog with Nathan Abbott</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Nathan Abbott Team - your professional Florida's Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ownemeraldcoast.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 14:18:14 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 14:18:14 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Year-End Market Update as We Look Ahead to 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7hbt2uTrKKU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve entered into the new year, we’d like to wish you all the best in 2019! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a moment to look back at our active, yet unique, 2018 market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spring of 2018 saw a strong upsurge in activity—the busiest season in our market that I can remember.&lt;/strong&gt; On the whole, this boom was generally characteristic of 2018’s market, and it led to a strong finish. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we saw changes in the market, as well.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As spring turned to summer, activity waned a little, which was likely due to an extremely strong market performance from the previous season and other factors typical of a market slowdown like kids being out of school, families going on vacation, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came out of the summer plateau with another burst of activity as fall arrived—it was, again, as busy as I can remember. We appeared to be well on our way to repeating (or even topping) that earlier boom we experienced in the springtime. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Market activity rebounded, and we were busy again as 2018 came to a close.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/a-year-end-market-update-as-we-look-ahead-to-2019.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Market activity rebounded, and we were busy again as 2018 came to a close.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But then, disaster struck—Hurricane Michael reached our shores.&lt;/strong&gt; Though it didn’t directly impact our area, it was definitely a catalyst for some changes in our market. The level of activity we saw throughout much of 2018 sunk a little from there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all of that, our year actually ended on a high note; market activity rebounded, and we were busy again as 2018 came to a close. This bodes well for our market in the new year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have a lot of people discovering our area for the first time, and with more people working remotely from home, there are great opportunities for our residential market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please reach out to us with any of your real estate concerns and questions. We’d love to make your real estate dreams a reality in 2019!&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/a-year-end-market-update-as-we-look-ahead-to-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/a-year-end-market-update-as-we-look-ahead-to-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Shows Why We Love to Call This Place Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5_6pqUKkD_8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy this gorgeous aerial tour of everything our area has to offer, from Crystal Beach in Destin all the way to Rosemary Beach on East 30 A. It’s easy to see why people love Northwest Florida’s Gulf Coast. The clarity of our water, the white sandy beaches, and the southern charm make this place incredibly special. I was born and raised here and there is truly no place like home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/this-shows-why-we-love-to-call-this-place-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/this-shows-why-we-love-to-call-this-place-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Enjoy this aerial tour of luxurious Alys and Rosemary Beach</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NkNf0Ctp2P8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alys Beach and Rosemary Beach are two of the most luxurious communities along Florida’s Gulf Coast. Both of these amazing, masterplanned, urban communities are extremely pedestrian-friendly. When you’re in Alys Beach, you feel like you’re in the Greek Isles with all the whitewall architectural design, the broken stone walkways, greenspaces, and other amazing amenities. The neighboring Rosemary Beach is also extremely special, with beautiful contemporary design properties that are reminiscent of a European coastal town. CNN recently named Rosemary Beach as one of America’s most romantic towns, and for good reason—you’re surrounded by amazing parks, greenspaces, restaurants, shopping centers, and other family entertainment venues. I strongly encourage you to come by Alys Beach and Rosemary Beach today, as all your coastal desires will come true.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/enjoy-this-aerial-tour-of-luxurious-alys-and-rosemary-beach.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/enjoy-this-aerial-tour-of-luxurious-alys-and-rosemary-beach.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>See One of the Most Special Places Santa Rosa Beach Has to Offer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/G7WjAgyDhVE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have another great aerial tour to take you on today, and this time we’re flying over Watersound Beach, a world-class beach destination along scenic Highway 30A. Sitting on 256 acres of land and featuring over a mile of beach frontage, it provides a perfect blend of master-planned, ultra-luxurious homes and tons of bicycle trails, walking paths, and some of the most beautiful nature you’ll find in our area. It also neighbors Deer Lake State Park, which makes it a great place for families to explore the outdoors. Just outside the gates of Watersound, you’ll also find the Hub, which is a great place to go out to eat, listen to some live music, and enjoy all sorts of fun family entertainment. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/see-one-of-the-most-special-places-santa-rosa-beach-has-to-offer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/see-one-of-the-most-special-places-santa-rosa-beach-has-to-offer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It’s Time to Offer Our Aid to Those Impacted by Hurricane Michael</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UyEhc2R65zs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Hurricane Michael, Panama City, Lynn Haven, Mexico Beach, Port St. Joe and surrounding areas to the north are in a state of ruin. Buildings were torn asunder, trees were snapped under the force of the storm, and debris was scattered in thick swaths across the coastline. As harrowing as this scene may be, the mere sight of it cannot begin to truly illustrate the full experience of those affected. Yet hope is not lost. The more willing we are to offer our help to those in need, the more quickly our affected communities can recover. Your donation could make all the difference in the lives of those affected.  If you have a Facebook account and desire to contribute please, click&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/donate/341437133081419/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; here&lt;/a&gt; or you can call Nathan Abbott at 850-803-7653 to coordinate additional contribution options. These families truly need our help! Thank you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📷: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daiglephotography.com/&quot;&gt;www.DaiglePhotography.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/its-time-to-offer-our-aid-to-those-impacted-by-hurricane-michael.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/its-time-to-offer-our-aid-to-those-impacted-by-hurricane-michael.html</guid>
        
        <category>Hurricane Michael</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seaside and Watercolor: An Aerial Tour</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TdLaSkLp7ek?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seaside and Watercolor is a gorgeous area. It’s so beautiful, in fact, that it’s been used in a number of films, like “The Truman Show”. These master-planned communities have a multitude of amenities and fun activities to be enjoyed by the whole family. The location takes on a perfect coastal village charm, with an infrastructure based on pedestrian and bicycle friendly communities close to everything you need to enjoy an elegant coastal lifestyle. See what life is like in Seaside and Watercolor. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/seaside-and-watercolor-an-aerial-tour.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/seaside-and-watercolor-an-aerial-tour.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hurricane Michael- The Light After Dark Skies</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ln3pJ_kfyVI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurricanes create supernatural skies.  They always seem to deliver a beautiful sunset before and after the storm that wreaks havoc. Learning to navigate through the dark skies in between resembles life as we know it. Even in your darkest days, you can find light if you search for it.  More beautiful days ahead. Our thoughts and prayers are with everyone in Panama City, Mexico Beach, and to the east which has a long road of recovery.  We will be setting up our office as a headquarters to collect donations and needed items for relief efforts. We are located at &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/5iF61fFhaDC2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://goo.gl/maps/5iF61fFhaDC2&lt;/a&gt;  and will provide updates as we receive them. Thank you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more updates, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC1y00cFB4V9xULUkZMt5eSA?sub_confirmation=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;subscribe to our YouTube Channel.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/hurricane-michael-the-light-after-dark-skies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/hurricane-michael-the-light-after-dark-skies.html</guid>
        
        <category>Hurricane Michael</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Enjoy This Breathtaking Aerial Tour of Grayton Beach</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/M_stJHodyyM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grayton Beach is one of my all-time favorite places—as one of the top-rated beach destinations, it’s truly in a league of its own. This is one of the largest beaches in the area and connects to beautiful Western Lake, where you can enjoy by paddle boarding or kayaking. Grayton Beach is rich in history with homes dating back to the early 1900s. It’s a laid-back community where all you truly need is a pair of flip-flops and a swimsuit in order to enjoy everything it has to offer. The neighboring Grayton Beach State Park is an amazing place to explore and you are walking distance to several incredible restaurants and entertainment. Come see today what makes Grayton Beach so special.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/enjoy-this-breathtaking-aerial-tour-of-grayton-beach.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/enjoy-this-breathtaking-aerial-tour-of-grayton-beach.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>See What Makes Topsail State Park a Phenomenal Place to Explore</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Gy-l0eFM6hc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topsail State Park is one of the staples of Miramar Beach and Santa Rosa Beach, and I have a quick aerial tour of the area to show you today. With many lakes and walking trails to choose from, it’s a phenomenal place to explore. The Gulf frontage is untouched, and is surrounded by some of the most incredible resorts along our coastline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Topsail State Park is a great place to enjoy everything our coastline has to offer.%20http://ownemeraldcoast.com/see-what-makes-topsail-state-park-a-phenomenal-place-to-explore.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Topsail State Park is a great place to enjoy everything our coastline has to offer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grand Boulevard is also close by, and it offers a variety of entertainment options. As a local, my own office building is located just five minutes away, and I can tell you that it’s easy to avoid the traffic most times of the year. Overall, it’s a great place to enjoy everything our coastline has to offer. To get the full aerial tour, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/see-what-makes-topsail-state-park-a-phenomenal-place-to-explore.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/see-what-makes-topsail-state-park-a-phenomenal-place-to-explore.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Aerial Tour of the Beautiful Crystal Beach</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/l3f2pPQ0GG0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy this aerial tour of Crystal Beach and Scenic Highway 98 in Destin, Florida. Crystal Beach is one of my absolute favorite locations along our coast—it’s a charming coastal town that really takes on a Nantucket feel. It’s low-density and welcoming to pedestrian, bicycle, and golf cart traffic all along Scenic Highway 98.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more is that you’re centrally located just south of the Destin Commons, one of the biggest hotspots for shopping and entertainment in the Destin area. For the complete aerial tour of this scenic coastal destination, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more great videos like this, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC1y00cFB4V9xULUkZMt5eSA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;subscribe to my YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ownemeraldcoast.com/an-aerial-tour-of-the-beautiful-crystal-beach.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ownemeraldcoast.com/an-aerial-tour-of-the-beautiful-crystal-beach.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
