<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1000 Calls A Day | Done-For-You Outbound Teleprospecting</title>
    <description>We offer done-for-you calling of your database or cold list, up to 1,000 attempts a day, to identify new, missed or unconverted opportunities for your sales team.</description>
    <link>http://1000callsaday.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://1000callsaday.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 12:55:57 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 12:55:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interviewing Savvy Real Estate Investor Aaron Bowman</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aDPzZS9g0R4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining me today is real estate investor Aaron Bowman. Though his initial path wasn’t in real estate, he made a transition around three years ago and has since found faster-than-normal success in this industry.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in our interview.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;0:05—A little bit about Aaron and his background &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:55—How Aaron got his start in real estate investing and how he conducts his business &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:55—Challenges he faces in the business  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:55—Challenges Aaron encountered before working with 1000 Calls A Day &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:33—How he leverages his strategy to get sellers to transact for less money &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:10—The business-related pains and problems 1000 Calls a Day helped Aaron overcome &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15:41—What his process is from receiving lists to the follow-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18:20—The longest it’s taken Aaron to land a deal &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21:45—How he establishes timelines for sellers who aren’t yet ready&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23:20—A look at how Aaron organizes his lead generation and follow-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24:55—A word of advice for those aspiring to get into real estate investment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;26:02—Aaron’s final words of wisdom &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We thank Aaron for taking the time to chat with us today. If you have any further questions for us, please don’t hesitate to reach out. We’d love to hear from you! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 01:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/interviewing-savvy-real-estate-investor-aaron-bowman.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/interviewing-savvy-real-estate-investor-aaron-bowman.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Us Help You Expand Your Reach &amp; Grow Your Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9v6n7EX0Nq0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 1000 Calls A Day, we can make many different kinds of calls on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a Realtor, &lt;strong&gt;we make traditional real estate calls on your behalf&lt;/strong&gt;, including calling “For Sale By Owners,” calling expired or withdrawn listings, as well as doing circle prospecting and open house calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can also do re-engagement calls with past prospects or clients&lt;/strong&gt;. Let’s say you’re a Realtor and you have a list of 10,000 old Zillow leads. Those leads never did anything; they said they were interested in at the time, but maybe you didn’t follow up with them well enough, or maybe they just went dark on you. Regardless, we can enact a re-engagement calling plan to reconnect with all those people, see where they are currently, follow up with them, maybe offer them a free gift, touch base, and/or confirm that we have their correct contact information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we can do some &lt;strong&gt;non-traditional real estate calls&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, if you purchase a data list of people who are most likely to sell their homes in the next 12 to 24 months, we could help you connect with them. These are people who are statistically identified through different indicators that they would be most likely to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This data list could consist of mortgage data, life events, how much equity they have, and so on. Whatever the case, lists like these provide great opportunities for you to bring people into your world who have never been there—before your competition does. However, you’ll need to keep in touch with, drip on, and nurture these leads for anywhere from 12 to 24 months; these are for longer-term sales, but it’s always good to increase your sphere.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We would love to schedule a consultation call with you to learn more about your business and discuss how we can help you scale your outbound calling and help you grow.%20http://1000callsaday.com/let-us-help-you-expand-your-reach-grow-your-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We would love to schedule a consultation call with you to learn more about your business and discuss how we can help you scale your outbound calling and help you grow.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This next type of call we do very commonly is for investors&lt;/strong&gt;: If an investor is putting together a list of leads they want to go after—distressed properties, motivated sellers, people in financial troubles, etc.—we can absolutely help them pursue those types of calls. Our most common campaign is calling motivated sellers for investors. Now, investors would provide that data to us, or else we could help you connect with one of our data providers to purchase a list like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final type of call we can do for you is specific to recruiting. If, for example, you’re a Realtor who is growing your real estate team, &lt;strong&gt;we could help make calls to recruit new members for you.&lt;/strong&gt; We could also do outbound messaging, where you have a set script of messages that they’re sending out to people through social media, email, and text, on top of the other tools we have available to distribute outbound messages. By doing this, we can see who is interested, and follow up with those people, pre-qualify them, and then pass them on to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind you, if your business isn’t in real estate, there’s still a good chance that we can help and work with you. These are simply some of the most common types of calls and campaigns that we run here at 1000 Calls A Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or are interested in working with us, reach out to us by phone, or else visit our website at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.1000callsaday.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.1000callsaday.com&lt;/a&gt; and opt-in for a free consultation call. We would love to schedule a consultation call with you to learn more about your business and discuss how we can help you scale your outbound calling and help you grow. We hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 09:06:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/let-us-help-you-expand-your-reach-grow-your-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/let-us-help-you-expand-your-reach-grow-your-business.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who We Call and How We Get Our Lists</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kS7iKLINl5o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list of prospects we call on your behalf is a form of data, &lt;strong&gt;and data can be purchased.&lt;/strong&gt; Though you may already have lists of past clients, prospects, and leads from various forms of marketing, you can always purchase more to add to your list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you work in the real estate industry, we can determine your past leads, re-engage clients, and even go after FSBOs, expired listings, withdrawn listings—you name it. Any sort of in-house calls you’re making are calls we can make for you. Many of our clients choose to buy new lists of leads or subscribe to other services that will get new prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For investors, we can go after distressed and vacant properties, but this type of data is typically found from a data company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also deal with propensity data, &lt;strong&gt;which is a longer-term nurturing opportunity.&lt;/strong&gt; It finds leads in people who are likely to sell within the next 12 to 24 months. This is purchased from a data company, and we handle all the calls for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We simply help you purchase great data and follow up on it by creating custom campaigns for calling and taking advantage of those lists.%20http://1000callsaday.com/who-we-call-and-how-we-get-our-lists.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We simply help you purchase great data and follow up on it by creating custom campaigns for calling and taking advantage of those lists.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve included a PDF of the top data suppliers and companies we’ve used. We test all this data so we know what sources get good leads for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regardless of which industry you’re in, you own the data involved.&lt;/strong&gt; We simply help you purchase great data and follow up on it by creating custom campaigns for calling and taking advantage of those lists. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://1000callsaday.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1000CallsADay.com&lt;/a&gt; and get a free consultation today. In the meantime, we look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 15:52:13 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/who-we-call-and-how-we-get-our-lists.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/who-we-call-and-how-we-get-our-lists.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Data Can Help You Locate the Ideal Client &amp; Boost Your ROI</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kbRh0Ko_RF0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secret to getting to outbound prospecting and securing the best ROI possible is &lt;strong&gt;acquiring great data.&lt;/strong&gt; So where does it come from? Well, there’s no single data gold mine, and finding the best data heavily depends on the industry you’re in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better define what data is, think of it as a list; in essence, it’s a list comprised of people that are the ideal client you’ve set your sights on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In order to obtain the best data, we recommend you purchase propensity-based data with predictive analytics.&lt;/strong&gt; The company you purchase from will likely be a cut above more industry-specific options, and your list should be fairly large, containing approximately 25,000 contacts. If you’re in the real estate industry, a list of this size should keep the caller busy for anywhere from four to six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those in real estate may have to look to data sources beyond the propensity-based variety, though, due to the disparate types of lists you may need. Real estate-specific data often comes from places like Cole Realty, Vulcan 7, RedX, etc., so &lt;strong&gt;it’s important to look into what source will help you pinpoint your ideal client and market to them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In order to obtain the best data, we recommend you purchase propensity-based data with predictive analytics.%20http://1000callsaday.com/how-data-can-help-you-locate-the-ideal-client-boost-your-roi.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In order to obtain the best data, we recommend you purchase propensity-based data with predictive analytics.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to get on a call with you to discuss some of the best practices for purchasing data and get to know you and your business to see if working together is a fit for you. Visit our website at 1000CallsADay.com to sign up for a free call today!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 14:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/how-data-can-help-you-locate-the-ideal-client-boost-your-roi.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/how-data-can-help-you-locate-the-ideal-client-boost-your-roi.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get More Leads With Outbound Prospecting</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p6RKg2Qgj-8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three primary ways you can get leads: through your sphere, through inbound prospecting, and through outbound prospecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the sphere tends to be the strongest source for clients. &lt;strong&gt;The problem is that spheres aren’t scalable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what about inbound? As you know, this involves running ads using Facebook, Google Pay-Per-Click, or Boomtown (if you’re in real estate). This is all well and good, but it’s also expensive. Also, internet leads aren’t always the highest quality. And, on top of that, a single change in a website’s algorithm can completely stifle your growth by hindering the number of leads you’re getting for the amount you’re used to spending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you work with us, you control the data, the money you spend, the number of dials, and everything else.%20http://1000callsaday.com/get-more-leads-with-outbound-prospecting.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you work with us, you control the data, the money you spend, the number of dials, and everything else.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In short: There are some issues with inbound prospecting.&lt;/strong&gt; Even though it is fairly scalable and can be a good supplement to your overall plan for lead generation, it won’t be enough on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why we at 1000 Calls A Day focus on outbound prospecting. &lt;strong&gt;We know how difficult it can be to sit on the phone for hours on end, so we’ve made it so that you don’t have to.&lt;/strong&gt; We have made outbound prospecting completely scalable. When you work with us, you control the data, the money you spend, the number of dials, and everything else. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or are interested in scheduling a free consultation, then feel free to give us a call, send us an email, or visit our website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://1000callsaday.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.1000callsaday.com&lt;/a&gt;. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 12:41:41 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/get-more-leads-with-outbound-prospecting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/get-more-leads-with-outbound-prospecting.html</guid>
        
        <category>Outbound Prospecting</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 2 Main Reasons We Don’t Set Appointments</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bXnPLrvlXeM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People always ask us whether we set appointments for our clients. The truth is that this task isn’t part of what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our goal as a business is to go after cold traffic so that we can dig up and pre-qualify leads for you.&lt;/strong&gt; We generate warm leads and then pass them on to you, but not before making sure that they’re a good prospect. This allows your inside sales staff to get right to work on setting appointments and scaling your business.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of reasons why we don’t set appointments. The biggest reason is that &lt;strong&gt;we want you and your staff to be able to pre-qualify each lead for yourself&lt;/strong&gt; before going on a meeting with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, because we’re calling cold traffic, certain leads may be interested but not ready to commit in the near future. It would, therefore, be better for you to put these leads into your CRM and then nurture them until they’re ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We aren’t appointment setters—we are outbound prospectors who find warm leads and pass them back to you.%20http://1000callsaday.com/the-2-main-reasons-we-dont-set-appointments.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We aren’t appointment setters—we are outbound prospectors who find warm leads and pass them back to you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your time is valuable, and we know you’re busy. We don’t want you to go on appointments with leads who aren’t entirely qualified or ready to move forward. In short, we aren’t appointment setters—we are outbound prospectors who find warm leads and pass them back to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re interested in scaling up your outbound prospecting, visit our website &lt;a href=&quot;https://1000callsaday.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.1000callsaday.com&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 12:45:35 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/the-2-main-reasons-we-dont-set-appointments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/the-2-main-reasons-we-dont-set-appointments.html</guid>
        
        <category>Outbound</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Type of Conversion Rate Can You Expect With Different Data?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vDhg6Q3OlF8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people want to know what kind of conversion rate they can expect when working with us. Here’s the thing: &lt;strong&gt;We don’t have the ability to track all of our clients’ results.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re required to report back to you, so we report our numbers and our analytics. However, our clients don’t always report their numbers back to us regarding their sales and profits. We try to help people track their numbers, but we can’t require clients to send them to us. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the purposes of this article, I’m going to discuss conversion rates with real estate clients.&lt;/strong&gt; We have hundreds of campaigns in this arena so we know pretty well what these numbers should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, we’re making between 450 and 750 calls per day. Of those calls, a good contact rate is about 5%. That equates to about 25 to 40 people per day. On an average day, we know the conversion rate depending on the list or type of data you’re using. Here are the best kinds to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first and best is propensity data that you buy from a data company—&lt;/strong&gt;specifically, the kind of data where you can get very specific with these numbers and even have the data company add a “most likely to sell” filter. If we have a list like this, there’s a good chance that 10% of those people are going to become leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A good contact rate is around 5%.%20http://1000callsaday.com/what-type-of-conversion-rate-can-you-expect-with-different-data.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A good contact rate is around 5%.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second-best is the low-hanging fruit in the real estate world, &lt;strong&gt;including for sale by owners, expireds, canceleds, and withdrawns.&lt;/strong&gt; Of the people we talk to on this kind of list, we’re able to convert about 8% of them to leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next on the list is other propensity-type data that you don’t have the ability to add your criteria in to. The likelihood of converting those people to leads is about 6%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we have straight neighborhood data. There are no filters or other indicators on it. This cold traffic only leads to about a 1% to 2% conversion rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go through these numbers and calculate them out, you see that the best data source, by far, is that propensity data with additional filters to your exact criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this was helpful. If you’re interested in talking with us about how we can help you scale your outbound prospecting and grow your business, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email today. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 14:06:10 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/what-type-of-conversion-rate-can-you-expect-with-different-data.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/what-type-of-conversion-rate-can-you-expect-with-different-data.html</guid>
        
        <category>Database</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Use 1000 Calls A Day?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v2D2WX7QLO0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/why-use-1000-calls-a-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/why-use-1000-calls-a-day.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Type of Outbound Prospecting Can We Do for You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qKFQZNXeogM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at 1000 Calls A Day, we can pretty much run any type of outbound prospecting campaign that you’d like us to. A campaign is simply a fancy name for a script and a list. &lt;strong&gt;If you have a script and a list that go together, that’s a campaign.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the clients that hire us have anywhere from three to five outbound prospecting campaigns going on at once. We can track the numbers and analytics of each one of these campaigns so that you know &lt;strong&gt;where you’re getting your leads, see which campaigns are working, and are advised on where you should be spending your time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the real estate world, there are a lot of different options when it comes to campaigns. We can run campaigns for FSBO, expired/withdrawn, just listed/just sold, open houses, database reengagement, and more. If you’re an investor, we can go after different types of distressed properties, foreclosures, tax liens, and anything else you can get a list and a script for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Most of the time, you don’t even need a script because we already have one ready.%20http://1000callsaday.com/what-type-of-outbound-prospecting-can-we-do-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Most of the time, you don’t even need a script because we already have one ready.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of it is that you really don’t need to put a script together most of the time. &lt;strong&gt;We have hundreds of scripts that our clients are using around the country and we can borrow the best-performing ones and use them for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also call your database. This includes old customers, clients and prospects who you haven’t talked to in a while. We can re-engage with them, get updated contact information, and announce something to them that you want them to know or an offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As you can see, the possibilities are pretty much endless when it comes to running campaigns and scaling your outbound prospecting.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any questions for us in the meantime or you’re interested in working with us, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email today. We’d love to hear from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 14:45:03 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/what-type-of-outbound-prospecting-can-we-do-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/what-type-of-outbound-prospecting-can-we-do-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Outbound</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Reason Why We Don’t Give Exclusive Calling Rights</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MYYGIilQ4pE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m answering a question we often hear from prospective clients: “Do I get exclusive calling rights in my area?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a common question because Realtors and other business owners want to know if they have a competitor that has already hired us in their city.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t give exclusive rights to any one area and here’s the reason why: We’re calling based on your data, not theirs. We’ll certainly tell you if we’re working with someone in your industry or in your city, but &lt;strong&gt;you don’t need exclusive rights to your area if you’re working with us because you’re providing the data to us to do the calling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Since you own your data and your competitors don’t, exclusive rights don’t really matter.%20http://1000callsaday.com/the-reason-why-we-dont-give-exclusive-calling-rights.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Since you own your data and your competitors don’t, exclusive rights don’t really matter.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are the first person who is scaling up outbound prospecting in your area and you hire us, it’s definitely a competitive advantage. &lt;strong&gt;However, we do have multiple clients in the same market and exclusive calling rights have never been an issue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or you’re interested in scaling up your outbound calling, give us a call or send us an email today to see if we could be a fit together. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 10:05:51 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/the-reason-why-we-dont-give-exclusive-calling-rights.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/the-reason-why-we-dont-give-exclusive-calling-rights.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
