<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Real Estate Video Blog with Ashley Carter</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carter Group Chicago - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 15:40:03 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 15:40:03 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Is Our Market in 2021?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sm3-FoyMWpA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are the latest numbers from our Chicago market so far in 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is our 2021 real estate market doing so far? In the single-family market in Chicago, compared to this time last year, more properties have closed, but &lt;strong&gt;fewer have come onto the market, making it more difficult for buyers to find the ideal house.&lt;/strong&gt; The median sales price has increased by 8.8%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Many active buyers are out in the market, but the inventory across the board has been reduced.%20http://localhost:4000/how-is-our-market-in-2021.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Many active buyers are out in the market, but the inventory across the board has been reduced.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the condo market, which includes townhomes and any other attached housing, more have been listed, sold, and gone under contract compared to last year. Their median sales price has risen by 3.9%, and there are fewer properties available. In the two-bedroom, two-bath condo market specifically, prices have dropped by 2.5%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the multi-unit property market, we’ve seen fewer properties listed, but more have sold.&lt;/strong&gt; The median price for multi-units has climbed by 12.7% from this time last year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many active buyers are out in the market, but the inventory across the board has been reduced. If you or anyone you know is considering making a move and needs help figuring out their situation, give us a call or shoot us an email or text. Contact us if you have any questions, as well. We’re always glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 03:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-is-our-market-in-2021.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-is-our-market-in-2021.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Stage Your For-Sale Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jt2lqwYXVyw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;These are the top four reasons you need to stage your for-sale property.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, in the first installment of our two-part series about home staging, I’m sharing four reasons why staging works when selling your home:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Living is different from selling.&lt;/strong&gt; The way we live in our homes is different from the way we sell houses. The way you live in your home accommodates your lifestyle, family size, and how you want the space to function. A professional stager or interior designer puts a space together to present it in its most photogenic and appealing way to buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The right furniture.&lt;/strong&gt; Unfortunately, you don’t have the right furniture. That’s not a criticism; most of us don’t have the appropriate furniture to stage a house to appeal to buyers in the best way. We inherit furniture, bring two families together, or buy furniture over time; most people don’t have an entire matching set. Some also have too much furniture, and a stager knows what to eliminate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Staging is still one of the key things we can do to prepare your house for the market.%20http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-stage-your-for-sale-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Staging is still one of the key things we can do to prepare your house for the market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Buyers expect staging.&lt;/strong&gt; Due to online listings, HGTV, Instagram, Pinterest, and so on, buyers have been trained to think that a staged appearance is how a property should look when it’s for sale. A very high bar has been set over the last few years for sellers that you need to match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Your competition is staging.&lt;/strong&gt; Your competition is painting, decluttering, and usually staging to prepare for sale, and you don’t want a buyer choosing their home over yours simply due to its staging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real estate climate has shifted, but staging is still one of the key things we can do to prepare your house for the market. Pricing correctly is the most crucial thing, but the property’s physical condition and appearance is the second-most essential aspect of a sale. We don’t see that changing anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay tuned for part two of this home staging series&lt;/strong&gt; where we’ll do a case study of a staged home! If you or anyone you know is considering making a move and would like to speak with us about what to do to prepare for a sale, please reach out via phone or email. We’re happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-stage-your-for-sale-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-stage-your-for-sale-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Feel When You See These Pics?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qDHVNX8inDk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are some before-and-after pics that prove staging’s efficacy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s case study of the power of proper staging: a vintage condominium in the Rogers Park neighborhood of Chicago that had been fully remodeled 13 years ago and is presently in good condition. &lt;strong&gt;Starting at 1:36 in the video above, you’ll see some before-and-after photos of rooms in the property&lt;/strong&gt;—the former having been taken by the latest top-model iPhone camera, the latter having been captured by our professional photographers post-staging. It’s clear just how beneficial a professional’s use of digital image correction tools can be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People relate better to fully furnished properties because they have a hard time otherwise understanding how the dimensions of their possessions will square with the dimensions of the space they’re seeing online. How big is my couch? Would my lamp look good in that corner, or would it seem a little too awkward? Where would I hang artwork?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Staging fosters that all-important leap in a buyer’s mind from ‘This is a nice place’ to ‘Wow, I can see myself living here.’%20http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-feel-when-you-see-these-pics.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Staging fosters that all-important leap in a buyer’s mind from ‘This is a nice place’ to ‘Wow, I can see myself living here.’”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, &lt;strong&gt;artwork has a huge psychological and emotional effect on people&lt;/strong&gt;; if we go into a property void of decorations, the buyer’s interaction with the home would be fundamentally different. It’s not that the walls would somehow seem to be in worse condition, but rather that the artwork so greatly enhances the &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; of the space. Towels and a few tiny, appropriate decorations can make bathrooms feel cozy and homey. With staged dining rooms, buyers will be able to get a baseline of many guests they’d be able to entertain and what &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; could then do with the space to make it reflect their tastes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, we aim to facilitate that all-important leap in a buyer’s mind from “This is a nice place” to “Wow, I can see myself living here,” or, “I can imagine how my family would use these spaces.” &lt;strong&gt;Staging &lt;em&gt;shows &lt;/em&gt;the buyers what it could be like to live in a property.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of scratching their head and wondering whether their couch will fit, buyers can truly engage with the spaces. Remember: The initial decision to buy a property is largely an &lt;em&gt;emotional&lt;/em&gt; one; logic is used retroactively to justify the positive feelings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this case study has helped you to understand how even the most gorgeous, move-in ready properties benefit from professional staging and photography. If you have further questions on this or any other topic or are thinking about making a move soon, please feel free to reach out by phone or email. We’d love to hear from you and consult you on a wide range of options for staging your home and preparing it such that it fetches top dollar on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 18:22:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-feel-when-you-see-these-pics.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-feel-when-you-see-these-pics.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Sell in the Winter?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8MzbKQ2XBU4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are the three main reasons winter is an excellent time to sell.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, you may want to consider selling now instead of waiting for the spring. Though spring is the “traditional” time to sell, it’s not always the best option. Here are the three top reasons you may want to sell in the winter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Less competition.&lt;/strong&gt; There are many homeowners who wanted to sell but decided not to, their home didn’t sell so they took it off the market, or they’re debating it so they’re waiting to list. This means fewer properties competing against yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Focused and serious buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers who didn’t need to buy likely wouldn’t be looking this time of year, so they’re motivated to purchase. Since there’s not a ton of new inventory on the market this time of year, your house will stand out more than it would in a busier market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Spring is the ‘traditional’ time to sell, but it’s not always the best option.%20http://localhost:4000/why-sell-in-the-winter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Spring is the ‘traditional’ time to sell, but it’s not always the best option.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Decorated homes show well.&lt;/strong&gt; Your property is probably decorated for the holidays, and that looks appealing this time of year. What people see, smell, and feel when they walk into your home is all part of the showing process. These senses help them make a personal connection and imagine themselves living in the space. Houses often show their best this time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people have needs or goals to move sooner than spring, but they hold themselves back because they think spring is a better time. Thankfully, you don’t have to, it’s still a great time to sell during the holidays and winter months. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d prefer to get the buying or selling process rolling or have any questions, reach out to us via phone or email. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 18:26:03 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-sell-in-the-winter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-sell-in-the-winter.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Did Our Market Defy Gravity in 2020?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-W11EcgVfy4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How did our market manage to stay afloat during COVID?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our real estate market has been surprisingly strong, so today I’m going to take a deep dive behind the scenes to explain why and how the real estate market has defied gravity during COVID. One figure in particular that we’ll focus on is the unemployment rate—first, we’ll compare this year’s rate to that of the Great Recession in the last decade; next, we’ll look at unemployment rates by industry; and then we’ll look at how unemployment varied by age group. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to follow along with our conversation in the video above or else use the timestamps below to navigate the discussion at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:43—Unemployment rates and the U.S. marketplace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:15—Comparing today’s market to that of the Great Recession&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:15—Unemployment rates by industry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:33—People who are most likely to own a home have been the least affected by COVID&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:56—Unemployment and housing by age groups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:26—Which age group was hit the hardest?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:40—Wrapping up the conversation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this data will help you understand why our market has managed to stay so strong despite all the chaos in the economy and the world at large. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about buying or selling homes, or would like to know more about the market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 11:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-did-our-market-defy-gravity-in-2020.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-did-our-market-defy-gravity-in-2020.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Did COVID Impact Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4_rVCH3YJUg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s how our area market performed over the last six months.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, during the time between March and September of this year, the number of home sales dropped by 8.5%. What might surprise you, however, is that &lt;strong&gt;prices have actually gone up by 3.2%&lt;/strong&gt; in that same time frame. That kind of price jump would have been a marker for a very robust and strong market even over a 12-month period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the uncertainty that came along with COVID and the resulting shelter-in-place orders, many home sellers put the brakes on their home sales while buyers were still active in the market. That increased competition among buyers in that short period, which is what led to our price increase over the last six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another major factor that we track in the residential market is the &lt;strong&gt;interest rates.&lt;/strong&gt; Rates were already incredibly good in March, hovering around 3.75% at that time, and now they’ve gone down more than a full point. Rates for regular condos, townhomes, and single-family homes are hovering somewhere between 2.5% and 3%. Good rates don’t hurt, but I think the main driving force behind the demand was that people were anxious about getting into their next homes so they could shelter in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Rates were already incredibly good in March, hovering at that time around 3.75%, and now they’ve gone down more than a full point.%20http://localhost:4000/q-how-did-covid-impact-our-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Rates were already incredibly good in March, hovering at that time around 3.75%, and now they’ve gone down more than a full point.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One point of concern that we’re keeping an eye on is the &lt;strong&gt;unemployment rate.&lt;/strong&gt; Obviously, some industries have been hit much harder than others, but this number could have an impact on our market. I’ll discuss that in more detail in my next video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about today’s topic or anything else to do with real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 15:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-did-covid-impact-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-did-covid-impact-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Should Sellers Keep In Mind When Scheduling Showings?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bnoxfDZDGdg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s why it’s so important for sellers to be flexible when it comes to scheduling showings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things we talk about with our selling clients is the fact that they need to be flexible when it comes to scheduling showings. That means, &lt;strong&gt;when your home goes on the market, you’ll have to set your personal lifestyle aside so that you can make your home always look show-ready.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to my business partner Laura Jones, the process is usually a bit more work than many sellers realize. Buyers have many things going on in their own lives, as do their agents, such that balancing everyone’s schedule can be difficult. Many buyers end up blocking off a limited four-hour period to go view homes. During this period, Laura can schedule showings of multiple properties in a row, which means that she has to stay right on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=That’s why it’s critical for sellers to be flexible with their own schedules; failure to be open could result in losing buyers.%20http://localhost:4000/q-what-should-sellers-keep-in-mind-when-scheduling-showings.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“That’s why it’s critical for sellers to be flexible with their own schedules; failure to be open could result in losing buyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a property was unavailable at the requested time (which doesn’t often happen), &lt;strong&gt;then the property often falls off the buyer’s radar&lt;/strong&gt;—they often find the home they want within the first couple of days when they start viewing houses. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes about four or five days for a client of Laura’s to go from being just a lead to actually getting in the car to go out for a showing. During this time, they compile and fine-tune a list of houses the buyer is interested in, and 48 hours before going to a showing, she puts together a schedule of showings for the properties that were narrowed down. That’s why it’s critical for sellers to be flexible with their own schedules; failure to be open could result in losing buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about today’s topic or other real estate-related questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. In the meantime, stay tuned to our blog for more tips and tricks for both the buying and selling side of real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 11:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-should-sellers-keep-in-mind-when-scheduling-showings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-what-should-sellers-keep-in-mind-when-scheduling-showings.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Should Sellers Know About a Buyer’s Perspective?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HFz9ocp_yGs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what sellers should know before listing their home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m joined once again by my friend and business partner Laura Jones so she can answer some important home seller questions and offer her best advice. Laura handles the buyer side of our team’s transactions, so she brings a unique perspective that can help you sell quickly and for top dollar if you’re putting your home on the market soon. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, what’s the most important thing a seller can do when preparing their home for the market?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Laura, it’s pricing your property according to the market. None of her buyers get excited about the prospect of overpaying for a property they like and going through the uphill battle of negotiating. Testing the market and overpricing your home by $20,000 or $30,000 will never work to your advantage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do buyers think if they assume a property is testing the market in this way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, Laura tries to find out whether the seller did some extra work to the home that’s not showing up in the photos. In general, though, buyers feel discouraged. They’re comparing the property to several others, and they’re definitely not thinking, “We’ll go ahead and offer $20,000 or $30,000 more for this home than the one down the street.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A buyer’s mindset is affected by their reaction to a home’s value package.%20http://localhost:4000/what-should-sellers-know-about-a-buyers-perspective.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A buyer’s mindset is affected by their reaction to a home’s value package.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re going through a comparative shopping experience and looking at multiple properties in a row, so the reality of this is fresh in their minds. They’ll pretty easily be able to make a strong comparison between Property A and Property B. If one home goes off the market, they turn their attention back to the same pool of listings, and the best ones always sell quickly. &lt;strong&gt;Condition, location, and price are the most important factors. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A buyer’s mindset is affected by their reaction to a home’s value package. Does it have the same features other properties have, and is it priced reasonably for what’s included? When buyers look at homes online, they make all kinds of determinations and value judgments on sellers and their agents in terms of what they have and haven’t done to their listings. You can’t know what they’re looking at specifically; all you can know is who wants to see your home in person. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay tuned for future videos&lt;/strong&gt; where we’ll dive deeper into what goes on behind the scenes in real estate transactions. If you have questions about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 10:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-should-sellers-know-about-a-buyers-perspective.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-should-sellers-know-about-a-buyers-perspective.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>“Inside the Mind of a Buyer” With Laura Jones</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tgS7lY4CqiA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;
I’m interviewing buyer specialist Laura Jones to gauge how buyers think.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buyers hop in the car, buckle up, and get ready to view a home on which they could potentially submit an offer, what’s going through their mind? Generally speaking, what’s their approach? As Carter Property Group Buyer Specialist Laura Jones reminds us, buyers have already narrowed down a location and a budget by that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, they’re asking these all-important questions: “What is the best thing we can get for the money? What is the best overall value? Which five things are most important to me, and which property delivers on them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once they’ve figured out the geography and budget, the most common criterion for buyers is the general condition of the property—is it a fixer-upper, or is it move-in ready? &lt;strong&gt;Other major considerations include bedroom count, outdoor spaces, and storage areas.&lt;/strong&gt; How a buyer then defines value beyond those common criteria becomes a highly individualized matter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The most common criteria for buyers is the general condition of the property.%20http://localhost:4000/inside-the-mind-of-a-buyer-with-laura-jones.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The most common criteria for buyers is the general condition of the property.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s environment, buyers will often claim that they’re willing to fix up a bathroom if the house is perfect otherwise or that they don’t mind putting in a little work to turn a good home into a great home. While they may genuinely mean that, Laura pointed out that buying behavior doesn’t quite reflect that sentiment: “Once we get out and look, the [property] that goes the quickest, the property that everyone seems to make offers on, is the one that’s in the best condition. One that’s been decluttered, its carpets are clean, and the one that’s likely the most updated.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buyers see a home that’s in great condition as a sort of relief; they won’t have to put as much money into the home.&lt;/strong&gt; “It might seem like a selfish answer, but buyers are looking for the best home for their budget. They’re not really thinking about who’s on the other side of the transaction and who’s selling the property,” Laura said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it: An inside glimpse into the mindset of the modern buyer. Remember, sellers: If you want a successful home sale, you have to think like a buyer and be willing to take a step back and view your home from their perspective. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have further questions on this or any other real estate topic, please feel free to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 16:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/inside-the-mind-of-a-buyer-with-laura-jones.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/inside-the-mind-of-a-buyer-with-laura-jones.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Are Homes Still Selling?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eAtQZC5n3fc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our market has slowed, but you can still buy and sell amid COVID-19.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this pandemic, I keep getting asked the same questions: How’s the market, and am I still selling homes? When the health crisis hit, we were in a very busy market here in Chicago. We’re now a month into the shelter-in-place order, so naturally, the market has slowed. However, if you’re still considering buying, selling, or investing in real estate, please give me a call, I’d love to speak with you. Homes are still being bought and sold, even during the coronavirus. To hear my full message, watch the short video above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:22:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-are-homes-still-selling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-are-homes-still-selling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
