<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Stern Team: Home Page</title>
    <description>Salt Lake City Utah best Realtors are on The Stern Team, led by Joshua Stern. Follow us for latest market info and be prepared to buy or sell real estate.</description>
    <link>http://sternteam.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sternteam.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 13:17:18 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 13:17:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Different Ways Real Estate Deals Fall Apart</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_3SCcZOReHM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying and selling real estate can be complicated and there are a lot of opportunities along the way for transactions to fall apart. &lt;strong&gt;Here are the primary reasons that real estate deals fall apart based on our experience:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Pre-contract deal-killers.&lt;/strong&gt; The first stage of a transaction occurs before an offer is even made. On the side of the seller, a few things could keep them from going through with a deal. They might change their mind after a lowball appraisal, a low offer, or a repair list that’s much too long. Overall, most of these pre-contract deal killers come from the buyer, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Post-contract deal-killers.&lt;/strong&gt; After there is an accepted purchase contract that’s signed, there is another list of potential problems that could arise and kill the deal. Most revolve around money, repairs, and who is going to fix or pay for them. Sometimes, however, buyers simply get cold feet because they didn’t do their homework up front. Maybe they weren’t prepared for a big to-do list or there were some larger issues uncovered during a home inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Buyers who made a contingent offer but were unable to sell.&lt;/strong&gt; Every home is sellable. However, some homes take longer to sell for a variety of reasons. One of the most common reasons a real estate deal falls through is that a potential buyer can’t sell their current home or buy their new home without selling it first. If you’re selling your home and receive a contingent offer, you should not count on that particular buyer shaking your hand at the closing table. Home sale contingent offers in real estate have a much higher risk of failing than offers that don’t have home sale contingencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The buyer is denied their financing or loan.&lt;/strong&gt; In a perfect world, every potential homebuyer with a pre-approval would get to the closing table, but this simply isn’t the case. Having a pre-approval letter is important for a buyer, but it doesn’t guarantee your mortgage will be fully funded. Until the closing occurs, a buyer isn’t guaranteed to receive a loan. There are situations, such as the buyer losing their job or experiencing health issues, that no loan officer can control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Pre-settlement walk-throughs.&lt;/strong&gt; The biggest issues here have to do with things being left behind, not being left behind, or fixtures or window coverings that should have been taken. Unknown utility liens and property taxes can pop up, too. For most of these problems, a bit of money or making a small change to the contract’s terms will fix the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you should know that &lt;strong&gt;about one in four real estate &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;contracts&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;that are accepted end up failing.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s a rather high number. This is why it’s important to work with a highly experienced real estate agent when navigating the home buying and selling process. Be aware of the common pitfalls of failed transactions, because that increases the odds that your deal won’t fall through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/5-different-ways-real-estate-deals-fall-apart.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/5-different-ways-real-estate-deals-fall-apart.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Do to Prepare Your Home for Sale?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/n_qVJ7yRJAw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to discuss six ways to get your home ready for sale this spring:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Let natural light in.&lt;/strong&gt; Open up your blinds, windows, and let that natural sunlight in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Renovate what’s outdated.&lt;/strong&gt; If your kitchen or bathroom is stuck in the 1980s, it’s time to freshen it up a bit to get top dollar for your home. Updated faucets, towel racks, and cabinets are things you can do even if you’re on a tight budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Think small with renovations.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t overdo it with expensive renovations. Instead of replacing all of your cabinets, just paint or replace the doors. If you’re going to spend money, spend it on curb appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Paint with whites and neutrals.&lt;/strong&gt; A fresh coat of paint is relatively inexpensive and an easy way to give your house a facelift. Keep the colors neutral so that buyers can better imagine the home as their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Fix anything that’s broken.&lt;/strong&gt; Repairs can take some time, but getting them out of the way allows you to sell your home much faster. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Pay attention to odors.&lt;/strong&gt; The smells inside your home can kill a home sale, and you may not even notice a lot of them. If you have pets, smoke, or regularly cook fragrant foods, consider getting your carpets freshly cleaned and adding a fresh coat of paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Let as much natural light in as possible.%20http://sternteam.org/what-can-you-do-to-prepare-your-home-for-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Let as much natural light in as possible.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate-related questions or needs that I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/what-can-you-do-to-prepare-your-home-for-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/what-can-you-do-to-prepare-your-home-for-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Developments From Our Wasatch Front Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_kkmCv5hAIo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do our first quarter statistics tell us about our Wasatch Front market? And how do these numbers stack up against last year’s Q1? We’ll answer both of those questions in today’s market update. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s jump right in: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By the end of 2019’s first quarter, our market had undergone an 11% decline in overall home sales.&lt;/strong&gt; The average home price, meanwhile, went up by a solid 5.6% over that same period. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to this point, the Wasatch Front has had more than 8,000 single-family homes, townhomes, and condos sell in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also through Q1 of 2019, the average sale price spanning all homes types along the Wasatch Front was around $342,185. We finished out the first quarter of 2018 at an average sale price of  $323,371—that’s nearly a year-over-year increase of 6%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the data point by point, t&lt;strong&gt;he average sale price for single-family homes in 2018’s first quarter rose by 5.06% to $369,382.&lt;/strong&gt; The average sale price for townhomes and condos soared by 11% to $258,110 in that same year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We may finally have a formula that tilts the scale toward buyers.%20http://sternteam.org/the-latest-developments-from-our-wasatch-front-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We may finally have a formula that tilts the scale toward buyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning our attention to average days on market, the average home is currently spending 53 days on market, which is a 10% increase from the 48-day average we saw last year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wasatch Front’s inventory for all housing types is at 4.6 months’ worth of supply. Although this is considered a low amount of inventory, anything that falls in the four- to six-month range is seen as a sign of market stability.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With ever-growing home prices comes a greater availability of inventory and coupled with stable interest rates that opens up buyer affordability, we may finally have a formula that tilts the scale toward buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final note, &lt;strong&gt;we saw some of the lowest interest rates we’ve had in a while by the conclusion of Q1 this year.&lt;/strong&gt; The Fed originally set the expectation that four or five rate increases were on the way this year, and after withdrawing that announcement and making new assertions that no increases were coming in 2019, the market responded favorably.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any real estate-related questions or needs, please get in touch with us. We’d be happy to help however we can! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/the-latest-developments-from-our-wasatch-front-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/the-latest-developments-from-our-wasatch-front-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should I Buy a Starter Home in Today’s Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J7XL1dbdwFA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A question about the viability of purchasing a starter home in today’s market was recently posed to us, and it boils down to this: &lt;strong&gt;Should you invest now in a starter home or would it be more prudent to wait and save for your forever home?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s first make sure we’re talking about the same thing—among economists, the prevailing definition of a starter home is one that falls within the lower-third of the market’s valuation, unlike, say, trade-up or luxury homes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homebuyers themselves may define a starter home a little differently, though; rather than a starter home’s defining characteristic being price, &lt;strong&gt;the question that’s front and center for buyers relates to time.&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore, to a buyer, a starter home is one that they may only live in for a few years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the dilemma really lies. If you choose to purchase a starter home, the bulk of your payments in the first few years of ownership will go toward interest, which hampers your ability to build any equity in the home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The best time to buy is imminently approaching.%20http://sternteam.org/should-i-buy-a-starter-home-in-todays-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The best time to buy is imminently approaching.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, some estimates indicate that the break-even point for starter homeownership is somewhere around five to seven years. To put it simply, &lt;strong&gt;if you plan to live in the home for a short period of time, it might not make sense to buy at all.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be perfectly clear: We aren’t necessarily telling you not to buy a starter home. &lt;strong&gt;In some cases, going this route may be squarely within a buyer’s interests.&lt;/strong&gt; Staying in a home for more than five years, for example, will allow you to build savings that might otherwise go to rent and also build equity over time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might also find that, with the right renovations and care, your starter home could blossom into your forever home. Alternatively, you could keep the home and rent it out at a later time if your plans change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this decision should be based on decisions and preferences specific to your situation. Let’s say, after careful consideration, you’ve decided a starter home is right for you. If that’s the case, take note: &lt;strong&gt;The best time to buy is imminently approaching.&lt;/strong&gt; Why? Per Trulia, starter home inventory sharply increases and listing prices drop in fall and winter, which translates to maximal choices at less cost to you.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious about what homes are becoming available in your area, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sternteam.com/search&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;check out this list.&lt;/a&gt; If you’re looking to sell a property,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sternteam.com/homevalue/ssl-homevalue&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; click here for a free home evaluation. &lt;/a&gt;Either way, if you have questions related to real estate in any way, give us a call at 801-859-7509. We’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/should-i-buy-a-starter-home-in-todays-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/should-i-buy-a-starter-home-in-todays-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lock In Your Interest Rate With This Great New Program</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FEtPUr3WOuY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Interest rates are on an upward trajectory, but not everyone can take advantage of the low rates we have now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m joined today by &lt;strong&gt;Mandi Henriod of Intercap Lending&lt;/strong&gt;, who shared with us a great way buyers can lock in current interest rates. Let’s say rates are 5.25% now and you know you want to buy a home within the next year, but by then, the rate will likely increase to 6.25%. Intercap Lending’s new program can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Their clients can now lock in a rate for up to 120 days while shopping for a home.&lt;/strong&gt; Most lenders won’t lock in a rate without having a purchase contract, but that’s not the case with this program. Intercap Lending will be able to lock it in with no up-front fees, and they can even lock the rate on a specific property for up to 360 days (with a fee). This is a great option if you have a home under construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Most lenders won’t lock in a rate without having a purchase contract, but that’s not the case with this program.%20http://sternteam.org/lock-in-your-interest-rate-with-this-great-new-program.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Most lenders won’t lock in a rate without having a purchase contract, but that’s not the case with this program.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike any other option we’ve seen, the up-front fee is refundable at the time of funding. All of their rate-lock options allow for renegotiation if rates somehow decrease. &lt;strong&gt;They’re able to offer this on all agency loan programs, including FHA, VA, and conforming loans.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to make a move within the year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intercaplending.com/loan-officers/mandi-henriod/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;contact Mandi at Intercap Lending&lt;/a&gt; so you can lock in a low rate today. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/lock-in-your-interest-rate-with-this-great-new-program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/lock-in-your-interest-rate-with-this-great-new-program.html</guid>
        
        <category>Josh Stern Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Buy Property Through a Partnership</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_MMGjV_75vU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always our goal to keep you educated about all things real estate so you can accomplish your buying, selling, and investment goals. Today we’ll be talking about how co-borrowers works in real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen home values increase by over 30% in the last five years, and combined with recent interest rate hikes, &lt;strong&gt;affordability has been affected—especially for first-time homebuyers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, we’re seeing more and more people purchase properties together. It makes sense: Rather than waiting to afford something on their own, they’re compounding their homeownership efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-borrowers are creating long-term partnerships of five to 10 years, even creating LLCs to spell out the terms. Others have taken title as tenants in common instead of through common joint tenancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re seeing more and more people purchase properties together.%20http://sternteam.org/how-to-buy-property-through-a-partnership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re seeing more and more people purchase properties together.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tenancy in common imposes joint liability and several liability of tenants, &lt;strong&gt;meaning each owner can be liable for property taxes and deductions equal to the amount they paid.&lt;/strong&gt; Simply put, tenancy in common allows several people to share their interest in real property while retaining the freedoms that would be restricted through joint tenancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’d like to buy real estate but are unable to on your own, and you have a friend or family member who’s in the same boat, consider a partnership.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether you want to have a home to live in or a property to invest in, you can compound your purchasing power together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that when you’re purchasing as a partnership, both credit scores will be used. The lowest score will determine the financing ability and interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any topics you’d like us to cover in the future, have any questions, or need further information, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/how-to-buy-property-through-a-partnership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/how-to-buy-property-through-a-partnership.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Wasatch Front Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WF4T-zjjToU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the latest news from our Wasatch Front market as we move further along into 2019?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer that question, let’s first compare the statistics from the fourth quarter of 2018 with 2017’s fourth quarter. Home sales dropped 7% from just over 9,600 to 8,994. The average sale price, meanwhile, increased 8% to $350,000. For new construction homes, the average asking price rose a little over 8%. The average days on market for all housing types decreased 5% from 43 to 41 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With interest rates rising almost a full percentage point during that time and an exceptionally low number of starter homes available, &lt;strong&gt;first-time buyers are being squeezed pretty tightly right now. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, we have a tale of two markets. Our supply of inventory for all home types is at 5.3 months, and because a six-month supply is considered a level market, we’re close enough to that mark to be considered a level market too. However, for homes priced under $350,000, there’s just a 3.9-month supply, which is a strong seller’s market. For homes priced over $500,000, we have a 10-month supply, which is a strong buyer’s market. In other words, the higher you go in price, the more we become a buyer’s market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our market can also be described as more of a trickle-up market&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning first-time buyers dictate the rest of the market’s movement. When a first-time buyer buys a home, that seller is able to move up into the next price range. In that sense, we can see how a lack of supply impacts the higher price ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Slightly slower economic and demographic growth along with higher prices and interest rates will dampen demand.%20http://sternteam.org/a-wasatch-front-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Slightly slower economic and demographic growth along with higher prices and interest rates will dampen demand.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the year-over-year numbers from 2018 as a whole?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of total home sales stayed relatively flat compared to 2017. The average home price increased 9% to nearly $340,000, while the median price rose 10% to $300,000. The average market price decreased 5%. Like our fourth quarter snapshot, home prices continued to rise while affordability decreased. That being said, the supply of inventory increased from 3.19 months to 4.06 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s in store for 2019? Slightly slower economic and demographic growth along with higher prices and interest rates will dampen demand, which will mean fewer single-family home sales but more condo and townhome sales as more buyers seek affordable housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, prices are expected to rise between 5% and 7%. Single-family home sales are expected to decline 8%, while condo sales are expected to increase 7%. When you combine the two, we expect the total number of sales to drop 4%. &lt;strong&gt;With fewer expected sales but higher sale prices, it’s still a great time to sell your home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we finished the fourth quarter of 2018, the Federal Reserve was expected to increase interest rates four times this year, and there was some speculation that we could see rates rise as high as 6%. Those expectations have been tempered a bit, and we’re now expecting just one adjustment this year. &lt;strong&gt;If you’ve been holding off on buying a home due to high interest rates, it might be time to get off the fence and make a move.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of buying or selling a home or you have any more questions about our Wasatch Front market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/a-wasatch-front-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/a-wasatch-front-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Guide to the Tax Benefits of Homeownership</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IYTUbmlQdsY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick note before we begin today’s topic: We’re not tax professionals here at the Stern Team, so &lt;strong&gt;please be sure to meet with a qualified CPA for more details.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t know one, we’re happy to refer one whom we trust completely to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every four years, some candidate for higher political office tries to focus our attention on equalizing the tax laws and repealing the homeowner benefits, but these arguments have consistently fallen on deaf ears. Thankfully, our own local political action committee has successfully fought off and worked diligently to ensure that our legislators don’t tack on the insidious transfer fee, which gets charged to the seller or buyer at closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of us who own homes, here’s a list of the itemized tax deductions available to the average homeowner. Every year, you’re permitted to deduct the following expenses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Taxes.&lt;/strong&gt; Real property taxes, both state and local, can be deducted. The one exception is that tax filers can deduct on Schedule A any combination of state and local property taxes, as well as income or sales taxes, but only up to a total of $10,000. Interestingly, married couples who file their own separate tax returns can only deduct up to $5,000. However, it should be noted that real estate taxes are only deductible in the year that they’re paid to the government. Thus, if in the year 2018, your lender held money in escrow for taxes due in 2019, you can’t take a deduction for these taxes when you file your 2018 tax return.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mortgage lenders are required to send an annual statement to borrowers by the end of January each and every year that reflects the amount of mortgage interest in real estate taxes that the homeowners actually paid during the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Mortgage and interest.&lt;/strong&gt; Interest on mortgage loans on a first or second home is fully deductible, subject to the following limitations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acquisition loans—up to $1,000,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home equity loans—up to $100,000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are married but file these separately, these limits are split in half. Note that for the new loans taken out after December 14, 2017, the limit on the deductible mortgage debt is reduced to $750,000. Loans in existence prior to that date are grandfathered in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You must understand the concept of the acquisition loan: To qualify for such a loan, you must buy, construct, or substantially improve your home. If you refinance for more than the outstanding indebtedness, the excess amount does not qualify as an acquisition loan unless you use all of the excess to improve your home. However, any other excess may qualify as a home equity loan; if you pull out a home equity loan, you actually have to use that money to improve your house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Points.&lt;/strong&gt; Because mortgage rates are still considerably low, not too many borrowers right now are paying points. But with interest rates on the rise, this is something to attend to. When you obtain a mortgage loan in order to get a lower-rate mortgage, you would pay one or more points up front. Whether referred to as loan origination fees, premium charges, or discounts, they’re still points. Each point is essentially 1% of the amount that’s being borrowed. If you obtain a loan of $170,000, each point will cost you $1,700 and the interest rate on your loan will then be lowered. The IRS has also ruled that even if points are paid by sellers, they’re still deductible by the homebuyer. Points paid to the lender when you refinance your current mortgage are not fully deductible in the year that they’re paid; you have to allocate the amount over the entire life of the loan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For example, if you paid 1,700 points for a 30-year loan, each year you’re permitted to deduct only $56.66. However, when you pay off this new loan, any remaining portion of the points that you have not deducted are then deductible in full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It should be noted that real estate taxes are only deductible in the year that they’re paid to the government.%20http://sternteam.org/a-guide-to-the-tax-benefits-of-homeownership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It should be noted that real estate taxes are only deductible in the year that they’re paid to the government.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, if you have any questions about these tax benefits, discuss them with your financial and legal advisors. We hope that this topic has been useful for you, and if you have any real estate questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We are happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/a-guide-to-the-tax-benefits-of-homeownership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/a-guide-to-the-tax-benefits-of-homeownership.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Will I Pay Less Commission If I Find My Own Buyer?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L8JE5uNnSF4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a misconception among many sellers out there that any commission they pay to their Realtor will be reduced if they’re able to secure a buyer on their own. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of the real estate transaction, the goal is to obviously find a buyer to sell the property to, but there’s much more that goes into finalizing the process. In the event that you find your own buyer, it’s oftentimes spelled out in your contract that you, nevertheless, remain beholden to pay a specific amount to your agent. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this in mind, you can request a flexible commission plan.&lt;/strong&gt; If you make a point of requesting this up front, your agent may be agreeable to establishing this type of plan with you. Should you find your own buyer, this will allow for the possibility of adjustable commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is the true value you extract from your agent’s efforts? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contrary to what you might think, finding a buyer is a relatively small piece of the process for your agent.&lt;/strong&gt; Once you’ve accepted the buyer’s bid, your agent has the responsibility of doing paperwork with all other parties involved—the buyer’s agent, legal representation, and even title companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Contrary to what you might think, finding a buyer is a relatively small piece of the process for your agent.%20http://sternteam.org/will-i-pay-less-commission-if-i-find-my-own-buyer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Contrary to what you might think, finding a buyer is a relatively small piece of the process for your agent.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before signing an agreement with an agent, take the opportunity to discuss services and commission. If you have a pre-established idea of what you’re willing to pay and it’s somewhat lower, understand that this means the scope of services your agent provides might be narrower. &lt;strong&gt;As the old adage goes: You get what you pay for. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, your agreement should detail what you’ll pay, whether or not you can cooperate with other agents, your agent’s responsibilities, the length of the contract, and whether or not you can cancel.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For help with any and all of your real estate needs, please give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to help however we can! &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/will-i-pay-less-commission-if-i-find-my-own-buyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/will-i-pay-less-commission-if-i-find-my-own-buyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Does Reduced Home Affordability Mean for You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xW1E1v_uSy0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home affordability is shrinking rapidly, according to research by Arch Mortgage Insurance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first quarter, affordability (defined as the size of the monthly mortgage payment needed to buy a home) dropped by 5%. &lt;strong&gt;This was mainly due to the increase in mortgage rates.&lt;/strong&gt; As a consequence, more people are now stretched and taking on greater debt relative to their income. Other buyers are being pushed out of the market altogether. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There’s no need to panic if you’re a homebuyer.%20http://sternteam.org/what-does-reduced-home-affordability-mean-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There’s no need to panic if you’re a homebuyer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s not all: &lt;strong&gt;Affordability is expected to drop an additional 15% to 20% by the end of the year.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s because home prices continue to rise, and the Federal Reserve is expected to ratchet up its reference interest rate, which often leads mortgage rates, two more times this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to sell, &lt;strong&gt;you won’t have a hard time finding a buyer&lt;/strong&gt;. Even with decreasing affordability, demand for homes still far outstrips supply. However, it’s certain that buyers will look to take advantage of current conditions before affordability drops further. That means that this spring and summer might see an additional rush in the real estate market. It also means that &lt;strong&gt;right now might be a very good time to list your home&lt;/strong&gt; if you’ve been thinking about selling for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you are thinking of buying a home, you might think that this news spells doom for you. However, there’s no need to panic. While affordability is dropping, it is still well above historical averages (just like current mortgage rates). In fact, Arch Mortgage Insurance estimates that &lt;strong&gt;homes are now 15% to 20% more affordable than they were in the period from 1987 to 2004.&lt;/strong&gt; When rates go up, it will affect what your monthly payments will be on a new home. From this perspective, &lt;strong&gt;it makes sense to move now in case you’ve been looking to buy before rates rise further. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s the next step?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, give us a call. We’d be happy to answer any questions you may have. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/what-does-reduced-home-affordability-mean-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/what-does-reduced-home-affordability-mean-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
