<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Real Estate Careers in Utah</title>
    <description>Salt Lake City Utah best Realtors are on The Stern Team, led by Joshua Stern. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <link>http://millionaireagentmindset.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://millionaireagentmindset.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 15:37:44 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 15:37:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learn Your “Why” at My Latest Millionaire Agent Mindset Series Class</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pWDU24YLXs8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the founder and instructor of the Millionaire Agent Mindset Series, I always seek to help others tap into their potential for greatness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, &lt;strong&gt;I want to invite you to another live Millionaire Agent Mindset Series class I will be teaching on June 19 from 4 p.m. to 5 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt; There are no costs involved and no strings attached. The class will be held at 2121 South McClelland Street, Suite 201, Salt Lake City, Utah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month’s class will focus on the “why.” In other words, why the millionaire agent mindset produces massive success and how you can do the same with your personal mission (or your own “why”), which is the rocket fuel for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I would love for you to attend my latest Millionaire Agent Mindset Series class.%20http://millionaireagentmindset.com/learn-your-why-at-my-latest-millionaire-agent-mindset-series-class.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I would love for you to attend my latest Millionaire Agent Mindset Series class.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one sets out to be average, yet why do so few agents make it past their first license renewal? It’s because they lack a “why.” They lack a vision or a clear purpose that causes them to get out of bed each morning with enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In this class, you will complete a mission statement that outlines your vision, values, beliefs, and perspectives.&lt;/strong&gt; These factors will equal your “why.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this upcoming class, please feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I would be happy to speak with you. In the meantime, I hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://millionaireagentmindset.com/learn-your-why-at-my-latest-millionaire-agent-mindset-series-class.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://millionaireagentmindset.com/learn-your-why-at-my-latest-millionaire-agent-mindset-series-class.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A One-Page Business Plan to Achieve Your Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cTWFV_A3QGA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a millionaire agent mindset tip for you today: how to create a one-page business plan to move your career forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think the No. 1 thing that prevents people from reaching their goals is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is clarity. See, in real estate, we must start out by asking ourselves, “What’s the math that I need to do?” For instance, your units multiplied by the average home price will equal your sales volume. Your volume multiplied by your average commission equals your net income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this going to take care of your big dreams? That’s the question you should ask yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you have the numbers nailed down, here’s what your 1-3-5, or your GPS plan (goals, priorities, and strategies), will look like:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three priorities necessary to achieve your one goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Five strategies under each priority to help  you reach the goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the basic format—&lt;strong&gt;here are the rules:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your plan must fit on a single sheet of paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your whole team needs to use the same format that you do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone must follow the template.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share it with others, or you won’t be held accountable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose the the real estate professional’s GPS goal is: I will close X number of homes, equaling X in volume, equaling X in GCI. With that, your No. 1 goal will be a dollar amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Priority No. 1: Number of buyers closed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll need to decide on what percentage of that GCI will actually be buyers closing. Underneath that priority, your strategies could be :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sphere of influence: what percentage of your buyers will you have to close via your sphere to hit your number?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open houses: what percentage of the buyers will come from open houses?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet leads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signs and flyers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First-time and move-up homebuyer classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as all the strategies added up are greater than your priority, then you know you’ll hit it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you really want to put the 1-3-5 business plan on steroids, you can create a separate page for each strategy, outlining five more strategy to accomplish each main one.%20http://millionaireagentmindset.com/a-one-page-business-plan-to-achieve-your-goals.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you really want to put the 1-3-5 business plan on steroids, you can create a separate page for each strategy, outlining five more strategy to accomplish each main one.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Priority No. 2: Number of sellers closed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decide on a percentage and put in a number based on your goal. If you’re newer to the business, I find that 30% sellers and 70% buyers seems to be fairly normal, but as you age into the business, you’ll probably want to start focusing on the selling side. For the listing side, some of your strategies might be similar to the buyer side:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sphere of influence: what percentage of your buyers will you have to close via your sphere to hit your number?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open houses: what percentage of the buyers will come from open houses?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet leads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expired/FSBO listings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Farming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Priority No. 3: “Who-Have-Know-Be”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to get different results, you need to know different things, have different tools, know different people, and be in business with talent. Here are the strategies you might use to achieve success here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a coach.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hire an assistant.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hire a showing agent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get your systems in place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Educate yourself on leadership.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you really want to put the 1-3-5 business plan on steroids, you can create a separate page for each strategy, outlining five more strategies to accomplish each main one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The GPS plan is your roadmap. If you do it, you’ll find the holes in your business. If you share it, you’ll get results. If you unpack each strategy with further strategies, you’ll have a manual for how to run your business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next video, I’ll talk about how you can execute your GPS plan by using a document called a 4-1-1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about today’s topic, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to discuss the GPS plan with you further.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://millionaireagentmindset.com/a-one-page-business-plan-to-achieve-your-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://millionaireagentmindset.com/a-one-page-business-plan-to-achieve-your-goals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can Understanding the 80/20 Rule Help You Succeed?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PP_msCvmGK0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding and applying the 80/20 rule can help you tremendously with your success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the 80/20 rule? The 80/20 rule, also known as “Pareto’s principle,” was conceptualized by Italian economist Vilfredo Pareto. In 1906, he discovered that 80% of the wealth in Italy was owned by 20% of the population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;80/20 distribution of cause and effect occurs frequently.&lt;/strong&gt; In the real estate world, 80% of the homes are sold by 20% of the real estate agents. Actually, in any professional occupation, you’ll discover that 80% of the results (e.g. productivity and profitability) come from 20% of your (or the company’s) effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to real estate sales, we know there are five income-producing activities: &lt;strong&gt;scripts and role play, lead generation, lead follow-up, appointments, and negotiating contracts.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important to understand that not everything matters equally. You must focus your efforts on the 20% that matters most. We don’t need to master everything—we simply need to master the 20% that produces the 80%. Your goal in real estate sales should be to spend 80% of your own time in the 20% of those five activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does this work? If you have a list of 10 items to accomplish, two of those items will be worth more than the other eight items put together. The sad fact is, most people procrastinate on the top 10% or 20% of the items that are the most valuable and busy themselves instead with the more trivial 80%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What is the one thing you can do that, just by doing it, will make everything else easier or unnecessary?%20http://millionaireagentmindset.com/how-can-understanding-the-8020-rule-help-you-succeed.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What is the one thing you can do that, just by doing it, will make everything else easier or unnecessary?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you apply the 80/20 rule to goal-setting and your overall productivity? First, take a piece of paper and write down 10 goals. Then, &lt;strong&gt;ask yourself if you could only accomplish one goal today, which one would have the greatest impact on your life? &lt;/strong&gt;After that, pick the second-most important goal. After you finish this exercise, you’ll have predetermined the most important 20% of your goals that will help you more than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, success is sequential. It’s not simultaneous. It’s like a geometric progression in life that’s set up like a row of dominos. If you focus on knocking down that first domino, you can rest assured that the rest will fall. This sounds simple, but it’s not easy. In real estate, easy is being distracted and focusing on urgent things that are cleverly disguised as important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, ask yourself, what is the one thing you can do that, just by doing it, will make everything else easier or unnecessary?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about applying the 80/20 rule to your goal-setting or there’s anything else I can help you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, good luck with your focus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://millionaireagentmindset.com/how-can-understanding-the-8020-rule-help-you-succeed.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://millionaireagentmindset.com/how-can-understanding-the-8020-rule-help-you-succeed.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
