<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1000 Calls A Day | Done-For-You Outbound Teleprospecting</title>
    <description>We offer done-for-you calling of your database or cold list, up to 1,000 attempts a day, to identify new, missed or unconverted opportunities for your sales team.</description>
    <link>http://1000callsaday.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://1000callsaday.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 10:49:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 10:49:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Way to Organize a Sales Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/95gLo4YzTDU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you define your different sales opportunities, it’s important to understand how each role within the sales organization fits within those sales opportunities. &lt;strong&gt;It’s important to have your sales team divided up into four core parts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Inbound lead qualification&lt;br /&gt;2. Outbound prospector&lt;br /&gt;3. Closers. Generally called account executives or outside sales agents in real estate.&lt;br /&gt;4. Fulfillment. These include your account managers and customer service reps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Closers are generally terrible prospectors.%20http://1000callsaday.com/the-best-way-to-organize-a-sales-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Closers are generally terrible prospectors.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The reasons why you want to have these roles divided are:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. It takes different personality types to master these roles.&lt;br /&gt;2. Your productivity will be exponentially greater.&lt;br /&gt;3. You will have more predictable revenue and happier salespeople.&lt;br /&gt;4. It gives teams the ability to create raving fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we want to focus on here is the outbound strategy.&lt;/strong&gt; The outbound prospector is the person who is looking at a highly targeted list and reaching out on an outbound basis to convert those people into potential clients. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once they are identified as a potential client, they become part of the inbound team. That team would then qualify the lead to make sure it’s a quality lead and can be passed on to the outbound sales person who can close the lead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People who are closers are generally terrible prospectors and great prospectors aren’t always the greatest closers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/the-best-way-to-organize-a-sales-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/the-best-way-to-organize-a-sales-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why the Type of Lead You Attract Matters</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ntotPUI2wFQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you define the market, message, and medium you’ll use to deliver your messages, it’s important to understand the different kinds of leads these messages will generate. The book “Predictable Revenue” by Aaron Ross and Marylou Tyler places leads in three categories: seeds, nets, and spears. Seeds are leads you receive by word of mouth, nets are those you’ve received through inbound marketing, and spears are those you’ve gotten via outbound marketing. When you implement a strong outbound strategy, many of your leads will fall into this last category, and your revenue will become more predictable as a result. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/why-the-type-of-lead-you-attract-matters.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/why-the-type-of-lead-you-attract-matters.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Set Up a Good Outbound Marketing Plan</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5oVDSVd1Hd0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that you need to understand in order to develop a good outbound marketing plan is the marketing triangle. &lt;strong&gt;It contains the three most important factors to your marketing success:&lt;/strong&gt; your market, your message, and the media you use to deliver the message to your market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first thing you need to define is your market.&lt;/strong&gt; Who are you going to be targeting with your outbound marketing plan? What types of sellers are you looking for? Are you an investor looking for distressed sellers or an agent looking for listings? This is the first place you need to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We use the telephone to deliver our clients’ messages to their prospects.%20http://1000callsaday.com/how-to-set-up-a-good-outbound-marketing-plan.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We use the telephone to deliver our clients’ messages to their prospects.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you’ve defined your market, it’s time to craft your message.&lt;/strong&gt; What message do you want to deliver to your potential clients? You want to address their fears, their concerns, and how you can solve their problems. Being very clear on who your market is and what message you want to deliver to them is incredibly important. One can not function without the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, let’s talk about your media. &lt;strong&gt;There are lots of different ways to deliver your message out there.&lt;/strong&gt; Here at 1000 Calls A Day, we focus on using the telephone to deliver your message out to prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us about the marketing triangle or about how we can work together to get your message out to as many people in your market as possible, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/how-to-set-up-a-good-outbound-marketing-plan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/how-to-set-up-a-good-outbound-marketing-plan.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Habits All Successful Investors Should Utilize</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UR3EUhZ1qyg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of successful investors have a certain set of habits in common. Today, we’ll share five of the most important:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Consistency.&lt;/strong&gt; In order to succeed as an investor, you need to frequently contact your list of leads—or have someone do so for you. Making follow-up calls and otherwise reaching out to motivated sellers on a daily basis is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Constant learning.&lt;/strong&gt; Another component of being a successful investor is to approach your business with an education-oriented mindset. There’s always room to learn and grow your skill set, so seek out learning opportunities whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you market yourself effectively, you’ll be the first person that sellers in your area call when they’re ready to make a deal.%20http://1000callsaday.com/5-habits-all-successful-investors-should-utilize.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you market yourself effectively, you’ll be the first person that sellers in your area call when they’re ready to make a deal.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Always making offers.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ve got to cast a wide net to grow your investment portfolio, so making offers frequently is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Knowing the market.&lt;/strong&gt; Every market is different, so understanding the trends that influence yours can help guide the way you approach investing. Having a target market allows you the opportunity to identify deals as they come along, rather than trusting the opinion of an out-of-state contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Mastering your marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether it’s by using direct mail, outbound calling, or social media marketing, you need to leverage a diverse array of marketing techniques in order to effectively grow your brand and build your business. When you market yourself effectively, you’ll be the first person that sellers in your area call when they’re ready to make a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/5-habits-all-successful-investors-should-utilize.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/5-habits-all-successful-investors-should-utilize.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Find Off-Market Opportunities</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T4KellVKJjk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often ask us about where they can find more off-market opportunities, so we’d like to tackle this question today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, &lt;strong&gt;we at 1000 Calls A Day are more than happy to do the legwork for you in this regard.&lt;/strong&gt; Our team finds motivated sellers by cold calling the lists you send us. All you need to do is find a data provider that can give very detailed information about the listed sellers’ motivations, as well as information like the sellers’ age, the length of time they’ve lived in the home, and the amount of equity they have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The quality of the data will impact the quality of your results.%20http://1000callsaday.com/how-to-find-off-market-opportunities.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The quality of the data will impact the quality of your results.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, you can easily extract these sellers’ contact information by skip-tracing the data. From there, our team can go through and call all the motivated sellers. We’re equipped to handle up to 5,000 records per caller each month, so if you’re looking to cover a large area, we’ve got you covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to understand is that the quality of the data will impact the quality of your results. &lt;strong&gt;If the data you’ve purchased lacks necessary information, we’re going to have a lower contact rate and, therefore, a lower conversion rate.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To recap: The best way to find off-market deals is to have clean data, to have a target audience, and to consistently call those leads. We would love to take that last step off your plate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/how-to-find-off-market-opportunities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/how-to-find-off-market-opportunities.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Focus Your Efforts in These 3 Areas to Gain More Qualified Leads</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/INHFL2oFDuU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you could increase your qualified leads by 21 times? Studies have shown that if you do NOT call your lead within the &lt;strong&gt;first 5 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;, your conversion rate &lt;strong&gt;drops by 21 times&lt;/strong&gt; and after 20 hours, the odds of contacting them drops by over 1000 times. Having that long-term mindset can help you focus on following up with clients and building a relationship so you can track your pipeline for future business. During this video I’ll help spell out the three &lt;strong&gt;must-know&lt;/strong&gt; things that will help you accomplish this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KEY POINTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Understanding the “long-term mindset” when following up with leads&lt;br /&gt;-Increasing your lead conversions: 1. Speed to lead&lt;br /&gt;-Increasing your lead conversions: 2. Follow-up  &lt;br /&gt;-Increasing your lead conversions: 3. Script&lt;br /&gt;-Asking permission to follow-up if a lead isn’t quite ready &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about all that we covered today, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to assist you in your business!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RESOURCES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email: info@1000callsaday.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phone: (409)-210-0166&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 11:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/focus-your-efforts-in-these-3-areas-to-gain-more-qualified-leads.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/focus-your-efforts-in-these-3-areas-to-gain-more-qualified-leads.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interviewing Savvy Real Estate Investor Aaron Bowman</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aDPzZS9g0R4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABOUT AARON BOWMAN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining me today is real estate investor Aaron Bowman. Though his initial path wasn’t in real estate, he made a transition around three years ago and has since found faster-than-normal success in this industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll learn how Aaron Bowman took initiative to build his own Real Estate business and how you can model his approach to building your business with an amazing sales team. Over time he has developed a script and training program to implement by overcoming multiple challenges in the real estate industry. Aaron also discusses how he convinces sellers to transact for less money by building the relationship and asking five basic questions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KEY POINTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How he leverages his strategy to get sellers to transact for less money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What his process is from receiving lists to the follow-up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How he establishes timelines for sellers who aren’t yet ready&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A look at how Aaron organizes his lead generation and follow-up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RESOURCES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email: aaronb@mazzhomes.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phone: (860)633-1843&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bowmanrealtyct.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.bowmanrealtyct.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BowmanRealtyGroupCt/&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/BowmanRealtyGroupCt/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=aaronbow78&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/search?q=aaronbow78&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/aaronbowmanrealtor/&quot;&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/aaronbowmanrealtor/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 01:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/interviewing-savvy-real-estate-investor-aaron-bowman.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/interviewing-savvy-real-estate-investor-aaron-bowman.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Us Help You Expand Your Reach &amp; Grow Your Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9v6n7EX0Nq0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 1000 Calls A Day, we can make many different kinds of calls on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a Realtor, &lt;strong&gt;we make traditional real estate calls on your behalf&lt;/strong&gt;, including calling “For Sale By Owners,” calling expired or withdrawn listings, as well as doing circle prospecting and open house calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can also do re-engagement calls with past prospects or clients&lt;/strong&gt;. Let’s say you’re a Realtor and you have a list of 10,000 old Zillow leads. Those leads never did anything; they said they were interested in at the time, but maybe you didn’t follow up with them well enough, or maybe they just went dark on you. Regardless, we can enact a re-engagement calling plan to reconnect with all those people, see where they are currently, follow up with them, maybe offer them a free gift, touch base, and/or confirm that we have their correct contact information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we can do some &lt;strong&gt;non-traditional real estate calls&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, if you purchase a data list of people who are most likely to sell their homes in the next 12 to 24 months, we could help you connect with them. These are people who are statistically identified through different indicators that they would be most likely to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This data list could consist of mortgage data, life events, how much equity they have, and so on. Whatever the case, lists like these provide great opportunities for you to bring people into your world who have never been there—before your competition does. However, you’ll need to keep in touch with, drip on, and nurture these leads for anywhere from 12 to 24 months; these are for longer-term sales, but it’s always good to increase your sphere.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We would love to schedule a consultation call with you to learn more about your business and discuss how we can help you scale your outbound calling and help you grow.%20http://1000callsaday.com/let-us-help-you-expand-your-reach-grow-your-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We would love to schedule a consultation call with you to learn more about your business and discuss how we can help you scale your outbound calling and help you grow.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This next type of call we do very commonly is for investors&lt;/strong&gt;: If an investor is putting together a list of leads they want to go after—distressed properties, motivated sellers, people in financial troubles, etc.—we can absolutely help them pursue those types of calls. Our most common campaign is calling motivated sellers for investors. Now, investors would provide that data to us, or else we could help you connect with one of our data providers to purchase a list like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final type of call we can do for you is specific to recruiting. If, for example, you’re a Realtor who is growing your real estate team, &lt;strong&gt;we could help make calls to recruit new members for you.&lt;/strong&gt; We could also do outbound messaging, where you have a set script of messages that they’re sending out to people through social media, email, and text, on top of the other tools we have available to distribute outbound messages. By doing this, we can see who is interested, and follow up with those people, pre-qualify them, and then pass them on to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind you, if your business isn’t in real estate, there’s still a good chance that we can help and work with you. These are simply some of the most common types of calls and campaigns that we run here at 1000 Calls A Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or are interested in working with us, reach out to us by phone, or else visit our website at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.1000callsaday.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.1000callsaday.com&lt;/a&gt; and opt-in for a free consultation call. We would love to schedule a consultation call with you to learn more about your business and discuss how we can help you scale your outbound calling and help you grow. We hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 09:06:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/let-us-help-you-expand-your-reach-grow-your-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/let-us-help-you-expand-your-reach-grow-your-business.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who We Call and How We Get Our Lists</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kS7iKLINl5o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list of prospects we call on your behalf is a form of data, &lt;strong&gt;and data can be purchased.&lt;/strong&gt; Though you may already have lists of past clients, prospects, and leads from various forms of marketing, you can always purchase more to add to your list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you work in the real estate industry, we can determine your past leads, re-engage clients, and even go after FSBOs, expired listings, withdrawn listings—you name it. Any sort of in-house calls you’re making are calls we can make for you. Many of our clients choose to buy new lists of leads or subscribe to other services that will get new prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For investors, we can go after distressed and vacant properties, but this type of data is typically found from a data company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also deal with propensity data, &lt;strong&gt;which is a longer-term nurturing opportunity.&lt;/strong&gt; It finds leads in people who are likely to sell within the next 12 to 24 months. This is purchased from a data company, and we handle all the calls for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We simply help you purchase great data and follow up on it by creating custom campaigns for calling and taking advantage of those lists.%20http://1000callsaday.com/who-we-call-and-how-we-get-our-lists.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We simply help you purchase great data and follow up on it by creating custom campaigns for calling and taking advantage of those lists.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve included a PDF of the top data suppliers and companies we’ve used. We test all this data so we know what sources get good leads for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regardless of which industry you’re in, you own the data involved.&lt;/strong&gt; We simply help you purchase great data and follow up on it by creating custom campaigns for calling and taking advantage of those lists. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://1000callsaday.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1000CallsADay.com&lt;/a&gt; and get a free consultation today. In the meantime, we look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 15:52:13 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/who-we-call-and-how-we-get-our-lists.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/who-we-call-and-how-we-get-our-lists.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Data Can Help You Locate the Ideal Client &amp; Boost Your ROI</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kbRh0Ko_RF0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secret to getting to outbound prospecting and securing the best ROI possible is &lt;strong&gt;acquiring great data.&lt;/strong&gt; So where does it come from? Well, there’s no single data gold mine, and finding the best data heavily depends on the industry you’re in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better define what data is, think of it as a list; in essence, it’s a list comprised of people that are the ideal client you’ve set your sights on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In order to obtain the best data, we recommend you purchase propensity-based data with predictive analytics.&lt;/strong&gt; The company you purchase from will likely be a cut above more industry-specific options, and your list should be fairly large, containing approximately 25,000 contacts. If you’re in the real estate industry, a list of this size should keep the caller busy for anywhere from four to six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those in real estate may have to look to data sources beyond the propensity-based variety, though, due to the disparate types of lists you may need. Real estate-specific data often comes from places like Cole Realty, Vulcan 7, RedX, etc., so &lt;strong&gt;it’s important to look into what source will help you pinpoint your ideal client and market to them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In order to obtain the best data, we recommend you purchase propensity-based data with predictive analytics.%20http://1000callsaday.com/how-data-can-help-you-locate-the-ideal-client-boost-your-roi.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In order to obtain the best data, we recommend you purchase propensity-based data with predictive analytics.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to get on a call with you to discuss some of the best practices for purchasing data and get to know you and your business to see if working together is a fit for you. Visit our website at 1000CallsADay.com to sign up for a free call today!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 14:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://1000callsaday.com/how-data-can-help-you-locate-the-ideal-client-boost-your-roi.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1000callsaday.com/how-data-can-help-you-locate-the-ideal-client-boost-your-roi.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
