<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacksonville Real Estate Video Blog with Shawn O'Neill and Dan Stephenson</title>
    <description>Our mission at Expert Home Advisors is to be your best resource for Jacksonville real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Expert Home Advisors, your professional Jacksonville Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 12:39:01 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 12:39:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Write a Strong Offer on a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xq1ln9I5MB8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have three tips to make sure that the offer your agent drafts for you is going to stick the landing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Talk about things other than price.&lt;/strong&gt; The details in the offer are important. Your agent should call the listing agent and get as much information as they can. Oftentimes they’ll only consider the price as a negotiating term and not the appliances. Get those details before drafting the offer so that you can write the strongest offer possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure that your offer is clean.%20http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/how-to-write-a-strong-offer-on-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure that your offer is clean.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Make sure that your offer is clean.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure that it’s easy to understand and digitally produced. Get the answer to as many questions as possible before the offer is presented. That way, you are shortening the lag time that the seller will have to respond because you addressed their concerns in the initial offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Choose the right lender.&lt;/strong&gt; We can recommend you to some. It’s incredibly important that your lender understands how strong you are as a buyer. In some cases, they may advise waiving that financing contingency to make the offer stronger. Your lender should verify your employment and handle any objections before you present the offer. That way, you can keep it clean and close as fast as possible, or at least on time for the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about buying a home or preparing an offer, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 14:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/how-to-write-a-strong-offer-on-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/how-to-write-a-strong-offer-on-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Extra Costs to Consider Before Buying a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wM7EANuAY-s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying a home, there are a few costs you must consider beyond the price of the property itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’re planning on moving out to the suburbs, don’t forget about the increase this move will make in your transportation costs. Whenever you make a move, you should consider how doing so will impact your daily commute. &lt;a href=&quot;http://monthlyexpensecalculator.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check out this convenient tool you can use to calculate your commute expenses, here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another point to consider is utility costs. If you’re moving into a larger or older home than your current one, you could see a rise in your utility costs. On the other hand, you may see a decrease in your monthly bills if the home you’re moving into has energy-efficient features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also think about the kind of community your new home is located in. If you’re moving to a property within a homeowners association or a community development district, there may be additional costs that need to be accounted for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Before taking on any home improvement projects, make sure the expense of doing so will be worth it.%20http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/extra-costs-to-consider-before-buying-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Before taking on any home improvement projects, make sure the expense of doing so will be worth it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the community it’s located in, there are also considerations to be had regarding the home itself. Before making your purchase, ask yourself if there are any home improvements you would like to make to the property. If there are, &lt;strong&gt;consider the expense of these improvements, as well as the value they might add.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improving the home may or may not be worth it, and the same can be said for landscaping projects. Any changes or updates you make to the property must be worth it in the long run. There are a number of projects that may cost you more than they’re worth. General maintenance is another key issue to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, there is the matter of home warranty. &lt;strong&gt;No matter what kind of home you’re purchasing, we always recommend obtaining a home warranty.&lt;/strong&gt; The cost you’ll pay for a home warranty will be well worth it, since it could save you from other major expenses down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 09:24:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/extra-costs-to-consider-before-buying-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/extra-costs-to-consider-before-buying-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Make Your Home Shine Before You Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Dqx3lcgUocw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s springtime, which means that many homeowners are preparing their homes to list on the market. But what all goes into preparing a home for the market? Today, I have some tips and advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Use professional photography. &lt;/strong&gt;One of the very first things a buyer will see is a picture of your home online. These days, we only have seconds to impress, so having the best shot with the best photography is your opportunity to hook a buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These days, we only have seconds to impress, so having the best shot with the best photography is your opportunity to hook a buyer.%20http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/3-tips-to-make-your-home-shine-before-you-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These days, we only have seconds to impress, so having the best shot with the best photography is your opportunity to hook a buyer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Maintain your curb appeal. &lt;/strong&gt;Similarly to the first point, you need to make a great first impression when the buyer actually gets the home, which means that the exterior of your home needs to be in top shape. It may sound very specific, but your front door area is one of the most critical points to maintain in order make a lasting, positive impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Clean up your backyard.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure your backyard presents a lifestyle. This doesn’t mean that you need to go all out; just make sure you define the area with some plants or flowers and some neat outdoor furniture. Let your buyers imagine themselves enjoying the backyard, rather than seeing it as a project to be maintained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about preparing your home for the market or selling in general, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 12:23:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/3-tips-to-make-your-home-shine-before-you-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/3-tips-to-make-your-home-shine-before-you-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of the Pre-Certification Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RsMqIMwxc6c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to talk a little bit about the pre-certification process. One of the elements involved here is having your home inspected before it hits the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the biggest reasons we encourage our home sellers to get a pre-inspection is to uncover any issues that you might not have known about.&lt;/strong&gt; Some issues can hide in a home for years. We don’t want a buyer to discover something is wrong before we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We want our inspection report to be identical to the buyers’.%20http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/the-benefits-of-the-pre-certification-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We want our inspection report to be identical to the buyers’.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important element to the pre-certification is the fact that we’re going to provide the buyer with our home inspection report. Odds are they won’t believe it, but once they get their home inspection and it lines right up with ours, it will build trust. &lt;strong&gt;We aren’t trying to hide anything in our report.&lt;/strong&gt; We want it to be identical with theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a quick peek at the services we provide for homes when they’re listed on the market. If you have any questions or need any assistance in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 14:37:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/the-benefits-of-the-pre-certification-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/the-benefits-of-the-pre-certification-process.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Top 4 Benefits of Working With an Expert Home Advisor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BqETtu87WRM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the four advantages of working with an expert home advisor when buying a home:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. We can make sure you get the best home for the best price with the least amount of stress.&lt;/strong&gt; We believe so strongly in our ability to do this that we will sell your home for free if you don’t love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. You’ll get a home warranty guarantee.&lt;/strong&gt; We believe you should have a home that’s move-in ready, and we’ll make sure you have a home warranty to cover any unknown things that can happen. If we can’t negotiate it, we’ll pay for it out of our own commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you don’t love the home we help you buy, we’ll sell it for you for free.%20http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/the-top-4-benefits-of-working-with-an-expert-home-advisor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you don’t love the home we help you buy, we’ll sell it for you for free.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. We work with the best lender and mortgage companies.&lt;/strong&gt; This means we can give you our best rate guarantee. This fact can often get overlooked, but it can save you tens of thousands of dollars over a 15-, 20-, or 30-year period. This is a completely free service, and if you already have a lender that you like, we can at the very least get you a second opinion and possibly save you at least $1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. You pay nothing out of pocket to use us.&lt;/strong&gt; The seller pays for our services!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions about how we can benefit you during your home search or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 11:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/the-top-4-benefits-of-working-with-an-expert-home-advisor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/the-top-4-benefits-of-working-with-an-expert-home-advisor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Sets Our Team Apart?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/t2whwG-qYFs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that differentiates myself and my team from the average agents out there is one of the things that we offer to all of our sellers: a pre-certification process. &lt;strong&gt;It allows us to prepare their home perfectly before it goes onto the market so that it makes the best impression possible when it goes live.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pre-certification process has three parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Professional staging&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) A pre-inspection by a licensed inspector&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) A pre-appraisal by a licensed appraiser&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This allows us to prepare the home perfectly.%20http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/what-sets-our-team-apart.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This allows us to prepare the home perfectly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to these things, we also offer a “coming soon” program. &lt;strong&gt;This will allow us to send your home to over 20,000 potential buyers before it even hits the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we also offer a quality of life upgrade analysis, as well as professional photography. Each of these services is designed to give your home the best possible first impression with buyers online and in-person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about how we help sellers or you’re interested in hiring us to help you sell your home, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 11:43:54 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/what-sets-our-team-apart.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/what-sets-our-team-apart.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Smart Sellers Are Listing Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QpY7YlOYXEs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently asked the question, “Should I list my home now or wait until spring?” I thought I’d offer my answer up today if you’ve been wondering the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mortgage interest rates are still hovering around 4% for now, but the National Association of Realtors predicts they will go up three or four times this year. Once they reach 5%, we will start to see downward pressure on home values. &lt;strong&gt;So the answer is yes, you should put your home on the market as soon as you’re able to if you plan on selling anytime in the next year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A balanced market like this is pretty rare.%20http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/why-smart-sellers-are-listing-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A balanced market like this is pretty rare.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another factor that makes now a perfect time to sell is the fact that inventory is incredibly low right now. In Jacksonville, depending on your price range, we have very low inventory. Other sellers have not brought their homes on the market yet. &lt;strong&gt;That’s why you should get ahead of the market by listing now and taking advantage of these conditions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A balanced market is pretty rare, but that’s kind of what we’re seeing right now. Sellers can put their home on the market and get top dollar while still being able to find affordable inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listing now will help you net the most money possible. If you want to learn how we can help and what we’ll do to get your home sold, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 08:17:41 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/why-smart-sellers-are-listing-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://trustedexperthomeadvisor.com/why-smart-sellers-are-listing-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
