<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Margolis Team</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Margolis Team - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 13:43:13 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 13:43:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Going on With Mortgage Rates?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B6o24P76VUU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mortgages rates reached all-time lows, then immediately started to climb. Here&amp;rsquo;s why that happened. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rates have been dropping over the last month, and many people have been refinancing their mortgages to lock in lows of 3.25% and 3.5%. They’ve been dropping in response to the volatility in the stock market and the fear of the economy slowing down in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, however, rates started to climb back up. Why did that happen? &lt;strong&gt;Usually, when the yield on the Treasury goes up, mortgage rates go up too, and when yields go down, mortgage rates follow suit. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the yield on the Treasury is as low as it’s been in recent memory—well under 1%. Counterintuitively, rates have risen though, and that’s due to several factors. One of the largest factors is that &lt;strong&gt;lenders are overloaded.&lt;/strong&gt; A flood of applications has come their way, and they simply don’t have enough operational capacity to process all of these in a timely manner. This problem will be only exacerbated by the need for more people to work from home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The best thing you can do is get pre-approved now so you’re prepared to take advantage when rates drop again.%20http://localhost:4000/whats-going-on-with-mortgage-rates.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The best thing you can do is get pre-approved now so you’re prepared to take advantage when rates drop again.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An artificial rate hike allows lenders to curb the volume of refinances&lt;/strong&gt; (if a sizable chunk of existing mortgages was paid off through refinance, lenders would see less in profits). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s a lot of uncertainty, but we’re likely looking at low or negative growth in our economy over the next six months,&lt;/strong&gt; which supports the theory that, without any underlying inflation, mortgage rates should remain stable and low. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you missed the wave of low rates, you’re more than likely to have a second chance. When everything settles down, and once the banks have a chance to process their loans, we’ll probably see another dip in the rates. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing you can do is get pre-approved now so you’re prepared to take advantage when rates drop again. As always, reach out if you have any questions on this or other real estate topics. I hope you stay safe, and I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-going-on-with-mortgage-rates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-going-on-with-mortgage-rates.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Did the Kauai Real Estate Market Perform in 2019 &amp; What's Ahead?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J9mSjk6tvtc/?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SALES STATS 2ND HALF OF 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://margolisteamblog.com/first-quarter-kauai-market-update.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;As we mentioned in our market updates at the beginning of last year&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; we anticipated a slowdown in sales of single family homes at the mid-to-lower price points. We anticipated, like with most of the nation, that the lack of inventory would keep prices strong. We anticipated that the luxury space (above $1M) inventory would continue to grow, with more sellers than buyers, and sellers needing to become more flexible to get their properties sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slowdown did not really materialize as low interest rates, low supply, and high demand sustained throughout 2019, helping to keep the market strong in the mid-range of the market. The high-end of the market did, however, lose some of its velocity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales of homes on Kauai were down 3.01% from 598 units sold in 2018 to 580 units sold last year. Sales in the Kapaa-Wailua areas, however, were up 6.74% and in Lihue (the closest thing we have to an urban town-core area) sales were up 12.74%. But in the Hanalei District (Princeville, Hanalei and beyond) sales of single-family homes were down a whopping 21.97%, from 132 sales in 2018 to 103 sales in 2019. Princeville is often the area of highest appreciation when the market is rising. Has the market topped in Princeville? Or did the devastation from the 2018 floods have an effect on the North Shore in general? My notion is that both contributed to the reduction in sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slowdown in condo sales were more pronounced with a 15.8% drop from a total of 481 condos sold in 2018 to 405 condos sold in 2019. Sales of condos were down in the Lihue, Kapaa and Princeville areas. In Poipu however, the number of condos sold was almost identical, 149 in 2018 to 148 in 2019. The main reason: the Pili Mai project by the Kiahuna Golf course is almost sold out. Many units which had been pending for a year, were completed and the sales closed. In fact, because the project is now sold out, we are starting to see resales of units for 10-15% above their original costs in 2018 and 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INVENTORY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This inventory graph shows the number of active listings in the main categories (we are not including businesses or commercial) and we have continued to hover under 700 listings for most of the last year. September was the month with the lowest inventory for 2019,  &lt;strong&gt;January 2020 shows an inventory slightly up from 2019 January levels.&lt;/strong&gt; Active inventory in February shows only 618 properties island wide with 217 listings under contract after the first week in February&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SALES PRICES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Real estate statistics are a great way to take the pulse of a particular market but knowing what the number you are looking at represents can sometimes be confusing. There are two main stats regarding selling price. They are  Average and Median prices. Average and median are both measures of central tendency, but the average can be skewed by very large or very small observations. The median is basically the point in the middle of all the properties. Literally, &lt;strong&gt;half the properties are less than the median price and half are greater than the median.&lt;/strong&gt; The average is, of course, simply the average. Take 10 sales, add up their volume, divide by 10 and voila, you have the average. People like to know the average price; however, &lt;strong&gt;the median is a better reflection of the market&lt;/strong&gt; because the  median is less likely to be skewed by outliers, like a $24M sale on Hanalei Bay for example. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, that was a mouthful and maybe more than you wanted to know. You can google “average vs. median price real estate” to find other variants of the definition! &lt;strong&gt;The average selling price for a home is down 2.8% from last year.&lt;/strong&gt; The median price is up 14.4% to $715,000. However, of the 277 single-family homes for sale, only 34 of them are priced at median or less. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For condos the average price moved up from $628,573 to $635,007 a modest change of 1% and the median condo price has dropped steadily since peaking in September. Since fall is typically our slower time of year, I can’t yet say this is a trend, especially since the median price is up 3%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAYS ON MARKET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The days on market is the number of days a property has been on the market until close of escrow.&lt;/strong&gt; In many larger markets, San Diego, Silicon Valley, even Honolulu, the days on market have grown indicating a market slowdown. Here on Kauai, that number vacillates from month-to-month but there is no big trend there that we can see. Normal financed sales take 45-60+ days, so on average homes and condos are frequently on the market up to 100 days before they go into escrow. &lt;strong&gt;Listings priced accurately in the area of the market with strong demand helps to bring the days on market down&lt;/strong&gt;. There are plenty of buyers waiting for the right property, and interest rates continue to be low, so if you have ever considered selling your property, it’s a great time to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about real estate in general, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you any way I can. Aloha and a hui hou!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 16:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-did-the-kauai-real-estate-market-perform-in-2019-whats-ahead.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-did-the-kauai-real-estate-market-perform-in-2019-whats-ahead.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy New Year From the Margolis Team!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FkHPJlvScOc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aloha! On behalf of my EXP Realty team on the beautiful Garden Island, I wanted to take the time to say thank you for trusting us with your real estate goals. &lt;strong&gt;We’re grateful for the opportunity to be of service. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team and I work hard so that buying or selling real estate can be easy for you. We do our best to understand what your property needs and wants are. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re always grateful to share our resources with you, whether that connecting you with an electrician, handyman, or a plumber. &lt;strong&gt;If you want to plug into the community and give back through one of our many nonprofits, we know a lot about that and we’d love to share that as well. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=My team and I work hard so that buying or selling real estate can be easy for you.%20http://localhost:4000/happy-new-year-from-the-margolis-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“My team and I work hard so that buying or selling real estate can be easy for you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we move into the new year, I’d like for you to tell me if there’s a specific topic or question you’d like to know more about. Not only will I incorporate it into one of my videos, but we’ll also send you a little gift for your question. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to wish you a safe, healthy, happy and prosperous new year—we’ll see you in 2020! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 2:00 in the video above, you’ll be able to see personalized messages from my team members Bailey Hutton and Gwen Margolis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about real estate in general, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you any way I can. Hauʻoli makahiki hou!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 12:29:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/happy-new-year-from-the-margolis-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/happy-new-year-from-the-margolis-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working to Give Back to the Community of Kauai</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lNF4_Y6QGOM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to helping people with their real estate needs, whether they’re looking to find their perfect island getaway or thinking of moving back to the mainland, I love giving back to our community here in Kauai. It’s a beautiful place filled with wondrous nature and people who embody the Aloha Spirit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the ways I work to give back to the community is through my rotary club. Back in 2006, I joined The Rotary Club of Hanalei Bay. Kauai has five rotary clubs, and if you’re not familiar with what a rotary club is, it’s a community service organization. &lt;strong&gt;Our motto is “Service above self,” and there are several causes we support.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we have an environmental committee that takes on projects like monthly or weekly highway cleanups. Last year, we collected over two tons of trash along the stretch from the Princeville Center down to Anini Beach. We also work with the Hanalei Initiative to reduce the impact of cesspools along the coastal waters that were created by the 2018 floods. Additionally, we’re involved with creating a session on climate change at the 2020 Rotary International Convention in Honolulu. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I love giving back to our community here in Kauai.%20http://localhost:4000/working-to-give-back-to-the-community-of-kauai.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I love giving back to our community here in Kauai.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have a community service section of the club that works with Habitat for Humanity to supply funding and build homes in Anahola. We helped get the Kilauea Community Agricultural Center off the ground, and we’re in the process of designing a new building that will have community gardens that local farmers can use to grow and distribute their food. We’re also raising money to build a building that will house the farmers market and the North Shore Food Pantry. Our Heart of Gold campaign has installed 54 automatic external defibrillators around the island, which can save a person’s life in the event of cardiac arrest. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We also work overseas.&lt;/strong&gt; We helped rebuild a school in Bolivia, for example, and we’re training surgeons in Romania in a pediatric craniofacial surgery clinic. We’re involved in Rotoplast, which provides free cleft palate surgery, and we’re building a clinic to provide post-surgery services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of nonprofits we also support, including elementary and high school mentoring clubs. Kauai has a high youth suicide rate. Studies show that last year, 9% of all Kauai high school students attempted suicide. Our after-school clubs are part of the action plan of the Kauai Resilience Project, which is to provide safe spaces and one-on-one attention in a mentoring environment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Junior Achievement is another organization for which I serve on the advisory board. This organization provides financial education for elementary and high school-aged kids. When I think about the work we’re doing, it makes me reflect on my childhood and how I never had this type of education. All these years later, I still don’t see enough widespread quality financial education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like I said, I (along with my wife) enjoy serving in these organizations and to giving back to the community.&lt;/strong&gt; We also go the extra mile for our real estate clients. I’d love to hear about the organizations you’re involved with in your community, so don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email if you want to talk more about giving back. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any real estate questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me as well. I wish you and your family a happy holiday season. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 13:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/working-to-give-back-to-the-community-of-kauai.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/working-to-give-back-to-the-community-of-kauai.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Update on the Kauai Market from July to October 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wkLq3S1kPmU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conditions in our market are continuing the same as they’ve been most of the year, though the volume of transactions was a mixed bag over the last four months as compared to 2018. For example, in July of this year, more homes and condos sold island-wide over last year. In August, more homes sold, but fewer condos left the market. In September, fewer homes and condos sold. In October, more of both sold. To me, that’s an indication that the market remains stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some associates of mine in Silicon Valley have told me that prices have gone down significantly. Surprisingly, &lt;strong&gt;that’s not the trend here on Kauai.&lt;/strong&gt; Why is that? It goes back to the low levels of inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 2019, the number of single-family homes is down by 4% over last year, and the number of condo sales is down by 18%. As of the recording of this video, there are 606 active listings. In terms of our inventory mix, &lt;strong&gt;this is pretty typical of what goes on in the nation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For homes in the resort markets, like Princeville on the North Shore, there are currently two homes listed for sale for under $1 million, and they sell at a rate of two per month. This shows us that we basically have one month of inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, there are 16 homes that are priced between $1 million and $2 million in the Princeville market, and they sell at a rate of one per month. That means if nothing else came on the market, it would take 16 months to sell all our inventory. Clearly, that segment of the market is slower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The bottom line is that the market remains in a stable condition.%20http://localhost:4000/an-update-on-the-kauai-market-from-july-to-october-2019.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The bottom line is that the market remains in a stable condition.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Lihue, there’s only a total of six homes under the $2 million price point for sale and seven in escrow, meaning there’s still a shortage of inventory. For people who want a quality home starting around, say, the $700,000 price point, there really isn’t much to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest rates are still low.&lt;/strong&gt; At the end of October this year, the Fed decided to drop the rates again, but according to one of my associates at Wells Fargo Private Banking, Wells Fargo predicts that rates will stay the same in 2020. As of now, the rate for a 30-year fixed mortgage for a primary residence in Kauai is 3.875%. For a 10-year ARM, the rate is 3.625%. Jumbo rates are still lower than conforming rates, hovering around 3.5% for a 30-year fixed mortgage and 3% on a 10-year adjustable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that the market remains in a stable condition. &lt;strong&gt;Buyers can get deals depending on the negotiation skills of their agent&lt;/strong&gt; and the motivations of the seller to give good value to the buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sellers, there’s not a lot of inventory, meaning you’ll have reduced competition, but appreciation has lowered. &lt;strong&gt;If you want to sell quickly, you’ve got to have the best price for your particular property’s style.&lt;/strong&gt; The longer you stay on the market, the more buyers will think that something is wrong with your listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the markets from Waimea and Kekaha all the way to Hanalei, reach out to me. I’d be happy to provide you with specifics from your area. Aloha and a hui hou!&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 11:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-update-on-the-kauai-market-from-july-to-october-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/an-update-on-the-kauai-market-from-july-to-october-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Discussing the Barriers Concerning Kauai Housing Affordability</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/n2EHd5RS3MI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here on Kauai, we currently have just over 31,000 housing units, and 63% of them are owner-occupied, meaning 38% of our homeowners are from the mainland (1% are owned by foreign investors). While Kauai homeowners who live on the mainland account for 35% of the housing, many of them vacation rental properties, the mainland owners account for 50% of the dollar value of the homes.  65% of Kauai’s housing is owned by Kauai residents which accounts for 49% of the home values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The population of Kauai has increased from 67,000 in 2010 to 72,000 according to last year’s census. Interestingly enough, according to Paul Brubaker from EZ Economics, &lt;strong&gt;our current domestic migration is negative&lt;/strong&gt;; that means we have more people leaving the island than we have coming in. Housing affordability is a key part of that trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back around the time of recession that started in 2007 and 2008, we had over $300 million in permits issued for housing each year before it sunk in 2010. Since then, the number of homes being built has only come back gradually. To give you an idea of the chasm, it’s projected that by 2035 that Kauai will need 9,000 more housing units. And yet, from 2015 to 2019, there were only 994 building permits issued. The projected demand of housing is that we will need another 4,400 housing unit by 2025. You can see how large the gap is between what is needed and the run rate of what is being built!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, &lt;strong&gt;Kauai’s housing sector has a lot of challenges to face.&lt;/strong&gt; One of those challenges is infrastructure; things like water, wastewater systems, road improvements to alleviate traffic. One interesting thing I learned at the seminar was how cars and traffic have nothing to do with housing units. In fact, since the 50s, the number of cars on the island has tripled, so the idea that we shouldn’t build more housing because it will make more traffic is one made in error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s projected by 2035 that Kauai will need 9,000 more housing units.%20http://localhost:4000/discussing-the-barriers-concerning-kauai-housing-affordability.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s projected by 2035 that Kauai will need 9,000 more housing units.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re thinking about buying property on the island of Kauai, it’ll come as no surprise that, because of building costs, most of the properties currently available couldn’t be rebuilt for the price they’re selling for. Over time, labor costs and material costs will increase because most everything comes from the mainland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve said  before, &lt;strong&gt;we’re starting to see a deceleration in our home value appreciation.&lt;/strong&gt; Though the market isn’t likely to crash anytime soon, the demand and the costs are such that the house appreciation that we experienced since 2015 has leveled out. Of course, the 2020 presidential election and all the talk of recession probably aren’t helping things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Habitat For Humanity did bring a bright note to the conference: The Kauai chapter actually builds more homes per year than all the other chapters around the state. &lt;strong&gt;They’ve figured out a way to build and deliver a home for $270,000!&lt;/strong&gt; Now, costs are kept down because the families that build with Habitat For Humanity have to put in a lot of sweat equity, but still—in a place where the median price of housing is over $600,000, to have a home for $270,000 is really a remarkable achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the summit thinking that maybe the county should hire Habitat For Humanity to make better inroads in our affordability crisis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about housing affordability or insights or thoughts about solving our challenges, reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you. Perhaps your community has found solutions that could be used on Kauai?  Mahalo Nui Loa and Aloha from Kauai!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 15:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/discussing-the-barriers-concerning-kauai-housing-affordability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/discussing-the-barriers-concerning-kauai-housing-affordability.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Midyear Snapshot of Our 2019 Kauai Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nwLeUXEjyzY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’re past the midway point of 2019, it’s time to assess the state of our Kauai market by looking at some of the latest year-to-date statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve said previously, our market—like many markets throughout the US—has slowed down just a little bit, and prices have leveled off as well. &lt;strong&gt;Island-wide, sales are down 10.7%, and the volume of those sales decreased by 24% from $612 million to $463 million. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The median sale price of single-family homes, meanwhile, dropped 12% from $732,000 to $642,000. Because this statistic represents the middle of the market, though, it can be influenced by a small number of transactions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we delve further into the latest numbers, we see more revealing data. Market prices have been rising since 2014, and right now we have a lot of properties listed at or near the top of the market. There’s still robust activity going on, but that’s not the case in the luxury markets. In the North Shore, for example, sales are down 32%, and the volume of those sales dropped 65%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve mentioned before, this could be because there weren’t enough multi-million dollar home sales during the first six months of the year. In general, though, because prices are highest in the North Shore and appreciate the most, it’s normal for conditions to stagnate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our market—like many markets throughout the US—has slowed down just a little bit, and prices have leveled off as well.%20http://localhost:4000/a-midyear-snapshot-of-our-2019-kauai-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our market—like many markets throughout the US—has slowed down just a little bit, and prices have leveled off as well.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a seller, it’s still a good time to get your property sold,&lt;/strong&gt; but a global event like a trade war with China will have an immediate impact on our market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the more affordable areas of our market, such as the east side of the island, year-to-date sales are up 13.25%, the volume of those sales is up 24%. This is where more affordable homes are located, so there will naturally be more transactions. Demand is still strong, and prices are still inching upward. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of active listings has remained fairly consistent. As of the recording of this video, there are 644 homes on the market and 235 properties under contract. A significant number of properties under contract come from two specific projects: the PiliMai luxury air-conditioned townhomes in Poipu (38) and Ho’oluana development by DR Horton (13).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about any of these statistics or the future of our Kauai market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 10:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-midyear-snapshot-of-our-2019-kauai-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-midyear-snapshot-of-our-2019-kauai-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Road to Ke'e Beach is NOW OPEN! Here's How the Hanalei Initiative is Helping Kauai Recover!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Au1AgwVMmF0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that many of you are interested to learn more about how last year’s flooding has continued to impact the north shore of Kauai, so I recently sat down with a special guest to discuss this topic exactly. This guest, Joel Guy, is a long-time North Shore resident, as well as the newly appointed executive director of the Hanalei Initiative—a nonprofit organization whose goal is to help the North Shore to recover and move forward with improved sustainability practices following the flood. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;00:13 - An introduction to today’s video &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;01:40 - Joel explains the recovery process of the North Shore and where things stand today&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;08:40 - How residents of Kauai have responded to the recovery plan put in place by the Hanalei Initiative&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:32 - What to do if you plan to travel to Kauai &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15:20 - A few closing words about traveling to the North Shore&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 13:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-road-to-kee-beach-is-now-open-heres-how-the-hanalei-initiative-is-helping-kauai-recover.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-road-to-kee-beach-is-now-open-heres-how-the-hanalei-initiative-is-helping-kauai-recover.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Homebuyer Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/crF4A3b-eyA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the market for a new home, today we’ll be going over five tips you should keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know your budget.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important to understand how much you can afford. If you’re going to be getting a mortgage, make sure to get a pre-approval—this will help you see exactly what you’re qualified to buy and will also strengthen your offer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be prepared to write a letter.&lt;/strong&gt; Tell the seller about you and your family’s situation, why you want the property, how great the property is, and so on. Forming an emotional connection with the seller can help your offer get accepted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Separate your needs and your wants.&lt;/strong&gt; Since there is a low amount of inventory currently on the market, it’s unlikely that you’ll find exactly what you want. You’ll have to make some tradeoffs, so focus primarily on what your needs are instead of your wants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bid competitively with minimum contingencies.&lt;/strong&gt; When a good property comes on the market, it’s going to sell very quickly. Make sure your offer stands out (in a good way).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be able to make a quick decision.&lt;/strong&gt; As mentioned, things get competitive. If you have everything lined up and the perfect home goes on sale, jump on it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 14:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-homebuyer-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-homebuyer-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Quarter Kauai Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/w_1YMmudS7k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’ve got a quick market update for you today that covers the first quarter of 2019 here on the garden island. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sales have slowed so far this year and the market is continuing to level off.&lt;/strong&gt; When we go on the MLS and look at the list-to-sale price ratio, there are a few more discounts happening these days. Homes are selling a percentage point or two lower than they were, which is further indicative of the slowdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the curious things that we’re going to need to keep a closer eye on is our volume.&lt;/strong&gt; The decrease in the number of transactions is somewhat related to our limited inventory. I keep waiting to see that inventory grow, but it just hasn’t happened yet. There are only 268 homes for sale on Kauai, along with 210 condos and 171 parcels of land. That gives us a total of 649 listings. That’s a pretty low figure for our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ll continue to keep an eye on the market for you.%20http://localhost:4000/first-quarter-kauai-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ll continue to keep an eye on the market for you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I’ve noticed is that the number of home sales is down by 58% from last year. &lt;strong&gt;The dollar volume of those sold homes is down a whopping 70% from last year.&lt;/strong&gt; This is all the proof I need that the market is slowing down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This slowdown could be a good thing for some. It might give buyers more motivation to be flexible when making offers.  Another big benefit for buyers right now is interest rates. Mortgage interest rates are right around 4.28% for a conforming loan here in Hawaii. Jumbo loan rates are even lower. This is all good news for buyers, although the limited inventory might make things a little more tricky in the interim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that the median price is up, the volume is way down, and we’ll continue to keep an eye on market prices for you as they change. &lt;strong&gt;Whether you’re in the market to buy or sell, we’ll help get the right information out to you so that you can make an informed decision.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the real estate market or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 09:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/first-quarter-kauai-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/first-quarter-kauai-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
