<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Zach Sikes - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 13:00:14 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 13:00:14 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Know a Good Fit for Our Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YaILvfLqrWM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wouldn’t be where we are today without your support for our team over the years. As a result, we’ve continued to grow, and now we need to grow our staff and were hoping you could help out. If you or someone you know is humble, hungry, smart, and interested in starting a career in real estate, we’d love to hear from you. Our goal is to staff up as quickly as possible, so reach out as soon as possible. To learn more about this opportunity, watch this short video above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 10:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/do-you-know-a-good-fit-for-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/do-you-know-a-good-fit-for-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Have You Heard Our Big Announcement?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K9h_wcl7q1U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s announcement is fantastic news for homebuyers.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am excited to announce the launch of House and Home Mortgage, our in-house mortgage brokerage at Homestead &amp;amp; Co. We’ve heard your complaints about the home buying process being too cumbersome and complicated by too many price fluctuations, and we’re here to address them. We’ve partnered with proven industry leaders and experienced loan officers, and backed it all up by industry-leading investors. This will allow us to give you a much smoother transaction process when buying a home. To learn more about this exciting new development, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 09:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-have-you-heard-our-big-announcement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-have-you-heard-our-big-announcement.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Happens If You Get a Low Appraisal?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jdlBUm0oAnM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;If the appraisal comes in low, you have four options as a buyer or seller.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low appraisals are happening more frequently this year because low inventory is putting upward pressure on pricing. In most residential single-family unit sales, they’re basing pricing on comparable sales data, otherwise known as comps. The comps they’re using have already closed, so it’s historical data. As inventory is lowered and prices increase, the data is months old, so it isn’t justifying the higher price. The appraisers will keep up with the market but only at a conservative rate, which could lead to appraisal shortfalls, or low appraisals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have four options if you receive a low appraisal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Either party can walk away.&lt;/strong&gt; The earnest money can return to the buyer, and no deal happens. That’s always an option in an Oklahoma real estate commission contract. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The buyer can bring cash to cover the difference.&lt;/strong&gt; If they’re putting 20% or more down, it may not even affect their loan amount to cover the distance between the appraisal and purchase price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The seller can lower the price to the appraised value.&lt;/strong&gt; This generally happens when the buyer doesn’t have enough cash to cover the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The buyer and seller can meet in the middle.&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe the buyer only has a few thousand extra dollars, so the seller can come down some of the way. You can bridge the gap to get the deal done. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issues like this can always arise, which is why we always recommend you work with an experienced, educated real estate agent to guide you through the process, whether you’re a buyer or seller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We always recommend you work with an experienced, educated real estate agent.%20http://localhost:4000/q-what-happens-if-you-get-a-low-appraisal.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We always recommend you work with an experienced, educated real estate agent.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have further questions about low appraisals or anything else concerning real estate, reach out via phone or email today. I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 11:47:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-happens-if-you-get-a-low-appraisal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-what-happens-if-you-get-a-low-appraisal.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Do You Win Out in a Multiple-Offer Situation?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rE3jK7gQmU8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Speed and strength are what make a winning offer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of right now, we have just 1.5 months of inventory in our Oklahoma City metro market, which is incredibly low. If no new homes came onto the market, it would take just a month and a half to sell off all homes across all price points. Since six months of inventory is considered a balanced market, we’re in a very strong seller’s market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means many properties are fetching multiple offers and prices are being pushed upward. If you’re a buyer, there are two keys to remember to compete in a multiple-offer situation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Speed.&lt;/strong&gt; Submit your offer as quickly as possible—I recommend doing it the very same day the home goes on the market. We always advise sellers that their first offer is usually their best, so the quicker you turn your offer in, the better your chance of having it accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Strength.&lt;/strong&gt; When it comes to strength, there are four areas to focus on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Price: The higher the price, the more likely the seller will pick your offer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Closing costs: Are you paying your own or asking the seller to pay some of them? With so much pressure on pricing, there’s a higher likelihood that some appraisals will come in low. If you’re asking the seller to pay some closing costs in this situation, your offer becomes less attractive. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Earnest money: Purchase contracts in Oklahoma are very favorable in terms of buyer protection, meaning you can put down more earnest money and still be protected. It won’t cost you any more to show the buyer you’re serious. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flexibility: If you use a good agent, they’ll chat with the listing agent to find out if there’s anything your party can do to tailor the contract to the seller’s needs. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Many properties are fetching multiple offers and prices are being pushed upward.%20http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-you-win-out-in-a-multiple-offer-situation.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Many properties are fetching multiple offers and prices are being pushed upward.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus tip: Cover appraisal shortgages.&lt;/strong&gt; When prices are being pushed upward, sellers can get concerned that their home’s appraisal will come in low in a financed deal. If you want to make your offer more attractive, offer to cover appraisal shortages up to a certain amount. For example, if a house is agreed to be sold for $300,000 but only appraises for $290,000, the buyer can typically back out of the deal unless the seller agrees to drop the price to the appraised amount. If you really want to win the home, though, you can tell the seller that you’ll cover any appraisal difference as long as it doesn’t exceed $10,000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 15:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-you-win-out-in-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-you-win-out-in-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Difference Between Appraisals and Inspections?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jADEU0IRjJg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m explaining the difference between appraisals and inspections.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When purchasing a home, everyone’s told to get an inspection and appraisal. However, some mistakenly think they’re the same thing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anytime you’re financing a property, your bank will hire an appraiser.&lt;/strong&gt; The bank you receive a loan from will use your home as collateral, and an appraisal provides proof of your property’s value. Some types of loans such as FHA, VA, and sometimes USDA have rigid requirements regarding the home’s condition, so any issues found by an appraiser must be fixed. If an appraiser says, for example, that three particular things need to be repaired, those fixes are mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Appraisers look for value, inspectors look for condition.%20http://localhost:4000/whats-the-difference-between-appraisals-and-inspections.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Appraisers look for value, inspectors look for condition.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An inspection is a little different. An inspector will do a more thorough examination of the house than an appraiser. &lt;strong&gt;Issues found by an inspector are only recommendations&lt;/strong&gt; and are completely negotiable between the buyer and seller. These may include a leaking roof, unsafe wiring, broken A/C, and more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: Appraisers look for value, inspectors look for condition. This is why it’s critical to have an agent in your corner to explain and help you through everything in a real estate transaction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you need a real estate agent, give us a call or send an email. Also, contact us if you have any questions about real estate. We would love to help with whatever you need.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-the-difference-between-appraisals-and-inspections.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-the-difference-between-appraisals-and-inspections.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are Home Buying Conditions Like?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i6X4gKCB3fg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;If you want to move this summer, you need to start now. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer’s here, but what does that mean for real estate? For those of you with kids out of school for the summer and want to move into a new school district, now is the time to look at buying. In the best-case scenario, the home purchase process is going to take at least 30 days. It’s time to get a plan in place to make sure you’re in your new home by fall, and the new school year begins. To learn more about how we can help, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 09:04:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-home-buying-conditions-like.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-are-home-buying-conditions-like.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Worked With Us in 2020?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wd8_SgChBfk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;We want to say a big thank-you to all our clients and agents in 2020.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we wanted to reach out and say a huge thank-you. First, thank you to our customers and clients who trusted us with their real estate needs in 2020. &lt;strong&gt;We’ve been able to help a record number of families throughout the first half of the year.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn’t have done this without our excellent agent partners. We’re continuing to bring on more agent partners to help even more families. We have nothing but gratitude for all our clients and partners!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope to help you all with your real estate needs in the future. If you ever have any questions, feel free to reach out via phone or email. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 13:52:55 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/have-you-worked-with-us-in-2020.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/have-you-worked-with-us-in-2020.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Key Stipulation Regarding Mortgage Forbearances</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JgtQy_0OHUQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;If you can still make your mortgage payments, we recommend not taking on a forbearance. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forbearance—it’s a buzzword that’s become ubiquitous among homeowners ever since the coronavirus pandemic hit. A forbearance is the ability to defer your mortgage payments if you encounter financial hardship. This is of great assistance to those who truly can’t pay their mortgage, but if you still can, we recommend &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; taking on a forbearance. To find out why, watch the short video above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 12:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-key-stipulation-regarding-mortgage-forbearances.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-key-stipulation-regarding-mortgage-forbearances.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Update on the Edmond Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U9nLbZYdPR4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;When you want to know how the market is doing, you need to know the price range that you&amp;rsquo;re looking in. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One question I get asked all the time is, “How’s the market?” It’s a really hard question for us to answer because it depends on a number of different factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every price range has a different market.&lt;/strong&gt; When we hear this question, our agents will pull a quick analysis of your particular market, which you can see at 0:37 in the video above. It shows all of the homes in a given price range in a given area, as well as the months of inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, six months is considered a balanced market. Anything less is a seller’s market, and anything more is a buyer’s market. In a seller’s market, prices typically have an upward pressure and in a buyer’s market, there’s downward pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The $100,000 to $200,000 price range in Edmond is a hot market.%20http://localhost:4000/a-quick-update-on-the-edmond-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The $100,000 to $200,000 price range in Edmond is a hot market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, take a look at the Edmond market between $100,000 and $200,000. There were 355 homes sold in the last six months, for an average of around 60 per month. There are only 33 properties on the market right now, so we have just 0.5 months of inventory. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re in the $100,000 to $200,000 price range in Edmond, it’s a fantastic time to enter the market. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s contrast that with what the market is doing in Edmond in the $400,000 to $500,000 market. There have been 150 home sales in the last six months, which means we’re selling around 25 homes per month. With 122 homes active on the market right now, we have just about five months of inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does all of this mean? &lt;strong&gt;You really need an expert on your side who knows the market that you’re in and what it’s doing.&lt;/strong&gt; In the lower price ranges, sellers have the advantage, while it’s more balanced in the higher price ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about the numbers in your area or anything else related to real estate, feel free to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 09:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-quick-update-on-the-edmond-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-quick-update-on-the-edmond-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Difference Between When Mortgages and Rents Are Paid</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YBMm0iWFa6E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;The way you paid mortgages and rents are different. Today we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss this.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know the difference between how mortgages and rents are paid? Here’s a quick overview to refresh your memory:  Rent is paid in advance. For example, if you pay your rent on January 1, that rent applies to the entire month of January. Mortgages are the opposite. Your January mortgage payment won’t be due until February. &lt;strong&gt;This knowledge comes in handy when moving from a place you’re renting to a home you’re buying&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a lease that’s up, for example, on June 30, we can shoot for a target closing date on your new house somewhere in the middle of June, so let’s say June 15. This gives you two weeks to move out of your current residence and into your new property, and time to get your rental into a condition in which to get your deposit back. If you close on June 15, your first payment won’t actually be due until August 1. You will pay interest for the month of June, then the July payment isn’t due until August 1. This is invaluable when working with moving costs and ensuring you aren’t making double payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about how this may work for your situation or real estate in general, please give us a call or send us an email. We would love to help you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 09:39:24 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-difference-between-when-mortgages-and-rents-are-paid.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-difference-between-when-mortgages-and-rents-are-paid.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
