<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Syracuse Real Estate Journal</title>
    <description>Our mission at Chip Hodgkins Team of Hunt Real Estate is to be your best resource for  real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Chip Hodgkins Team of Hunt Real Estate, your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 13:03:11 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 13:03:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Things You Need to Know About Staging a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7Qnk2txi0y4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home staging is an underrated way to boost your home’s sale price.
Here’s how our friend and favorite home stager, Lorrie White, does her magic on homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Selling your Central New York home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a Central New York home?  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/results-gallery/?userID=all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was delighted to be joined recently by Lorrie White of Lorrie White Staging Company, aka “The Secret Weapon” to talk about what she does and to see her work in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re at one of Coldwell Banker Properties 6797 Dutch Hill Road. in Dewitt, NY.&lt;/strong&gt; This house has been on the market for a little while, and the owners have had Lorrie come in to stage the entire house. &lt;strong&gt;Watch the video above to get the full home tour after Lorrie and her team did their magic.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that according to the National Association of Realtors, 80% of homes that are professionally staged and professionally photographed will sell quicker and for more money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Lorrie, &lt;strong&gt;these are the top three things people need to know about staging a house:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Staging is affordable.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people are under the impression that staging is too expensive or not worth the money. It’s important to know that there are many different variations of staging. Lorrie is always willing to work with budgets, and &lt;strong&gt;some home staging is better than no staging at all.&lt;/strong&gt; Even just working with a few key first-impression spaces can make a drastic difference in the presentation of the home during staging. Lorrie’s consultations typically take anywhere from one to two hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=80% OF HOMES THAT ARE PROFESSIONALLY STAGED AND PROFESSIONALLY PHOTOGRAPHED WILL SELL QUICKER AND FOR MORE MONEY, ACCORDING TO THE NAR.%20http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-why-home-staging-works.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“80% OF HOMES THAT ARE PROFESSIONALLY STAGED AND PROFESSIONALLY PHOTOGRAPHED WILL SELL QUICKER AND FOR MORE MONEY, ACCORDING TO THE NAR.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Staging is not the same as decorating.&lt;/strong&gt; Even the best-decorated home can sit stagnant on the market for a number of reasons. They may be a little too taste-specific or individualistic. Decorating is more of a personal thing for everyday living. &lt;strong&gt;Staging is done for marketing purposes&lt;/strong&gt; to help a product appeal to the most number of buyers possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Square footage sells.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s extremely important to your home’s value. Certain things in a space can make a home feel smaller (i.e. large area rugs, dark paint colors, and too much furniture). It’s all about opening up your home, which Lorrie did wonderfully as you can see above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Lorrie or want to get in touch with her to see how she can help expedite your home sale, visit her &lt;a href=&quot;https://stageitwithlorrie.shutterfly.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, follow her on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/happyhomestager/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, or give her a call at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:315-420-9291&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the meantime about home staging, the market, or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 12:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-why-home-staging-works.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-why-home-staging-works.html</guid>
        
        <category>Central New York Real Estate Agent</category>
        
        <category>Central New York Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Chip Hodgkins Team Has Barbara Corcorans Seal of Approval </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cng9g4U_kL0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re proud to announce that our team is endorsed by none other than Barbara Corcoran, one of the most respected names in real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Selling your Central New York home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a Central New York home?  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/results-gallery/?userID=all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s only team Barbara Corcoran trusts to sell her home in our marketplace, which is why she endorses the The Chip Hodgkins Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She recognizes our proven success, because the numbers don’t lie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We attract full-price offers every day due to our extensive marketing, and we guarantee that if we don’t sell your home, we’ll buy it ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=CHIP ATTRACTS MORE BUYERS IN ONE DAY THAN MOST AGENTS ATTRACT ALL YEAR. - BARBARA CORCORAN%20http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-why-barbara-corcoran-recommends-us.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“CHIP ATTRACTS MORE BUYERS IN ONE DAY THAN MOST AGENTS ATTRACT ALL YEAR. - BARBARA CORCORAN”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about our guarantee program and how we attract so many buyers, visit SyracuseHomeLink.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To hear Barbara’s full endorsement, watch the video above. If you have any other questions or you’re looking to get your home sold, don’t hesitate to call or email us. We’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 16:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-why-barbara-corcoran-recommends-us.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-why-barbara-corcoran-recommends-us.html</guid>
        
        <category>Central New York Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Thing You Must Do Now If You Are Going to Sell Your House in the Spring  </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jFEmOhqDfLM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re selling your home next spring,
you need to take pictures of your home now before it’s too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Selling your Central New York home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a Central New York home?  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/results-gallery/?userID=all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of selling your home sometime in the spring, you’ve got to go out and take pictures of it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall is coming, and soon the foliage will be gone. Right now, your home looks better than it will in March. When the time comes to put it on the market, you’ll have a whole catalog of beautiful pictures ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DON’T DELAY ANY LONGER.%20http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-you-must-do-this-as-soon-as-possible.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DON’T DELAY ANY LONGER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You only have a week or two at best to get this done, so don’t delay any longer!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about taking listing photos or would like to enlist the services of a professional photographer, don’t hesitate to get in touch with me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 12:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-you-must-do-this-as-soon-as-possible.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-you-must-do-this-as-soon-as-possible.html</guid>
        
        <category>Central New York Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meat Paradise in Manlius at Sidehill Farmers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EltiHWgvW40?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for a good butcher in central New York?
Look no further than Sidehill Farmers right here in Manlius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Selling your Central New York home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a Central New York home?  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/results-gallery/?userID=all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to introduce you to another great local business calling Manlius home. This time, we’re with Greg Rhoad of Sidehill Farmers. I’ve been a big fan of theirs for a while now. This is easily one of the best butcher shops in central New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidehill Farmers has been in Manlius for three years now. Their mission is to bring local products from local farmers to local consumers in Manlius, Syracuse, and surrounding areas. &lt;strong&gt;They are a real farm-to-table business, representing over 60 farmers around the area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ve got pasture-raised beef, pork, lamb, chicken, and more. All their meats are hormone and antibiotic free as well. People come from all over central New York for a cut, or just for a bite at the sandwich shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU CAN COME IN AND GET A QUICK BITE, A HOLIDAY ROAST, OR ANYTHING IN BETWEEN.%20http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-the-best-place-to-get-meat-in-manlius.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU CAN COME IN AND GET A QUICK BITE, A HOLIDAY ROAST, OR ANYTHING IN BETWEEN.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidehill Farmers is a whole-animal butchery, meaning they utilize every part of the animal from snout to tail. &lt;strong&gt;They also take pride in their ability to provide any and every customer with the proper education about the meat they are buying and how they should prepare it.&lt;/strong&gt;  You can come in and get a quick bite, a holiday roast, or anything in between. Whenever you need meat, go head over to Sidehill Farmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for them, you can give them a call at (315) 682-MEAT(6328) or visit their website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sidehillfarmers.com/contact-us/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any other questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out anytime. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 14:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-the-best-place-to-get-meat-in-manlius.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-the-best-place-to-get-meat-in-manlius.html</guid>
        
        <category>Meat Paradise</category>
        
        <category>Manlius</category>
        
        <category>Sidehill Farmers</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Great Place to Enjoy a Craft Beer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iR_e-F48oKE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Great Place to Enjoy a Craft Beer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re itching to sit down and enjoy a nice craft beer, I recommend you check out All Who Wander.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Selling your Central New York home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a Central New York home?  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/results-gallery/?userID=all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If craft beer and good company is your idea of a good night on the town, you’ll like today’s local business spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m talking about All Who Wander, a craft beer bar and grill at 315 Fayette St. According to co-owners Dan Chapman and Joe Ori, the name “All Who Wander” speaks to the experience of finding your place to enjoy a nice craft beverage, a grilled cheese sandwich, and having a nice social experience. For them, it’s as simple as taking the products that they love and sharing them with their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of products, &lt;strong&gt;they not only have wine and many regional beers on tap, but also on-tap nitro coffee.&lt;/strong&gt; If you haven’t heard of this new trend, nitro coffee is cold-brew coffee infused with nitrogen so it pours out of a tap just like a Guinness would. It adds a silky, smooth flavor that’s nothing short of delicious on a warm day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DAN AND JOE CONSIDER IT AN IMPORTANT PART OF THEIR JOB TO REPRESENT BEER ITSELF.%20http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agentaround-town-around-town-at-all-who-wander.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DAN AND JOE CONSIDER IT AN IMPORTANT PART OF THEIR JOB TO REPRESENT BEER ITSELF.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All of the craft beers they serve are hand-selected by Dan and Joe.&lt;/strong&gt; They consider it a very important part of their job to represent the beer itself and share with people the way certain beers are supposed to taste. Furthermore, the history and story of the beer brings more to the drinking experience (I call this “knowledge-based drinking”). One of the fulfilling things about their work is sharing stories back and forth with their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To know more about All Who Wander, you can visit them online at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wanderhere.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.wanderhere.com&lt;/a&gt; or send them an email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:letstalk@wanderhere.com&quot;&gt;letstalk@wanderhere.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 14:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agentaround-town-around-town-at-all-who-wander.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agentaround-town-around-town-at-all-who-wander.html</guid>
        
        <category>Central New York Community Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing the Hottest New Barbershop in Town </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mlTNXRC5PDU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving Face Barbershop is a versatile and high-end barber shop that I highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Selling your Central New York home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a Central New York home?  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/results-gallery/?userID=all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in need of a quality shave or haircut, I have the perfect place to introduce you to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That place is &lt;strong&gt;Saving Face Barbershop,&lt;/strong&gt; where I’m live on location speaking with barber and co-owner Taylor Horseman. Located at 127 East Seneca St., Saving Face has been in business at this new location for about four months. They also have another location in Camillus that’s been open for seven years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Taylor, what makes &lt;strong&gt;their establishment different is that their employees have been at their jobs for a long time and have a passion for what they do.&lt;/strong&gt; Cutting hair is more of an art than a job to them. With the communal atmosphere they present, they intend Saving Face to be a place where men can hang out and build friendships in addition to getting a haircut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=AT SAVING FACE BARBERSHOP, CUTTING HAIR IS MORE OF AN ART THAN A JOB.%20http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“AT SAVING FACE BARBERSHOP, CUTTING HAIR IS MORE OF AN ART THAN A JOB.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you wait for a haircut, you can watch TV, play shuffleboard, or pour yourself a nice cup of coffee. They like to be versatile and able to accommodate any customer, so they perform many different types of cuts, including straight-razor shaves and full facial treatments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Saving Face Barbershop or to schedule an appointment, you can visit them online at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.savingfacebarbershop.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.savingfacebarbershop.com&lt;/a&gt; or email them at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:savingfacemanlius@gmail.com&quot;&gt;savingfacemanlius@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend that you visit this location in the near future. It’s great for Manlius, and I look forward to featuring more local businesses in the near future. If you have any other questions, give me a call. I look forward to talking to you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 13:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nassau County Real Estate Other</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Supporting the Caregivers through David's Refuge</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UOlWPsx9GA8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to be donating an amount equal to 12% of all our commissions from buyers and sellers who do a transaction with us in April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Selling your Central New York home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/sell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a free home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buying a Central New York home?  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodgkinshomes.com/results-gallery/?userID=all&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team is not only dedicated to our clients, we’re also dedicated to our community and we are always looking for ways to improve it and the lives of those who share it with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we are here today with Kate Houck of David’s Refuge. This nonprofit is all about caring for the caregivers. They are able to serve parents who have a child with special needs or a life-threatening illness with their support. &lt;strong&gt;They send the families on beautiful two-night getaways in order to refresh them, show appreciation for them, and remind them they are not alone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE COULDN’T BE MORE HAPPY TO SUPPORT DAVID’S REFUGE%20http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-we.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE COULDN’T BE MORE HAPPY TO SUPPORT DAVID’S REFUGE”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn’t be more happy to participate in a worthwhile cause like this. In the month of April, we are donating an amount equal to 12% of our commissions to David’s Refuge. The more people we are able to help buy and sell homes, the more families we’ll be able to help. We are aiming to help 60 different families in the next year with the help of David’s Refuge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about David’s Refuge, visit their website here. If you have any other questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 12:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-we.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://syracuserealestatejournal.com/central-new-york-real-estate-agent-we.html</guid>
        
        <category>Central New York Special Event</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
