<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dallas Mortgage Lender – The Betz Team</title>
    <description>The Betz Team are your local Dallas mortgage lenders. There’s more to a mortgage than the close. Request your consultation today.</description>
    <link>http://winningwithwade.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://winningwithwade.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 11:27:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 11:27:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How You Can Protest Your Property Taxes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OfA2E_7jlsY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year during the month of April, homeowners receive a letter from the appraisal district notifying them of their home’s current assessed value. This assessed value is important because it’s what the county uses to multiply your current tax rate each October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of my clients have been fortunate to have their properties appreciate over the last year, which is great for resale purposes, but not so great for property tax purposes. Many of my other clients, then, have been asking me how they can lower their property tax bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the only ways you can lower your property tax bill is by protesting the assessed value your property taxes, and there are a few ways you can do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first way is by &lt;strong&gt;compiling any comparable data you have, taking that data down to the appraisal district, and protesting your case.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I’d be glad to refer you to a professional who can help you protest your property taxes.%20http://winningwithwade.com/how-you-can-protest-your-property-taxes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I’d be glad to refer you to a professional who can help you protest your property taxes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, not everyone is equipped with the knowledge to do this, so you can also try &lt;strong&gt;hiring a property tax consulting firm.&lt;/strong&gt; They’ll do all the work, and you don’t pay them anything unless they save you money. The downside of doing this, though, is they’ll take anywhere from 30% to 50% of what they save you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, a lot of these firms have assessed value cutoffs where they’ll only accept cases for properties over a certain threshold because of the time it takes to protest these taxes. If using one of these firms isn’t an option for you, &lt;strong&gt;there are some do-it-yourself vendors out there who can provide you with all of the data you need&lt;/strong&gt; for a small nominal fee in exchange for you doing all of the work with the courthouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have contacts in all of these fields, so if you’re interested in working with one of these professionals, I’d be glad to refer you or anyone you know to one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about protesting your property taxes or you have any other mortgage needs I can help you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/how-you-can-protest-your-property-taxes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/how-you-can-protest-your-property-taxes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You May Not Know About Freezing Your Credit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is freezing your credit all about? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a tool that restricts people and companies from accessing your credit report without your specific permission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not the same as a fraud alert. &lt;strong&gt;It does not affect your credit score. You can still request your free credit report once a year. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you can temporarily remove the credit freeze.  Or, you can permanently remove the credit freeze.  And it does not cost you anything to do so. It can be done within minutes of your requesting an “unfreeze” (but double check the time frame with each bureau). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line, it makes it harder for identity thieves to steal your credit and personal information or open new credit in your name. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have listed below the three main credit bureaus to call or go online to learn about it further. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s what they will need from you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Name&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Date of birth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social security number&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other than creditors, here are some other reasons you may need to unfreeze your credit report access:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applying for a new job&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New credit card&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New credit requests you have initiated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utility or cell phone companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a credit freeze is in place, it secures your credit file so nobody can access it unless you give direct authorization to the credit bureaus, usually through a password-protected credit bureau website or PIN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact me if you would like more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equifax:&lt;/strong&gt; Call 800-685-1111 or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freeze.equifax.com/Freeze/jsp/SFF_PersonalIDInfo.jsp&quot;&gt;go online&lt;/a&gt;. Check out a step-by-step &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nerdwallet.com/blog/finance/equifax-credit-freeze/&quot;&gt;Equifax credit freeze&lt;/a&gt; guide.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experian:&lt;/strong&gt; Call 888-397-3742 or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.experian.com/freeze/center.html&quot;&gt;go online&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s a detailed walk-through on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nerdwallet.com/blog/finance/experian-credit-freeze/&quot;&gt;credit freeze with Experian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TransUnion&lt;/strong&gt;: Call 888-909-8872 or &lt;a href=&quot;https://freeze.transunion.com/sf/securityFreeze/landingPage.jsp&quot;&gt;go online&lt;/a&gt;. Read our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nerdwallet.com/blog/finance/transunion-credit-freeze/&quot;&gt;TransUnion credit freeze.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 08:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/what-you-may-not-know-about-freezing-your-credit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/what-you-may-not-know-about-freezing-your-credit.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do Points Mean to Your Mortgage?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C7QV-SJereU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people when they hear the word “points,” they associate it with a higher cost on their loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the reality is one point equals 1% of the loan amount. This means that ​if you are borrowing $100,000, paying one point would increase the closing cost by $1,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet most people don’t realize that points can work in reverse, as well. ​In exchange for you agreeing to a higher interest rate, you can actually receive a lender credit which can go to lowering some of the closing costs. ​This is called premium pricing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not you pay points or get lender credit depends on your particular situation. We can analyze that as part of a cost break-even analysis to determine which one is going to be appropriate for you given your holding period and your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Whether or not you pay points or get lender credit depends on your particular situation.%20http://winningwithwade.com/what-do-points-mean-to-your-mortgage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Whether or not you pay points or get lender credit depends on your particular situation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep in mind, though, that one point equals roughly a .25% difference in interest rate.&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore, if you pay a point, you can expect the interest rate to be about a quarter of a percent lower. If you increase the rate by a point, or if you get a lender credit for a point, you can expect it would be about a quarter of a percent higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want you to think that if you pay a point, your interest rates will be a full percent lower. This is not how it works. &lt;strong&gt;It is just a rule of thumb.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on points, lender credits, and closing costs, please visit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consumerfinance.gov/ask-cfpb/what-are-discount-points-and-lender-credits-and-how-do-they-work-en-136/&quot;&gt;https://www.consumerfinance.gov/ask-cfpb/what-are-discount-points-and-lender-credits-and-how-do-they-work-en-136/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 08:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/what-do-points-mean-to-your-mortgage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/what-do-points-mean-to-your-mortgage.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Escrow Accounts Work</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kXi4s6fQn_o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Escrow accounts are accounts that are set up to fund your property taxes and/or homeowners insurance.&lt;/strong&gt; Every month, you put money into that account so your servicer will have the full amount to pay those bills when they’re due.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the thing, though—we only collect from the escrow account based off of what the previous year’s bill was, and unfortunately, property taxes and homeowners insurance tend to increase over time. This means that &lt;strong&gt;each year, you’ll have a small deficit in your escrow account that you’ll need to cover. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We only collect from the escrow account based off of what the previous year’s bill was.%20http://winningwithwade.com/how-escrow-accounts-work.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We only collect from the escrow account based off of what the previous year’s bill was.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, let’s say your property tax increases $1,200 year over year. You might be thinking that your monthly payment will have to increase by $100 to account for that, and you’d be correct, but what you might not realize is that your escrow account was likely $1,200 short the previous year, so your future payment will have to increase by another $100 to account for that as well. Therefore, a single $1,200 year-over-year increase in your property tax actually equates to a $200 increase in your monthly payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why it’s important that you &lt;strong&gt;partner with a lender who’ll keep the servicing of their loans&lt;/strong&gt;. This way, if you have any questions or any problems arise, you’ll have a single point of contact who can help you. If you work with a lender whose servicing rights get sold over and over again, you’re more likely to get treated as a nameless, faceless customer. We, on the other hand, are committed to being your long-term lender, and we always have your best interests at heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this or any other mortgage-related topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/how-escrow-accounts-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/how-escrow-accounts-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Are Interest Rates Determined?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uqQNY4fZgDk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people don’t seem to understand how interest rates are set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, interest rates track the mortgage-backed securities market. We’ve gotten a lot of comments from clients saying that the 10-year Treasury did this or that, but in actuality, the 10-year Treasury and the mortgage-backed securities market don’t always move in step—&lt;strong&gt;sometimes, one will move in one direction while the other goes a different way&lt;/strong&gt;, leading to occasional discrepancies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The 10-year Treasury and the mortgage-backed securities market don’t always move in step with each other.%20http://winningwithwade.com/how-are-interest-rates-determined.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The 10-year Treasury and the mortgage-backed securities market don’t always move in step with each other.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why &lt;strong&gt;it’s a good idea to talk to a lender,&lt;/strong&gt; so you can learn what the real rates are at any given time. Yes, they do change every single day so make sure that you know what you’re talking about and that you’re not comparing apples to oranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to reach out to my team. We’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 16:54:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/how-are-interest-rates-determined.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/how-are-interest-rates-determined.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Does Mortgage Insurance Help Us?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VvE2SWhqAM8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mortgage insurance has a bad reputation, to be sure. However, the reality is that it is an insurance policy that you, the consumer, pay to benefit us, the lender, in case you default as a borrower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is important because back in the day, banks did not often lend more than an 80% loan-to-value; people once had to put down a very large down payment. &lt;strong&gt;Mortgage insurance came along, and that changed the scene dramatically.&lt;/strong&gt; Now you are able to get into a home with a lower down payment. As a result, mortgage insurance is now included with the mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Back in the day, banks did not often lend more than an 80% loan-to-value; people once had to put down a very large down payment.%20http://winningwithwade.com/how-does-mortgage-insurance-help-us.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Back in the day, banks did not often lend more than an 80% loan-to-value; people once had to put down a very large down payment.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a multiple ways you can structure your mortgage insurance policy.&lt;/strong&gt; Most people are familiar with having it included in your monthly payment, but you can also factor it into the loan amount, or build it into the interest rate—each has its pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to have a conversation about which might be the best structure for you, please reach out to me. Hearing from you would mean the world to me, and I will take great care of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 16:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/how-does-mortgage-insurance-help-us.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/how-does-mortgage-insurance-help-us.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Your Monthly Payments Are Applied</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FoTj_IZCUD0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since not everyone is aware, today I want to explain how your mortgage payments are applied to your most homeowners know that their payment is due the first of the month, but it generally is not late until the 15th..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most homeowners know that their payment is due on the 1st of the month, but it is not late until the 15th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your payoff amount will always be larger than your principal because it includes the interest that you have yet to pay.%20http://winningwithwade.com/how-your-monthly-payments-are-applied.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your payoff amount will always be larger than your principal because it includes the interest that you have yet to pay.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing you might not realize, however, &lt;strong&gt;is that interest is paid in arrears&lt;/strong&gt;.  That means your July payment would cover July’s principal, but would cover June’s interest. This is the reason you typically skip a payment when you close on a new loan, and also why you might have a little bit extra due over your principal balance when you go to pay off your loan. Your payoff amount will always be larger than your principal because it includes the interest that you have yet to pay, since interest is collected in arrears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this or would like to walk through how that works for you specifically, please feel free to reach out to me. It would mean the world to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/how-your-monthly-payments-are-applied.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/how-your-monthly-payments-are-applied.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Need a 20% Down Payment to Buy a Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kM951nk4tXA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many myths about the real estate market. Today I am discussing the biggest myth surrounding down payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest myth I hear is &lt;strong&gt;“I need a 20% down payment.”&lt;/strong&gt; After the last recession, underwriting guidelines tightened across the country, and the perception became that you needed at least a 20% down payment to qualify for financing. While this was true at the time for jumbo financing, it has since changed. There are a wide array of loan programs with different down payment options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=An FHA loan has a 3.5% down payment minimum, assuming you have a credit score over 580.%20http://winningwithwade.com/do-you-need-a-20-down-payment-to-buy-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“An FHA loan has a 3.5% down payment minimum, assuming you have a credit score over 580.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Texas, jumbo loans are set by the government, and this year, &lt;strong&gt;the amount for a jumbo loan is anything over $453,100.&lt;/strong&gt; A loan larger than this will usually still require a 20% down payment. However, there are plenty of lenders who will loan at 100% loan-to-value for the right borrower. Just remember that the lower the down payment, the higher the interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loans lower than $453,100 will be considered a conventional loan, and their down payments can range from as low as 3% to however high you want to make it.&lt;/strong&gt; These loans will have different requirements for mortgage insurance that you should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your next option is the FHA loan, which has a 3.5% down payment minimum, assuming you have a credit score over 580. If you have a credit score of less than 580, it will be hard to qualify for financing, but at that point, 10% is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final two loan programs you can use are USDA and VA loans. &lt;strong&gt;U&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDA loans are used for rural properties and VA loans are for veterans&lt;/strong&gt;. Neither requires any down payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there is definitely a wide range of down payment possibilities. If you have any further questions about the myth of the 20% down payment or how to best use your funds, please don’t hesitate to ask. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 17:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/do-you-need-a-20-down-payment-to-buy-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/do-you-need-a-20-down-payment-to-buy-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Truth About Investment Properties and LLCs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XsuZSruLMo0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Fannie Mae enacted a few changes in regards to transferring the ownership of investment properties into entities such as an LLC. You may remember the recent video I filmed on this topic, but, of course, things have changed again. This time, there are essentially three points you need to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The loan must have been securitized by June 1, 2016 or later.&lt;/strong&gt; This means you must have closed on or after this date in order to carry out this kind of transfer in ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The LLC must be in good standing with the state.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You must be the majority owner of the LLC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recent change is actually very positive. A lot of my investor clients have taken advantage of it already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A lot of my investor clients have already taken advantage of this recent change.%20http://winningwithwade.com/the-truth-about-investment-properties-and-llcs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A lot of my investor clients have already taken advantage of this recent change.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is thinking of investing in real estate, please think of us at Guardian Mortgage. We have a lot of experience and offer several loan programs. We would love to help guide you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more, visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fanniemae.com&quot;&gt;http://www.fanniemae.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, of course, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 12:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/the-truth-about-investment-properties-and-llcs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/the-truth-about-investment-properties-and-llcs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Answering Your Questions About Purchasing a Second Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Gj5XjpUzsUs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of our customers contact us with questions about owning a second home. The good news is that &lt;strong&gt;transactions for second homes are treated almost identically to transactions for primary residences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one big difference is that a lot of lenders will look closely at the distance between your primary and secondary residence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Lenders will pay a lot of attention to the distance between your potential second property and your primary residence.%20http://winningwithwade.com/answering-your-questions-about-purchasing-a-second-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Lenders will pay a lot of attention to the distance between your potential second property and your primary residence.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something like a vacation home, located far away from where you currently reside, will make sense. However, a secondary residence in the same, or near the same, neighborhood as your first home isn’t going to pass a sniff test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;strong&gt;talk with your lender ahead of time to develop a roadmap for making a successful offer on your second home&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://winningwithwade.com/answering-your-questions-about-purchasing-a-second-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://winningwithwade.com/answering-your-questions-about-purchasing-a-second-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
