<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your Journey with Jennie | Jennie Wolek</title>
    <description>Jennie Wolek, a top Real Estate Agent in Tulsa, shares her own internal real estate agent training for free. Her Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 12:25:08 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 12:25:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Ready to Get Smarter Every Week?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Or1RvUpEt8A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;My new weekly series is the learning opportunity you&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Want to ask me anything? Well now is your chance! &lt;strong&gt;I’m launching a weekly series on Fridays at 12 p.m. CST where, for 30 minutes, we’ll dive deep into one specific topic&lt;/strong&gt; and dissect the tactics and strategies involved so you can implement them into your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that, when given the right opportunity and the right learning environment, people always bring up the best questions. Wouldn’t it be so cool for us to learn and grow together? For many installments of this series, I’ll bring on special guests, and we’ll also be providing this live in “Your Journey With Jennie,” our closed Facebook group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just head to the &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/yourjourneywithJennie/&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; and click on the events tab to RSVP&lt;/strong&gt;. By doing so, you’ll receive an event reminder as well as the Zoom link so you can participate with us and be fully engaged! You’ll also be able to see this week’s topic so you can better prepare and get the most out of the discussion!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to talking with you soon. Of course, feel free to share any questions, ideas, or topics that are on your heart or in your mind. We’ll see you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-ready-to-get-smarter-every-week.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-ready-to-get-smarter-every-week.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Has Vyral Marketing Improved My Business?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DdiDbsQgLDQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how Vyral Marketing helped improve my marketing and business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this edition of “Your Journey With Jennie,” I’m joined by my friend Frank Klesitz of Vyral Marketing. Frank and I go way back and have been working together for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch it in its entirety, or use these timestamps to browse specific points at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:00 — Frank discusses his background in real estate, marketing, and what led him to the founding of Vyral Marketing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:30 — How Vyral has helped me get more business from my database, and how to track your return on investment with Vyral Marketing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:35 — How I measure my return on investment and overall success with Vyral’s program&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:55 — What are the best types of videos to make and share with your database?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:40 — How to use Facebook advertising to your advantage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15:25 — Are enough agents using video in their marketing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18:50 — Why you shouldn’t overthink or be nervous about being on video&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:20 — Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Frank about Vyral Marketing or what they do, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;http://www.getvyral.com&quot;&gt;visit their website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; or attend &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.getvyral.com/classroom&quot;&gt;one of their weekly training sessions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-has-vyral-marketing-improved-my-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-has-vyral-marketing-improved-my-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Reviews and Referrals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Plan a “Call in to Win Day”?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cya9Hqxwokw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;By planning a &amp;ldquo;Call in to Win Day,&amp;rdquo; you can get people to call &lt;u&gt;you&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What is the “Call in to Win Day,” and how can you make this event work for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The “Call in to Win Day” is a day where people call you and provide their contact information to enter a giveaway drawing&lt;/strong&gt;. To pull this off successfully, you first need a goal, a plan, and a big enough giveaway to inspire people to want to call you. That’s where the challenge lies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll use the same marketing plan you have for any of your events and have a two- to three-week period where you’ll promote save-the-date notifications so they don’t forget about it. You want to make sure they call on that day, and within a certain time frame, for a chance to win. Make sure you enlist sponsors and vendor partners because they can pitch in to cover the cost while you help promote them along the way via social media and emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You first need a goal, a plan, and a big enough giveaway to inspire people to want to call you.%20http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-plan-a-call-in-to-win-day.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You first need a goal, a plan, and a big enough giveaway to inspire people to want to call you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now is the time to focus on what will happen during the day of the event. Our team used Zoom as a forum and had Google Voice feed each call to different team members. We also had Google Forms pulled up so we could input new data and record any referrals. We had a blast that day, and I know you will, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You also need to plan for after the event&lt;/strong&gt;. We announce our winner the next day on Facebook Live and send out an email to each participant in case they miss it. After that, we make sure all new contact information is entered into our database, and every new contact receives a welcome campaign. Of course, if any referrals or other new introductions were made, we reach out to them as soon as possible and let them know we can help with all of their real estate needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about how to make your own “Call in to Win Day” or there’s anything else I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d also love to know some of the ideas you come up with for this fun event!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-plan-a-call-in-to-win-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-plan-a-call-in-to-win-day.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Benefits of a Buyer “Love Letter?”</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/34yaZTvz2qQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s why including a buyer &amp;lsquo;love letter&amp;rsquo; can be a game changer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How are you being creative with helping your clients win the deal? I don’t know if your market is like mine here in Tulsa, but our listing inventory is low and the market is hot. We love to think outside of the box for our clients, and one way we do that is to encourage our buyer clients to write a ‘love letter’ when submitting their offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing a letter lets your buyer client share their genuine enthusiasm about the prospect of living in that home&lt;/strong&gt;. Not only does it show the seller the buyer’s sentimental link to their property, but it also gives you, the agent, more insight into why your client is so interested in it—you get to learn some cool information about people sometimes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason why buyer love letters are great is that they allow us to show up for our clients as professionals. When we think outside the box and offer our buyers these sorts of ideas, it exemplifies our commitment to getting them into a new home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, &lt;strong&gt;buyer love letters help buyers win!&lt;/strong&gt; They can get the contract moving and bring your buyers one step closer to their ideal home. It also humanizes the whole experience thereafter; the buyer, seller, and seller’s agents will be more connected and have a more positive working relationship throughout the transaction when it’s understood that everyone is equally invested in making this deal work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When we think outside the box for our buyers, it exemplifies our commitment to getting them into a new home.%20http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-benefits-of-a-buyer-love-letter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When we think outside the box for our buyers, it exemplifies our commitment to getting them into a new home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you’re using buyer love letters in your offer and how this strategy is working out for you! As always, reach out with any questions or concerns you may have; I’m here to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-benefits-of-a-buyer-love-letter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-benefits-of-a-buyer-love-letter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Passing the Baton?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I6QlNAtjCr0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;With a team, you can pass the baton to win in a transaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Have you ever run track or seen a relay race? If so, then you know the necessity of passing the baton from one team member to another. A good track coach will tell you that &lt;strong&gt;a relay is won or lost in the transfer of the baton&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at The Wolek Group believe in the importance of passing the baton in real estate too. If you don’t have a team, you have no one to pass the baton to and must do all the work yourself. We pass three different batons during our real estate transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, when working with a seller, we pass a baton from the listing agent to the listing manager. The second baton is passed from the buyer agent to the transaction coordinator during pending, or from the listing manager to the transaction coordinator when working with a seller. Third, &lt;strong&gt;between 24 and 48 hours before closing is when the baton is passed back to the real estate agent&lt;/strong&gt; from the transaction coordinator. This arms the agent with all the information they need to know before closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What truly matters is communication between team members.%20http://localhost:4000/are-you-passing-the-baton.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What truly matters is communication between team members.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When passing all these batons, what truly matters is communication between team members. Every time a baton is passed, it’s followed by a debriefing, a conversation between team members to ensure we completely understand all the intricacies and needs of the client. Anytime the ball is dropped it goes back to a lack of communication. We do our best to not allow that to happen; &lt;strong&gt;it’s our goal to win the relay!&lt;/strong&gt; We win by getting to closing with elated clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about how we pass the batons, I’m sharing the information in my closed Facebook group Your Journey With Jennie. Join today! If you ever have any questions about real estate, reach out to us via phone or email. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-passing-the-baton.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-passing-the-baton.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect at the &quot;Implement My Business&quot; Seminar?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/07nAD8x4_mI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to learn how to put our systems into action!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thank you to all the amazing real estate agents who joined me in June to learn how to “Mirror My Business!” I provided you with lots of systems, tools, and tips on how to build a big business, with much of it coming from your database. Today I’m excited to share with you a follow-up series and a deeper dive to teach you how to “Implement My Business,” launching in July!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For six weeks starting on July 7, we’ll hold 90-minute sessions in which we’ll discuss accountability and connect with like-minded agents who look forward to building a big business&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ll even throw in a extra systems and tools that I couldn’t fit into the “Mirror My Business” workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I’m excited to dive deeper and share with you how to Implement My Business!%20http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-expect-at-the-implement-my-business-seminar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I’m excited to dive deeper and share with you how to Implement My Business!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/implement-my-business-6-week-series-tickets-106686466092&quot;&gt;sign up today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;! If you already attended the “Mirror My Business” workshop, simply &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;mailto:jennie@thewolekgroup.com?subject=%E2%80%9CImplement%20My%20Business%E2%80%9D%20seminar&quot;&gt;send me an email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;I’ll share the discount code with you&lt;/strong&gt;. If you didn’t, that’s okay, because you’ll receive all the same materials and documents as the other students as well as links to my Google Drive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out. I can’t wait to see you and share how to implement my business strategies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-expect-at-the-implement-my-business-seminar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-expect-at-the-implement-my-business-seminar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Experience of Being Hacked &amp; Deleted From Facebook</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hXoFFdDlcOQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting your Facebook hacked stinks, but here&amp;rsquo;s what I learned from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Recently my Facebook account was hacked and deleted. Here’s what I learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. When we are a “serf on someone else’s digital land,”&lt;/strong&gt; as a friend of mine phrased it best, bad things can happen. Every day, we willingly give our thoughts, insights, and pictures to social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Facebook and Instagram are connected&lt;/strong&gt;—if you lose one, you lose them both! Ouch… again, it was not fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. We must own where we put our content&lt;/strong&gt;, or at least back it up, so that way if it’s lost, it’s not lost forever. I acted fast and reached out to my business coach and marketing friend for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. I had an addiction&lt;/strong&gt;. I used it to fool myself into thinking that I was always connecting with people and working when I was on those apps. I noticed that, on the first day of not having these apps, I still naturally kept going to the icons on my phone and clicking them. I finally deleted them and that helped a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Frustratingly, there is no way to contact a real human at Facebook for help.%20http://localhost:4000/my-experience-of-being-hacked-deleted-from-facebook.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Frustratingly, there is no way to contact a real human at Facebook for help.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. My mindset is strong&lt;/strong&gt;. Sometimes, there are things in life that I cannot control. It’s OK! Once I realized the likely fate of what happened, I accepted it and moved on quickly to find solutions for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. I’m still gun shy with social media&lt;/strong&gt;. Maybe I’m still a bit mad, too. Frustratingly, there is no way to contact a real human at Facebook for help. After a few days, I was able to create a new account, and I’m very slowly working through accepting new friend requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. We always need to find the silver lining&lt;/strong&gt;. I no longer have 5,000 Facebook friends, through which I must scroll to find someone to remove whenever I add a new friend. Though no longer publicly displayed on Facebook, all of my memories last within me and with my friends and family. I’ve left the Facebook and Insta apps on the last page of my phone, and the addiction has slightly subsided. I have been more present and focused on my work and family over the last five days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found this encouraging, whether you’ve suffered such an experience or not. As always, please feel free to reach out to the Wolek Group by phone or email if you have any questions about real estate. We’re here to help (and a live person will always be there to talk to you).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-experience-of-being-hacked-deleted-from-facebook.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/my-experience-of-being-hacked-deleted-from-facebook.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Starting the Day Off Great</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LTM7XoDIOlI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sharing my morning routine, hoping it helps you with yours.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I often get asked about my morning schedule, so today I’m sharing it with you. Years ago, I learned that the most successful people, at least in my business, all had one thing in common: they got up early. To me, early meant 5 a.m., so that’s when I started getting up every day. I quickly noticed that it was a great way to get ahead of my day. Since I enjoy a cup of coffee in the morning, I decided to wake up even earlier—around 4:45 a.m.—to have some coffee, think, and prepare for the day ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After my morning coffee and daily goal-planning, I exercise&lt;/strong&gt; by doing some yoga, using the treadmill, or even going outside for a walk or run—anything that allows me to feel good about myself, both mentally and physically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I take a shower and have a smoothie for breakfast. I’ve had the same smoothie almost every morning for at least five years. It’s packed with all kinds of good things: spinach, a frozen triple berry blend, protein powder, etc. At this point, my stomach is full, my mind is good, and my heart is strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’m the type of person who wears makeup and takes care of their hair, I’ll do that next before listening to a podcast or reading a book. Over time, I’ve learned that’s a way to think bigger and generate new ideas throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, &lt;strong&gt;I write a post in a closed Facebook group called &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/yourjourneywithJennie&quot;&gt;Your Journey With Jenny&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; every single morning&lt;/strong&gt;. Members can always tell what I’m working on, thinking about, and reading. Click on the above link to get permission to join if you haven’t already!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you plan out your morning with a powerful, intentional schedule, the rest of your day falls into place.%20http://localhost:4000/the-key-to-starting-the-day-off-great.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you plan out your morning with a powerful, intentional schedule, the rest of your day falls into place.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’m through with all that, I’ll connect with my team at 8:15 a.m. to share what we’re grateful for as well as what our intentions and goals are for the day. Then from 9 a.m. to 11 a.m., we work on lead generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that when you plan out your morning with a powerful, intentional schedule, the rest of your day falls into place and you’ll be more positive and ready to connect with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to reach out to me to share your morning routine!&lt;/strong&gt; If there’s anything I can do to help, don’t hesitate to ask. I’m here for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-key-to-starting-the-day-off-great.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-key-to-starting-the-day-off-great.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Want to Mirror My Business?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xgpeSgm7hWE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re hosting a &quot;Mirror My Business&quot; webinar, so come learn from us!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Want to mirror my business? Now you can! I’ve been in the real estate business for 19 years, and for the first time, &lt;strong&gt;I’m offering a three-hour “Mirror My Business” workshop&lt;/strong&gt;. I want to share our successful practices with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be sharing the systems, tools, and models that we use to help over 100 families each year. We’ll discuss mindset, mission, lead generation and conversion, marketing, setting appointments, listings and buyer presentations, agent and affiliate referrals, reviews, and ‘clients for life.’ I look forward to spending time with you in our small group webinar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To register, &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/mirror-my-business-workshop-with-jennie-wolek-tickets-104824745636&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the workshop or real estate in general, please reach out via phone or email. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/want-to-mirror-my-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/want-to-mirror-my-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <category>Listing Presentation</category>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Golden Handoff?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I5v34C_-fXc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many agents come and go in the real estate business. The Golden Handoff ensures their clients are taken care of after they leave.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have been in the real estate business for a very long time, and no matter what is happening in the market, many agents come and go constantly. What’s sad about this is that those &lt;strong&gt;Realtors have put time, energy, money, and often their love into developing and nurturing tons of relationships&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When agents leave the business for any reason, their clients are just left there, without a real estate agent to help them. I believe all real state agents should think like the businessperson they are and ensure that their clients are taken care of in the future. They should have a plan. That’s what the Golden Handoff is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Golden Handoff is entrusting a database to another agent and receiving a referral fee in return. That new real estate agent will have a plan and stay in touch with these clients. How smart and simple is that? This doesn’t cost the departing agent any time, energy, or money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Golden Handoff is entrusting a database to another agent and receiving a referral fee in return.%20http://localhost:4000/what-is-the-golden-handoff.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Golden Handoff is entrusting a database to another agent and receiving a referral fee in return.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please let me know if you’ve used the Golden Handoff in your business&lt;/strong&gt;, I’d like to hear about your experience with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the Golden Handoff or real estate in general, reach out to me via phone or email. I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-the-golden-handoff.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-the-golden-handoff.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <category>Reviews and Referrals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
