<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools &amp; Training for Central Iowa Real Estate Professionals</title>
    <description>A Video Blog about Central Iowa Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 15:16:09 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 15:16:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Talking To Abbi About Her SOLDwisch Team Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XDc6f0Dbd4A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Abbi Gilson discusses her experience with the SOLDwisch team so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re pleased to be speaking with Abbi Gilson, a great agent on the SOLDwisch Team. We’ll discuss how she got into real estate, her experience so far, and what drew her to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abbi is from Prairie City, Iowa, so she is very familiar with the Central Iowa area. She played softball in her youth, and she was even on Missouri State’s collegiate team while she attended school there. As soon as she graduated, she jumped into real estate, and she’s been a valuable member of our group for two and a half years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Abbi, the reason why most people get into real estate is that they’re crazy, so she supposes she’s in the same boat. As a communications major in college, she wasn’t sure what she wanted to do after graduation. When she thought real estate might be her path, she knew she didn’t want to start off in the business alone. **Misty’s team approach seemed inviting, so Abbi attended one of her meet and greets, and the rest is history. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Every agent on the SOLDwisch team supports each other.%20http://localhost:4000/talking-to-abbi-about-her-soldwisch-team-experience.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Every agent on the SOLDwisch team supports each other.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since she joined the SOLDwisch team, Abbi’s experience has been very different from a solo agent. Instead of juggling different roles at the same time, she has the pleasure of talking to new clients when they call the team about new listings or selling a home. She’s at the frontline of our business, which frees up time for our other agents to be out in the field working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Abbi talks to buyers, especially first-time buyers, she tries to set up a meeting in our office. &lt;strong&gt;The process can be overwhelming for buyers, so this gives us a great opportunity to explain what they can expect when looking at properties.&lt;/strong&gt; Some people may be vaguely aware they need a mortgage, but many buyers don’t know exactly what they need or what they can afford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We encourage all our buyer clients to find an agent they can work with one on one. This way, if they have any questions, they have a resource on our team willing to walk them through whatever they need. Everyone on the team relies on one another to provide the best experience for our clients, just like how Abbi worked together with her softball team to compete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank Abbi once again for taking the time to speak with us; it was great to catch up with her! If you have questions about a career in real estate or anything else, please call or email us. We are always willing to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/talking-to-abbi-about-her-soldwisch-team-experience.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/talking-to-abbi-about-her-soldwisch-team-experience.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Rene Soldwisch Loves Our Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dmS5LxSPyOI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Rene Soldswitch talks about the real estate industry and our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we want to share a clip from an interview we had with Rene Soldwisch, Misty’s sister-in-law. She’s been in real estate for a little over eight years. Before that, she was in mortgage lending, interior decorating, and even the radio business. Her skills all came together when she started as an agent, contributing to her success. We asked her a few questions about the industry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like most about real estate?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people. I love to help people achieve their goals and find their dream home. Some clients cry tears of joy when they find that perfect house, and being a part of that is a big deal. That home is where they’re going to live and make memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We have each other’s back, and we keep each other positive.%20http://localhost:4000/why-rene-soldwisch-loves-our-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We have each other’s back, and we keep each other positive.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the biggest obstacles for buyers and sellers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They want to make sure they’re getting a good deal and doing the right thing. I work with all kinds of buyers, and I help guide them toward the right decision and alleviate their concerns. Buying a home is a big investment for most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the best part about working on Misty’s team? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re very unique. We fit together very well as a team. We have each other’s back, and we keep each other positive. Misty is a great leader, and many other agents don’t have that sort of guidance; they’re just floundering. If one of us has a question, there’s a plethora of information at our fingertips. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our team or real estate in general, feel free to call or email us. We’d love to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-rene-soldwisch-loves-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-rene-soldwisch-loves-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Books That Helped my Career</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xuwDZYu0sBQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are three books that will spur your real estate journey in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve received a lot of great advice over the years, but what has stuck with me the most are the business and mindset books that put me in the right space to succeed. That’s why today I want to share three great books that will help your real estate journey in 2022:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. “Atomic Habits” by James Clear.&lt;/strong&gt; This book dives deep into how habits are the basis of everything else we do. One of my favorite things about James is his weekly three-two-one newsletter, which is always full of exciting ideas. I see him as a big thought leader in business today, and this book is a great introduction to his ideas if you haven’t encountered them already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Each of these books has changed my life for the better.%20http://localhost:4000/3-books-that-helped-my-career.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Each of these books has changed my life for the better.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. “Fanatical Prospecting” by Jeb Blount.&lt;/strong&gt; I love this book because most agents overcomplicate prospecting. Jeb breaks down the prospecting mindset and shares some great exercises to get more out of your hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. “How To Win Friends and Influence People” by Dale Carnegie.&lt;/strong&gt; This one is old school. It may have been written in the 1930s, but it’s a great resource if you want to understand how to connect with people. It also has a more formal style than we’re used to today, so it’s a nice change of pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about today’s topic or anything else, please call or email me. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-books-that-helped-my-career.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-books-that-helped-my-career.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Some Didn’t Have the Best 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2G_AxKWdmLM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;For some agents, 2021 was a great year. For others, not so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you reflect on 2021, do you think that you lived up to your potential and had a satisfying year in real estate? A lot of people did; it was a tremendous market that had a lot of good things come of it. However, I coach many agents from around the country, and &lt;strong&gt;not everyone had a spectacular year.&lt;/strong&gt; These kinds of people fall into two different categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first group recognized that the market was hot, but they had trouble connecting with clients and keeping them loyal. They might have struggled with articulating their value propositions. In a busy market, sometimes sellers don’t feel that an agent has as big of an impact as they might in a more challenging market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Many can’t imagine maintaining the same pace as they did in 2021.%20http://localhost:4000/why-some-didnt-have-the-best-2021.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Many can’t imagine maintaining the same pace as they did in 2021.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other group may have had the most financially successful year that they’d had in a while, but they had no work-life balance. Many couldn’t imagine maintaining that same pace heading into 2022 and were concerned about burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’d love to hear what your year has been like so far and what you hope to achieve in 2022.&lt;/strong&gt; Give me a call or send an email, and I’d be happy to set up a no-obligation strategy session where I can provide you with three strong action steps to take to help you build your business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-some-didnt-have-the-best-2021.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-some-didnt-have-the-best-2021.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Greg Talks About Working on the Misty SOLDwisch Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r4pnldC4wDM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Greg Wallenstein shares his story and what he likes about Misty’s team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down with one of our agents, Greg Wallenstein, and asked him to share his story and why he likes working on the Misty SOLDwisch Team. Here’s what he had to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I moved here about five and a half to six years ago from Saint Petersburg, Florida, which is just outside of Tampa. I was there for 14 years, and before that, I lived in Brooklyn, New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started at a different company where I got my real estate license. Somebody on Misty’s team reached out to me and said I needed to interview with Misty and Keith. I stepped up to the plate, interviewed with them, and it went very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Misty really has seen it all.%20http://localhost:4000/greg-talks-about-working-on-the-misty-soldwisch-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Misty really has seen it all.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of the difference comes down to the team atmosphere. When you’re a solo agent, you don’t have the backing that we do on our team. We have a client service department that takes inbound and outbound calls all of the time. &lt;strong&gt;They not only set and prescreen appointments but also make sure that clients get pre-approved&lt;/strong&gt;. By the time they meet with an agent, they’re ready to go see houses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to joining Misty’s team, I sold four properties. &lt;strong&gt;The first year on Misty’s team, I sold 69 properties, and that number has gone up every year since&lt;/strong&gt;. I was working another job on top of real estate before joining Misty’s Team, but after I joined, I gave up that second job. I didn’t need it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Misty has shown me how to think outside the box. A lot of other agents get tunnel vision when working on a deal. I can call Misty any time of the day and bounce ideas off of her. That’s one of the reasons I’ve stayed on the team and have been so successful; &lt;strong&gt;we collaborate well together&lt;/strong&gt;. If one of us doesn’t know how to handle something, we can talk to Misty, and she’ll know what to do. She really has seen it all, and since we do so many transactions a year, we know a lot more than your average brokerage.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to buy, sell, or have any real estate questions, feel free to give us a call. We’d love to put you in touch with one of our great agents like Greg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/greg-talks-about-working-on-the-misty-soldwisch-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/greg-talks-about-working-on-the-misty-soldwisch-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Life Is Better on the Misty SOLDwisch Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rLLdWw3Oac4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s the story of how Emily Burton become our Director of Sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Burton is originally from Indianola, Iowa, where she graduated from Simpson College. She worked as a bartender for many years before she stumbled into the real estate business. She had just received her degree in public relations and was looking for a job. She initially interviewed to be an agent’s assistant; that agent told her that she would be perfect as an agent and that she should get her license. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Emily did; &lt;strong&gt;she worked as an individual agent for about seven months.&lt;/strong&gt; It was a difficult time for her. She wanted real estate to be her career, but she was struggling. Solo agents don’t have the support that agents who work on a team do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=‘I can’t imagine doing this amount of business on my own.’%20http://localhost:4000/why-life-is-better-on-the-misty-soldwisch-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“‘I can’t imagine doing this amount of business on my own.’”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, in 2017, she received a call from the Misty SOLDwisch Team to schedule an interview, and she’s been with us ever since. The difference between her life as a solo agent and as a member of our team couldn’t be starker. &lt;strong&gt;We have multiple departments on our team designed to help our agents succeed&lt;/strong&gt;, like our client services and transactions departments. Emily also doesn’t have to worry about marketing because our team has systems in place to take care of that so she can focus on working with clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about working with the Misty SOLDwisch Team or are interested in beginning your real estate career, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image001-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 03:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-life-is-better-on-the-misty-soldwisch-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-life-is-better-on-the-misty-soldwisch-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do I Handle Multiple-Offer Situations?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QWbCqBXPFVI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s how I like to respond when one of my clients gets multiple offers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are a seller and have multiple offers on your home, it’s very common for your agent to say back to all the buyers, “Give me your highest and best offer and we’ll make a decision at 5 p.m. tomorrow.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the term “highest and best” denotes a finality that is premature in my opinion. Instead, &lt;strong&gt;the approach I like to take goes something like this:&lt;/strong&gt; “You sent us an offer, and I want you to know we have multiple offers. Let us know if you’d like to make any adjustments to your offer knowing that there are multiple interested parties out there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do this because we could counter any of these offers, not just the highest one. &lt;strong&gt;A lot of people get caught up on the highest price without understanding the importance of contingencies, financing, and everything else that could cause you to lose more than you gain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 03:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-handle-multiple-offer-situations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-handle-multiple-offer-situations.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Win a Bidding War for the Home You Want?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4AmTNmFjv3Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are six tips that will make your offer stand out in a bidding war.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nationally, multiple offers are becoming more and more frequent in the real estate market, and that’s certainly true in most segments of our Des Moines market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buyers make an offer for the home they want, it has to be presented in a way that will actually win the home. If you’re a buyer and work with an inexperienced agent who doesn’t have a strategy, you’ll end up making offer after offer with nothing to show for it. The key is to work with the right agent. Additionally, there are six tips to help make your offer stand out in a multiple-offer situation: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Have a strategy in the presentation.&lt;/strong&gt; My team and I sell hundreds of listings each year, and I can tell you that your agent isn’t doing you any favors by just sharing your offer and not saying anything about it. This leads me to my second tip…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Share the love.&lt;/strong&gt; We often have our buyers write a letter or take a picture of themselves to share with sellers because it’s a way of adding a personal touch and showing why they love the home. Many of us have a sentimental connection to our homes, which means sellers will want a buyer who will enjoy their home the way they did. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Shorten or waive contingencies.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want to make it difficult for the seller to like you, and asking for closing costs, or a 21-day inspection period (as opposed to the normal seven-day period), or the walls to be professionally painted is a good way to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Pre-inspect the home.&lt;/strong&gt; This is somewhat of a continuation of the previous tip, since getting a pre-inspection allows you to waive the inspection contingency in your offer. Plus, it will help you uncover any potential problems with the home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Make your best offer.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, don’t test the seller by offering less than what you’re able. In a multiple-offer situation, it behooves you to put your cards on the table. You don’t want to miss out on the home you want over $500 or $1,000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Make it easy for the seller.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, they may have to wait to take possession of their next home, so give them extended possession of your home after closing to make the moving process easier. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember—win the bidding war for the home you want before worrying about the appraisal, inspection, etc. Have a strategy to win and don’t try offering less than the list price. If a home’s hit the market in the last week and it has multiple offers, that means it’s priced or underpriced for the market, which means you’re underpaying by paying the asking price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about how to win the home you want or there’s anything else I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-win-a-bidding-war-for-the-home-you-want.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-win-a-bidding-war-for-the-home-you-want.html</guid>
        
        <category>Agents Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Want to Get Paid to Show Families Their Potential Dream Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HTFjhXusbRM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Showing homes to clients only makes up about 5% of what an agent does, but you can make it 100%.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the latest episode of my podcast with Van and Bonnie, I have exciting news to share: &lt;strong&gt;The Misty SOLDwisch Home Selling Team is looking for showing agents to show houses for our team.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that I love real estate. There are so many different aspects of it, and we’re making a difference in people’s lives. Being in real estate also means you have to be good at many different things. It’s not just about showing a house—you have to do paperwork, handle inspections, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the advantage our team brings to the table. We have people who fill specialized roles, and this new role we’re launching is designed for people who love focusing on the fun part of real estate and don’t want to handle the more challenging aspects of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people tell me they want to sell real estate because they love looking at houses, but the reality is that showing houses is only about 5% of what a full-time agent does. &lt;strong&gt;This new role makes showing homes 100% of what you do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This position is a great fit for anyone that loves spending time with people and helping them find their dream home.%20http://localhost:4000/want-to-get-paid-to-show-families-their-potential-dream-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This position is a great fit for anyone that loves spending time with people and helping them find their dream home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agents in this new role will set their own schedule to show houses for our clients. Instead of working on commission, you’ll earn an hourly rate for simply being there for our clients during the fun part of real estate. Having a real estate license is a requirement for the job, but your schedule can be very flexible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This position is a great fit for anyone that loves spending time with people and helping them find their dream home. You can work as many hours as you want. The right candidate can be part-time or full-time, depending on what your needs are. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one else in the industry offers this role to the same degree that we do, but I’m excited about it because I know there are some great people out there who’d love to be in the business on a more expanded level. If they have a real estate license and aren’t putting it to good use or their career hasn’t turned out exactly how they wanted it, this could be their solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you want to get paid to show a bunch of brand-new houses to families looking for their dream home, give me a call today or visit www.SOLDinCentralIowa.com. I’d love to hear from you. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 13:27:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/want-to-get-paid-to-show-families-their-potential-dream-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/want-to-get-paid-to-show-families-their-potential-dream-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design Tips for Home Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KMlXQZpRSk4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re a home seller, knowing the latest in home design and style will help your home shine much brighter. Here’s why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m back once again with Max Wilker, the Style Director for Better Homes and Gardens. This time, he’s here to give us some quick tips on freshening up your home decor to help maximize your sale price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s an outline of our conversation, with timestamps so that you can skip ahead to the section(s) that interest you the most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:34- How to freshen up your dining room and kitchen spaces with the latest styles and trends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:15- A great alternative to installing marble countertops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:10- Some of the latest living room design trends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30- Bed and bedroom design trends and staging tips&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks so much to Max for joining me and giving out so many great tips for freshening up the most important parts of your home before selling. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 10:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/design-tips-for-home-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/design-tips-for-home-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
