<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calgary Real Estate Video Blog with Eric Mortimer</title>
    <description>Our mission at Eric Mortimer &amp; Associates is to be your best resource for Calgary real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Eric Mortimer &amp; Associates, your professional Calgary Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 16:05:22 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 16:05:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Make It a Fun, Safe Halloween With This Spooktacular Guide</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mFD8loLuEaE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halloween will be here before you know it, so today I&amp;rsquo;ll share some quick tips that will help you and your family have a fun, safe holiday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skeletons, spiderwebs, and Jack-o’-lanterns galore are popping up all over our neighborhoods, and that can only mean one thing: Halloween is just around the corner. If your preparations so far have involved stocking up on candy and choosing the perfect costume for yourself or your children, you’re on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting in the Halloween spirit is great, but decking out your yard with spooky decor and buying sweets for trick-or-treaters isn’t the only thing you should be doing to get ready for the holiday ahead. &lt;strong&gt;Ghouls and goblins might be nothing more than fun, fictional frights, but there are some real dangers to watch out for on Halloween night&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, by following a few simple safety tricks, you can help make this Halloween a fun and safe treat for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. If you’re a homeowner expecting trick-or-treaters, make sure you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep your home, yard, and sidewalks brightly lit (and shoveled if applicable)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clear debris and obstacles from your yard, steps, and walkways&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep pets kenneled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Park your car in the garage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use LED candles instead of real candles inside Jack-o’-lanterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tone down extra-scary decor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep a close eye on your front door&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. If you’re a parent with children who plan to trick-or-treat, make sure you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always accompany young children to each house they visit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visit neighborhoods with sidewalks to avoid walking in the street&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always use crosswalks and look both ways before crossing the street&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add reflective tape to your child’s costume&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep masks at home, as they can obstruct your child’s vision&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have your child carry a flashlight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish a curfew for older children venturing out on their own&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remind older, unsupervised children to call 911 in case of emergency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell unaccompanied children to never enter a stranger’s home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can help make this Halloween a fun and safe treat for everyone.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/make-it-a-fun-safe-halloween-with-this-spooktacular-guide.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can help make this Halloween a fun and safe treat for everyone.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. If you’re going to be driving on Halloween night, make sure you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stay alert and watch for children in the street&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eliminate any distractions within your vehicle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drive slowly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be especially cautious at intersections and corners&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be mindful when pulling in or out of driveways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Halloween holding such a high risk of accidents involving child pedestrians, following these safety tips will be essential. Still, even after your children have made it home with their Halloween haul, there is one more important safety concern you’ll need to address: their candy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Check candy for the following red flags before letting your trick-or-treaters dig into their treats:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An unusual or discolored appearance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoiled or unwrapped items&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tears or holes in wrappers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to following these tips, you should also &lt;strong&gt;be wary of homemade items or baked goods&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don’t personally know who made them, these should be discarded. As a general rule for any treat: When in doubt, throw it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents should also be mindful of treats that could pose a choking hazard. Hard candies, gum, peanuts, and small toys should only be given to older children. If you have any additional questions regarding tainted or unsafe candy, you can contact Poison Control or your local police department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By following these tips, you and your trick-or-treaters will be all set to have a safe and happy holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fangs for reading and sharing this. Happy Halloween!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 16:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/make-it-a-fun-safe-halloween-with-this-spooktacular-guide.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/make-it-a-fun-safe-halloween-with-this-spooktacular-guide.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winter Is Coming: Is Your Home Ready?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FR8tnXjfGuM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today Barry Malesh from A Buyer&amp;rsquo;s Choice Home Inspections joins me to provide you with some tips on how to prepare your home for the winter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Calgarians are getting ready for winter—they’re preparing their cars and their garages are swamped with snow tires. But what about their houses? Barry Malesh from A Buyer’s Choice Home Inspections is here to give you some tips about what you should be doing to prepare your home for the coming winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Service your furnace&lt;/strong&gt;. Now’s the time of year that you’ll start needing your furnace the most. Make sure you get it serviced and have your ducts cleaned out because you don’t want to have any problems with it when the temperature is 40 below. Cleaning your unit and changing the filters will also help you avoid carbon monoxide leaks, keep the air in your home clean, and keep your bill lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Check your smoke detectors every time you change your clocks&lt;/strong&gt;. This includes carbon monoxide detectors, as well. Change out the batteries regularly, and replace your units once about every five years, since they don’t last forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Reduce the inside temperature when you’re gone to save heat&lt;/strong&gt;. Many people think that if they lower the temperature at night, they’re just wasting money reheating the house the next day. Tests on this scenario have been done, and it’s actually been proven that the larger the temperature differential between the inside of the house and the outside of the house, the more heat is lost. So, if you do lower the temperature in the house when you’re gone more than four hours, you can save on heating costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Make sure the attic is the same temperature as the outside of your home&lt;/strong&gt;. Here’s a great tip for keeping the heat in your home from leaking out of your attic: seal off your attic hatch with vapor barrier, and be sure to weather strip it, as well. Make sure that the vents for your bathroom and kitchen range lead to the outside, too; that air is warm and moist, so the condensation could freeze and cause damage if it isn’t vented outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat escaping from the attic will also cause melting on your roof and create ice dams. Barry has seen homes where, because of ice damming, water seeps under the shingles and the melt runs down the interior walls, shorting the electrical system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Change out smoke and carbon monoxide detector batteries regularly.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/winter-is-coming-is-your-home-ready.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Change out smoke and carbon monoxide detector batteries regularly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Always shut off your outside taps&lt;/strong&gt;. Disconnect your garden hoses, turn off the water shutoff valve, and then go back outside and open the tap so that the air can escape. It’s the compressed air in water lines that causes them to break, not the ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Have your downspouts extended at all times&lt;/strong&gt;. If ice on the roof melts and runs down your house without proper drainage, the water will pool at the foundation. Here, it can freeze, crack your foundation, and let more water in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. When going away for winter vacation, shut off the main water to the home&lt;/strong&gt;. This way, if anything starts to leak, you won’t have any water issues. The valve for this is in the basement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, have someone walk through your house while you’re gone. Your insurance might have a clause that mentions this as well: Every three days to once a week, someone should walk through the house to make sure the heat’s on and that there aren’t other issues with the home. Failure to do this might allow for problems to go unnoticed, and your insurance may not cover it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like more tips about how to protect your home in the winter, reach out to me. I’ll send you a free report that includes a checklist you can follow every fall and spring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/winter-is-coming-is-your-home-ready.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/winter-is-coming-is-your-home-ready.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top Secret Listings &amp; Agents You Should Know About</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YGImXFgXuaU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our team has access to a secret set of listings that you won&amp;rsquo;t find on the MLS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am going to share with you, not one but three of our top coming soon listings before they are out on the MLS and available for purchase to anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you been, or do you know someone who is, frustrated because you keep just missing out on the best deals? You find a place you love and go to the open house or call the agent and it’s already gone. This can feel like a waste of time and be heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you be surprised to know that you are probably missing places that were actually perfect for you because they were gone so fast? &lt;strong&gt;It happens to people every day, particularly in the styles, communities, and price ranges with the highest demand&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often this happens because somebody else heard about it either before it hit the market or the instant it came on. Our coming soon inventory is constantly changing, so make sure you let us know if you are looking for anything in particular, and we can keep you updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have access to a number of other agents and their coming soon listings. &lt;strong&gt;This not only gives you a secret advantage over other buyers, but it also makes sure you don’t miss out on some of the best places&lt;/strong&gt;. All three of these properties are in desirable areas in the fastest moving price range of $375,000 to $475,000. As you’ll see, these homes are going to see a lot of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These will get scooped up quickly.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/top-secret-listings-agents-you-should-know-about.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These will get scooped up quickly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our first property is a bungalow in the SW neighbourhood Westgate&lt;/strong&gt;. It is currently being painted, so it’s going to look even better than it does now. People just love the mature trees and the easy access to bow trail and downtown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The next property is a 1,400 square foot bungalow with hardwood floors in the NW neighbourhood Dalhousie&lt;/strong&gt;. This is located on a great crescent and close to sought-after schools. This really has some great potential for somebody that is willing to do a little bit of work and updating. Do you want to build some sweat equity? This is an opportunity to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third secret deal is a nearly 1,600 square foot two-story with a double-attached garage and a fully developed basement for under $375,000&lt;/strong&gt;. It is currently being painted inside and the huge back decks are being stained. This one will get scooped up quickly. It’s also close to schools, shopping, transit, and the Stoney and Deerfoot trails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more information on these, other properties, or our other unique home marketing systems and strategies, give us a call or send us an email today. We’d be happy to put our particular set of skills to work for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/top-secret-listings-agents-you-should-know-about.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/top-secret-listings-agents-you-should-know-about.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Let These Common Buyer Fears Wreck Your Home Search</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6QjuPqURuNQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;To have a successful home purchase, there are certain buyer fears you need to overcome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, if you can acknowledge your fears about the home buying process, you can overcome them and move forward with your purchase with clarity, courage, and commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of fears do buyers usually have? Here are four of the most common:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Fear of loss&lt;/strong&gt;. In this case, buyers will come across a property and get scared that they have to buy it soon or someone else will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Fear of missing out&lt;/strong&gt;. Here’s where the analytical brain kicks in and tells you that, even though you really love this house, it’s only the third one you’ve looked at, and there are thousands of more listings on the market you should look at too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Fear of overpaying&lt;/strong&gt;. Nobody wants to look like they overpaid for something. If you think a house is overpriced, the tendency is to not want to pay too much for it, wonder why someone else hasn’t bought it yet, and/or wonder whether you’d get a good deal or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Fear that something is wrong with the house&lt;/strong&gt;. What if there’s a structural defect and that’s why nobody has bought it? If it’s a condo, a structural defect might necessitate a special assessment or increased fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s not a perfect market out there, and a home’s list price might be either above or below its true value.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/dont-let-these-common-buyer-fears-wreck-your-home-search.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s not a perfect market out there, and a home’s list price might be either above or below its true value.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard the phrase, “What you think about, you bring about.” In other words, the fears you think about can manifest themselves in the form of mistakes because you overcompensate to avoid those fears. With that in mind, here are five common mistakes buyers make that are caused by the fears above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Not getting pre-approved&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s common for people to start searching for homes and making offers without knowing how much they can afford. This can cause you to lose out on the home you want or lead you to become “house poor.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Overpaying&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s not a perfect market out there, and a home’s list price might be either above or below its true value. Not everyone has access to records of previously sold listings, expired listings, or other statistics that indicate where the market is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Not having access to all properties&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition to the properties listed on the MLS, there are “coming soon” listings, “For Sale by Owner” listings, off-market properties, and other options available to buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Listening to the wrong people&lt;/strong&gt;. There are all sorts of people out there who claim to be real estate experts, so make sure you listen to an actual expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Not having your own agent&lt;/strong&gt;. Make sure you hire a proper buyer’s agent to represent you. They’ll have a fiduciary duty to you and only you, which will save you thousands of dollars in the long run. Also, make sure you hire the right agent—one who has a team of professionals behind them to look after all of your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, most agents average between zero and three deals per year. Our team, on the other hand, closed three deals just last week. I don’t say this to brag—I say it to assure you that we cover all our buyer clients’ needs. &lt;strong&gt;Here are some specific services we offer that you should look for when selecting your agent:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have a VIP buyer program that gives you access to all properties online and offline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We do a careful market analysis to make sure you never overpay for a property&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We supply competent affiliates and professionals (home inspectors, lenders, lawyers, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/dont-let-these-common-buyer-fears-wreck-your-home-search.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/dont-let-these-common-buyer-fears-wreck-your-home-search.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Tell if Your Home Is Overpriced</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XDND9P_8AzA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are three signs you need to watch out for to know whether your home is overpriced.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re putting your home on the market, it’s important that you price it correctly from the start. Overpricing it can cost you tens of thousands of dollars—not just in terms of carrying costs, but because you’ll end up chasing the market downward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people assume a buyer will eventually make an offer for less than what they ask, but that doesn’t happen very often. Think of the TV show “Shark Tank,” where people offer a percentage of their company in exchange for an investment: Some of those companies are amazing, but their founders will still walk away without a deal because they ask for too much of an investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same thing can happen to sellers in our Calgary market, so if you do overprice your home, you’ll need to adjust quickly. How can you tell if this is the case, though? Here are the three signs you should watch out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Your listing has expired&lt;/strong&gt;. If it’s been on the market for six months or more, it’s already gone through a lot of exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Overpricing it can cost you tens of thousands of dollars.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-tell-if-your-home-is-overpriced.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Overpricing it can cost you tens of thousands of dollars.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The Rule of 10&lt;/strong&gt;. In other words, for every 10 showings you have, you should get at least one offer—if you go 10 days without a showing, your home is overpriced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Feedback&lt;/strong&gt;. People will give you feedback after a showing if your Realtor is doing a great job. Make sure you listen to it. A lot of sellers try to block this feedback out, but if buyers give you feedback without wanting to buy your home, it means they’re trying to help you. A lot of their minor complaints can be solved once the price is right. If your price is right, the only feedback you want to hear is an offer or a clarifying question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your home has been sitting on the market and you want it sold soon, we specialize in fixing bad listings, so give us a call and we’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-tell-if-your-home-is-overpriced.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-tell-if-your-home-is-overpriced.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can Photography Do for Your Home’s Sale?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VGgYrv5m70o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Having great photos of your home is a great way to start the home sale process. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s competitive market, you need to do everything right in order to sell. One of those things is capturing the right photographs of your home. We look at bad real estate pictures every week, and that’s not where you want to be. We’re joined by a real estate photo expert today to answer some common questions about what he does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a big believer in the 80/20 rule that says 80% of our results come from 20% of our efforts. &lt;strong&gt;In real estate, photography comes within that 20% of work&lt;/strong&gt;. Danny Boutet of Visual Marketing knows a lot about this topic. He’s been in business for 11 years and has shot over 7,000 homes in and around the Calgary area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;According to Danny, the biggest mistake he sees homeowners make when it comes to photos is not having their spaces decluttered&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’re not using something, get it out of the way. Misplaced shoes, clothes, jackets, and trinkets should be out while photos are being taken. He also recommends double checking your lights, windows, and mirrors to ensure they are clean. HDR photos can pick up things that we didn’t have to worry about in the past, but it can also show your home off in a way that’s never been possible before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=80% of our results come from 20% of our efforts.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/what-can-photography-do-for-your-homes-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“80% of our results come from 20% of our efforts.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Danny about how you can make your home’s photos sparkle, give him a call at (403) 470-4350 or send him an email to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#118;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#097;&quot;&gt;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#118;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#097;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to watch one of our previous videos on &lt;a href=&quot;https://calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-focus-on-product-and-promotion-when-prepping-your-home.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;prepping your home&lt;/a&gt; as well. If you have any other real estate-related questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/what-can-photography-do-for-your-homes-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/what-can-photography-do-for-your-homes-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Focus on Product and Promotion When Prepping Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uFB8riahq1Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two of the four keys to marketing your home are product and promotion, and here&amp;rsquo;s how you can focus on each.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we know, product and promotion are two of the four keys to marketing your home (the others being pricing and distribution), but how can you make sure you focus on these two keys so that your home sells quickly and for top dollar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow along in the video above, I’ll show you how you can by using these tips.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;start with a clear palate, which means you need to declutter and depersonalize&lt;/strong&gt;. Remove any oversized furniture and pack up any personal items, knick-knacks, and fragile items. Also, remove your valuables and any items that aren’t going with you to your new home. Make sure you keep your countertops and surfaces clear of any portable electronics, and if you have a pet, try to minimize any evidence of their presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to your deck and patio areas, bring the outside in by laying down some carpet and sitting up tables and chairs. Don’t tell buyers you have a great outdoor space—show them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your home’s marketing should happen both online and offline.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-focus-on-product-and-promotion-when-prepping-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your home’s marketing should happen both online and offline.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t cheap out. Hire professionals to help you do the job. We have professional stagers and photographers on our team who would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;if you really want to turn your home sale into a blockbuster, you have to promote it well in advance&lt;/strong&gt;. Can you imagine if the producers of the next Star Wars film only started promoting it after it hit theaters? In this regard, your home’s marketing should happen both online and offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about how to market your home or you have any other real estate questions, feel free to call or email me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-focus-on-product-and-promotion-when-prepping-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-focus-on-product-and-promotion-when-prepping-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quick &amp; Easy Tips to Prime Your Home for the Spring Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/orlhP5TCUSg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;The spring market has arrived, so here are a few key tips that will have your home ready to sell quickly and for top dollar once you list it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you prepare your home for the spring market? There are a few simple tips to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, keep in mind that &lt;strong&gt;nothing is more important than curb appeal&lt;/strong&gt;. In the video above, I’m at the home of one of my seller clients, and they’ve power-raked their lawn so that it will grow extra green in the coming weeks. They’ve also added fresh mulch to their landscaping. Besides doing these kinds of things, power washing your home’s exterior is always a good idea, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the home, the owners have done a great job handling another important task: &lt;strong&gt;cleaning and decluttering&lt;/strong&gt;. Specifically, don’t forget to clear the countertops in your kitchen and bathrooms. In general, do whatever you can to show off the master bedroom, master bathroom, and the kitchen area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each room, the beds should be made and the closets should only be half full. The goal is to show off how much storage you have, so pack up all your winter clothes and store them away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Do whatever you can to show off the master bedroom, master bathroom, and the kitchen area.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/quick-easy-tips-to-prime-your-home-for-the-spring-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Do whatever you can to show off the master bedroom, master bathroom, and the kitchen area.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the windows, they should be cleaned from both the inside and the outside. This brightens everything up and enhances the home’s cleanliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you have a great deck, don’t be afraid to show it off—sweep the floor, bring out your furniture, and clean everything off. Also, don’t forget to power-rake your backyard just like you did your front yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These tasks might seem like a hassle in the short term, but they’ll pay huge dividends down the line&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact us for more information, or to receive a guide on how to prepare your home for sale for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about preparing your home for the spring market or you have any other real estate questions for me, feel free to call or email me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/quick-easy-tips-to-prime-your-home-for-the-spring-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/quick-easy-tips-to-prime-your-home-for-the-spring-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A SWOT Analysis of the 2019 Calgary Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/R3yPKTOBvQc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a SWOT analysis of the Calgary real estate market&amp;mdash;that is, identifying its strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats, as well as what they&amp;rsquo;ll mean to you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Calgary Real Estate Board released their 2019 forecast a few weeks ago, and in the past, I haven’t been in full alignment with the numbers they’ve put out. Last year, they predicted 0% growth, whereas I saw house prices fall 2% and apartment prices fall 5%. This year, however, I think we’re more in line with the Board’s predictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s first take a look at what happened in 2018:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detached home&lt;/strong&gt; sales dropped 15.95% and prices dropped 1.45%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apartment&lt;/strong&gt; sales dropped 7.24% and prices fell 2.70%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attached home&lt;/strong&gt; sales dropped 15.43% and prices decreased by 1.49%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the City of Calgary overall&lt;/strong&gt;, there was a 14.61% drop in sales and a 1.52% decrease in prices. As always, putting too much stock in averages can be dangerous—if your head is in the oven and your feet are in the freezer, your average temperature would be okay, but you’d be dead anyway. Perspective does matter when it comes to analyzing these figures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, as I said, we’re more in alignment with predicted trends. Overall in Calgary, home prices dropped 2.35%, which makes this the fourth consecutive year of price decreases in our city. That constitutes a decline of about 9% since 2014; those who purchased their homes in 2014 will be the most affected by the current market conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this happening? Well, in addition to oil prices and the uncertainty of the political environment, &lt;strong&gt;interest rates are a big factor&lt;/strong&gt;. Not only have interest rates been creeping up, but when the stress test came into effect on January 1 of last year, it was the equivalent of having a 2% increase in interest rates—this really reduces people’s buying power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is negatively impacting home prices in 2019?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The energy sector and the economy are continuing to soften.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consumer confidence is down. People aren’t certain about their real estate prospects, and when people aren’t certain, they either fight, flee, or freeze—a lot of people are freezing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The number of good-paying jobs continues to decrease.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The lending market is tightening rules as interest rates continue to rise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The housing supply continues to rise, and when that happens, prices decrease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Overall in Calgary, home prices dropped 2.35%, which makes this the fourth consecutive year of price decreases in Calgary.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/a-swot-analysis-of-the-2019-calgary-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Overall in Calgary, home prices dropped 2.35%, which makes this the fourth consecutive year of price decreases in Calgary.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;the increasing population and net migration to Calgary are working in our favor&lt;/strong&gt;. Many immigrants who come begin by renting for a couple years before buying homes, which contributes to the decreasing vacancy rates over the past year. This creates opportunity for investors: If you can buy for less and your vacancy rates are decreasing, your rates will begin to increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other opportunities to be had, as well, if you’re looking at moving up or down. Right now, properties—especially detached homes between $350,000 and $450,000—are really hot. We’re even generating multiple offers in some cases; though it may take two or three sometimes, we’re still getting the job done. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re someone who owns a home in that hot zone and wants to move up to a higher-priced home, then that market is softer and you can get a better deal&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking at moving down, the condominium market is softer, and &lt;strong&gt;there are better deals there than ever&lt;/strong&gt;. The gap that you’re paying is actually smaller; if you remove your personal reservations about selling your house for less and look at your net numbers, you’ll see that there are some pretty significant savings and opportunities that we haven’t seen in Calgary for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What threats might present themselves if the 2019 predictions don’t come true?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pipelines/energy sector. If major employers move into the area or leave it, that will affect the market.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employment. Jobs are the biggest driver of real estate trends.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consumer confidence. People’s reservations and optimism definitely affect the market.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interest rates/lending markets. We’re expecting interest rates to creep up, but not much, since it’s an election year. Again, rising interest rates do reduce buying power.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Government. With this year being an election year, there’s some uncertainty in the market. A lot of people may be waiting to see what happens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all of these factors are important, they all take a long time to shift. If you need help reaching your real estate goals, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’ll help you with your own customized SWOT analysis to help you solve your problems and realize your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/a-swot-analysis-of-the-2019-calgary-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/a-swot-analysis-of-the-2019-calgary-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Renovation Mistakes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QIyOU-LfKUo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what to avoid during your home renovation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When renovating your home, there are a lot of things that can go wrong. Joining me today is &lt;strong&gt;Ian Galvin of Velao Projects&lt;/strong&gt;, a home restoration and remodeling company. Ian has over 30 years of residential construction experience, and we’ll be discussing three of the biggest mistakes you can make during a home renovation. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s what to avoid doing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Not hiring a competent design professional&lt;/strong&gt;. Some services both design and build while others do not, so it’s important to find out what you’re getting. Who is going to build the project? Who is going to advise them? You want everything laid out for you from the beginning: What your countertops will be made of, the colors of cabinets, the type of wood, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Being your own supplier&lt;/strong&gt;. Problems arise when you provide your own products for others to install. If there’s a mistake, what happens? Who looks after you if something is broken? That’s between you and your contractor, and it can be a messy situation to navigate. It’s advised to use an outside supplier to avoid the issues that can arise from supplying your own products, especially during larger projects. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Not asking enough questions&lt;/strong&gt;. Don’t ever assume things are going smoothly. You want to visit the project and get updates on its progress. Make arrangements with your contractor to review the project periodically so you can catch things before it’s too late. Things can move very quickly during a renovation, so fixing problems before they grow is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make arrangements with your contractor to review the project periodically.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/3-renovation-mistakes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make arrangements with your contractor to review the project periodically.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a specific license for Alberta contractors that allows them to handle the process of advanced payment. So if they ask for advanced payment, &lt;strong&gt;ask for the license&lt;/strong&gt;. Beware of large payments unless they are defined—front-end draws can be substantial if there are a lot of materials to pre-order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more information on preparing for a renovation or have any questions, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/3-renovation-mistakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/3-renovation-mistakes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
