<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Dave Friedman Team - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://davefriedmancoaching.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 15:07:07 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 15:07:07 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Story Behind Building Our Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ola_0999bCA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting as a solo agent, I was eventually able to make real estate a lucrative business. However by the end of my first breakout year, I was isolated from friends and family and enjoyed life less than when I was only making $40,000; something had to change. In today’s interview with Lars Hedenborg, I share my journey of building the Dave Friedman Team, and explain the world-class model I built it around that affords agents real opportunities for growth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:23—Dave reflects on his breakout year in real estate, going from 30 to 60 transactions &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:42—The problems with success: How Dave sought to revolutionize the industry model &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:40—Explaining the Dave Friedman Team mantra and structure &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:57—How the Friedman Team culture and the ‘seven Fs’ compare to other real estate teams that are disorganized and loose-knit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:50—The opportunities available for those interested in joining the Friedman Team &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15:00—The ‘why’ behind the Dave Friedman vision; helping others succeed and manage life with work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18:24—How to handle growth on your team and elevate team members &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:10—What the training process looks like on the Dave Friedman Team &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24:30—Anecdotes of success; wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have real estate-related questions for me, or you’re interested in buying or selling a home, please reach out by phone or email. My team and I are always happy to hear from you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 11:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/the-story-behind-building-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/the-story-behind-building-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking to Grow Your Real Estate Career?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8u7ftuU0Doo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got an exciting announcement to make. &lt;strong&gt;This month, we are looking for two special people to join us on The Dave Friedman Team.&lt;/strong&gt; A real estate license is required, but the opportunity here is huge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first open position we have is for a buyer’s specialist. The total target income is a minimum of $100,000 and easily over $200,000 for those who want to get after it. It’s an exciting opportunity where you can generate new business every day, meet with buyers, and gain their trust to work with you. Our team structure will also help you get more free time in your schedule. &lt;strong&gt;You’ll make more money by working less than you would as a solo agent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A real estate license is required, but the opportunity is huge.%20http://davefriedmancoaching.com/looking-to-grow-your-real-estate-career.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A real estate license is required, but the opportunity is huge.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second open position is for a market specialist. This person works with our buyer’s specialist and the buyer. They show the buyers all the homes they want to take a look at, which allows the specialist to spend more time generating business or just relaxing. &lt;strong&gt;The target income here is between $75,000 and $85,000.&lt;/strong&gt; This position will also attend closings and inspections while showing homes to all of our buyers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re interested in either of these positions or know someone who might be, reach out ASAP.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re making our selections over the next few weeks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 11:03:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/looking-to-grow-your-real-estate-career.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/looking-to-grow-your-real-estate-career.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interested in Joining One of Charleston’s Top Real Estate Teams?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hDQM78Y7cxg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dave Friedman Team has continued to grow, and because of that, we’re looking to make a few more key hires to help us maintain that growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m also excited to announce that I’m personally going to be training these new hires to make sure that they are rockstars in the industry and have the right skills, knowledge, habits, and attitude in order to be successful.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason that so many of our clients have been so satisfied with our level of service is that that’s a big focus of ours. We’re looking for folks who align with that customer-first mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re looking for folks who align with our customer-first mindset.%20http://davefriedmancoaching.com/interested-in-joining-one-of-charlestons-top-real-estate-teams.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re looking for folks who align with our customer-first mindset.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right now, we’re looking to hire a lead listing specialist and two buyer’s agents.&lt;/strong&gt; There is an opportunity right now for a new hire to serve 126 new clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’ve ever thought about joining a team or wondered about what joining a team can do for you, we’d love to chat with you and get to know you.&lt;/strong&gt; Feel free to reach out to us on our website &lt;a href=&quot;https://davefriedmancoaching.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, where you can learn more about our open positions, or reach out to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#067;&amp;#104;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#097;&amp;#064;&amp;#100;&amp;#097;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#102;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#067;&amp;#104;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#097;&amp;#064;&amp;#100;&amp;#097;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#102;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 11:55:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/interested-in-joining-one-of-charlestons-top-real-estate-teams.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/interested-in-joining-one-of-charlestons-top-real-estate-teams.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Expanding Our Team, and We Want You!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/koqS73MHZFY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our goal for 2019 is to achieve a 50% growth in our business, &lt;strong&gt;we need to find some great, motivated agents and staff to help bolster our ranks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agents have reached out to us, speaking of how they were unable to reach their goals in 2018. No matter how experienced in real estate you are, you can always use a helping hand. We’d like to offer one to you through a variety of new positions we have open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A listing agent.&lt;/strong&gt; The listing agent’s primary role is to go out into the market and meet with sellers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A licensed closing coordinator.&lt;/strong&gt; The closing coordinator helps agents from contract to close. We prefer our coordinators to be licensed so they can help with repair negotiations, post-occupancy agreements, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Four inside sales staff.&lt;/strong&gt; In this new role that we’re currently developing, we’re looking to coach four individuals into becoming professional sales consultants who can help to further grow our business.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A director of lead generation.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re looking for someone to replace me in this role so I can better focus on coaching the new department.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know would be interested in any of these positions, feel free to reach out to us to learn more. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/were-expanding-our-team-and-we-want-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/were-expanding-our-team-and-we-want-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Hosting a Mastermind and Helping With Hurricane Relief</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LHtiegJYbfY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got two different things to share with you today. &lt;strong&gt;The first is how you can personally sell 100 listings in one year.&lt;/strong&gt; We have two agents on our team who will sell just about 200 listings between them, so we are hosting a FREE agent mastermind to share how they are able to do that with our team’s leads, leverage, and systems. This mastermind will take place on September 28 from 11 a.m. until 2 p.m. All agents from all brokerages are invited to join us at this free mastermind. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/charleston-agent-mastermind-how-to-focus-on-listings-in-a-shift-tickets-50232513801&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RSVP here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second thing I wanted to talk about was our Hurricane Florence relief efforts.&lt;/strong&gt; Some of us stayed around after the evacuation and bought a lot of water, supplies, and more that we don’t need right now but others do. We’ll be donating those, and we invite you to donate any supplies you might have to our office. We’re going to get a truck together to ship those items to North Carolina to people in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The mastermind is on September 28 from 11 a.m. until 2 p.m.%20http://davefriedmancoaching.com/were-hosting-a-mastermind-and-helping-with-hurricane-relief.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The mastermind is on September 28 from 11 a.m. until 2 p.m.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you know anyone who might be interested in the mastermind or in dropping some supplies off at our office, please feel free to share this with them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 12:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/were-hosting-a-mastermind-and-helping-with-hurricane-relief.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/were-hosting-a-mastermind-and-helping-with-hurricane-relief.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Looking for a Career Opportunity Like This?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m9FCFvyqivE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are growing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…And, we are looking for a few great team members to join our rockstar sales team!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you, or someone you know, is looking for the right career opportunity in sales and/or real estate, &lt;strong&gt;we want to talk to you.&lt;/strong&gt; We are actively building a team of &lt;em&gt;INSIDE SALES AGENTS&lt;/em&gt; to help us generate new business for our agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the video above to learn how you can make 6-figures in your first year! In fact, we are so confident in your ability to achieve these goals, that we will even GUARANTEE you will make $90k in twelve months after you complete our paid 90-day training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are we looking to hire?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highly-motivated individuals with a passion to grow their career&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team players who are willing to work in our Mount Pleasant call center to find new business (Monday-Friday shifts available + occasional Saturday shift)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sales or service professionals who are excited to help our clients find their dream home or market their existing house&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fun, energetic individuals who want join Charleston’s favorite real estate team (as voted by the readers of &lt;em&gt;The Post&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;Courier&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No prior experience or real estate license required!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply today at &lt;a href=&quot;https://davefriedmancoaching.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;davefriedmancoaching.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 10:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/are-you-looking-for-a-career-opportunity-like-this.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/are-you-looking-for-a-career-opportunity-like-this.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Secret to Our Open House Success</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LpiywJxgHbI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a lot of agents ask me recently about how we have such success with our mega open houses, so I wanted to explain our strategy today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start advertising for our open houses about a week in advance. &lt;strong&gt;When we decide to hold an open house, the home has to be right.&lt;/strong&gt; It has to have awesome curb appeal, and be within a few miles of some major traffic areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is the marketing. We start that one week in advance on all the major websites. We have our ISAs circle prospect the neighborhood, let the neighbors know, and we send some direct mail pieces out as well. &lt;strong&gt;We also do a lot of email marketing to our database of over 60,000 in addition to social media marketing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the day of the open house, the most critical thing is that we put out a lot of signs. We hire couriers to go out and place signs, so all our agents have to do is show up to the open house, smile, and create some great relationships with some future prospects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ve had over 85 potential clients register at one of our open houses.%20http://davefriedmancoaching.com/the-secret-to-our-open-house-success.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve had over 85 potential clients register at one of our open houses.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even if nobody buys the home or makes an offer,  you’ll still have the opportunity to work with some new buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; We average about one new buyer per open house who actually ends up doing business and closing on a purchase with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the open house is done, the couriers take down the signs, and you can follow up with all of the great contacts you made at the open house. &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;’ve had over 85 people register with us at one of these open houses before.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open houses are still useful in today’s market and can really help you take your business to the next level. If you want to learn more about our strategy or if you just have any questions, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email today. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/the-secret-to-our-open-house-success.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/the-secret-to-our-open-house-success.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why My Team Uses Trello and We Recommend That You Do Too</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T21ehL7jlG0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is Trello? Why do we at the Dave Friedman Team swear by it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trello is a simple and accessible web-based operations tool we use to manage all of our transactions. But how does it work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time one of our agents sets an appointment (or an ISA sets an appointment for them), our operations team creates a card on Trello that details important information about the client the appointment is for. They also attach to the card whichever agent or ISA set the appointment. Once the agent meets with the client and they sign a buyer agency or listing agency agreement, they can then move that card from “set” to “met” to “signed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The card can then be moved to our “active listing” or “active buyer” board. When it moves to one of these boards, a whole checklist of tasks (e.g., taking pictures of the home) gets added to it that helps us help that client. In addition, our operations team does all kinds of customer service tasks on behalf of our agents so that they can focus on home sales and develop more business. Every time our operations team checks off a task box on that card, the corresponding agent is notified every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Trello is free, so you know it’s the right price.%20http://davefriedmancoaching.com/why-my-team-uses-trello-and-we-recommend-that-you-do-too.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Trello is free, so you know it’s the right price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the client goes under contract, their card gets moved from the active listing or active buyer board to the “contract to close” board. Once it gets moved there, the agent is continuously notified as more tasks (e.g., home inspections) get checked off until closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it all happens through this amazing operations tool. &lt;strong&gt;I highly recommend you check out Trello.&lt;/strong&gt; If you need more examples of how we use Trello to facilitate or home buying and home purchasing processes, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to share them with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, just call or email me anytime if you have any questions. I look forward to speaking with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 13:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/why-my-team-uses-trello-and-we-recommend-that-you-do-too.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/why-my-team-uses-trello-and-we-recommend-that-you-do-too.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Introduction to Some Great Goal-Setting Workbooks</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6rEdoTBM0pY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about a great workbook and planner written by Lars Hedenborg that can help you reach the goals you’ve set for yourself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Below, I’ve sectioned off the highlights from today’s video:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:20- How this workbook will help you think about where you are right now and where you want to take your life.&lt;br /&gt;1:15 - Why my team loved this workbook so much.&lt;br /&gt;2:00 - Introducing the “Intensive Workshop” workbook.&lt;br /&gt;3:20 - Session 1: Putting your life first.&lt;br /&gt;4:02 - Questions what will help you understand your “why.”&lt;br /&gt;8:53 - Exercises to help you identify what you don’t want in your life and what you do want in your life.&lt;br /&gt;9:36 - An exercise to help you identify your priorities and what’s in your way.&lt;br /&gt;10:08 - Writing your own eulogy.&lt;br /&gt;10:43 - Writing your purpose statement and your personal goals.&lt;br /&gt;11:39 - Switching over to “The Business Freedom Planner.”&lt;br /&gt;13:38 - Questions that will help you identify your personal and professional goals this quarter.&lt;br /&gt;14:15 - The Business Freedom Planner’s five P’s: planning, priorities, projects, potential, and positive focus.&lt;br /&gt;14:45 - Bridging the gap between the results you’re committed to creating and the results you’ve produced in the past.&lt;br /&gt;15:04 - How to make room for the “Big Rocks” in your bucket this quarter.&lt;br /&gt;18:44 - Organizing and scheduling your five P’s for the entire 13 weeks of your quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This workbook and planner are a great way to stay on top of your goals%20http://davefriedmancoaching.com/an-introduction-to-some-great-goal-setting-workbooks.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This workbook and planner are a great way to stay on top of your goals”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re interested in using this workbook and planner, just get in touch with me and I’ll send them to you&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 10:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/an-introduction-to-some-great-goal-setting-workbooks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/an-introduction-to-some-great-goal-setting-workbooks.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Answering Your Questions About Zillow as a Lead Source</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oq0wxIQbg_8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been getting a lot of questions about  Zillow, including whether I use it to purchase leads, what kind of ROI it brings, and whether the site is worthwhile as an advertising tool at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zillow is a great, user-friendly platform, but it does have some drawbacks. It doesn’t update in real time, for instance. &lt;strong&gt;There are a lot of listings our buyer clients might find on there that are shown as active on the site despite already actually being under contract or closed.&lt;/strong&gt; This can cause a lot of frustration for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for whether it’s worth it to purchase leads on Zillow, it depends on your market. I can tell you that if you visit the site’s advertising portal, it’ll actually show you the availability for each ZIP code as well as ROI projections based on how much you spend. I’ve found that these ROI calculations are pretty accurate. They have a lot of data to draw upon. According to Zillow, the average Realtor who purchases ZIP code leads through their site will see a 3% to 4% conversion rate. In other words, an agent purchasing a hundred leads would end up closing on three to four of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Zillow representatives have even claimed to see a conversion rate of up to 10%. This is fantastic, but you would really have to work your leads to see such high conversion. Having said that, the ROI Zillow estimates you will make on a specific ZIP code is based on a few different factors.  &lt;strong&gt;It’s based on the average price point for the area and also the assumption that you are seeing a conversion rate of 3% or 4%.&lt;/strong&gt;In addition, it also depends on how many leads you’re purchasing and how much those leads cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our area, the average ROI that is shown across local ZIP codes is usually about 2.2x to 3.5x. The more expensive the ZIP code, the higher the cost per lead is. Consumers in these more affluent areas, though, may be more careful about giving out personal information and therefore more difficult to reach. It can be easier to convert leads in ZIP codes with lower price points, but you have to convert more leads to make the same amount of money when working with lower price points as opposed to higher ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The ROI you are willing to earn in your business is completely up to you.%20http://davefriedmancoaching.com/answering-your-questions-about-zillow-as-a-lead-source.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The ROI you are willing to earn in your business is completely up to you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ROI you are willing to earn in your business is completely up to you. &lt;strong&gt;It’s all relative to the lead sources you could, or already do, invest in.&lt;/strong&gt; However, returns look much different for single agents versus teams. Let’s say an average team will pay out 50% of their commissions to an agent. If that commission check is $10,000 and the ROI is 3x. If you’re investing $3,300 into 16 Zillow leads and you’re able to convert one, that $10,000 commission check is essentially a 3x return for a single agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if a team owner invests $3,300 into 16 Zillow leads and converts one, this is a pretty high conversion. The $10,000 commission check is then split between the agent and the team owner. So the agent gets $5,000 and the team leader gets $5,000. But if you look at the true revenue, which subtracts expenses from the net total, your ROI ends up only being 1.5x. &lt;strong&gt;In other words, you would be spending $3,300 to be making approximately $5,000 in total. For most teams, this simply isn’t worth it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of lead sources out there that can bring returns as high as 30x to 40x. A source that brings you a consistent rate of return is the obvious choice. It doesn’t make sense to allocate your resources into an investment that brings smaller returns. If you do plan on investing in Zillow, make sure you negotiate with them on getting either your 10 most expensive or 10 most recent listings for free. Getting the ROI on ZIP code leads from Zillow is all about striking an equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 10:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://davefriedmancoaching.com/answering-your-questions-about-zillow-as-a-lead-source.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://davefriedmancoaching.com/answering-your-questions-about-zillow-as-a-lead-source.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
