<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>Our mission at The John Schuster Group is to be your best resource for Twin Cities real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The John Schuster Group, your professional Twin Cities Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 13:52:31 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 13:52:31 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join The John Schuster Group at the 2019 Home Seller Forum moderated by Paul Douglas</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lXpKarBbpc4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnschustergroup.com/home-seller-forum.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.johnschustergroup.com/home-seller-forum.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing the impact that having a quality real estate team on your side can have. To illustrate this, I recently brought on Paul Douglas and Jordana Green from WCCO Radio—two friends and past clients of mine to talk about their experience working with the John Schuster Group. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;According to Paul, the decision to work with us not only solved his real estate needs, but also resolved some marital tension.&lt;/strong&gt; Before partnering with the John Schuster Group, Paul and his wife were working with another agent. Unfortunately, this agent did a poor job. Things just weren’t working out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The uncertainty and ambiguity they faced while working with this agent created so much stress that the experience began to put a strain on their relationship. Thankfully, as I mentioned before, all was resolved when they turned to us for help. We were able to successfully guide them through their transaction and, as a result, help reduce the tension that had grown in their marriage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jordana had a similar story to share. She had also listed with another agent before coming to our team for help, and, like Paul, found that things just weren’t working out. Worse still, the agent wouldn’t let her out of the contract—leaving her to suffer for six months with no offers on her home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When the six-month contract was up, Jordana decided to come to the John Schuster Group.&lt;/strong&gt; Her experience with us couldn’t have been more different from what she faced with her previous agent. She received multiple offers almost immediately and within just three weeks was under contract with a great buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We are constantly striving to help people just like them meet and exceed their real estate goals.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/join-the-john-schuster-group-at-the-2019-home-seller-forum-moderated-by-paul-douglas.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We are constantly striving to help people just like them meet and exceed their real estate goals.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team is so happy to have been able to help Paul and Jordana, and theirs are just two of the many success stories we help create all the time. We are constantly striving to help people just like them meet and exceed their real estate goals. Part of the way we do this is by hosting educational events like the Home Seller Forum we held last September, where sellers had the chance to learn about the resources and techniques necessary to succeed in our market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 120 people showed up to that event, so we’ve decided to host a few more. If you’re looking to learn how to maximize your home selling success, join us on either January 23 or January 24 at the Plymouth Community Center, or on January 26 at the Braemar Golf Course. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Space is limited, so don’t delay in reserving your spot. You can register &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnschustergroup.com/home-seller-forum.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for the date and time that works best for you. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 15:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/join-the-john-schuster-group-at-the-2019-home-seller-forum-moderated-by-paul-douglas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/join-the-john-schuster-group-at-the-2019-home-seller-forum-moderated-by-paul-douglas.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why We’re Thankful for You This Year</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uwd50Yplu_o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’re all gearing up for the holiday season, I just wanted to take a moment to acknowledge all of our supporters and raving fans. We hope you and your family have an absolutely fabulous Thanksgiving and we wish you the best this holiday season. Gratitude is huge for our team, so we just wanted to let you know how thankful we are for your trust and support. I’m personally thankful for our amazing team and the fabulous year we’ve had in 2018. From the bottom of my heart and my team’s heart: Thank you and have a happy Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 16:11:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/why-were-thankful-for-you-this-year.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/why-were-thankful-for-you-this-year.html</guid>
        
        <category>Happy Thanksgiving</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Way That The John Schuster Group Is Giving Back</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GdktnsXKOqs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, we’ve talked about how important gratitude is to us at The John Schuster Group. That’s why we’ve partnered with Move Forward Minnesota, a great organization that is working to combat suburban youth homelessness. &lt;strong&gt;We have committed to giving everyone who comes to that organization needing a place to live a brand-new bed. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the video above starting at the :50 mark, you can see just how big of an impact that our donation has made to Move Forward Minnesota and their clients. We’re happy to help them be able to serve such a great cause. We appreciate the kind words that the team over at Move Forward Minnesota had for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ve committed to providing a bed for all those who need it.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/one-way-that-the-john-schuster-group-is-giving-back.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve committed to providing a bed for all those who need it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If any of you would like to help out this organization as well, they’re always looking for items such as bedding, kitchen utensils, and toiletries.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any questions for us or would like to donate, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 13:19:01 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/one-way-that-the-john-schuster-group-is-giving-back.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/one-way-that-the-john-schuster-group-is-giving-back.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Community</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Day at the Zoo Couldn’t Have Been Possible Without You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/osAdqR0YgPE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We want to thank everyone who attended our recent client appreciation event at the Minnesota Zoo.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/our-day-at-the-zoo-couldnt-have-been-possible-without-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We want to thank everyone who attended our recent client appreciation event at the Minnesota Zoo.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently had the pleasure of hosting our first ever client appreciation event at the Minnesota Zoo, and we want to thank everyone who showed up to help us celebrate. We had a great lunch, toured the zoo with all of our wonderful past clients, and did a live drawing for a free RCI vacation certificate. We had an absolute blast, and we’re grateful for your trust and your referrals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, if there’s ever anything we can do to help you achieve your real estate goals, don’t hesitate to reach out to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 15:37:58 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/our-day-at-the-zoo-couldnt-have-been-possible-without-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/our-day-at-the-zoo-couldnt-have-been-possible-without-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Our Transitioning Market Means</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/obVlKtACsnc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s okay, you can rest easy—our market’s not headed for another crash. However, I believe we’re starting to transition into more of a balanced market, and there are certain trends buyers and sellers need to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past seven years, we’ve seen aggressive price appreciation. If you bought a home in 2011 or 2012, you’ve probably built up a lot of equity in your home. The great thing is that most of the sales taking place in today’s market are traditional sales. There aren’t as many lender-mediated sales, short sales, or foreclosures happening anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we’re already seeing is our annual seasonal slowdown. Inventory is growing, so &lt;strong&gt;if you’re a seller, your home has to be in turnkey condition when you bring it to the market&lt;/strong&gt; because buyers have more supply to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need to know the right time to enter the market.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/what-our-transitioning-market-means.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You need to know the right time to enter the market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a buyer, this transition is good news because, as I just said, you’ll see more inventory and have more homes to choose from.&lt;/strong&gt; You need to be careful watching the market, though, because interest rates are on the rise. Every 1% increase in interest rates decreases your buying power by 11% or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In either case, you need to know the right time to enter the market. If you’re a buyer, we’d love to meet with you for a buyer consultation so we can come up with a game plan. You can also visit our website if you’d like to search all the latest listing from the Twin Cities area. If you’re a seller and you’re wondering what your home is worth in this market, we’d love to meet with you as well so we can provide you with a detailed equity analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about our market or you’d like to meet with us to get started on accomplishing your real estate goals, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We look forward to speaking with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 14:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/what-our-transitioning-market-means.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/what-our-transitioning-market-means.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join Us for Our 1st Annual Client Appreciation Event at the Minnesota Zoo</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XL-8l5add_g?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Will you join us October 6 for a fun, free event at the Minnesota Zoo?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT INFORMATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where&lt;/u&gt;: Shady Oaks Picnic Shelter&lt;br /&gt;&lt;u&gt;When&lt;/u&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picnic&lt;/strong&gt; [10:30 am - 12:30 pm]  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lunch&lt;/strong&gt; [11:30 am - 12:30 pm] &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RCI Certificate Drawing&lt;/strong&gt; [12:00 pm]
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;**You must be present to win**&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To RSVP to the event, click &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnschustergroup.com/zoo.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;We’ve got exciting news to announce: You’re invited to the John Schuster Group’s first annual client appreciation event at the Minnesota Zoo! Join us on Saturday, October 6 for this free event, which is our way of thanking you for your business and trust over the years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;From 10:30 a.m. to 12:30 p.m., we’ll be hosting a picnic lunch with ice cream, desserts, and more at the Shady Oaks Picnic Shelter. Lunch will be served from 11:30 a.m. to 12:30 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Also, in addition to your free passes, parking, and catered lunch, we’ll be giving away one free RCI certificate, good for a one-week vacation for you and your family. The drawing is at 12:00 p.m., and you must be present to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You’re invited to the John Schuster Group’s first annual client appreciation event at the Minnesota Zoo!%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/join-us-for-our-1st-annual-client-appreciation-event-at-the-minnesota-zoo.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You’re invited to the John Schuster Group’s first annual client appreciation event at the Minnesota Zoo!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;To ensure your entry to this great event, &lt;strong&gt;make sure to RSVP by September 23. Space is limited.&lt;/strong&gt; To RSVP, simply reach out to us by phone, email, or by clicking &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnschustergroup.com/zoo.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. To pick up your passes, visit us at the Shady Oaks Picnic Shelter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Again, &lt;strong&gt;thank you so much for supporting us, and we hope to see you on October 6. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to seeing you at this great upcoming event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/join-us-for-our-1st-annual-client-appreciation-event-at-the-minnesota-zoo.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/join-us-for-our-1st-annual-client-appreciation-event-at-the-minnesota-zoo.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learn How to Maximize Your Home Sale at Our Upcoming Forum</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3tmmZ12VnAE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking of selling your home in the next two years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we’ve got great news. &lt;strong&gt;You’re officially invited to a free home seller’s forum we’re hosting at Braemar Golf Course on September 11 and September 12.&lt;/strong&gt; The September 11 session will start at 6:45 p.m., and the September 12 session will start at 11:30 a.m. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to your home sale, small details can make a huge difference and make you thousands of dollars more. We want to teach you how to get the most money for your home in our current market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We want to teach you how to get the most money for your home in our current market.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/learn-how-to-maximize-your-home-sale-at-our-upcoming-forum.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We want to teach you how to get the most money for your home in our current market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moderator for this forum will be Paul Douglas, who turned to us when he needed a home to sell. Paul himself taped a special message attached to the video above. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space is limited and seats are filling up fast, so &lt;strong&gt;click on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnschustergroup.com/home-seller-forum.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to register.&lt;/strong&gt; We hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions at all, feel free to call or email us anytime. We’d be happy to help you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/learn-how-to-maximize-your-home-sale-at-our-upcoming-forum.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/learn-how-to-maximize-your-home-sale-at-our-upcoming-forum.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips From WCCO Dave Lee on Preparing Your Spring 2019 Listing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B7J5wFh3_OA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring is one of the best times to sell your home quickly and for top dollar. If you’re thinking of listing next spring, it isn’t too soon to start getting ready. The season may seem far off, but now is actually the perfect time to prepare. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Well, consider this: &lt;strong&gt;Frost and snow from the winter and early spring months don’t do a lot of favors for your curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt; If you wait to take pictures of your listing until right before you sell in the spring, you could be stuck with drab, grey photos. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly why now is the time to prepare for your spring sale. Right now, our team is offering free photography and staging services to anyone looking to list this coming spring. And for sellers who live on an acreage or lake, we also offer drone filming services. &lt;strong&gt;This way, you can capture photos and videos of your property while the landscape is still green&lt;/strong&gt; and the skies are still blue. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our team has all the processes in place necessary to help you maximize the equity in your home when it comes time to sell.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/tips-from-wcco-dave-lee-on-preparing-your-spring-2019-listing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our team has all the processes in place necessary to help you maximize the equity in your home when it comes time to sell.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would love to meet with you to sit down and discuss the ways you should prepare your home over the next five to six months. Our team has all the processes in place necessary to help you maximize the equity in your home when it comes time to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re thinking of selling your home in 2019, please reach out to us today.&lt;/strong&gt; We want to help you get your home in the best condition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 07:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/tips-from-wcco-dave-lee-on-preparing-your-spring-2019-listing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/tips-from-wcco-dave-lee-on-preparing-your-spring-2019-listing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Could You Be the Next Rockstar Agent to Join Our Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wXoHPa6wSik?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently sat down for an interview with one of our team’s rockstar agents, Jessica Wolleat, and I’d like to share some of what we spoke about with you today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica was born and raised in Minnesota, and has actually dreamed of a real estate career since she was a child. She was fascinated by homes and even grew up to get a degree in architecture from the University of Minnesota. All of this just solidified her desire to get into the world of real estate. &lt;strong&gt;Now she’s been working with our team for about two years and has absolutely loved it.    &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, she loves the fast-paced environment. “Everything can change in the blink of an eye,” says Jessica. But it’s the clients, Jessica added, is what she really loves about this industry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Jessica’s positive attitude is just the kind of outlook we’re looking for in new team members.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/could-you-be-the-next-rockstar-agent-to-join-our-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Jessica’s positive attitude is just the kind of outlook we’re looking for in new team members.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“To see clients happy is a really good feeling,” Jessica concluded.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team is so happy to have Jessica on board with us. We absolutely love her positive attitude. In fact, this is just the kind of outlook we’re looking for in new team members. Right now, our team is seeking talented and passionate individuals, so &lt;strong&gt;if you or anyone you know is interested in pursuing a career with us, we’d love to hear from you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you have any other questions, would like more information, or would like our help realizing your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/could-you-be-the-next-rockstar-agent-to-join-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/could-you-be-the-next-rockstar-agent-to-join-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Here Is to Life, Liberty, and the Pursuit of Happiness</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7MId4xyOelM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;242 years ago this July 4, our Founding Fathers took the first steps in creating American independence. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is during times such as these that we should reflect on the famed, familiar words of Thomas Jefferson: &lt;strong&gt;“We hold these truths to be self-evident: That all men are created equal;&lt;/strong&gt; that they are endowed by their creator with certain unalienable rights; that among these are life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We hope you’re able to spend this holiday celebrating life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/here-is-to-life-liberty-and-the-pursuit-of-happiness.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We hope you’re able to spend this holiday celebrating life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Fourth of July, we would like to encourage all of you to spend the holiday with family and friends in celebration of these values. Our team is so grateful for the bountiful opportunities provided to us as citizens of this great nation. And &lt;strong&gt;we’re also grateful for all of you, our clients, and your continued support.&lt;/strong&gt; Happy Fourth of July!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about real estate or would like to discuss your goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 06:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/here-is-to-life-liberty-and-the-pursuit-of-happiness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/here-is-to-life-liberty-and-the-pursuit-of-happiness.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
