<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Stern Team: Home Page</title>
    <description>Salt Lake City Utah best Realtors are on The Stern Team, led by Joshua Stern. Follow us for latest market info and be prepared to buy or sell real estate.</description>
    <link>http://sternteam.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sternteam.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 13:26:15 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 13:26:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Real Estate Numbers Along the Wasatch Front</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QEi7lveDkDI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re back with another update on the Wasatch Front real estate market. In the third quarter of 2019, we saw a significant jump in sales. &lt;strong&gt;Year to date, we’re up 2.1% with over 37,700 homes sold so far in 2019.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average price for all home types is over $383,000. At the same time last year, our average price was just over $354,000. That’s an 8.2% year-over-year increase, which is &lt;strong&gt;great news if you’re a homeowner looking to capitalize on your equity by selling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our average days on market along the Wasatch Front is 47 days—a 20% increase from the 39-day average we saw at this time last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Prices are rising, but so is our supply of homes.%20http://sternteam.org/the-latest-real-estate-numbers-along-the-wasatch-front.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Prices are rising, but so is our supply of homes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our overall inventory for all housing types is at a 3.8-month supply. Anything less than six months is considered a seller’s market. The market is still very good, but homes are taking slightly longer to sell. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third quarter also brought us some of the lowest interest rates we’ve seen in a few years. As we finish the third quarter, rates jumped up a bit, but are still fantastic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prices continue to go up, but there’s more inventory available.&lt;/strong&gt; Couple that with solid interest rates and we have a good market for buyers and sellers right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/the-latest-real-estate-numbers-along-the-wasatch-front.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/the-latest-real-estate-numbers-along-the-wasatch-front.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Becoming More Financially Responsible</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bBq3TlcsE_Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to improve your finances? Many do, but maybe you don’t know where to start. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, promoting your own financial health all starts with measuring some basic skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;learn how to budget.&lt;/strong&gt; Budgets can be boring, but they are the cornerstone of financial responsibility. They can help you no matter what the situation is, be it paying the bills, chipping away debt, saving for retirement, or buying a home. Budgeting can help you answer the dreaded question, “Where did all my money go!?” that you may ask yourself at the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you can’t afford it, don’t buy it.%20http://sternteam.org/5-tips-for-becoming-more-financially-responsible.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you can’t afford it, don’t buy it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;use credit cards correctly.&lt;/strong&gt; Credit cards can be a valuable financial tool that can help you build credit or repair poor credit. Just be sure to avoid getting caught in a bad cycle with credit cards; only buy what you can afford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;strong&gt;pay yourself first.&lt;/strong&gt; This seems impossible, but it’s incredibly important that you make sure to pay yourself first by transferring money into your savings account before paying any of your bills. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll also want to learn how to &lt;strong&gt;invest wisely.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether you invest in a small stock portfolio or you own your own home, learning how to invest is a keystone of your financial health and wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;live within your means.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t compare yourself to others, and if you can’t afford it, don’t buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about becoming more financially responsible or about real estate, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be glad to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/5-tips-for-becoming-more-financially-responsible.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/5-tips-for-becoming-more-financially-responsible.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Things to Remember When Building a New Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gDBCTOjy1BE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inventory has been shrinking recently, which has a large number of&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;buyers building new homes, instead. When buyers do this, though, they need to ensure that they’re being well-represented. There are three reasons this is so important: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The on-site agent is working for the builder.&lt;/strong&gt; The person you meet when you visit a model home may be perfectly pleasant and knowledgeable, but they aren’t there with your best interests in mind. Rather, they’re there to protect and advocate for the builder. So, given that the builder has an agent on their side, why wouldn’t you want one on yours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Many builders use their own purchase agreement.&lt;/strong&gt; Without professional training, interpreting such documents (which are often upwards of 30 to 40 pages long) can be difficult. This is yet another reason why having an agent working on your behalf is so critical. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The builder has an agent on their side, so why wouldn’t you want one on yours?%20http://sternteam.org/3-things-to-remember-when-building-a-new-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The builder has an agent on their side, so why wouldn’t you want one on yours?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Agents can offer a neutral perspective&lt;/strong&gt;. Buying a home is an emotional decision. After all, this is the place where you’re going to make memories and put down roots. With all of these things on your mind, trying to parse out the logistics of the purchase itself can be hard. An agent not only brings a high level of knowledge and experience to the table, but also a neutral perspective, which will help ensure you get the best possible deal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about this or any other real estate subject, or would like to learn how we can help you meet your own buying, selling, or investing goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/3-things-to-remember-when-building-a-new-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/3-things-to-remember-when-building-a-new-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Buy a New Home or Sell Your Old Home First?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9OYipvuTpO8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most home sellers are also homebuyers. Because of this, the inevitable dilemma of which transaction to complete first comes up. Buying first is ideal because it allows you to take your time and there are much fewer hoops to jump through. Most people can’t afford two mortgages at once, however, so selling first is a reality for many. In either case, there are plenty of different options that will lead to a smooth process. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/should-you-buy-a-new-home-or-sell-your-old-home-first.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/should-you-buy-a-new-home-or-sell-your-old-home-first.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who’s Responsible for Keeping a Property Show-Ready?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rG726jGGmT8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home sellers and their agents want their properties to remain show-ready at all times while they’re on the market; but ensuring that this is the case can be a chore—especially if said sellers have already moved out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whose job is it to pick up the newspaper, shovel the driveway, and keep the grass trimmed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it usually isn’t feasible for a seller who has already moved away to take care of these daily or weekly tasks. So whose shoulders does this home maintenance fall on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Until the property has sold, its condition remains the responsibility of the seller.%20http://sternteam.org/whos-responsible-for-keeping-a-property-show-ready.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Until the property has sold, its condition remains the responsibility of the seller.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, until the property has sold, its condition remains the responsibility of the seller. Buyers will lose interest and neighbors will become testy if your home becomes an eyesore. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t assume your real estate agent is your gardener or maid.&lt;/strong&gt; Even though they also have a vested interest in making sure your home sells quickly and at a high price, it isn’t their job to stay on top of its general upkeep. Some agents may be up to the task, but you shouldn’t presume this to be the case until you’ve had a candid discussion about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some agents may refuse to take responsibility for these tasks not because they mind doing the work, but because they don’t want to be blamed in case anything goes wrong. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, &lt;strong&gt;the best way to ensure a vacant home is well-maintained while its on the market is to hire relevant contractors or a property manager to take care of the necessary tasks.&lt;/strong&gt; Your agent will likely be happy to help coordinate the fine details so long as you, the seller, are the one taking bids and making payments. A good agent will also often have a network of vendors with whom they can connect their seller, if necessary. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that, &lt;strong&gt;no matter the situation, a quality real estate agent will have your best interests at heart&lt;/strong&gt; and will be more than willing to guide you through whatever obstacles you encounter during your home selling experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/whos-responsible-for-keeping-a-property-show-ready.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/whos-responsible-for-keeping-a-property-show-ready.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Q2 Stats From the Wasatch Front</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ke99nAMnVHM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do 2019’s second-quarter statistics say about the Wasatch Front market? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home sales are up 4% compared to last year, with over 13,000 single-family homes, townhomes, and condos being sold. Year to date, sales are down 2.5% with nearly 24,000 total homes being sold. The good news is, the average sale price for all home types has risen to $375,000. Last year during this time, it was $355,000. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re a homeowner looking to capitalize on your equity, you’re in fantastic shape. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year over year, the average days on market increased by 20% from 40 days to 49 days. Meanwhile, inventory for all housing types is at 4.7 months, which is still relatively low. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Moving forward, we expect to see a wild ride for mortgage rates, so the only question is whether they’ll be more or less advantageous for home shoppers.%20http://sternteam.org/the-latest-q2-stats-from-the-wasatch-front.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Moving forward, we expect to see a wild ride for mortgage rates, so the only question is whether they’ll be more or less advantageous for home shoppers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mortgage rates have taken a turn for the better, and it has everyone rushing to buy homes. Specifically, Freddie Mac says the average 30-year rate hit 3.82% in June, which is the lowest it’s been in two years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the best times in history to purchase or refinance, but will rates remain this low? President Trump’s pressure on the Federal Reserve plus low inflation and lackluster economic data has one commentator predicting that we’ll see the lowest rates ever in the next 12 months. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, we expect to see a wild ride for mortgage rates, so the only question is whether they’ll be more or less advantageous for home shoppers. As prices go up, we see more and more available inventory. &lt;strong&gt;When you couple this with stable interest rates, which should help affordability, we have conditions that favor buyers. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/the-latest-q2-stats-from-the-wasatch-front.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/the-latest-q2-stats-from-the-wasatch-front.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Key Trends Homebuyers &amp; Sellers Should Monitor in 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rg517LuBsiE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple truth is that markets are like the weather—you can’t predict with absolute certainty how they will act, but you can get a sense of the direction that the winds of change are pushing things. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The economic research team at Realtor.com pored over a wealth of housing data to come up with a forecast of what’s in store for 2019 on both the buyer and seller side. Four key trends came out of that report, and we’ll discuss them today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one thing, Realtor.com found that &lt;strong&gt;inventory, especially in the luxury market, will continue to swell.&lt;/strong&gt; For years now, buyer demand has far outpaced supply, and because of this, market inventory has been tight. In fact, inventory nationwide hit its lowest point in recorded history this past winter. And finally, we’re beginning to see a recovery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That recovery period is expected to continue into 2020, but we don’t expect inventory growth to go gangbusters—less than 7%, to be exact.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is welcome news for buyers who’ve been stuck on the sidelines until now, but sellers are left to confront a new reality: While nationwide inventory growth is shaping up to be modest, it’ll be another story in the upper price ranges. In these markets, most of the expected inventory growth will be derived from luxury homes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=First-time buyers will be met with challenges, but those looking to sell their home and purchase a higher-priced property will reap the dual benefit of greater equity and selection in 2019’s market.%20http://sternteam.org/4-key-trends-homebuyers-sellers-should-monitor-in-2019.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“First-time buyers will be met with challenges, but those looking to sell their home and purchase a higher-priced property will reap the dual benefit of greater equity and selection in 2019’s market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that sellers have been sitting pretty for a number of years. Could the scales be tipping in favor of buyers now? The answer is yes and no. Thanks to increased inventory, life will be a little easier for buyers shopping for a new home. The combination of rising mortgage rates and appreciation, however, doesn’t bode as well and means that buyer affordability will remain a major pain point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, &lt;strong&gt;millennial buyers will be the prevailing force in the market.&lt;/strong&gt; Thought to be the new kids on the block just a few years ago, millennials are now the biggest generational group of homebuyers, making up 45% of mortgages. In contrast, baby boomers and Gen-X’ers account for 17% and 37%, respectively. Some of those millennials are even in the market as move-up buyers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, first-time buyers will be met with challenges, but those looking to sell their home and purchase a higher-priced property will reap the dual benefit of greater equity and selection in 2019’s market.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions related to today’s topic or your real estate needs, please reach out to us. We hope to hear from you soon!      &lt;br /&gt;   &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/4-key-trends-homebuyers-sellers-should-monitor-in-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/4-key-trends-homebuyers-sellers-should-monitor-in-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Different Ways Real Estate Deals Fall Apart</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_3SCcZOReHM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying and selling real estate can be complicated and there are a lot of opportunities along the way for transactions to fall apart. &lt;strong&gt;Here are the primary reasons that real estate deals fall apart based on our experience:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Pre-contract deal-killers.&lt;/strong&gt; The first stage of a transaction occurs before an offer is even made. On the side of the seller, a few things could keep them from going through with a deal. They might change their mind after a lowball appraisal, a low offer, or a repair list that’s much too long. Overall, most of these pre-contract deal killers come from the buyer, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Post-contract deal-killers.&lt;/strong&gt; After there is an accepted purchase contract that’s signed, there is another list of potential problems that could arise and kill the deal. Most revolve around money, repairs, and who is going to fix or pay for them. Sometimes, however, buyers simply get cold feet because they didn’t do their homework up front. Maybe they weren’t prepared for a big to-do list or there were some larger issues uncovered during a home inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Buyers who made a contingent offer but were unable to sell.&lt;/strong&gt; Every home is sellable. However, some homes take longer to sell for a variety of reasons. One of the most common reasons a real estate deal falls through is that a potential buyer can’t sell their current home or buy their new home without selling it first. If you’re selling your home and receive a contingent offer, you should not count on that particular buyer shaking your hand at the closing table. Home sale contingent offers in real estate have a much higher risk of failing than offers that don’t have home sale contingencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The buyer is denied their financing or loan.&lt;/strong&gt; In a perfect world, every potential homebuyer with a pre-approval would get to the closing table, but this simply isn’t the case. Having a pre-approval letter is important for a buyer, but it doesn’t guarantee your mortgage will be fully funded. Until the closing occurs, a buyer isn’t guaranteed to receive a loan. There are situations, such as the buyer losing their job or experiencing health issues, that no loan officer can control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Pre-settlement walk-throughs.&lt;/strong&gt; The biggest issues here have to do with things being left behind, not being left behind, or fixtures or window coverings that should have been taken. Unknown utility liens and property taxes can pop up, too. For most of these problems, a bit of money or making a small change to the contract’s terms will fix the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you should know that &lt;strong&gt;about one in four real estate &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;contracts&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;that are accepted end up failing.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s a rather high number. This is why it’s important to work with a highly experienced real estate agent when navigating the home buying and selling process. Be aware of the common pitfalls of failed transactions, because that increases the odds that your deal won’t fall through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/5-different-ways-real-estate-deals-fall-apart.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/5-different-ways-real-estate-deals-fall-apart.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Do to Prepare Your Home for Sale?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/n_qVJ7yRJAw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to discuss six ways to get your home ready for sale this spring:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Let natural light in.&lt;/strong&gt; Open up your blinds, windows, and let that natural sunlight in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Renovate what’s outdated.&lt;/strong&gt; If your kitchen or bathroom is stuck in the 1980s, it’s time to freshen it up a bit to get top dollar for your home. Updated faucets, towel racks, and cabinets are things you can do even if you’re on a tight budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Think small with renovations.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t overdo it with expensive renovations. Instead of replacing all of your cabinets, just paint or replace the doors. If you’re going to spend money, spend it on curb appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Paint with whites and neutrals.&lt;/strong&gt; A fresh coat of paint is relatively inexpensive and an easy way to give your house a facelift. Keep the colors neutral so that buyers can better imagine the home as their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Fix anything that’s broken.&lt;/strong&gt; Repairs can take some time, but getting them out of the way allows you to sell your home much faster. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Pay attention to odors.&lt;/strong&gt; The smells inside your home can kill a home sale, and you may not even notice a lot of them. If you have pets, smoke, or regularly cook fragrant foods, consider getting your carpets freshly cleaned and adding a fresh coat of paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Let as much natural light in as possible.%20http://sternteam.org/what-can-you-do-to-prepare-your-home-for-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Let as much natural light in as possible.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate-related questions or needs that I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/what-can-you-do-to-prepare-your-home-for-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/what-can-you-do-to-prepare-your-home-for-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Developments From Our Wasatch Front Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_kkmCv5hAIo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do our first quarter statistics tell us about our Wasatch Front market? And how do these numbers stack up against last year’s Q1? We’ll answer both of those questions in today’s market update. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s jump right in: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By the end of 2019’s first quarter, our market had undergone an 11% decline in overall home sales.&lt;/strong&gt; The average home price, meanwhile, went up by a solid 5.6% over that same period. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to this point, the Wasatch Front has had more than 8,000 single-family homes, townhomes, and condos sell in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also through Q1 of 2019, the average sale price spanning all homes types along the Wasatch Front was around $342,185. We finished out the first quarter of 2018 at an average sale price of  $323,371—that’s nearly a year-over-year increase of 6%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the data point by point, t&lt;strong&gt;he average sale price for single-family homes in 2018’s first quarter rose by 5.06% to $369,382.&lt;/strong&gt; The average sale price for townhomes and condos soared by 11% to $258,110 in that same year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We may finally have a formula that tilts the scale toward buyers.%20http://sternteam.org/the-latest-developments-from-our-wasatch-front-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We may finally have a formula that tilts the scale toward buyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning our attention to average days on market, the average home is currently spending 53 days on market, which is a 10% increase from the 48-day average we saw last year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wasatch Front’s inventory for all housing types is at 4.6 months’ worth of supply. Although this is considered a low amount of inventory, anything that falls in the four- to six-month range is seen as a sign of market stability.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With ever-growing home prices comes a greater availability of inventory and coupled with stable interest rates that opens up buyer affordability, we may finally have a formula that tilts the scale toward buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final note, &lt;strong&gt;we saw some of the lowest interest rates we’ve had in a while by the conclusion of Q1 this year.&lt;/strong&gt; The Fed originally set the expectation that four or five rate increases were on the way this year, and after withdrawing that announcement and making new assertions that no increases were coming in 2019, the market responded favorably.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any real estate-related questions or needs, please get in touch with us. We’d be happy to help however we can! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/the-latest-developments-from-our-wasatch-front-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/the-latest-developments-from-our-wasatch-front-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
