<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Central Iowa Real Estate Video Blog with Misty Soldwisch</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Misty SOLDwisch Home Selling Team is to be your best resource for Central Iowa real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Misty SOLDwisch Home Selling Team, your professional Central Iowa Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 12:21:52 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 12:21:52 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buyers: Don’t Make These 3 Mistakes!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cn_9183KlSc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are three mistakes not to make if you’re in the home-buying process.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today Chuck Simmons from Motto Mortgage Midwest joins us to discuss the three main things you shouldn’t do if you’re in the process of buying a home. Some of these things may seem obvious, but many people don’t know the ins and outs of how the process works. Don’t get caught making one of these mistakes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t change jobs.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re getting a mortgage, job stability is a crucial factor. If you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; change jobs, let your lender know because there are many extra verifications needed. Not communicating leads to delays in your closing. Just wait a couple of weeks until you close on the house to change jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t get caught making one of these mistakes.%20http://localhost:4000/buyers-dont-make-these-3-mistakes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Don’t get caught making one of these mistakes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Don’t take on new debt.&lt;/strong&gt; People often get excited and buy new furniture for their new home right before closing, for example. Even if they won’t be making a payment for 18 months, we still have to stop the process, verify that debt, and build in a payment. In the worst scenarios, this can cause huge problems for buyers. Chuck had to call a client on Black Friday once and ask them to stop making purchases!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Don’t miss any payments.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t miss payments or pay them late. Keep showing your creditworthiness. We don’t have to pull credit again for four months, but if you’ve missed a payment during that time, it causes issues. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These blunders are why it’s so critical to work with an expert who educates you about the process, though occasionally we have to explain it again because some people don’t quite make the connection as to why this is such essential advice. The lesson from today: Keep your situation the same while you wait to close on a property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about these buyer errors or real estate in general, please reach out to me. I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mottomortgage.com/offices/midwest-west-des-moines/contact-the-simmons-hemer-team/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Motto Mortgage Midwest site here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 03:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buyers-dont-make-these-3-mistakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buyers-dont-make-these-3-mistakes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Central Iowa Real Estate Scoreboard: Episode 7</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mpe8-UqlL0I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are two easy ways to prepare your home for the real estate market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it’s time to prepare your home for the market, there are a couple of simple fixes that make a huge difference and get you more than your money back:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Make it sparkling clean.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the easiest way to improve your house for the market and the most crucial. For some, this may seem obvious, but others don’t realize just how much of a difference this makes. People generally also acquire a ton of stuff, so you must also depersonalize the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=‘Agreeable gray’ is the current go-to ultimate neutral paint color.%20http://localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-scoreboard-episode-7.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“‘Agreeable gray’ is the current go-to ultimate neutral paint color.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Paint.&lt;/strong&gt; The most popular colors right now are soft grays, and many are even moving to whites again (I know, five years ago that would have sounded crazy). “Agreeable gray” is the current go-to ultimate neutral paint color that stagers and builders use. If anything looks a bit dull or scuffed up, painting can help. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about preparing your house for the market or real estate in general, I’d love to speak with you. Call or email me at your convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 04:07:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-scoreboard-episode-7.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-scoreboard-episode-7.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Central Iowa Real Estate Scoreboard: Episode 6</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ugMiVo5uEPQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;On this episode, we’re focusing on multiple-offer strategies for sellers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are a home seller who is receiving multiple offers, it’s very common for your agent to reach back out to buyers to ask for their highest and best offer by a certain time frame. I try a different approach because I’m not the biggest fan of the sense of finality conveyed by this strategy. &lt;strong&gt;The approach I take involves going back to the buyers, letting them know that we have a multiple-offer situation, and asking if they’d like to make any adjustments to their offer before proceeding. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this method, we can counter any of the offers that come in. It doesn’t just have to be the highest-priced offer; I think that’s something a lot of people get caught up on. &lt;strong&gt;A lot of agents don’t explain to their clients that price isn’t the only thing that should be considered;&lt;/strong&gt; terms like the earnest money deposit or inspection period are very important, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about how to choose the best offer or compete against multiple buyers in this market, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 11:42:26 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-scoreboard-episode-6.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-scoreboard-episode-6.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Best Multiple-Offer Strategies for Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ugMiVo5uEPQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this episode, we’re focusing on multiple-offer strategies for sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heather Burnside and I are back once again to give you the latest in Central Iowa real estate news. During this episode, we covered a lot, from multiple-offer strategies that can help sellers in this market to an interview with brand-new homeowner Emory Songer. Most of these strategies are things your agent should know about already, but if they don’t, we’re happy that we’re able to share them with you today. For example, feedback is extremely important from buyers, especially those who have made offers. To learn more about what it’s like to buy and sell real estate in Central Iowa right now, watch the latest episode here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 10:10:53 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-best-multiple-offer-strategies-for-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-best-multiple-offer-strategies-for-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reserve Your Free Thanksgiving Pumpkin Pie!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WYShNwbZMxE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s how you can get yours!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Van Harden and I met up (on Van’s first ever ZOOM call!) to talk about our holiday plans.  Thanksgiving is almost here, and we’re saying thanks this year with our 2nd annual Pumpkin Pie Giveaway. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re a past client, current client, or someone who just needs some more deliciousness in their lives, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soldincentraliowa.com/pumpkinpie&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;visit this link &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soldincentraliowa.com/pumpkinpie&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;to reserve your pie today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;RESERVE YOUR PIE NOW:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just go to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soldincentraliowa.com/pumpkinpie&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.soldincentraliowa.com/pumpkinpie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and complete the form or call 515-229-9764 to reserve yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can pick up your pie on Monday, November 23 at our West Des Moines location or on Tuesday, November 24 at our Indianola location.&lt;/strong&gt; We will offer curbside delivery if that is easiest for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure to reserve your free pie today!%20http://localhost:4000/reserve-your-free-thanksgiving-pumpkin-pie.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure to reserve your free pie today!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us about the event or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email today. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;A special THANK YOU to our sponsors:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bhgre.com/Better-Homes-and-Gardens-Real-Estate-Innovations-13307c/Misty-SOLDwisch-830527a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:259px; height:95px; margin-right:10px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soldincentraliowa.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:259px; height:95px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/g.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rightwayhi.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:289px; height:90px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hwahomewarranty.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:289px; height:90px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.desmoinesarearoofing.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:289px; height:90px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mottomortgage.com/offices/midwest-west-des-moines/contact-the-simmons-hemer-team/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:289px; height:90px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed-4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ebokker-fidelitybank.mortgagewebcenter.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:289px; height:90px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed-5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trubank.bank/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:289px; height:90px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed-6.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phillipsfloors.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:289px; height:90px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed-7.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.millerthekiller.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:289px; height:90px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed-8.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ameriservradon.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width:289px; height:90px;&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed-9.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 15:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/reserve-your-free-thanksgiving-pumpkin-pie.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/reserve-your-free-thanksgiving-pumpkin-pie.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Can You Win a Bidding War for the Home You Want?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9AbTy3Gw-5o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are six tips that will make your offer stand out in a bidding war.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nationally, multiple offers are becoming more and more frequent in the real estate market, and that’s certainly true in most segments of our Des Moines market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, when you make an offer for the home you want, it has to be presented in a way that will actually win the home. If you work with an inexperienced agent who doesn’t have a strategy, you’ll end up making offer after offer with nothing to show for it. The key is to work with the right agent. Additionally, there are six tips to help make your offer stand out in a multiple-offer situation: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Have a strategy in the presentation.&lt;/strong&gt; My team and I sell hundreds of listings each year, and I can tell you that your agent isn’t doing you any favors by just sharing your offer and not saying anything about it. This leads me to my second tip…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Share the love.&lt;/strong&gt; We often have our buyers write a letter or take a picture of themselves to share with sellers because it’s a way of adding a personal touch and showing why they love the home. Many of us have a sentimental connection to our homes, which means sellers will want a buyer who will enjoy their home the way they did. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Shorten or waive contingencies.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want to make it difficult for the seller to like you. Asking for things like closing costs, a 21- day inspection period (as opposed to the normal seven-day period), or professionally painted walls is a good way to do just that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Have a strategy to win and don’t try offering less than the list price.%20http://localhost:4000/q-how-can-you-win-a-bidding-war-for-the-home-you-want.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Have a strategy to win and don’t try offering less than the list price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Pre-inspect the home.&lt;/strong&gt; This is somewhat of a continuation of the previous tip, since getting a pre-inspection allows you to waive the inspection contingency in your offer. Plus, it will help you uncover any potential problems with the home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Make your best offer.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, don’t test the seller by offering less than what you’re able. In a multiple-offer situation, it behooves you to put your cards on the table. You don’t want to miss out on the home you want over $500 or $1,000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Make it easy for the seller.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, they may have to wait to take possession of their next home, so give them extended possession of your home after closing to make the moving process easier. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember—win the bidding war for the home you want before worrying about the appraisal, inspection, etc. Have a strategy to win and don’t try offering less than the list price. If a home has hit the market in the last week and it has multiple offers, that means it’s priced or underpriced for the market, which means you’re underpaying by paying the asking price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about how to win the home you want or there’s anything else I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 12:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-can-you-win-a-bidding-war-for-the-home-you-want.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-can-you-win-a-bidding-war-for-the-home-you-want.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Central Iowa Real Estate Scoreboard Episode 2: Pets and Pests</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S0srINzg-vM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drew Glenn with Miller Pest &amp;amp; Termite offers some great pest control tips.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the recent episode of The Central Iowa Real Estate Scoreboard on 1460 KXNO and 106.3, Heather Burnside and I discussed the impact that lovable pets and loathsome pests have on real estate. We were joined by Drew Glenn of Miller Pest &amp;amp; Termite, who shared some phenomenal tips on how homeowners can eliminate creepy crawlers within their home and better manage the presence of those around it. Miller Pest &amp;amp; Termite, aka “Miller the Killer,” is a local company with 20+ years of experience; The Misty SOLDwisch team has partnered with them many times because their wood-destroying insect report is an indispensable service. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:51 — What are pet owners (dog lovers especially) looking for when they search homes? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:00 — Addressing pet odors and what to do with pets when showing your home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:30 — The myriad ways fleas, ants, and other pests can get inside your home &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15:55 — A look at the latest activity in our Central Iowa market:  A stronger seller’s market? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19:15 — How does a wood-destroying pest inspection work, and why is it so important? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21:33 — How homeowners can better manage the presence of bugs &lt;em&gt;around&lt;/em&gt; their property &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22:40 — Some tough news about the mulch in your yard and some fresh landscaping tips &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24:00 — How Miller Pest and Termite got started, and how they operate safely today &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;26:04 — Home of the Week: a new construction townhome at Deer Run &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A special thanks to Drew for joining us this episode. The bottom line: You can take easy steps to ensure that your pets don’t have to impede your home sale, and pests in and around your home can be controlled by simple preemptive measures. If you’re in need of professional’s help, make sure you remember this catchy tagline: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.millerthekiller.com/&quot;&gt;Millerthekiller.com&lt;/a&gt;, tell your dad, tell your mom!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, reach out to us if you have questions pertaining to the Central Iowa market or have any upcoming real estate needs. We’re here to help, and we look forward to hearing from you! Stay tuned for the next episode of The Central Iowa Real Estate Scoreboard! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 12:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-scoreboard-episode-2-pets-and-pests.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/central-iowa-real-estate-scoreboard-episode-2-pets-and-pests.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sellers: Take Advantage of Our Certified Pre-Owned Program</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_sDLh1r-Ug?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I recently appeared on a talk radio show with Heather Burnside to discuss our certified pre-owned program for sellers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been doing the &lt;strong&gt;certified pre-owned program&lt;/strong&gt; for several years now, and it is a great marketing feature for our sellers. However, there’s more intent behind it than just marketing to appeal to buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find that when sellers are going through the process, the home inspection is the most stressful stage because someone else is critiquing every aspect of the home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the stress comes from the fact that, after the seller has negotiated everything down to the penny, they’ll then have to go through a second negotiation 10 days later based on the results of their inspection. There are many things that can come up during the inspection that might scare buyers, even if those things aren’t that big of a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With our certified pre-owned program, your home will be fully vetted, which allows you to choose what repairs you’ll take care of and know the cost of those items.%20http://localhost:4000/sellers-take-advantage-of-our-certified-pre-owned-program.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With our certified pre-owned program, your home will be fully vetted, which allows you to choose what repairs you’ll take care of and know the cost of those items.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We explain to our sellers that &lt;strong&gt;we want to put them in the driver’s seat&lt;/strong&gt; of this part of the process. With our certified pre-owned program, your home will be fully vetted, which allows you to choose what repairs you’ll take care of and know the cost of those items. That way, when you’re negotiating the sale price, you can have that in mind instead of having to take care of thousands of dollars in surprise repairs after you already thought your home was sold. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Certified Pre-Owned Home program also includes a 13-month home warranty through Home Warranty of America to help repair or replace any issues found&lt;/strong&gt; with a seller’s major systems—home warranties usually last for 12 months, so you’ll get a bonus month from HWA!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our certified pre-owned program, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to give you more information and help you take charge of your home sale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 16:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/sellers-take-advantage-of-our-certified-pre-owned-program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/sellers-take-advantage-of-our-certified-pre-owned-program.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business Spotlight: Rightway Home Inspections</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/78FOz_WMCZE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;
Adam McCarty from Rightway Home Inspections is here to answer a few home inspection questions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s message, I sat down with Adam McCarty from Rightway Home Inspections on my weekly radio show “The Central Iowa Real Estate Scoreboard” on 106.3 KXnO to discuss a few key questions people tend to have about his industry, including the importance of pre-inspections, things that tend to surprise sellers about inspections, and the kinds of technology that help inspectors spot issues that homeowners might not even be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Do you need to be a certified home inspector?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of really good inspectors in the state who were previously in the HVAC, plumbing, or construction industries, and that prior experience is a big plus for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“How important is a pre-inspection?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of having to negotiate twice, it just makes sense for a seller to get everything out of the way with a pre-inspection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“What kinds of things do people need to do to prepare for an inspection?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you already know there are issues with your home, Adam recommends taking care of them before he comes to your home for the inspection. In terms of preparing the house, that homeowners need to provide clear access to things like your furnace, electrical panel, attic, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Do the sellers need to be present for the inspection?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They don’t have to be, but it’s great if they are. That way, Adam can explain what items buyers are concerned about and what sellers should do to prevent issues later on in the transaction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“What is a thermal camera?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thermal cameras are a special type of camera that allows Adam to see differences in heat within the home. This allows him to spot issues that sellers might not know about because they can’t see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“What are the biggest surprises during an inspection?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers often don’t realize how hazardous electrical panels can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about home inspections and the services that Adam and Rightway Home Inspections offer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://rightwayhi.com/&quot;&gt;visit their website&lt;/a&gt; or call him at (515) 802-0141.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions about buying or selling homes, don’t hesitate to reach out to the Misty SOLDwisch Home Selling Team. We’re here to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecentraliowarealestatescoreboard.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Listen to “The Central Iowa Real Estate Scoreboard” with Misty SOLDwisch and Heather Burnside Sundays 9:30am on KXnO.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 15:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/business-spotlight-rightway-home-inspections.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/business-spotlight-rightway-home-inspections.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Did You Catch My On-Air Debut?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/sh/4kdzbmgmywlv04l/AADBsNlvgh8HqYfBq133gQX_a/Episode%201/Scoreboard%20-%20Episode%201%20-%20LIVE.mp4?dl=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/introducing-the-central-iowa-real-estate-scoreboard-email.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;790&quot; height=&quot;510&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s everything you need to know about our new radio half-hour!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our new radio show, The Central Iowa Real Estate Scoreboard, is aptly named but not just because it airs on sports station 1460 KXNO; the parallels between the sports world, life itself, and the real estate market run deep. For instance, life could throw you a huge curveball, and suddenly you need to relocate for a new job. Maybe after quarantining with your family for two months, you’ve finally admitted to yourself that your house isn’t big enough (something we’ve been hearing from folks a lot lately). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, &lt;strong&gt;every Sunday at 9:30 a.m., I’ll be updating you on an ever-changing real estate market, and answering your questions so you can be equipped as a potential home seller, buyer, or investor.&lt;/strong&gt; Ours is an equally exciting and challenging market to navigate. Since the onset of the coronavirus, the Misty Soldwisch Home Selling Team—like countless other professionals nationwide—has had to adapt our model for success. That’s the benefit of having a whole team behind you though; when things get flipped upside down, you’re able to change course rather quickly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Ours is an equally exciting and challenging market to navigate.%20http://localhost:4000/q-did-you-catch-my-on-air-debut.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Ours is an equally exciting and challenging market to navigate.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we studied those markets affected earliest by the virus and asked, “How are real estate professionals there responding, and how can we apply the most effective responses to Iowa?” Then, we leveraged the tools and technology we’d already been using by integrating it further into the process. Ultimately, people need to buy and sell no matter what’s going on in the world—we had to be prepared to meet our clients’ evolving needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the conversation. Feel free to watch the full message, or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:40 — The switch to virtual open houses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:50 — How the virtual process works&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:20 — Who is active in our market? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:18 — Changing trends in home buying &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:39 — The real value of swimming pools versus their perceived value &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:53 — Which home exterior projects are worthwhile investments?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:59 — What homebuyers need to know about interest rates &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18:28 — Is demand still outpacing our housing inventory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22:35 — What is a ‘normal’ real estate cycle, anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24:11 — The Misty Soldwisch guarantee explained &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25:45 — The featured home of the week &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28:00 — Wrapping up the show &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about anything discussed in this week’s episode or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out by phone or email or visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soldincentraliowa.com/&quot;&gt;soldincentraliowa.com&lt;/a&gt;. Our team is here to be a resource for you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 12:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-did-you-catch-my-on-air-debut.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-did-you-catch-my-on-air-debut.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
