<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>Our mission at The John Schuster Group is to be your best resource for Twin Cities real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The John Schuster Group, your professional Twin Cities Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 11:50:31 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 11:50:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join Us for Our 1st Annual Client Appreciation Event at the Minnesota Zoo</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XL-8l5add_g?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Will you join us October 6 for a fun, free event at the Minnesota Zoo?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT INFORMATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where&lt;/u&gt;: Shady Oaks Picnic Shelter&lt;br /&gt;&lt;u&gt;When&lt;/u&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picnic&lt;/strong&gt; [10:30 am - 12:30 pm]  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lunch&lt;/strong&gt; [11:30 am - 12:30 pm] &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RCI Certificate Drawing&lt;/strong&gt; [12:00 pm]
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;**You must be present to win**&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To RSVP to the event, click &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnschustergroup.com/zoo.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;We’ve got exciting news to announce: You’re invited to the John Schuster Group’s first annual client appreciation event at the Minnesota Zoo! Join us on Saturday, October 6 for this free event, which is our way of thanking you for your business and trust over the years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;From 10:30 a.m. to 12:30 p.m., we’ll be hosting a picnic lunch with ice cream, desserts, and more at the Shady Oaks Picnic Shelter. Lunch will be served from 11:30 a.m. to 12:30 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Also, in addition to your free passes, parking, and catered lunch, we’ll be giving away one free RCI certificate, good for a one-week vacation for you and your family. The drawing is at 12:00 p.m., and you must be present to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You’re invited to the John Schuster Group’s first annual client appreciation event at the Minnesota Zoo!%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/join-us-for-our-1st-annual-client-appreciation-event-at-the-minnesota-zoo.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You’re invited to the John Schuster Group’s first annual client appreciation event at the Minnesota Zoo!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;To ensure your entry to this great event, &lt;strong&gt;make sure to RSVP by September 23. Space is limited.&lt;/strong&gt; To RSVP, simply reach out to us by phone, email, or by clicking &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnschustergroup.com/zoo.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. To pick up your passes, visit us at the Shady Oaks Picnic Shelter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Again, &lt;strong&gt;thank you so much for supporting us, and we hope to see you on October 6. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to seeing you at this great upcoming event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/join-us-for-our-1st-annual-client-appreciation-event-at-the-minnesota-zoo.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/join-us-for-our-1st-annual-client-appreciation-event-at-the-minnesota-zoo.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learn How to Maximize Your Home Sale at Our Upcoming Forum</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3tmmZ12VnAE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking of selling your home in the next two years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we’ve got great news. &lt;strong&gt;You’re officially invited to a free home seller’s forum we’re hosting at Braemar Golf Course on September 11 and September 12.&lt;/strong&gt; The September 11 session will start at 6:45 p.m., and the September 12 session will start at 11:30 a.m. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to your home sale, small details can make a huge difference and make you thousands of dollars more. We want to teach you how to get the most money for your home in our current market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We want to teach you how to get the most money for your home in our current market.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/learn-how-to-maximize-your-home-sale-at-our-upcoming-forum.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We want to teach you how to get the most money for your home in our current market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moderator for this forum will be Paul Douglas, who turned to us when he needed a home to sell. Paul himself taped a special message attached to the video above. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space is limited and seats are filling up fast, so &lt;strong&gt;click on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnschustergroup.com/home-seller-forum.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to register.&lt;/strong&gt; We hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any questions at all, feel free to call or email us anytime. We’d be happy to help you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/learn-how-to-maximize-your-home-sale-at-our-upcoming-forum.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/learn-how-to-maximize-your-home-sale-at-our-upcoming-forum.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips From WCCO Dave Lee on Preparing Your Spring 2019 Listing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B7J5wFh3_OA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring is one of the best times to sell your home quickly and for top dollar. If you’re thinking of listing next spring, it isn’t too soon to start getting ready. The season may seem far off, but now is actually the perfect time to prepare. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Well, consider this: &lt;strong&gt;Frost and snow from the winter and early spring months don’t do a lot of favors for your curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt; If you wait to take pictures of your listing until right before you sell in the spring, you could be stuck with drab, grey photos. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly why now is the time to prepare for your spring sale. Right now, our team is offering free photography and staging services to anyone looking to list this coming spring. And for sellers who live on an acreage or lake, we also offer drone filming services. &lt;strong&gt;This way, you can capture photos and videos of your property while the landscape is still green&lt;/strong&gt; and the skies are still blue. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our team has all the processes in place necessary to help you maximize the equity in your home when it comes time to sell.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/tips-from-wcco-dave-lee-on-preparing-your-spring-2019-listing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our team has all the processes in place necessary to help you maximize the equity in your home when it comes time to sell.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would love to meet with you to sit down and discuss the ways you should prepare your home over the next five to six months. Our team has all the processes in place necessary to help you maximize the equity in your home when it comes time to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re thinking of selling your home in 2019, please reach out to us today.&lt;/strong&gt; We want to help you get your home in the best condition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 07:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/tips-from-wcco-dave-lee-on-preparing-your-spring-2019-listing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/tips-from-wcco-dave-lee-on-preparing-your-spring-2019-listing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Could You Be the Next Rockstar Agent to Join Our Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wXoHPa6wSik?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently sat down for an interview with one of our team’s rockstar agents, Jessica Wolleat, and I’d like to share some of what we spoke about with you today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica was born and raised in Minnesota, and has actually dreamed of a real estate career since she was a child. She was fascinated by homes and even grew up to get a degree in architecture from the University of Minnesota. All of this just solidified her desire to get into the world of real estate. &lt;strong&gt;Now she’s been working with our team for about two years and has absolutely loved it.    &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, she loves the fast-paced environment. “Everything can change in the blink of an eye,” says Jessica. But it’s the clients, Jessica added, is what she really loves about this industry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Jessica’s positive attitude is just the kind of outlook we’re looking for in new team members.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/could-you-be-the-next-rockstar-agent-to-join-our-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Jessica’s positive attitude is just the kind of outlook we’re looking for in new team members.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“To see clients happy is a really good feeling,” Jessica concluded.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team is so happy to have Jessica on board with us. We absolutely love her positive attitude. In fact, this is just the kind of outlook we’re looking for in new team members. Right now, our team is seeking talented and passionate individuals, so &lt;strong&gt;if you or anyone you know is interested in pursuing a career with us, we’d love to hear from you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you have any other questions, would like more information, or would like our help realizing your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/could-you-be-the-next-rockstar-agent-to-join-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/could-you-be-the-next-rockstar-agent-to-join-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Here Is to Life, Liberty, and the Pursuit of Happiness</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7MId4xyOelM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;242 years ago this July 4, our Founding Fathers took the first steps in creating American independence. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is during times such as these that we should reflect on the famed, familiar words of Thomas Jefferson: &lt;strong&gt;“We hold these truths to be self-evident: That all men are created equal;&lt;/strong&gt; that they are endowed by their creator with certain unalienable rights; that among these are life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We hope you’re able to spend this holiday celebrating life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/here-is-to-life-liberty-and-the-pursuit-of-happiness.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We hope you’re able to spend this holiday celebrating life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Fourth of July, we would like to encourage all of you to spend the holiday with family and friends in celebration of these values. Our team is so grateful for the bountiful opportunities provided to us as citizens of this great nation. And &lt;strong&gt;we’re also grateful for all of you, our clients, and your continued support.&lt;/strong&gt; Happy Fourth of July!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about real estate or would like to discuss your goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 06:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/here-is-to-life-liberty-and-the-pursuit-of-happiness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/here-is-to-life-liberty-and-the-pursuit-of-happiness.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of ISAs to Buyers and Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v7iTSwexsS0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is an ISA, and why is it so important that you hire an agent or a team that has one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISA stands for ‘inside sales agent.’&lt;/strong&gt; This kind of agent does not show or list homes; they strictly work on immediately getting leads for your home to agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are they so important? If you are a seller, think about it: we spend tons of money to make your listing look fabulous online. We pay thousands of dollars each month to move it to the top of all the aggregators, so when a buyer comes through and they request more information, you need to respond to that as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like nowadays, everyone is impatient with their communication—they want a response immediately. Our ISAs respond to all online inquiries and anyone reaching out to the John Schuster Group within five minutes during business hours and within 15 minutes on nights and weekends. &lt;strong&gt;That means an interested client will get into our sellers’ homes faster.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our ISAs respond within five minutes during business hours and within 15 minutes on nights and weekends.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/the-benefits-of-isas-to-buyers-and-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our ISAs respond within five minutes during business hours and within 15 minutes on nights and weekends.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer, ISAs are also important, especially in today’s competitive market. &lt;strong&gt;You need a resource on your side to find inventory that isn’t actively available on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; Inventory has come down by a third from where it was last year, and many buyers are losing homes in bidding wars. People who choose to work with us on the buy side will benefit from our ability to identify neighborhoods and communities they’ll want to live in. Our ISAs will call out to every home in that neighborhood in the attempt to find inventory that’s not yet available. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or are thinking about buying or selling a home, please feel free to reach out to us. We would love to work with you and explain more about why our ISA program might be a benefit to you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 09:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/the-benefits-of-isas-to-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/the-benefits-of-isas-to-buyers-and-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>John Schuster Talks with KQRS Morning Show Co-Host Michele Tafoya</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/d8kF_Hfk48k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here at the 92 KQRS radio station to do a podcast with the famous sportscaster Michele Tafoya, who will be taking time to answer a few fun questions. &lt;strong&gt;Refer to the timestamps below to peruse the interview at your leisure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:51—What has Michele been doing since the Superbowl?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:47—The craziest, most embarrassing sideline interviews Michele has ever done in any sport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:48—Ten rapid-fire questions about Michele’s favorite things&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:23—Michele’s glowing praise for the John Schuster Group&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank Michele for being such a rockstar and advocate for our team. I appreciate everything she does for us, and I’m sure some of our clients and KQRS listeners will enjoy getting to know her a little better.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you ever need assistance with buying, selling, or investing in real estate, you are invited to reach out to us any time. We’d love to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 10:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/john-schuster-talks-with-kqrs-morning-show-co-host-michele-tafoya.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/john-schuster-talks-with-kqrs-morning-show-co-host-michele-tafoya.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>John Meets with WCCO’s Paul Douglas &amp; Jordana Green</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nny5MYU66ys?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*As WCCO Radio’s Paul Douglas and Jordanna Green can attest, our comprehensive marketing strategy helps all of our clients sell their homes quickly and for top dollar. *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m joined by Paul Douglas and Jordanna Green, the hosts of “The Paul &amp;amp; Jordanna Show” on WCCO Radio, to share some insight into how our group became the No. 1 listing team for the entire state of Minnesota for Coldwell Banker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love WCCO and their listeners. We’re lucky to have endorsements from people like Paul and Jordana; we recently had the privilege of selling both of their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jordana tried selling her home with another agent but didn’t have any luck. After she hired us, we sold her home in three weeks for more than its original listing price. Paul also tried selling his home with a previous agent, but nothing worked for him either. That’s when he hired our team and got almost instant results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are believers,” Paul said. “You guys have figured out the formula. The marketing is out of this world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, our market is red-hot right now. Inventory is down 23% compared to last year, and many of our clients’ homes are selling with multiple offers. How do we get such consistent results from our listings?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of it boils down to our &lt;strong&gt;comprehensive marketing strategy.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of our clients aren’t ready to enter the market immediately, and it takes a while to get a listing ready. This is why we’ve mastered “coming soon” marketing. If we take on a listing that won’t be on the market for a month or two, we initiate our coming soon marketing plan to create a large pool of buyers for that house once it does hit the market. That’s how we generate multiple offers. By doing this, our clients sell faster and for more money. They’re happy, we’re happy, and our team is having a blast right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our comprehensive marketing strategy helps our clients sell their homes quickly and for top dollar.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/john-meets-with-wccos-paul-douglas-jordana-green.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our comprehensive marketing strategy helps our clients sell their homes quickly and for top dollar.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another strategy we’ve implemented is &lt;strong&gt;using pocket listings.&lt;/strong&gt; This is for sellers who don’t want to enter the MLS but would still sell for the right offer and perhaps want to test the market a little. In our low-inventory market, we’ve been getting fabulous offers for sellers with pocket listings. This way, we sell about 10% to 15% of our listings before they hit the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I always tell people, unless you’re ready to move, don’t list with John, because he is going to sell that house,” Jordanna said. “If you call John, start packing, because that’s what’s going to happen for you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of selling your home and you’d like to know what it would sell for, don’t hesitate to give us a call or shoot us an email so we can meet with you and give you a consultation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to thank Paul and Jordanna for joining me today. Don’t forget to tune into WCCO from 3 p.m. to 6 p.m., Monday through Friday, to catch the “The Paul &amp;amp; Jordanna Show.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or real estate needs, feel free to reach out to me anytime. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 09:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/john-meets-with-wccos-paul-douglas-jordana-green.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/john-meets-with-wccos-paul-douglas-jordana-green.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Homeowners: Don’t Forget These 7 Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ffTWe46lHQw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;New homeowners may be excited about finally having a place to themselves, but there are seven things they often forget to keep in mind when it comes to maintaining the home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m going to discuss seven things that new homeowners don’t know that they need to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s just the joy of homeownership—plumbing issues, appliances breaking down, and natural disasters.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/new-homeowners-dont-forget-these-7-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s just the joy of homeownership—plumbing issues, appliances breaking down, and natural disasters.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save for unexpected problems.&lt;/strong&gt; I know that you already did an inspection, but things are bound to happen when you buy a home. It’s just the joy of homeownership—plumbing issues, appliances breaking down, and natural disasters. Put some money away into an account so that you won’t be caught unawares.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Form an inspection habit.&lt;/strong&gt; You need to inspect your house seasonally, at least once a year. Walk around the exterior, check for peeling paint, check the grading, look underneath the plumbing, and watch for pests.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy a lot of furnace filters.&lt;/strong&gt; We recommend changing your filters once a month. You can order filters online from Amazon and have them shipped to your home. You can even set it up to have them auto-shipped to your home on a monthly basis to remind yourself to do it. Otherwise, most home goods and hardware stores will have them available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get to know your appliances.&lt;/strong&gt; There are certain appliances that need to be tuned up seasonally, like your furnace. We also recommend getting a safety check done going into the colder months. Clean out those burners and make sure that you’re not pumping carbon monoxide into your house. Do the same thing with your air conditioning unit. Additionally, know the life expectancy of your appliances; for example, furnaces often last between 10 to 15 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take advantage of tax credits.&lt;/strong&gt; When you’re upgrading some appliances, you can actually get some tax credits. Take a look at Energy Star appliances to make sure they still qualify. Solar technology is also a hot item. Just make sure to look at the rate of return because some of those do require more of a cash outlay once you buy them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start keeping records.&lt;/strong&gt; Keep records when you buy anything, when you get anything installed, or do service dates underneath your mechanicals. I’m old school, meaning folders and file cabinets. But you can also make a Google Doc to record when the dates of when you service something or when you buy any appliances.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beef up your insurance.&lt;/strong&gt; You should be shopping for insurance once a year. We recommend that you look at possibly getting a little higher deductible but also getting more coverage. You’re not going to take out a homeowner’s claim for a $500 ratio; it will probably be $2,000 or more, so you might as well have a higher deductible and get more coverage. Make sure you’ve got sewage backup coverage on your policies—a lot of policies don’t cover sewer backups. You might also want to talk to your insurance agent about getting some umbrella coverage over and above your standard policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in the Twin Cities area, please feel free to reach out to us or visit our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnschustergroup.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, where you can find a list of available homes and calculate the value of your current home. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 11:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/new-homeowners-dont-forget-these-7-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/new-homeowners-dont-forget-these-7-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We'd Like to Thank You for Your Support</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1m90uYFk87M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some huge news to share with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I would like to thank all of our clients, friends, and family for your support, love, trust, and referrals. It means the absolute world to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We couldn’t have done it without your support.%20http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/wed-like-to-thank-you-for-your-support.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We couldn’t have done it without your support.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Because of you, we were named the No. 1 Listing Team out of Coldwell Banker in Minnesota! &lt;/strong&gt;Out of all 15 offices, we were No. 1 last year. We are so honored. Thank you so much for helping us reach this achievement!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. My team and I would be happy to help you. Let’s make 2018 another great year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/wed-like-to-thank-you-for-your-support.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://johnschustertwincitiesrealestateblog.com/wed-like-to-thank-you-for-your-support.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
