<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Kohler Group</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Kohler Group - your professional St. Charles Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thekohlergroupblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 09:54:37 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 09:54:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Happened With Mortgage Rates?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Hy31oOawRp0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends and clients: We were so happy to see you at our recent client appreciation event at Porter’s Pub in the breathtaking Bowe’s Creek Country Club. We want to thank all of you who came out to enjoy food, drinks, fun, and our driving range raffle. The raffles consisted of two rounds of 18 holes at Bowe’s Creek provided by Toll Brothers and the driving range raffle provided by Bowe’s Creek. The Kohler Group raffled two tickets to a Cougars game! Congratulations to the winners, by the way. All of this is simply to remind you of how important you are to us. We appreciate you so dearly, so we were so glad see you there. As always, if you have any other questions or would like more information about anything related to real estate, please give us a call or send us an email. If you were not able to attend, we sure would love to see you at the next one!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/what-happened-with-mortgage-rates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thekohlergroupblog.com/what-happened-with-mortgage-rates.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Buying New Construction</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ANCtC7X7NBE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever thought about buying a new construction home? So many of us love our new homes because we are able to get the most current floor plans, trim work, and appliances. A home like this, located at 5N287 Switchgrass Ln, Saint Charles, IL 60175, also comes with a one-year builder’s warranty, which is another great incentive to buy. According to our friend Bill Pendley with Caliber Home Loans, they can also offer a lower interest rate for one of these homes than what you would find on the market otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/the-benefits-of-buying-new-construction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thekohlergroupblog.com/the-benefits-of-buying-new-construction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Is Now the Perfect Time to Find Your Dream Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7jWFGTbPqPA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video presented at 39W665 S. Mathewson in Geneva, IL of which is proudly being marketed by Kari Kohler and can be fully viewed at &lt;a href=&quot;TheKohlerGroup.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TheKohlerGroup.com&lt;/a&gt; or by calling for your private showing at 630-587-4700.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t already living in your dream home, we’d like to make you aware of an incredible opportunity available in our market right now. Currently, interest rates are incredibly low. Beyond that, there are many, many gorgeous listings up for sale right here in St. Charles. So if you’re ready to make a move and find your dream home, please reach out to us. We would be honored to assist you. And if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/why-is-now-the-perfect-time-to-find-your-dream-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thekohlergroupblog.com/why-is-now-the-perfect-time-to-find-your-dream-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Preparing Your Home for a Showing &amp; Getting a Pre-Approval</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mZL45Y-snhw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a seller, how do you prepare your home for a showing? If you’re a buyer, how do you prepare for getting a pre-approval?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer the first question, there are two main tips to remember. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;make sure everything about the exterior of your front door is perfect.&lt;/strong&gt; Everything should be perfect on the interior and around the foyer as well. These are the two areas where people make buying decisions: They make it on the way in, and they make it on the way out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Depending on your price range, cleanliness can get you anywhere from $5,000 to $15,000 more for your home.%20http://thekohlergroupblog.com/preparing-your-home-for-a-showing-getting-a-pre-approval.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Depending on your price range, cleanliness can get you anywhere from $5,000 to $15,000 more for your home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;make sure your home is clean&lt;/strong&gt;—clean countertops, dressers, bathrooms, etc. The home should even have a clean fragrance to it. Depending on your price range, cleanliness can get you anywhere from $5,000 to $15,000 more for your home. Remember to hire professionals for this work. We have plenty of vendors we’d love to refer you to who’d do an excellent job. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what about preparing for a pre-approval? According to Bill Pendley of Caliber Home Loans, there are three factors lenders look at that you need to examine as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Income:&lt;/strong&gt; You need to have a monthly income in order to pay your bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Assets:&lt;/strong&gt; You need to have the funds available to pay your down payment and your closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Credit:&lt;/strong&gt; 740 is the credit score you want to shoot for, and making a couple minor adjustments will help you get there. Paying off revolving debt, for example, can improve your credit score 20 or 30 points and save you thousands of dollars when closing on your home.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about these topics or you’re interested in scheduling a showing for the beautiful home we shot today’s video in, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/preparing-your-home-for-a-showing-getting-a-pre-approval.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thekohlergroupblog.com/preparing-your-home-for-a-showing-getting-a-pre-approval.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Buy or Sell Now?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/b7lEzn64uUQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to thank the sellers of the home at 39W165 Longmeadow Lane in St. Charles for allowing us to do this video at their home and we welcome you to schedule a showing as the property is on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes right now such a great time to buy or sell? There are actually a few reasons, and we’ll share just a handful of the most significant factors today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one thing, there are 2% fewer homes on the market in our area right now than there were at this time last year. Also, home values have risen by 3% on average. This means those who list now can enjoy lower competition and higher prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buying a home now means you’ll be able to build equity faster after you close.%20http://thekohlergroupblog.com/why-should-you-buy-or-sell-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buying a home now means you’ll be able to build equity faster after you close.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for buyers, one of the greatest advantages in today’s market is our incredibly low interest rates. It’s also good to know that, because home values are rising, buying a home now means you’ll be able to build equity faster after you close. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final note, &lt;strong&gt;we’d like to invite anyone looking to buy a home out to join us for a private showing and some lemonade by the pool at (ADDRESS).&lt;/strong&gt; And, of course, we’d like to thank the sellers of this great property for allowing us to film on location at their listing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/why-should-you-buy-or-sell-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thekohlergroupblog.com/why-should-you-buy-or-sell-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Our Fantastic Support Staff</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cfBBpgBGqE0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re excited to introduce you to three of our fantastic support staff members here at the Kohler Group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hannah Burke is not only the operations manager of the Kohler Group, but she is also a licensed agent.&lt;/strong&gt; She is responsible for transactions from start to finish and will be your main point of contact here at the office. She can answer almost any question that arises or direct you to the right person to answer it for you. She also has an encyclopedic knowledge of trivial facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison Rucinski is our transaction coordinator and your go-to person from contract to close.&lt;/strong&gt; She is a lifelong Dekalb-area resident and just recently purchased her own home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Hannah can answer almost any question that arises.%20http://thekohlergroupblog.com/introducing-our-fantastic-support-staff.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Hannah can answer almost any question that arises.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kandice Modene is our marketing coordinator.&lt;/strong&gt; She handles everything that has to do with social media, print advertising, and online advertising. She’s a lifelong Geneva resident with a passion for dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for or about our support staff that you met today, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 10:29:01 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/introducing-our-fantastic-support-staff.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thekohlergroupblog.com/introducing-our-fantastic-support-staff.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Excited for What 2019 Has in Store</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fsxbj_jVL6o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our entire team is here today to wish you and your family a Happy New Year. We had a great year in 2018 thanks to all of your support. We’re looking forward to helping even more of you with your real estate needs in 2019. Get in touch, and give us a call or send us an email at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 09:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/were-excited-for-what-2019-has-in-store.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thekohlergroupblog.com/were-excited-for-what-2019-has-in-store.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why St. Charles is The Place for You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PyHpc52P0Jo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve lived here in St. Charles for about 20 years, and it’s where I’ve happily raised my two sons. &lt;strong&gt;I absolutely recommend everyone to move here&lt;/strong&gt;; it’s a wonderful community with a vibrant downtown. In fact, they’ve just done all kinds of renovations and are adding restaurants, office buildings, and both two- and three-story parking garages. There are great places for shopping and other awesome businesses to stop in. There’s something for everyone in downtown St. Charles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The town runs right along the Fox River. A bike path runs along the river all the way to Batavia, and &lt;strong&gt;the river is the site of various festivals throughout the year&lt;/strong&gt;, which include riverboats, steamboats, bands, and much, much more. We recently had our annual Thanksgiving Day Parade, where businesses, students from the high school, and all sorts of people come out to participate. It’s a fun event for everyone in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel Baker is a beautiful historic building built right along the Fox River. With more than 50 rooms, &lt;strong&gt;it’s a great venue for hosting weddings and other elegant events.&lt;/strong&gt; Inside is Rox City Grill—a fabulous place for an upscale dining experience where you can get fish, steak, and a wide variety of other menu options. The menu is changed fairly frequently, so there will always be new and interesting dishes to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I mention the outstanding school districts? Park District is truly exceptional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;theres-something-for-everyone-in-downtown-st-charles&quot;&gt;“There’s something for everyone in downtown St. Charles.”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I’m so proud to represent JRH Properties, LLC, and the fine homes that they build. Recently, &lt;strong&gt;they’ve built a beautiful 150-homesite subdivision on the west side of St. Charles that you just have to see.&lt;/strong&gt; Each property is anywhere from a half-acre to an acre, and almost all of them are backed with some type of open space. Much of this greenspace is tree-lined and has bike paths, lakes, and ponds. It’s absolutely gorgeous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though they primarily build in St. Charles and Glen Ellyn, &lt;strong&gt;they’ve also built a series of beautiful custom homes that are typically 5,000 square feet or more and fall into the million-dollar price range.&lt;/strong&gt; The work on these properties is absolutely exceptional; the features and craftsmanship are state-of-the-art. JRH Properties, LLC is proud to build homes in Prairie Lakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I welcome everybody to come see the three spec homes we have available right now for occupancy. The kitchens will just knock your socks off if the rest of the houses don’t first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the properties available for purchase or about why St. Charles is such a fantastic place to make a home, please reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you. I would be proud to represent you on your sales.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 15:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/why-st-charles-is-the-place-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thekohlergroupblog.com/why-st-charles-is-the-place-for-you.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shining the Spotlight on the Local Moving Company, M.K Movers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/laGVA38WJPA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had the opportunity to speak with Mitch Katkus of M.K Movers about his moving business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitch’s father used to own a truck-rental company, and people would often ask him if there was anyone who could help load and unload. Mitch and his friend volunteered for the job when they were still in high school, heading to work after classes finished for the day. This was the beginning of Mitch’s career in the moving industry as this after-school job evolved into a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving into or out of a home can be stressful, but thanks to his many years of experience, &lt;strong&gt;Mitch is full of good tips to keep in mind when undergoing the task.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=He recommends you always get an estimate before hiring movers.%20http://thekohlergroupblog.com/shining-the-spotlight-on-the-local-moving-company-m-k-movers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“He recommends you always get an estimate before hiring movers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He recommends you always get an estimate before hiring movers; though doing it over the phone can work, an in-person estimate works better and shows the movers what they’ll be dealing with. It makes a difference in cost, especially when a client says they have 50 boxes when, in reality, it’s more like 200.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitch loves his town and loves to provide a helpful service to the community.&lt;/strong&gt; He enjoys seeing the many ways that St. Charles has improved and grown over the years in regard to dining, entertainment, and things for people of all ages to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M.K Movers are located in St. Charles but are willing to travel anywhere in the state of Illinois. If you’d like to contact M.K Movers or learn more, visit them at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mkmover.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.mkmover.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as always, if you have any questions about real estate or would like to discuss your buying or selling goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 15:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/shining-the-spotlight-on-the-local-moving-company-m-k-movers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thekohlergroupblog.com/shining-the-spotlight-on-the-local-moving-company-m-k-movers.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A New Series to Show You Why We’re So Proud of Our Community</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RHWnF0gUYMo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Kohler Group in St. Charles, we are a seven-member team. We have three amazing individuals who work on your transactions right here in the office. We have three incredible buyer’s agents who help you find your dream home here in the community. And then, there’s me; I work as the listing agent, and I also help people find the perfect home for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really pride ourselves on excellent customer service. &lt;strong&gt;We care about you and we want to make your transaction as successful as possible&lt;/strong&gt;; the Kohler Teams strives to do that every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a personal note: I have two sons—a 17-year-old who goes to North High School here in St. Charles and a 19-year-old who attends ASU in Arizona. I’m fortunate enough to have been able to provide an education for my boys all the way from preschool to college, and &lt;strong&gt;it’s in part because of the amazing community we have here in St. Charles.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve experienced the culture, the education, and the athletics here in the area, and I really cannot tell you another place I’d rather raise my children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I really cannot tell you another place I’d rather raise my children.%20http://thekohlergroupblog.com/a-new-series-to-show-you-why-were-so-proud-of-our-community.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I really cannot tell you another place I’d rather raise my children.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been an outstanding community, so &lt;strong&gt;when you’re making a decision about where to live in the future, I hope you’ll consider St. Charles and the surrounding Fox Valley area.&lt;/strong&gt; There are so many great things to offer here; Downtown St. Charles is so vibrant, and it’s expanding daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about real estate or our community here, reach out to us. For anything that we can do to help you in the real estate world, we are here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 09:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://thekohlergroupblog.com/a-new-series-to-show-you-why-were-so-proud-of-our-community.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thekohlergroupblog.com/a-new-series-to-show-you-why-were-so-proud-of-our-community.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
