<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sacramento's Best Real Estate Training and Coaching Team</title>
    <description>Dan Ellison, a top Real Estate Agent in Sacramento, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>http://realestatecareerssacramento.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://realestatecareerssacramento.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 15:08:39 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 15:08:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Got My Start in Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8JdqPd4P5SQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I get into the real estate business? The story starts back in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That year, my wife and I relocated from Southern California to the Sacramento area for the birth of our first child. I’d been working as a salesman for a company that sold paper products and I thought about getting into real estate, but I wasn’t sure what the transition back to the Sacramento area would be like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our child was born, I started dipping my toes in the water, so to speak. Then in November of that year, I was let go from my job. After that, I knew there was only one option—I had to get to work, and I did just that. In 2014, my first full year as a real estate agent, I sold a total of 38 homes for a GCI of $289,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I do it? &lt;strong&gt;I focused my attention on two activities specifically: Open houses and expired listings.&lt;/strong&gt; I believe it’s important in this business to stay focused and get really good at a couple of things instead of being just OK at 50 things. In real estate, you don’t want to be a jack of all trades and a master of none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Real estate is a phenomenal business, and I’m excited to continue to grow in it and provide opportunities to the real estate agent community at large.%20http://realestatecareerssacramento.com/how-i-got-my-start-in-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Real estate is a phenomenal business, and I’m excited to continue to grow in it and provide opportunities to the real estate agent community at large.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, though, I made sure I had the right mindset. I was very coachable and sought the advice of people who knew what they were doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open houses are something a lot of new agents focus on because they’re an easy segue into the business. It puts you right in front of buyers actively looking for homes and it helps you get the marbles out of your mouth in terms of talking about real estate. It also gives you a plan to work from and introduces you to the surrounding neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, during my first year, there was a house that an investor flipped that was located in my neighborhood, and one day I called that home’s broker and asked if I could host an open house there that weekend. After they agreed, I immediately created a flyer for it and started door-knocking. That home was on the market for three months, and I ended up hosting that same open house every weekend that whole time. This allowed me to keep going door to door in my neighborhood and get better traction in the area. It’s also how I got my first listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In my first year, I ended up doing six transactions in that neighborhood, and 17 of my 38 transactions overall came from open house properties.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After mastering open houses, I shifted my attention halfway through that first year to expired listings. I realized that if I wanted to control my time and business, then I need to start focusing on sellers and listings. After flipping the script, I sold 14 expired listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both open houses and expired listings are what I consider “now” business. Anyone whose home expires off the market probably needs to move soon, and buyers who are out looking at open houses are ready to pull the trigger and buy now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In building the foundation of my business this way, &lt;strong&gt;I learned that if you focus on activities that drive results, you can win in a big way.&lt;/strong&gt; The only downside was I was working 55 to 65 hours a week, which wasn’t ideal or healthy, but I knew I had to put in the work or nothing was going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why, after my first year, I started building a team and implementing Keller Williams’ systems and models. Once I had an assistant and a buyer’s agent by my side, we were able to sell 65 houses in 2015 and make about $500,000 in gross commission income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, I went deeper in terms of building leverage (systems, tools, and people) on my team. My goal was figuring out how to make this job turnkey for people who want to get in the business but don’t want to work 70 hours a week trying to crank out deals like I did. Now, an agent can join our team without having to figure out everything on their own like I did. They’ll have instant leverage and be able to stay in their preferred role and focus on activities that get results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It simply wasn’t sustainable for me to work like I was working. &lt;strong&gt;If I was going to have a life worth living and create a life worth living for those I was in business with, I needed to create a model for others to achieve success.&lt;/strong&gt; Since then, I’ve kept a small team behind me as I remained a listing agent. Currently, our team averages between 50 and 65 deals and makes roughly $600,000 in GCI each year&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate is a phenomenal business, and I’m excited to continue to grow in it and provide opportunities to the real estate agent community at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, if you have any questions or real estate topics you’d like me to discuss in a future video, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 14:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestatecareerssacramento.com/how-i-got-my-start-in-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestatecareerssacramento.com/how-i-got-my-start-in-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
