<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academy Mortgage with Patrick Fitzgerald</title>
    <description>Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 12:53:23 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 12:53:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Top 5 Ways to Derail a Loan Approval</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/auYNNxX-qrc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five key ways that you can derail your chances of being approved for a home loan. If you’re serious about purchasing a home, you’ll want to avoid:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Taking on new debt.&lt;/strong&gt; Doing so can change your debt-to-income ratios, which can upset your chances of being approved for a home loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Buying or leasing a new car.&lt;/strong&gt; This can become a big hit to your credit report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Letting someone pull your credit.&lt;/strong&gt; Some files have credit scores that are on the very edge of approval; allowing, for example, a furniture store to pull your credit could be the difference between your approval and rejection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Just wait until after your closing and everyone will be happier.%20http://localhost:4000/the-top-5-ways-to-derail-a-loan-approval.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Just wait until after your closing and everyone will be happier.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Changing or quitting your job.&lt;/strong&gt; Changing your job, even if it’s within the same field, may constitute a red flag under many loan guidelines where we need to gather 30 days’ worth of new pay stubs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Buying new furniture and appliances.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if you take advantage of an offer that has no interest for 18 months, the moment lenders see that you’ve taken on new credit, we have to count the interest in your minimum payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making any of these mistakes during the loan process can amount to potential rejection. Remember this: Mortgage lenders are bound by loan rules to pull a soft credit report on homebuyers either the day before or the day of closing, so don’t fall for the notion that no one will know that you’ve made one of these blunders. If you can’t close your home on time, you might lose your earnest money deposit or even get sued for non-performance on your contract. Just wait until after your closing and everyone will be happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re always here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 14:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-top-5-ways-to-derail-a-loan-approval.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-top-5-ways-to-derail-a-loan-approval.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Conforming Loan Limits</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B3UB0YxPYwA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The U.S. government just increased conforming loan limits for all loan types. What does this mean for homebuyers? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year the government sets maximum loan amounts for conventional, FHA, and VA loans. &lt;strong&gt;The loan limit for conventional and VA loans is now $510,400.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, all conventional loans for that amount or less can be secured for a minimum of 5% down. If you go above that amount, your loan turns into a jumbo loan, which requires other additional rules for your down payment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Each year the government sets maximum loan amounts for conventional, FHA, and VA loans.%20http://localhost:4000/conforming-loan-limits.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Each year the government sets maximum loan amounts for conventional, FHA, and VA loans.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VA loans don’t require a down payment for any loan size, but if your VA loan is above the limit, it becomes a VA high balance loan. Some lenders may impose additional guidelines for these types of loans, so check with your lender to see what their rules are. Also, they may price these loans differently—there might be more attention paid to the borrower’s credit score, debt-to-income ratio, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules are slightly different for FHA loans. In this case, the loan limits are set by the county. &lt;strong&gt;Here in Bexar County, the loan limit for FHA loans is $393,300.&lt;/strong&gt; Some county loan limits in Texas will be higher, others will be lower. It’s important to stay up to date on your county’s limit if you plan on purchasing a home with an FHA loan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any other loan topic, don’t hesitate to give me a call. It doesn’t cost a penny to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 16:27:05 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/conforming-loan-limits.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/conforming-loan-limits.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Real Value of Having a Will</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ywQZNWdFNoQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already have a will, it’s time to set one up. Even if you don’t think you need one right now, the truth is that unexpected tragedy can strike at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, a past client of mine who recently reached out to inform me of her husband’s passing. When I asked if he had a will, she said no. The widow assumed that all of his assets would become hers automatically, but this isn’t so. Inheritance laws do vary from state to state, but &lt;strong&gt;here in Texas, half of a deceased spouse’s assets will be given to their widow, and the other half will be divided equally between their children.&lt;/strong&gt; This isn’t an unusual arrangement for people with wills to choose, but the point is that not having a will eliminates any agency you would otherwise have over how (and to whom) your belongings are given. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The time it takes to set up a will is well worth it.%20http://localhost:4000/the-real-value-of-having-a-will.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The time it takes to set up a will is well worth it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assets distributed without a will are also subject to heavy legal fees,&lt;/strong&gt; meaning that none of the decedent’s beneficiaries will receive the entirety of what was left behind. Worse still, your estate cannot be passed on without first going through probate court, which is a very lengthy and expensive process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All of this can be avoided by simply getting a will.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t even need to go to an attorney to create one. All you need is to buy and complete a will kit, and then get it notarized. Of course, going to an attorney is also a good option for those willing to take a few extra steps. Whatever route you choose, it’s all well worth it to protect your assets, your wishes, and your loved ones’ futures. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 12:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-real-value-of-having-a-will.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-real-value-of-having-a-will.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is a One-Time Close?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wqYlVBtQpDg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A one-time close, or OTC, happens when a homebuyer wants to build a home on land they own, but needs a construction loan in order to fund the build. When the home is finished, then we create the 30-year mortgage to get them on down the road with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one-time close has many benefits. &lt;strong&gt;It pays off the land if you owe money on it, it provides funds to the builder to construct the home, and it builds in a 10% variant to accommodate any potential budget shortfalls.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You won’t have to worry about any closing costs or builder fees.%20http://localhost:4000/what-is-a-one-time-close.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You won’t have to worry about any closing costs or builder fees.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon completion of the home, the builder is paid and there’s nothing else for you to worry about. &lt;strong&gt;No appraisal issues, no closing costs, and no builder fees. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If rates are better at the construction of the home than when you got the loan, you do have the option to lock in those lower rates instead. If rates go up during that same time frame, you’re protected at your initial rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our company allows this one-time close to be used with VA, FHA, and conventional loans.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about one-time closes or anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-a-one-time-close.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-a-one-time-close.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Before You Buy an Investment Property</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fapjAK7Zn3k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’ve decided to buy an investment property. What kind of financial regulations should you be aware of before proceeding any further?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, since I’m known as the “VA loan guy,” let’s get this out of the way: You can’t use a VA loan to purchase an investment property unless you’re purchasing a duplex, triplex, or quadplex and you plan on living in one of the units yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investment property loans are always conventional loans, and the current conforming limit (the maximum for an investment property) is $484,350.&lt;/strong&gt; The mandatory down payment for an investment property is at least 20%, and you can get a slightly better interest rate if you put down more than that. Speaking of interest rates, they’ll always be considerably higher for investment properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The mandatory down payment for an investment property is at least 20%, and you can get a slightly better interest rate if you put down more than that.%20http://localhost:4000/before-you-buy-an-investment-property.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The mandatory down payment for an investment property is at least 20%, and you can get a slightly better interest rate if you put down more than that.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you must have up to six months’ worth of cash reserves (or the equivalent of six monthly mortgage payments) in your bank account after you make your down payment and pay your closing costs. &lt;strong&gt;In other words, buying an investment property requires a good deal of cash.&lt;/strong&gt; The seller can pay a small part of your closing costs when purchasing, but the limit is 2% of the purchase price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you count the current rents coming in? Absolutely, but only 75% of those rents. The reason why is this accounts for various long-term maintenance and insurance costs you’ll have to pay while owning the property. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this or any other subject regarding VA loans, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. It doesn’t cost a penny to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 14:11:38 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/before-you-buy-an-investment-property.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/before-you-buy-an-investment-property.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Is the VA Eliminating Down Payments?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TyVWxfvMMhI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In case you haven’t heard yet, the VA has eliminated down payments on all high-priced homes. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the conforming limit on a VA loan in most areas is $484,350. For a home purchase below that price, there is no down payment and no issue. For purchases above that price threshold, VA buyers have to pay 25% of whatever the overage is. For example, &lt;strong&gt;a veteran will need a $25,000 down payment on a home purchased for $584,000. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is a cool program we’re excited to learn more about.%20http://localhost:4000/why-is-the-va-eliminating-down-payments.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is a cool program we’re excited to learn more about.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting on January 1, however, down payments for homes above that conforming limit threshold will not require any down payment. &lt;strong&gt;If a veteran wants to buy a home for $1 million, they’ll be able to without any down payment.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a cool program that we’re excited to learn more about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email today. It doesn’t cost a penny to talk!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 10:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-is-the-va-eliminating-down-payments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-is-the-va-eliminating-down-payments.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Can’t Quit Your Job During the Loan Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9H8dK5BeVls?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re planning on buying a home and going through the loan process, don’t quit your day job. &lt;strong&gt;You’d be surprised at how often this happens.&lt;/strong&gt; Let me tell you a quick story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m doing an FHA loan right now for a wonderful client. &lt;strong&gt;We contacted her employer to verify her income, but the employer relayed to us that she no longer worked there.&lt;/strong&gt; Imagine the panic we had when finding out that information. We found out that she quit her new job, but started a better job with higher pay so she thought it wouldn’t be a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We had to delay the contract by about a month.%20http://localhost:4000/why-you-cant-quit-your-job-during-the-loan-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We had to delay the contract by about a month.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was a big deal, and here’s why.&lt;/strong&gt; Under FHA and VA loan guidelines, we need to have 30 days’ worth of paystubs at their new job to verify their income. Her contract was supposed to close on July 5, but now we’re going to have to delay it for a month or so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s causing all kinds of tension with the seller, the buyer, and their Realtors. &lt;strong&gt;If she would have contacted us before quitting, we would have advised her to wait about a month until the property closed to start her new job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re contemplating a job change, even if it’s higher-paying, better job, try to wait until your loan is closed. If you have any questions for me or know anyone in a situation like this, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 09:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-cant-quit-your-job-during-the-loan-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-you-cant-quit-your-job-during-the-loan-process.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Do When an Appraisal Comes Up Short</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3SVsI4ks0q4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens when an appraisal comes up short of what a home is sold for? If the buyer has a VA loan, here’s what it looks like. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s say a home is sold for $250,000 to a buyer with VA financing.&lt;/strong&gt; The mortgage company will send the appointed VA appraiser along with the contract for the property. The appraiser then goes to the property, measures it, looks at its condition, and formulates an opinion on its value. Then, the appraiser will go back and do some research to see what other, similar homes have sold for recently. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why it’s so important for your Realtor to complete a CMA, or comparative market analysis. This will give you a great idea of what the home will appraise for before the appraiser even gets there. Both your Realtor and the appraiser use the same sold database to know what homes in the neighborhood have sold for recently. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I’ve had a short appraisal three times in the last 30 days.%20http://localhost:4000/what-to-do-when-an-appraisal-comes-up-short.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I’ve had a short appraisal three times in the last 30 days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the appraiser cannot find the value that’s on the contract, he declares Tidewater.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a VA term that states the appraiser can’t find the value of the home that’s on the contract and gives the mortgage company 48 hours to find additional comparable properties to support the contract value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, this causes a great big problem. I’ve had this happen three times in the last 30 days, unfortunately. There are a few different ways with which to proceed in this, but it rarely happens. Typically, the seller will have to come down on the sale price to get the appraisal to come in. The VA buyer always has an out too and can cancel the contract if the appraisal comes up short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the meantime about any and everything VA loans, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 14:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-to-do-when-an-appraisal-comes-up-short.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-to-do-when-an-appraisal-comes-up-short.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>USDA Loan Changes Can Now Be Used for Manufactured Homes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2_TAErL6wfE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some recent changes to the USDA loan in regards to manufactured homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effective immediately in Texas, you can now use a USDA loan on pre-owned manufactured homes.&lt;/strong&gt; What’s so cool about this? Well, the USDA loan is a zero down conventional loan program, meaning buyers don’t have to make a down payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean all mortgage companies will do this, however. Each company has slightly different rules, so make sure you verify with yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Each company has slightly different rules, so make sure you verify with yours.%20http://localhost:4000/usda-loan-changes-can-now-be-used-for-manufactured-homes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Each company has slightly different rules, so make sure you verify with yours.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To qualify for the loan in Texas,&lt;/strong&gt; you must have a credit score of at least 620, the home must be a double wide, and it must be permanently attached to the ground or retrofitted (the foundation must meet HUD guidelines). The home must have been manufactured after January 1, 2006, and it has to be sitting where it was originally installed. A move doesn’t include the transport from the dealer or factory to where it was installed; it means moving it from one address to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 12:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/usda-loan-changes-can-now-be-used-for-manufactured-homes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/usda-loan-changes-can-now-be-used-for-manufactured-homes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pre-Approval vs. Pre-Qualification</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1tIZ05asMkI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to talk about the difference between being pre-qualified and being pre-approved. I get this question a lot, so I figured I’d answer it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A pre-qualification means that a lender has pulled your credit, examined your documents, and submitted an automated online approval with Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A pre-approval contains all of the above, plus we submit the file to an underwriter.&lt;/strong&gt; The underwriter looks at everything, asks for clarification, and makes a decision on whether you can afford a home or not. Once you’re pre-approved, you know exactly what you can afford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A pre-approval might take a few days longer, but it can save you a lot of trouble.%20http://localhost:4000/pre-approval-vs-pre-qualification.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A pre-approval might take a few days longer, but it can save you a lot of trouble.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer in the market and out there making offers, &lt;strong&gt;a pre-approval shows sellers and their Realtors that your approval is firm and that you actually can afford the home.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a really important thing, especially in today’s market where multiple offers are common. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pre-approval might take a few days longer, but it can save you a lot of trouble. If you have any questions for me or need more information, don’t forget that it doesn’t cost a penny to talk. I’d love to hear from you. Just give me a call or send me an email today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 16:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pre-approval-vs-pre-qualification.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pre-approval-vs-pre-qualification.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
