<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Beach and Sun Homes - your professional San Diego Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 16:28:47 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 16:28:47 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everyday Encinitas: All About You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MwoMvA_k1zg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;I recently had the pleasure of joining Rodrigo Ballon on an episode of &amp;ldquo;All About You&amp;rdquo; to talk about a variety of topics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For this episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” I’ll show you a recent guest spot I did on the TV show “All About You” with host Rodrigo Ballon. In this wide-ranging interview, I talk about what motivated me in my real estate career, why there’s nowhere else I’d rather work than North County, and what I predict for the rest of the 2020 market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch it in its entirety or use these timestamps to browse specific points at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:45 - How I got my start&lt;br /&gt;2:29 - What I was doing before real estate&lt;br /&gt;4:46 - Why I enjoy working in North County&lt;br /&gt;7:10 - The type of person I’m looking to bring on to my team&lt;br /&gt;9:00 - Where I see the market heading for the rest of 2020&lt;br /&gt;10:15 - Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about any of the topics discussed in today’s video or you’re an agent looking to join a team that can take you to the next level in your career, give me a call, email me, or &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.beachandsunhomes.com/&quot;&gt;visit my website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-all-about-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-all-about-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Appearance on “Inside the Masterminds”</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7fcgVTBORNc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;I recently appeared on &amp;ldquo;Inside the Masterminds&amp;rdquo; with Valli Williams, and I wanted to share the full segment with you today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the latest episode of “Inside the Masterminds” with Valli Williams, I joined the program to talk about several different topics including my journey in real estate, the current state of the real estate market, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s an outline of the discussion, with timestamps so that you can skip around to the section(s) that interest you most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:30 - A quick update on the North County real estate market&lt;br /&gt;1:25 - Talking about Everyday Encinitas and the experiences we’ve had with it&lt;br /&gt;3:30 - The difference between a seller’s market and a &lt;em&gt;strong&lt;/em&gt; seller’s market&lt;br /&gt;5:30 - A few reasons why inventory has been so low in our market lately&lt;br /&gt;6:10 - Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions for me about anything I discussed in the video above, feel free to reach out via phone or email today. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/my-appearance-on-inside-the-masterminds.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/my-appearance-on-inside-the-masterminds.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everyday Encinitas: American Legion Post 416</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ud-t7otj07M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the latest episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” I’m spotlighting American Legion Post 416 and chatting with Christian Schilling, one of its executive board members. The American Legion is a veteran-based nonprofit organization, and aside from having the coldest beer on F Street, Post 416 serves as a hub of community outreach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:51 - The American Legion’s history and purpose&lt;br /&gt;2:11 - A timeline of American Legion Post 416 and the types of community outreach they provide&lt;br /&gt;3:41 - Their recent bar remodel and their plans to renovate other areas of the building&lt;br /&gt;5:10 - A shoutout to their great staff&lt;br /&gt;6:19 - Open mic nights, live music, wings, and what a night on the town looks like at American Legion Post 416&lt;br /&gt;8:13 - Find more information at &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://calegionpost416.org/&quot;&gt;calegionpost416.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;8:49 - Wrapping things up with a quick toast&lt;br /&gt;9:11 - What Post 416 means to its community veterans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend you stop by American Legion Post 416 if you get a chance and salute the staff. It was my pleasure to learn more about our nation’s veterans and how we can help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own a local business or are a part of a community organization that you’d like to see showcased on a future episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-american-legion-post-416.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-american-legion-post-416.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everyday Encinitas: One Day Signs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/moYMfmvDX-o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;I recently met with Marco San Antonio, of One Day Signs, to discuss what his business offers to the people of Encinitas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today on “Everyday Encinitas,” our quest to spotlight local businesses and community organizations, brings us into the company of Marco San Antonio, owner of One Day Signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One Day Signs has been a staple in Encinitas for more than 30 years and boasts a rich history. It started back when Marco’s father Omar retired from the U.S. Navy after 22 years of service and went to Hawaii, where his brother owned a sign shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the business model, Omar relocated to Encinitas to open One Day Signs, which he and Marco operated together for many years before Omar’s retirement last year; Marco is excited to be the new owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s truly incredible what the San Antonio family and their team can do; &lt;strong&gt;producing high-quality signs in one day or less isn’t easy, but it has become their brand&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=One Day Signs has been a staple in Encinitas for more than 30 years and boasts a rich history.%20localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-one-day-signs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“One Day Signs has been a staple in Encinitas for more than 30 years and boasts a rich history.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve relied on One Day Signs many times for my real estate signs, but can anybody off the street come in and request a sign? Absolutely, says Marco, who also added that &lt;strong&gt;people can get just about any type of sign&lt;/strong&gt;, from garage sale signs to banners, and even large ‘For Lease’ signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the keys to One Day Signs’ success is that everything can be done right there on site; Marco likes to control the entire process that way, ensuring that he and his team are the ones helping customers design and draft whatever signage they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Marco, One Day Signs is a cut above the competition because of the deep commitment to service and the quality end product customers receive. So if you’re out and about, &lt;strong&gt;stop by &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/iqW5B18qnCgYYpV2A&quot;&gt;the shop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, located by D Street and Encinitas Boulevard, just north of the large Encinitas sign. Otherwise, you can &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.onedaysignsencinitas.com/&quot;&gt;visit their website here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a pleasure to meet the San Antonios. If you’re a local business or a community organization who would like to be featured on the next episode of Everyday Encinitas, please reach out to me by phone or email. I’d love to feature you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-one-day-signs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-one-day-signs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everyday Encinitas: Sunburst Shutters</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/w4d7-OKTfyw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sunburst Shutters brings a wide variety of shutters and other window accessories to our community. I sat down with CEO Tyson Williams recently to talk about this and more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In today’s edition of “Everyday Encinitas,” I’m joined by Tyson Williams, CEO of Sunburst Shutters, to talk a little bit about his exciting business and what they’re doing in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s an outline of our discussion, with timestamps so that you can skip around to the section(s) that interest you most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:45 - What services does Sunburst Shutters offer?&lt;br /&gt;1:25 - The history of Sunburst Shutters&lt;br /&gt;1:45 - Why did they choose San Diego for a second brick and mortar?&lt;br /&gt;2:15 - How Sunburst Shutters can help keep your home protected year-round from sun, ocean air, and more&lt;br /&gt;4:00 - A little more about the Sunburst Shutter team in San Diego&lt;br /&gt;5:00 - Why form and function are so crucial in finding the right shutters&lt;br /&gt;5:30 - A few reasons why people choose to hire Sunburst Shutters&lt;br /&gt;6:55 - Tyson’s favorite type of shutter and why&lt;br /&gt;7:30 - The pros and cons of buying shutters at different prices&lt;br /&gt;8:55 - A closer look at the Sunburst Shutters showroom&lt;br /&gt;10:20 - Warranty information&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks again to Tyson for joining me to talk about some of the finer aspects of his business&lt;/strong&gt;. There’s a reason that our clients can’t stop talking about Sunburst Shutters after they’ve worked with them. &lt;strong&gt;To learn more about Sunburst Shutters, &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://sunburstshutters.com/&quot;&gt;visit their website here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for me about real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-sunburst-shutters.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-sunburst-shutters.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everyday Encinitas: Kind Health Group</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ioymovnSE1k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;On today&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Everyday Encinitas,&amp;rdquo; I sat down with Dr. Georgine Nanos to talk about her work at Kind Health Group.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” where our goal is to spotlight local businesses and community organizations around the area to learn a little bit more about them. Today we had the pleasure of meeting Dr. Georgine Nanos, founder of the Kind Health Group. Here’s what she had to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to follow along in the video above or use the timestamps below to navigate the video at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:38 - Dr. Georgine Nanos, founder of Kind Health Group, tells me the story of its beginnings&lt;br /&gt;1:12 - The services that Kind Health uses to help people feel beautiful inside and out&lt;br /&gt;1:42 - How their laser hair and acne scar removal technology works&lt;br /&gt;2:59 - Dr. Nanos elaborates on her history with medicine in the area&lt;br /&gt;4:25 - A preventative, not reactive, approach to wellness&lt;br /&gt;5:52 - Meet the staff of Kind Health Group&lt;br /&gt;9:10 - Why people should pay Dr. Nanos and the Kind Health Group a visit&lt;br /&gt;10:12 - The Kind Health Group’s well-known procedure: Mona Lisa Touch Laser&lt;br /&gt;12:08 - Visit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://kindhealthgroup.com/&quot;&gt;KindHealthGroup.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for more details&lt;br /&gt;12:55 - Wrapping up today’s topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a local business or community organization who would like to be featured on an upcoming video, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to hear all about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-kind-health-group.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-kind-health-group.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everyday Encinitas: Dahms Acupuncture</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6tE9mFiJqN8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who knew that acupuncture could be so fascinating? I learned all about it today by sitting down with the owner of Dahms Acupuncture, Talia Dahms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my latest episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” I’m meeting with Talia Dahms from Dahms Acupuncture to chat about the wonders she’s working for those seeking treatment. Let’s go in and see what she has to say!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps of our conversation so you can skip ahead to the topic(s) you’re most interested in:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:55 - The basics of acupuncture, what Talia specializes in, and what a layperson might not know about acupuncture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:08 - What led Talia to this profession&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:15 - The science behind acupuncture treatment and how it “activates” channels in the body&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:25 - What is “cupping” and does it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:46 - The benefits associated with cosmetic acupuncture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:47 - How Talia generates most of her business&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:32 - Why Talia should be your go-to acupuncturist&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:05 - How to get in contact with Talia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You strategically choose certain points along certain channels, and they all communicate with each other to balance each other out.%20localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-dahms-acupuncture.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You strategically choose certain points along certain channels, and they all communicate with each other to balance each other out.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a pleasure to meet Talia Dahms and cast a spotlight on her business today. If you’d like to find out more, or schedule an appointment, you can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dahmsacupuncture.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;visit their website here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know of or are part of a local business or organization that you’d like to have featured on a future episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” please let me know. You can call me directly at (619) 752-4663. We’ll see you in the next episode!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 12:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-dahms-acupuncture.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-dahms-acupuncture.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everyday Encinitas: Besta-Wan Pizza</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_Nm2a9EXk-A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Besta-Wan Pizza may be one of the best-kept secrets right here in Cardiff-by-the-Sea, but today we&amp;rsquo;re revealing all of what makes this such a special local eatery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my latest episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” I’m sitting down with Kyle Schmuckle from Besta-Wan Pizza to chat about the restaurant’s history, culture, food and drink selections, and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps of our conversation so you can skip ahead to the section(s) that interest you most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:53 - The history behind Besta-Wan’s founding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:26 - How the current owners, Becky and Julio, have renewed Besta-Wan’s popularity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:05 - The warm, friendly environment Besta-Wan’s staff creates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:40 - All about Besta-Wan’s drink selection, including their famous “man-mosa”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:25 - What makes Besta-Wan’s pizza a cut (or slice) above the rest?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:05 - The story behind the “Schmuckle 5000” pizza—a now-favorite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:11 - Besta-Wan’s novel wall decor and where it came from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:06 - What are the main attractions of not only Besta-Wan, but also of the area as a whole?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:05 - Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The atmosphere is like 'Cheers'—where everybody knows your name.%20localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-besta-wan-pizza.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The atmosphere is like ‘Cheers’—where everybody knows your name.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to find out more about Besta-Wan Pizza, or take a look at their hours and menu, you can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thebestawanpizza.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;visit their website here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know of or are part of a local business or organization that you’d like to have featured on a future episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” don’t hesitate to let me know. You can call me directly at (619) 752-4663. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-besta-wan-pizza.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-besta-wan-pizza.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everyday Encinitas: Iron Cross Surfboards</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lfe3vIvmOiQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;At Iron Cross Surfboards, you can get everything you need to catch the perfect wave.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my latest episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” I’m visiting Iron Cross Surfboards and speaking with Jay Grygera to discover what makes them the go-to surf shop for local surfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps of our conversation so you can skip ahead to the section(s) that interest you the most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:02 - How Iron Cross Surfboards came to be&lt;br /&gt;3:11 - All the different types of custom boards they carry&lt;br /&gt;4:01 - What type of board is Jay riding these days?&lt;br /&gt;4:22 - A glimpse at their new Daily Driver longboard model&lt;br /&gt;4:51 - How they’ve been able to grow over the past few years&lt;br /&gt;6:13 - What they can do for you if your board’s been dinged up&lt;br /&gt;6:47 - What wetsuit Jay recommends&lt;br /&gt;7:54 - Getting to know their staff&lt;br /&gt;8:42 - Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Iron Cross carries every kind of surfboard for any skill level—all handmade.%20localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-iron-cross-surfboards.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Iron Cross carries every kind of surfboard for any skill level—all handmade.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an absolute pleasure to be able to sit down with Jay, and I thank him for allowing us to visit his family’s shop. If you’d like to know more about Iron Cross Surfboards, you can &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ironcrosssurfboards.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;visit their website here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own a local business or community organization, or you know someone who does and you think they’d be interested in being featured on a future episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” don’t hesitate to give me a call. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-iron-cross-surfboards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-iron-cross-surfboards.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everyday Encinitas: Best Pizza &amp; Brew</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZEuteljixJ8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome back to Everyday Encinitas. This time, we&amp;rsquo;re checking out Best Pizza &amp;amp; Brew.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another episode of “Everyday Encinitas,” where, as always, our goal is to shine a spotlight on the local businesses that help our community thrive. This time, we’re meeting with Mitchell Millar from Best Pizza &amp;amp; Brew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Located in Downtown Cardiff-by-the-Sea, Best Pizza &amp;amp; Brew has always been amazing, but after their recent remodel, they’ve become the talk of the town&lt;/strong&gt;. The windows that face the sea open garage-door style to create an indoor/outdoor ambiance. But that’s not all that makes them special—their menu truly makes them shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their fresh ingredients and made-to-order approach to what they serve makes all the difference, and their lunch specials are definitely crowd pleasers, as well. And if you’re looking to wet your whistle, they’ve got 20 beers on tap for you to enjoy while you dig into one of their signature slices. If wine is more your thing, they’ve got that available, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you visit Best Pizza &amp;amp; Brew, you’re going to have a great time no matter what.%20localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-best-pizza-brew.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you visit Best Pizza &amp;amp; Brew, you’re going to have a great time no matter what.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not only is it great food, it’s also the best vibe. You’re going to have a great time no matter what,” says Mitchell about the experience people have at Best Pizza &amp;amp; Brew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To learn more about Best Pizza &amp;amp; Brew, including their menu, hours, and location, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bestpizzaandbrew.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;visit their website here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-best-pizza-brew.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/everyday-encinitas-best-pizza-brew.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
