<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Stern Team: Home Page</title>
    <description>Salt Lake City Utah best Realtors are on The Stern Team, led by Joshua Stern. Follow us for latest market info and be prepared to buy or sell real estate.</description>
    <link>http://sternteam.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sternteam.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 10:51:54 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 10:51:54 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Important Message on Buying New Construction</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HsII9hjglcM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you thought about buying a new construction home? If so, there are five points you need to be aware of: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New construction homes aren’t always listed on the MLS.&lt;/strong&gt; Quite often, home builders have agents working as on-site salespeople in order to increase their control of the transaction while reducing total costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New construction homes are often sold before they’re built.&lt;/strong&gt; Builders will generally line up financing and the construction and sales process before a property is even built.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first buyers within a subdivision may get the greatest discounts.&lt;/strong&gt; However, As the saying goes, “the early bird gets the worm.” Acting quickly when a new subdivision is being built could lead to financial rewards. These rewards also come with the risk of being committed to a process before much is known about how it will play out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builders put a lot of emphasis on numbers.&lt;/strong&gt; Since a builder isn’t a traditional seller, they don’t have an emotional attachment to the home(s) they’re selling, and will therefore be more focused on making sure you’re qualified and ready to purchase than anything else.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discounts may be available in the form of upgrades.&lt;/strong&gt; If the property is close to the end of the sales cycle, builders may be willing to offer you an upgrade package that would reduce the overall cost of purchasing the home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 11:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/an-important-message-on-buying-new-construction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/an-important-message-on-buying-new-construction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Josh Stern Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2019: A Market Year in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/l_FKp1is30I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the numbers from the Wasatch Front in 2019:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Single-family home sales: 38,024&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Condo and townhome sales: 10,305 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Average home price: $376,000 (a 7% year-over-year increase)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Average days on market: 51 (a 16% year-over-year increase)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Absorption rate: 4 months (a 20% year-over-year increase)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The law of supply and demand, which drives all economies, says that if the supply is down and the demand is up, then prices go up. We’ve had a pretty good ride in terms of home price increases across the Wasatch Front over the last six years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If political volatility continues throughout the new year, we expect interest rates to remain low.%20http://sternteam.org/2019-a-market-year-in-review.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If political volatility continues throughout the new year, we expect interest rates to remain low.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In real estate, a level market is when you have between four and six months’ worth of available homes at any given time. If the supply drops below that point, it creates a seller’s market with upward pressure on pricing. If supply rises above that point, the market becomes a buyer’s market. &lt;strong&gt;Our market has four months of inventory, which is being driven by an increased supply of homes and lowering affordability.&lt;/strong&gt; While home appreciation is a good thing, over time, it can put limits on what buyers can purchase, especially first-time homebuyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended 2019 with some political volatility, which has continued to impact both the bond and stock markets; the big items impacting the market are our trade agreements with China and our relationship with Iran and the Middle East. If this volatility continues throughout the new year, we expect interest rates to remain low, and if it’s resolved, rates will likely rise as they react to inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about real estate or the market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re here to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 11:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/2019-a-market-year-in-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/2019-a-market-year-in-review.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Things Sellers Should Always Remember to Do</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uj5jBhC2ZoI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling a home can be a complicated process. As such, there are a few things that many home sellers simply forget about as they prepare their home for sale. Here are six things to keep in mind when selling your home:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on staging.&lt;/strong&gt; You may already like the way your furniture is arranged, but does it appeal to buyers? Your home should be set up in a way that shows off your living areas and opens up the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve your curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt; The outside may just be as important as what’s inside. Your home’s exterior is the first thing buyers see, so make sure it is maintained well and looks inviting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show off your smart-home tech.&lt;/strong&gt; If your home has smart locks, thermostats, carbon monoxide detectors, or any other smart-home technologies, make sure buyers are aware of them. Many people consider them necessary home fixtures in today’s digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your home should be set up in a way that shows off your living areas and opens up the space.%20http://sternteam.org/6-things-sellers-should-always-remember-to-do.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your home should be set up in a way that shows off your living areas and opens up the space.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tackle home odors.&lt;/strong&gt; Unpleasant smells can be a dealbreaker for buyers. Make sure your home is free of any uninviting aromas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update lighting hardware and fixtures.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers love brightly lit rooms, so make sure your bulbs are all working. If your fixtures are outdated, consider replacing them for a more modern feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimize decor.&lt;/strong&gt; The goal is to depersonalize your home so buyers can see themselves living in it. Though vibrantly colored walls may be your style, not everyone has the same tastes as you. It’s better to stick with neutral colors such as gray, white, and taupe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 11:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/6-things-sellers-should-always-remember-to-do.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/6-things-sellers-should-always-remember-to-do.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Keep Your Home Decluttered Forever</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qHA4bqArFcM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to decluttering, Marie Kondo is all the rage right now. She’s the Japanese lifestyle celebrity who has the miraculous ability to help people declutter their homes for good. What’s her trick? Only keep the things that spark joy or keep you happy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are three tips based on that principle that you should follow when decluttering:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, collect all of the same things around the house (e.g. all the books), touch each object once, and ask yourself whether it sparks joy. If it doesn’t, it needs to go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=At the end of the day, you’ll find that you only keep things that make you happy.%20http://sternteam.org/3-tips-to-keep-your-home-decluttered-forever.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“At the end of the day, you’ll find that you only keep things that make you happy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, remember to follow the right order when tidying up. Start with clothing, move on to books, papers, and other miscellaneous items, and then focus on mementos. By the time you get to mementos, you’ll understand the method. Don’t keep things because you think they might come in handy. The likelihood that they will come in handy is low, and you can always buy a newer version of an item that does spark joy in the off-chance that you’ll need it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;get rid of the clutter before buying storage containers&lt;/strong&gt; or other oversized products to organize your space. Take it slow and don’t stress over the process too much. You want to make sure you do it right and on your own time. At the end of the day, you’ll find that you only keep things that make you happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 11:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/3-tips-to-keep-your-home-decluttered-forever.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/3-tips-to-keep-your-home-decluttered-forever.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Is How Long a Pre-Approval Usually Lasts</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T93hCpM58DI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re hoping to buy a home, it’s smart to ponder the question, “How long does a pre-approval last?” Even after you’ve received a lender’s stamp of approval for your financing, weeks or even months could pass before you actually buy a house. Will that pre-approval you receive still be valid by then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since lenders realize that buying a house does take time, pre-approval dates have a shelf life, but not a definite one.&lt;/strong&gt; While the length of time varies, in general, a pre-approval is good for about three months. Here’s what homebuyers need to know to make the most out of this time frame, and what to do if your pre-approval is at risk of running out before you buy a home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step to buying a home should be to prove that you have the financial means to do so through a pre-approval. &lt;strong&gt;This is a process through which a mortgage professional examines a loan application to determine whether a potential buyer will qualify for a mortgage. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A pre-approval is usually good for anywhere from 90 to 180 days.%20http://sternteam.org/this-is-how-long-a-pre-approval-usually-lasts.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A pre-approval is usually good for anywhere from 90 to 180 days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To obtain a pre-approval, buyers need to provide a mortgage lender with information like their employment history, credit score, income, and debts. During this process, the lender will want to see bank statements, pay stubs, and tax returns. &lt;strong&gt;It can feel invasive, but lenders are looking to protect their interests by not loaning money to someone who could be considered “high-risk.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are people who have high, outstanding debts, inconsistent income, or a history of late payments. Once a lender reviews your finances, they will give you a pre-approval letter, detailing a good-faith willingness to extend mortgage financing based on its preliminary examinations of your assets, income stream, and creditworthiness. &lt;strong&gt;This letter will also detail the actual loan amount that you qualify for. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How long does a pre-approval last? Although there is no definite duration, the custom within our industry is that a pre-approval is good from anywhere for 90 to 180 days, but many may consider it “too old” after three months. The reason? In three months, your financial life can change drastically. You can buy appliances, a car, or do plenty of other things to affect your home buying prospects. &lt;strong&gt;Since pre-approvals do have a shelf life, it’s best to not get one until you’re seriously looking for a home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this information has been useful to you. If you have any other real estate questions or needs, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email today. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/this-is-how-long-a-pre-approval-usually-lasts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/this-is-how-long-a-pre-approval-usually-lasts.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Sellers Must Disclose About Their Listing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0RSN-pqF9rE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’ve lived in your home for a few years or a few decades, you know all about its quirks, its best features, and its flaws. When you decide to sell your home, some of this information might be necessary for you to share with buyers in the form of a seller disclosure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Including certain flaws in this document can feel uncomfortable; however, it’s best to be open and honest during the process.&lt;/strong&gt; Failing to disclose certain issues could land you in legal trouble or, at the very least, create significant hurdles for your home sale. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially true since buyers will find out through a home inspection, anyway, if any problems (major or minor) are present in your home. Alternatively, if a problem does manage to escape their notice, but they ultimately discover it after closing, you could be subject to a lawsuit if they believe you intentionally hid the issue during your deal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While different states have different laws about what you must disclose, federal laws do make it necessary for sellers across the nation to be forthcoming about one hazard in particular: lead paint. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Failing to disclose certain issues could land you in legal trouble or, at the very least, create significant hurdles for your home sale.%20http://sternteam.org/what-sellers-must-disclose-about-their-listing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Failing to disclose certain issues could land you in legal trouble or, at the very least, create significant hurdles for your home sale.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your home was built in or before 1978, you are legally responsible for ordering an inspection to check for lead paint.&lt;/strong&gt; You are also required to issue the results of this inspection to the buyer in the form of a seller disclosure document. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for what disclosure requirements you might be subject to in your specific area, these regulations change too rapidly for us to list any specifics here. Instead, we recommend that you speak to your agent directly about current local regulations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, though, problems that sellers should disclose regardless of local regulations include water damage, mold, pests, or any other major structural, mechanical, or safety-related issues. Buyers will also likely ask to see evidence that these problems have been resolved, so save all applicable receipts and paperwork from applicable repairs or insurance claims you’ve made. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some states even require sellers to disclose any risk of natural hazards like wildfires, earthquakes, or flooding, if these are common to the area.&lt;/strong&gt; So, again, check with your Realtor to see how you should proceed when it comes time to make your own disclosures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or would like to discuss your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/what-sellers-must-disclose-about-their-listing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/what-sellers-must-disclose-about-their-listing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winter Is as Good a Time as Any to Buy or Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/922Qw5-2nGk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For today’s topic, we’re going to discuss the benefits of buying or selling in the fall or winter. Contrary to what you might think, the passing of the summer season doesn’t necessarily equate to stagnation in the market now.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are great tax advantages to buying or selling late in the year.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers who close escrow before year’s end will enjoy tax write-offs that they otherwise wouldn’t receive in the new year. This can result in highly significant savings for you when tax season rolls around. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not just buyers that reap the benefits of end-of-year moves—closing costs and home improvements are also tax-deductible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don’t have to fight the winter weather.&lt;/strong&gt; If the frightful winter weather is keeping you from purchasing a home late in the year, it may be best to buy in the fall months. This comes with its own set of advantages that will not only allow you to dodge any unpleasant winter weather, but also to get cozy in your new home just in time for the holidays. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ll have greater availability to services.&lt;/strong&gt; Buying in the fall or winter can also open up greater access to resources, such as moving services, which the influx of buyers and sellers in the spring and summertime make hard to find.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The “off-season” is anything but.&lt;/strong&gt; Due to a higher scarcity of buyers and sellers in the fall and winter months, closing at a realistic asking price can be most easily accomplished during this window. Coming up with a good pricing strategy is sure to make your home shine brightly over the competition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Due to a higher scarcity of buyers and sellers in the fall and winter months, closing at a realistic asking price can be most easily accomplished during this window.%20http://sternteam.org/winter-is-as-good-a-time-as-any-to-buy-or-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Due to a higher scarcity of buyers and sellers in the fall and winter months, closing at a realistic asking price can be most easily accomplished during this window.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers will likely see an upsurge in the chances they’ll get a home that’s within their budget, since bidding wars and homes selling above asking price are less of a factor this time of year. Competition may drop in the fall since people often consider it to be the “off-season,” but this is far from the case for a serious buyer—there seldom is a drop-off in inventory in the fall and winter seasons. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Less competition and stable inventory are highly attractive to buyers. This is mutually beneficial to both buyers and sellers because it means that a seller’s agent won’t have to wade through one non-serious offer after another. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you need to make some last-minute home improvements before it’s time to sell, contractors and subcontractors tend to be more available and at a lower cost with the slower pace that the fall and winter bring. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, please give us a call or email us with any other real estate-related needs or questions. We’d be happy to assist you however we can. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 11:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/winter-is-as-good-a-time-as-any-to-buy-or-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/winter-is-as-good-a-time-as-any-to-buy-or-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why List During the Holidays?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qMzpKo1SOxU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer is now in the rear-view mirror but despite what some believe, the end of warmer weather does not mean our market has completely cooled off. Selling your home over the holiday season is often a smart move for sellers savvy enough to take advantage. Not only is there less competition during these later months, but the buyers who are out looking also tend to be much more serious about finding the right home. And these are just a couple of benefits sellers can enjoy when listing at this time of year. Homes also show well during the holidays thanks to seasonal decor and the warm-and-fuzzy feelings that tend to crop up as the year draws to a close. The bottom line is that if you want to sell in 2019, it isn’t too late. Our team would be happy to help you sell quickly and for top dollar this holiday season. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/why-list-during-the-holidays.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/why-list-during-the-holidays.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What All Homebuyers Must Know About New Construction Properties</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HsII9hjglcM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you thought about buying a new construction home? If so, there are five points you need to be aware of: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. New construction homes aren’t always listed on the MLS.&lt;/strong&gt; Quite often, home builders have agents working as on-site salespeople in order to increase their control of the transaction while reducing total costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. New construction homes are often sold before they’re built.&lt;/strong&gt; Builders will generally line up financing and line up the construction and sales process before a property is even built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The first buyers within a subdivision may get the greatest discounts.&lt;/strong&gt; As the saying goes, “the early bird gets the worm.” Acting quickly when a new subdivision is being built could lead to financial rewards. These rewards also come with the risk of being committed to a process before much is known about how it will play out, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Builders put a lot of emphasis on numbers.&lt;/strong&gt; Since a builder isn’t a traditional seller, they don’t have an emotional attachment to the home(s) they’re selling, and will therefore be more focused on making sure you’re qualified and ready to purchase than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Discounts may be available in the form of upgrades.&lt;/strong&gt; If the property is close to the end of the sales cycle, builders may be willing to offer you an upgrade package that would reduce the overall cost of purchasing the home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Acting quickly when a new subdivision is being built could lead to financial rewards.%20http://sternteam.org/what-all-homebuyers-must-know-about-new-construction-properties.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Acting quickly when a new subdivision is being built could lead to financial rewards.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/what-all-homebuyers-must-know-about-new-construction-properties.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/what-all-homebuyers-must-know-about-new-construction-properties.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Real Estate Numbers Along the Wasatch Front</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QEi7lveDkDI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re back with another update on the Wasatch Front real estate market. In the third quarter of 2019, we saw a significant jump in sales. &lt;strong&gt;Year to date, we’re up 2.1% with over 37,700 homes sold so far in 2019.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average price for all home types is over $383,000. At the same time last year, our average price was just over $354,000. That’s an 8.2% year-over-year increase, which is &lt;strong&gt;great news if you’re a homeowner looking to capitalize on your equity by selling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our average days on market along the Wasatch Front is 47 days—a 20% increase from the 39-day average we saw at this time last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Prices are rising, but so is our supply of homes.%20http://sternteam.org/the-latest-real-estate-numbers-along-the-wasatch-front.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Prices are rising, but so is our supply of homes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our overall inventory for all housing types is at a 3.8-month supply. Anything less than six months is considered a seller’s market. The market is still very good, but homes are taking slightly longer to sell. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third quarter also brought us some of the lowest interest rates we’ve seen in a few years. As we finish the third quarter, rates jumped up a bit, but are still fantastic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prices continue to go up, but there’s more inventory available.&lt;/strong&gt; Couple that with solid interest rates and we have a good market for buyers and sellers right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/the-latest-real-estate-numbers-along-the-wasatch-front.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/the-latest-real-estate-numbers-along-the-wasatch-front.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
