<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tulsa Real Estate Video Blog with Jennie Wolek</title>
    <description>Our mission at Keller Williams Realty Advantage is to be your best resource for Tulsa real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Keller Williams Realty Advantage, your professional Tulsa Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 09:13:07 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 09:13:07 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tulsa Foodie Episode 3: Ediblend Superfood Cafe</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TOzQH7z98zI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today on “Tulsa Foodie,” we’ve decided to feature Ediblend Superfood Cafe in Utica Square. To give us a better idea about what this great restaurant is all about, we decided to meet up with its founders: Piper Kacere and Amy Murray. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for Ediblend Superfood Cafe began years ago when Piper and Amy, who are sisters, decided to do a juice cleanse. They got off to a rocky start, but shortly after beginning their second attempt, Piper and Amy began to attract the interest of people around them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, they started making cleanses for these people and, before they knew it, &lt;strong&gt;they started receiving text messages and calls from total strangers who were interested in their product.&lt;/strong&gt; So they bought up all the mason jars and shower caddies they could find, then started making and packaging cleanses from a playroom in Piper’s home that they had converted into a kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Though these juice blends are where they got their start, the Ediblend Superfood Cafe has a lot more to offer.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-3-ediblend-superfood-cafe.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Though these juice blends are where they got their start, the Ediblend Superfood Cafe has a lot more to offer.”&lt;/a&gt;That coming summer, they moved their operation into a test kitchen they had rented out, and, lo and behold, they completely sold out for the season. Their satisfied customers couldn’t stop raving about their experience, so Piper and Amy knew it was time to open a permanent location. Now, &lt;strong&gt;since opening in 2014, the Ediblend Superfood Cafe has two locations and a massive fan base here in Tulsa.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at their wide range of healthy and delicious blends, like the Sweet Green, 1717, and Sexy Yowza, it’s no wonder why. And though these juice blends are where they got their start, the Ediblend Superfood Cafe has a lot more to offer. When you visit their restaurant, you can also enjoy great salads or one of their customizable açaí bowls. Best of all, everything in the cafe is made fresh every single day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, Amy and Piper are looking forward to expanding their business, and its menu, even wider. If you’re as interested as we are in seeing what’s on the horizon for Ediblend Superfood Cafe, or you’re curious about their hours, locations, or menu, &lt;strong&gt;be sure to follow them on &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ediblendcafe/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; or visit their website: &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://ediblend.com/&quot;&gt;https://ediblend.com/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 10:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-3-ediblend-superfood-cafe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-3-ediblend-superfood-cafe.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Need a Home Warranty</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J7n983EEXhQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you get a home warranty? I think so. There are many benefits of having a warranty, no matter if you just bought your home, currently own, or are looking to sell. To help me explain why home warranties are so important, I recently met with Shelley Carson of First American Home Warranty to discuss home warranties and all their benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have timestamped the conversation below so you can jump to the section(s) that you find the most interesting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are many benefits of having a warranty no matter if you just bought your home, currently own, or are looking to sell.%20localhost:4000/why-you-need-a-home-warranty.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are many benefits of having a warranty no matter if you just bought your home, currently own, or are looking to sell.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:25 – How Shelley got into the industry.&lt;br /&gt;1:20 – What she has learned about that value of home warranties.&lt;br /&gt;2:15 – The cost of adding a home warranty.&lt;br /&gt;3:00 – The benefit of adding a home warranty at the time of buying.&lt;br /&gt;4:40 – Why sellers should get a home warranty.&lt;br /&gt;5:50 – How a home warranty works for sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions about home warranties, you can reach out to Shelley by phone at (918) 480-0924.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about buying or selling, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 09:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/why-you-need-a-home-warranty.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/why-you-need-a-home-warranty.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Deal-Breakers That Can Wreck Your Home Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J95K--kz7os?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five deal-breakers sellers must prepare for and avoid if they want to sell their home quickly and for top dollar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Structural problems.&lt;/strong&gt; Here in Oklahoma, our houses move over time. Depending on how old your home is, you might be able to notice a few settlement cracks here and there. Sometimes these are the normal effects of settling, while other times they can be more serious and may require the installation of a few piers. A single pier costs around $500, so if you see some cracks around your house that look a little more extreme than normal settling, you’ll want to get that checked out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The roof.&lt;/strong&gt; Is your roof insurable and do you have proper coverage on it? If the buyer’s insurance company isn’t able to insure your roof, many times the only other solution is to replace it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The HVAC system.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a good idea to schedule regular maintenance checks for your HVAC system with a local heating and air company. When the appointment is finished, make sure to ask for a receipt or to have a sticker placed on your system. This way, you can prove to buyers that the system has been checked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Termites aren’t prejudiced—they love all types of wood and all types of houses.%20localhost:4000/5-deal-breakers-that-can-wreck-your-home-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Termites aren’t prejudiced—they love all types of wood and all types of houses.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Termites.&lt;/strong&gt; Termites aren’t prejudiced—they love all types of wood and all types of houses. If there’s termite activity in your house, treatment costs anywhere from $1,000 to $2,000. If your home had termite problems in the past, it may have been damaged, so get a visual inspection to see if that’s the case. If past termite damage is apparent and it isn’t fixed, termite inspectors will have to declare that your home needs termite treatment. Wood rot is another item that gets checked during a termite inspection, and if your home has this problem too, you need to get it cleaned up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Low appraisals.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a prevalent deal-breaker we’re seeing in our market right now. Appraisals are based on the current market, and appraisers have to look back in time at recent sales to make sure your home is priced correctly. There are always ups and downs in the market, though, so even though your appraisal might not be up to date with current trends, you have to go with what the appraiser says. A low appraisal hurts both sellers and buyers because when a buyer’s obtaining a mortgage, they can’t pay more than the price the appraiser sets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love helping sellers plan their move in advance, so if you’re thinking of selling your home any time soon, give us a call so we can help you get it ready for the market and have buyers wanting to pay full price for it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other real estate questions or you’re thinking of buying a home in our Tulsa market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us as well. We’d love to help you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/5-deal-breakers-that-can-wreck-your-home-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/5-deal-breakers-that-can-wreck-your-home-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Frustrated by Recent Market Inactivity? Don't Give up Yet</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/acJTn0FETrA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re more than halfway through 2018, and it’s been an amazing year for The Wolek Group. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been able to help more than 104 families buy and sell real estate so far, and we look forward to helping many more through the end of 2018 and beyond. Of course, another way we love to help all of you is by providing key insight into what’s happening in our market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At this point in the year, real estate tends to slow down a little bit.&lt;/strong&gt; With school starting up, buyers with families are mostly done shopping for homes by this point. This lull in our market is nothing out of the ordinary, but those looking to sell should be aware that it might take a little longer now than in recent months to find a buyer. Not to worry, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s not the time to throw in the towel, but it is time to be realistic about how you’re presenting your listing to the market.%20localhost:4000/are-you-frustrated-by-recent-market-inactivity-dont-give-up-yet.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s not the time to throw in the towel, but it is time to be realistic about how you’re presenting your listing to the market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After school is back in full swing and labor day is over, market activity will likely pick back up. Seasonal market changes are normal, and there is still plenty of time and opportunity to sell your home before 2019. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your home is already on the market and you’re feeling discouraged by current conditions, though, a price adjustment may be just the thing to jumpstart buyer interest.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyer activity may be down, but it is not stagnant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still people out there looking for homes, and, with the right strategy, your property could be the one they choose. It’s not the time to throw in the towel, but it is time to be realistic about how you’re presenting your listing to the market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or are curious how we can help you achieve your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 11:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/are-you-frustrated-by-recent-market-inactivity-dont-give-up-yet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/are-you-frustrated-by-recent-market-inactivity-dont-give-up-yet.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>“Tulsa Foodie” Episode 3: Wild Brew 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EGI-eFaTklI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On today’s episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” I’m at Wild Brew 2018 to sample some great artisan beers and food selections from both the local area and abroad. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are more than 50 breweries and 50 restaurants at this fun event, and if you follow along in the video above, you can hang out with me as I make the rounds and chat with several restaurateurs and brewers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the timestamped portions of the video along with the specific vendors I was able to visit and get some face time with:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:09 - Crushed Red&lt;br /&gt;2:22 - Laffa &lt;br /&gt;3:42 - Burnco BBQ&lt;br /&gt;5:14 - That Vault/Roppongi/Elote Cafe&lt;br /&gt;6:38 - R Bar &amp;amp; Grill/Prairie Brew Pub/Roosevelt’s&lt;br /&gt;7:27 - Old School Bagel Cafe&lt;br /&gt;8:14 - Nola’s Creole &amp;amp; Cocktails&lt;br /&gt;10:05 - Marshall Brewing Co.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are more than 50 breweries and 50 restaurants at this fun event.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-3-wild-brew-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are more than 50 breweries and 50 restaurants at this fun event.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had such a great time at this event, and I want to thank everyone I had the pleasure of meeting and speaking to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 10:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-3-wild-brew-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-3-wild-brew-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Satisfy Your Cravings With Fresh Local Flavors at Juniper</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6kddUMYjIlA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On today’s episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” we’re taking a look at one of my favorite downtown restaurants: Juniper. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you all a better idea of what makes Juniper great, and how it got its start, I met up with general manager Derek Hillman. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opened six years ago by first-time restaurateur Justin Thompson, Juniper has been a local favorite ever since. Juniper offers standout entrees such as seared duck, fried chicken curry, and a refreshing seared ahi salad. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Juniper’s menu is always changing. &lt;strong&gt;New dishes are released each week to fit the restaurant’s ever-shifting themes, as well as the seasons.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s no wonder why Juniper’s growth comes from its kitchen, where head chef Neil Trumpy works his culinary magic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Whether you’re in the mood for a savory meal or a sweet, tasty drink, you can find what you’re craving at Juniper.%20localhost:4000/satisfy-your-cravings-with-fresh-local-flavors-at-juniper.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Whether you’re in the mood for a savory meal or a sweet, tasty drink, you can find what you’re craving at Juniper.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chef Trumpy received his education from the Oregon Culinary Institute, where he developed a skill set based around sustainability and the use of local ingredients. As you’ll see in today’s episode, watching him work is an amazing sight to behold. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But delectable dishes aren’t the only thing there is to enjoy at Juniper. &lt;strong&gt;Diners can also enjoy any of the many refreshing signature cocktails they offer.&lt;/strong&gt; So whether you’re in the mood for a savory meal or a sweet, tasty drink, you can find what you’re craving at Juniper. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dining at Juniper is an amazing experience, so be sure to come check it out yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juniper (located at 324 East 3rd Street in downtown Tulsa)  is open for lunch Monday through Friday from 11 a.m. to 2 p.m., and for dinner from 4 p.m. to 10 p.m. on Monday through Saturday. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 10:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/satisfy-your-cravings-with-fresh-local-flavors-at-juniper.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/satisfy-your-cravings-with-fresh-local-flavors-at-juniper.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Hope to See You at WildBrew on August 25</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DJKwoYn5JY8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m back to talk about a fantastic event that’s coming up here in a few weeks. Angela Evans, who works in the marketing department for WildBrew, joined me recently to talk about the event and what you need to know about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They don’t call it the greatest party ever hatched for nothing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wildbrew.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WildBrew is a fundraiser for the Sutton Avian Research Center located in Bartlesville.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This is the 20th year for this festival, making it the oldest craft beer festival in Oklahoma!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The event is on Saturday, August 25th at the Cox Business Center downtown. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 50 local and non-local breweries and 50 amazing restaurants will be in attendance for this wonderful indoor festival. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s what a ticket to this festival will get you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All the beer tastings that you can responsibly handle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All the food from all the restaurants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Over 50 breweries and 50 restaurants will be in attendance.%20localhost:4000/we-hope-to-see-you-at-wildbrew-on-august-25.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Over 50 breweries and 50 restaurants will be in attendance.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General admission tickets are $65.00 and get you in for three hours from 5:00 p.m. to 8:00 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt; The patron-level tickets get you in an hour early and get you into a special area for an additional hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In addition to having a heck of a time, your ticket purchase will fund some amazing research.&lt;/strong&gt; The Sutton Avian Research Center played a crucial role in bringing the bald eagle off of the endangered animal list. More recently, they’ve been working with the Greater Prairie Chicken and the Masked Bobwhite Quail. For the Masked Bobwhite Quail, they incubate eggs, hatch them, then take the chicks to Mexico to mate and become released into the wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get tickets to this wonderful event, head on over to wildbrew.org. Experience the restaurants, the beers, and the ciders. &lt;strong&gt;It’s going to be a great time and we would love to see you there.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re very excited to sponsor this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about the event or about real estate in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 15:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/we-hope-to-see-you-at-wildbrew-on-august-25.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/we-hope-to-see-you-at-wildbrew-on-august-25.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Wouldn’t Be Able to Do What We Love Without You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oB36e_XQpc0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without you, we wouldn’t be able to do what we love every single day and have fun doing it. &lt;strong&gt;For this, we want to say thank you.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been able to help over 100 families buy or sell a home this year so far. What’s most exciting about this is it allows us to give back to our Tulsa community. Every time we help someone buy or sell a home, we make a commitment to donate to their favorite local nonprofit. On top of that, we donate to Keys to the City, which is a foundation that we set up that allows for strategic donation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Without you, we wouldn’t be able to do what we love every single day and have fun doing it.%20localhost:4000/we-wouldnt-be-able-to-do-what-we-love-without-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Without you, we wouldn’t be able to do what we love every single day and have fun doing it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we’ve donated $500 to Global Gardens, Emergency Infant Services, and the Community Food Bank of Eastern Oklahoma. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also put together an event where we collected donations for Dress for Success. Every time we host one of these events to raise money for a local nonprofit, we have so much fun, so &lt;strong&gt;if you have a favorite local nonprofit, don’t hesitate to mention them to us.&lt;/strong&gt; We’d be happy to include them in this initiative. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We appreciate you very much, so if there’s anything you need from us or we can assist you in any way, give us a call or send us an email anytime. We’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 11:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/we-wouldnt-be-able-to-do-what-we-love-without-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/we-wouldnt-be-able-to-do-what-we-love-without-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons to Hire a Real Estate Professional When Buying</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zi6xcyn_-v0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that it’s important for a homebuyer to use a licensed real estate agent when buying a home. But do you know why? Today I will share three of the top reasons. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. We have the inventory.&lt;/strong&gt; As real estate professionals, we have access to the multiple listing service (MLS), which is a database for Realtors. Of course, there are other websites out there that list houses for sale, but we all know that the MLS is the most up-to-date database for listings. Buyers who look for homes on other websites will only to be disappointed to find out they’re not available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, if we do not have the inventory, we have the tools and technologies and databases to help find you a home that fits all of your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When a seller lists their home on the market, they have already agreed to pay the buyer agent’s compensation.%20localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-hire-a-real-estate-professional-when-buying.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When a seller lists their home on the market, they have already agreed to pay the buyer agent’s compensation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. We have the negotiation skills.&lt;/strong&gt; As a homebuyer, you may be hesitant to speak your mind on certain points, for fear of offending the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an agent on your side, you will get the best deal and terms, you will know what is normal, and you will know what to expect. We will keep you up to date on timelines to make sure that you do not miss out on an opportunity for inspections or appraisals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. A buyer agent is free.&lt;/strong&gt; When a seller lists their home on the market, they have already agreed to pay the buyer agent’s compensation. There is no reason for you to do all of the work when you can use us. We can help you negotiate your best terms, hold the deal together to get you to closing on time, and provide you with all of our years of experience for free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions or are interested in buying, please feel free to call me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 16:34:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-hire-a-real-estate-professional-when-buying.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-hire-a-real-estate-professional-when-buying.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What 1 Organization Is Doing to Address Childhood Hunger</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MICgZZbH7B4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am excited to bring you some important information about a great local organization: the Community Food Bank of Eastern Oklahoma. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eileen Bradshaw, the executive director of the Community Food Bank, joined me to explain a little bit about what they do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With approximately 450 partner programs, this organization helps to distribute food throughout the state. According to Eileen, about one in every four children goes to bed hungry at night. And, as we can all agree, this is unacceptable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“It’s part of our job just to make sure [these children] get what they need,” says Eileen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was truly amazing to get a behind-the-scenes look at operations here at the Community Food Bank. Especially because at the time of my visit, they were preparing for “Summer Feeding.” The Summer Feeding program is one way that they are able to continue providing for kids who rely on school meals at other times of the year. On day one of this program, they fed an estimated 1,100 children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Approximately one in every four children goes to bed hungry at night, so the work the Community Food Bank is doing is critical.%20localhost:4000/what-1-organization-is-doing-to-address-childhood-hunger.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Approximately one in every four children goes to bed hungry at night, so the work the Community Food Bank is doing is critical.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workers at the Food Bank are also delegating more resources to their partner programs, as they know that their lines grow longer in the summer months, as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with as much as this organization does for our community, how can we give back and help them make a difference? Well, for every dollar donated, the Food Bank is able to produce four meals. Obviously, financial gifts are always welcomed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, volunteering your time and donating food are also great ways to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you want to get in touch with Eileen, you can give her a call at (918) 585-2800, or visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://okfoodbank.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;www.okfoodbank.org. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 11:36:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-1-organization-is-doing-to-address-childhood-hunger.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-1-organization-is-doing-to-address-childhood-hunger.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
