<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orange County Real Estate Video Blog with Alex Yu</title>
    <description>Our mission at  is to be your best resource for Orange County real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The , your professional Orange County Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://insideocrealestate.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:41:09 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:41:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Questions to Consider Before Moving Up</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jyZc4ZfbKI8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving up is an exciting topic, but it’s also one that generates a lot of questions from homebuyers. There are three questions, in particular, we get asked most commonly, and asking yourself these questions will help you get a better idea if now’s the time for you and your family to move up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What is my current home worth?&lt;/strong&gt; There are a lot of factors that go into this, but the majority of offers you’ll receive for your home will be using financing, which means your home will undergo an appraisal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from knowing what your home is worth, you also need to know what makes it unique and what features make it stand out. It’s not just about how nice your home is and what other homes are selling for in the area—it’s about what other homes people can buy in your community, your city, or the surrounding cities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How do I time the move?&lt;/strong&gt; Once you know your home’s value, you’ll know what kind of proceeds you’ll get that you can carry into your next home purchase. In this scenario, we create a net sheet for our clients to use. If you can buy without needing to sell your current home first, that makes you more attractive as a buyer because you’re not a contingent buyer. However, the downside is you may have to pay two mortgages at once for a short time. There are strategies around this scenario, such as renting out your home, that we’d be happy to discuss with you further. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Aside from knowing what your home is worth, you also need to know what makes it unique and what features make it stand out.%20http://insideocrealestate.com/3-questions-to-consider-before-moving-up-copy.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Aside from knowing what your home is worth, you also need to know what makes it unique and what features make it stand out.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What happens if I sell but I don’t find the right home to move into?&lt;/strong&gt; On our team, we always put our buyers in a strong position, so to prevent this from happening, we only accept offers that are subject to you being able to find a suitable replacement property. If you can’t find one, you don’t have to sell. This reduces your risk all around. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers will want assurances that you’re looking for other properties, and once you’ve found the next home you’d like to purchase, that seller will want to know that your current home is on the market and is desirable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be a stressful situation, but certain life events (e.g., a new addition to your family or a job promotion) either necessitate more space or allow you to buy a bigger home. In any case, we’ve created an in-depth guide for moving up that we’d be happy to share with you if you’d like to know more about this topic. Just send me a comment with the words “move up” and I’ll send you a copy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other real estate questions I can answer for you, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/3-questions-to-consider-before-moving-up-copy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://insideocrealestate.com/3-questions-to-consider-before-moving-up-copy.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Is Our Orange County Market Right Now?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3VOWsm5PFns?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer is in full swing here in Orange County, and our real estate market has definitely seen some interesting changes throughout this season. Today, let’s take a look at some of the most notable developments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one thing, inventory is way down. This July, there were 11% fewer listings available on our market than there were during that same month last year. &lt;strong&gt;The number of new listings hitting our market has also slowed, with a growth of just 2% year over year this July.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buyers, sellers, and investors alike can enjoy the unique opportunities presented by today’s dynamic market.%20http://insideocrealestate.com/how-is-our-orange-county-market-right-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buyers, sellers, and investors alike can enjoy the unique opportunities presented by today’s dynamic market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, given that homes are still taking approximately 91 days to sell, our market remains fairly balanced. Neither buyers nor sellers have a distinct advantage. This might surprise sellers who have fallen for the myth that summer is the hottest time of year to sell, but &lt;strong&gt;the truth is that spring, not summer, is actually the most active season for real estate.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once spring passes, the rate of home sales (and the rate of new inventory coming to the market) tends to slow down. And activity drops even more significantly by the time fall arrives.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, though, &lt;strong&gt;low interest rates have prevented our market from slowing down quite so severely as we progress further into summer.&lt;/strong&gt; This is because demand is rising more quickly than supply, which allows our market to keep moving forward even as fall draws near. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short: Buyers, sellers, and investors alike can enjoy the unique opportunities presented by today’s dynamic market. Whatever your goals, we would be happy to help you meet them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/how-is-our-orange-county-market-right-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://insideocrealestate.com/how-is-our-orange-county-market-right-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Are We Giving Back?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/51Z9WvMp1c0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past three years, our real estate team has partnered with [Organization] to source backpacks for local children, so that families without the resources to provide them on their own can still send their kids to school with all the necessary tools. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In addition to The Purist Group, we also work closely with local law enforcement to create these opportunities year after year for our area’s youth. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think of our impact on the community as being similar to the old folk tale of the young boy throwing starfish back into the sea after a storm. In the story, thousands of starfish have been stranded on a beach. The boy throws back as many as he can, but is obviously unable to save them all. As he’s working to help the starfish, an old man approaches him and says, “You aren’t making a difference. You can’t save them all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Every good deed matters.%20http://insideocrealestate.com/how-are-we-giving-back.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Every good deed matters.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throwing back another starfish into the sea, the little boy looks at the old man and says, &lt;strong&gt;“I made a difference to that one.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this same way, even knowing that we can’t help every child in America, our team is proud to know that we are making an impact at all. Every good deed matters. One local woman, a special education teacher named Karina, exemplifies this point. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three years ago, it was Karina who came to us with the idea of beginning our now-annual backpack drive.&lt;/strong&gt; Fast forward to this year, and we’re about to donate 2,000 supply-filled backpacks to children in our community. Katrina’s idea has grown into something amazing, and each of us has the capacity to make a difference, just like she did. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our real estate business, for example, we strive to do this every day. More than just selling properties, it’s our mission to connect families with their next home. The bottom line is that there are many ways to make a difference. Even something as simple as smiling at a stranger or holding open a door for someone has a positive impact. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about today’s message, would like more information about how we can serve your real estate goals, or would like to talk about other ways to give back, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/how-are-we-giving-back.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://insideocrealestate.com/how-are-we-giving-back.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What the Looming Recession Means for Our Housing Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/28A_K7-TeCE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A recession is looming, but there’s no reason to believe it will look anything like the crash of 2008. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stock market is close to all-time highs, unemployment is extremely low, and inflation is still seemingly in check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, this might be the last party before the crash. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent Wall Street Journal poll of 73 economists found that &lt;strong&gt;the majority believe a recession is coming in 2020&lt;/strong&gt;. Current homebuyers in the market echo these predictions, with 70% believing a recession will come in the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean in terms of our housing market? Nationwide, home prices continue to slow in growth. On top of that, the number of homes sales has slowed down too. This reminds me of the time between 2006 and 2008, but do we automatically think history will repeat itself? I don’t think so, and there are a couple of reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, unlike in 2008, &lt;strong&gt;there aren’t a ton of bad mortgages out there.&lt;/strong&gt; Back then, practically anyone could qualify for a mortgage. These days, a lot of rule changes have been implemented to protect the future of the housing market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A lot of rule changes have been implemented to protect the future of the housing market.%20http://insideocrealestate.com/what-the-looming-recession-means-for-our-housing-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A lot of rule changes have been implemented to protect the future of the housing market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the &lt;strong&gt;looming recession will not be an exception.&lt;/strong&gt; In recessions past, the housing market as a whole wasn’t affected the way it was in 2008. In my opinion, homes that are still desirable will continue to sell—even in a recession. Homes that are overpriced, don’t have the same features as the rest of the homes, or are somewhat affected by this recession will take longer to sell. That’s just the reality of the situation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a home seller, this means you need to focus on your needs, goals, and circumstances. After that, examine the market environment and look toward the future to see what makes sense for you. If you’re curious what your Orange County home is worth, you can use our home value calculator right here on our website. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of buying a home and are wondering if now’s the time to do it, you need to figure out what your short-, medium-, and long-term goals are. It might be in your best interest to rent, but it’s a good idea to get a feel for the available inventory before you make a final decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re looking to buy, sell, or invest, everyone’s needs are different, so if you have any more questions about our current market and how it affects you, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to speak with you and help you reach your future goals. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 15:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/what-the-looming-recession-means-for-our-housing-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://insideocrealestate.com/what-the-looming-recession-means-for-our-housing-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Start Your Real Estate Investment Career Off Right With These 5 Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5FRFfwRTjX0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate investing is hotter than ever, and it’s no wonder why. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mortgage rates are low, home prices continue to grow, and demand for rentals is strong.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you’re interested in investing in real estate, where do you start? And what do you need to know? Here are five crucial tips I’ve gathered from successful real estate investors to help you out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t stick to your own backyard.&lt;/strong&gt; Many fledgling real estate investors limit their search to neighborhoods they know well. This might cut into your potential for profit. The best deals might be a bit further away, and emerging neighborhoods might offer better growth potential and tax incentives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Use the 1% rule.&lt;/strong&gt; A good rule of thumb for real estate investing is to look for properties that will offer a monthly return that is greater than 1% of the sales price. In other words, if a home costs $100,000, you should only invest in it if you expect to get at least $1,000 a month in rent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It pays to know the many possible tax benefits associated with real estate investing.%20http://insideocrealestate.com/start-your-real-estate-investment-career-off-right-with-these-5-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It pays to know the many possible tax benefits associated with real estate investing.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Don’t over-rehab.&lt;/strong&gt; An investment property doesn’t have to look like a Pinterest photo shoot. Instead of trying to convert an investment into your dream home, go with middle-of-the-road fixtures—and save yourself both time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Look to single-family rentals.&lt;/strong&gt; Single-family homes tend to consistently appreciate. They are also most likely to attract good tenants, and they are something you have direct experience with—and can evaluate personally. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Understand the tax benefits.&lt;/strong&gt; It pays to know the many possible tax benefits associated with real estate investing. These include deductions for depreciation, mortgage interest deductions, and maintenance, as well as the benefits that come from investing through qualified plans like self-directed IRA accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, these five tips are valuable—but they are only a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re seriously considering real estate investing, I’d advise you to first &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexyuteam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;take a look at some of the great homes available around the Orange County area.&lt;/a&gt; And if this gets your investment appetite going, give me a call. There are two reasons why. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I can give you my impressions about which types of homes (and in which neighborhoods) might make for a sensible first investment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I can also point you to other professionals I personally trust—mortgage brokers, tax advisors, contractors—who can help you make that first investment profitable with the minimal amount of fuss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other real estate questions, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/start-your-real-estate-investment-career-off-right-with-these-5-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://insideocrealestate.com/start-your-real-estate-investment-career-off-right-with-these-5-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Should Think About as a Buyer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qnWfufxA2OU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the market to buy a new home, I’ve got some advice for you today. &lt;strong&gt;Here are the top things you should take into consideration before making the plunge:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Location, location, location.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ve probably heard this phrase before. When you’re looking at a new home, it’s important to know where you’re at and what school district you’re in. Even if you don’t have kids, the future resale value of your home is going to be affected by the district it’s in. Also, how close is the home to local shopping, dining, and entertainment options? These are all things to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Financial commitment.&lt;/strong&gt; Real estate is a long-term investment. If you want to move in a few years, you might want to consider renting instead. Having your money tied up in a home is not a great short-term investment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Running the well dry.&lt;/strong&gt; Most buyers spend every penny that they have to get into their new home, especially first-time buyers. Even though we’ll make sure you have a home warranty for your first year, it’s important to have a home savings fund for any repairs or maintenance that happens outside of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These are just five of the things that you need to consider.%20http://insideocrealestate.com/what-you-should-think-about-as-a-buyer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These are just five of the things that you need to consider.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Loving your space.&lt;/strong&gt; The reason that you want to love your space is that it’s not just the indoor area that you’re going to enjoy. You’re going to want to set up an entertainment area or spend a nice night in the backyard. However, if you’re busy, you might want something a little lower maintenance like a townhouse or a condo. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Untapped potential.&lt;/strong&gt; The truth is that there are a lot of different neighborhoods, but finding one that’s undergoing a renaissance is ideal. You might be able to find a home at a great price in a neighborhood that’s a little rough at the moment, but you’ll have the opportunity to be part of something great going forward as the neighborhood grows, improves, and changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just five of the things that you need to consider as a buyer. If you need help in your home search or just have any questions at all about the process, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/what-you-should-think-about-as-a-buyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://insideocrealestate.com/what-you-should-think-about-as-a-buyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Home Upgrades That Are Actually Worth Making</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gx-gQZYM2Sw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As home buying season really kicks off, sellers are in a prime position to earn top dollar—that is, assuming they take the time to properly prepare their properties for the market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to sell quickly and for a great price, you need to make sure your home is in the best possible shape before you list it. But not all home upgrades are worth making. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to share a list of three projects that will bring a high return on your investment so that you can avoid wasting money on projects that won’t. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Improve your curb appea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;l.&lt;/strong&gt; A fresh coat of paint and some landscaping can go a long way. The way your home looks from the outside serves as a buyer’s first impression, after all. Updating your curb appeal tends to cost between $3,000 to $5,000—an amount you’ll more than likely earn back (and then some) because of the positive impact this upgrade has on buyers. If you need design ideas, check out local new construction properties in your area. This will help you understand current popular styles, color palettes, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you want to sell quickly and for a great price, you need to make sure your home is in the best possible shape before you list it.%20http://insideocrealestate.com/3-home-upgrades-that-are-actually-worth-making.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you want to sell quickly and for a great price, you need to make sure your home is in the best possible shape before you list it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Upgrade your bathrooms—but not too much.&lt;/strong&gt; Mid-range bathroom upgrades bring about $1.71 for every $1, while high-end bathroom upgrades could actually hurt your bottom line. In other words, you need to choose your projects carefully. Adding in dual sinks, swapping out flooring, and changing out cabinets are all good upgrades to make, but make sure you don’t choose the most expensive options for each of these projects. Otherwise, your bathroom will look out of place compared to the rest of your home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Install new windows.&lt;/strong&gt; Mid-range, energy-efficient windows can bring you $1.15 return for every $1 spent. Not only do these new windows look nice, but they will also help your home’s new owner save money on their energy bills. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me or my team a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/3-home-upgrades-that-are-actually-worth-making.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://insideocrealestate.com/3-home-upgrades-that-are-actually-worth-making.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Homeownership the Key to Your Financial Future?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0gagZCy05nY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First-time homebuyers often focus on two things: the price of a home and the monthly payment they’ll be bound to after purchasing it. This is quite understandable. However, there’s one more thing you need to consider when buying a house: the future value of the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, appreciation, or the increase in prices over time, is how a majority of wealth is built in real estate. &lt;strong&gt;That’s why homeownership is a great, stable, long-term investment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are ultimately two ways to take advantage of your home’s equity: actively and passively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homeownership has traditionally been one of the most stable opportunities to build wealth.%20http://insideocrealestate.com/is-homeownership-the-key-to-your-financial-future.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homeownership has traditionally been one of the most stable opportunities to build wealth.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By paying off a mortgage during your working years, you actively eliminate a big expense from your plate during your retirement years. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more is that if you’re not great about having a savings plan, &lt;strong&gt;owning a home is a great opportunity to passively create a financial cushion that renting can’t.&lt;/strong&gt; If you start when you’re young, it gives you a longer opportunity to create wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, owning a home doesn’t necessarily guarantee that you can have a greater net worth, but homeownership has traditionally been one of the most stable opportunities to build wealth. Obviously, real estate values do fluctuate over time, but it’s still a great vehicle for stable growth for many people. It gives you an opportunity (and a structure) to build wealth.  After all, a home isn’t just four walls that provide you shelter—it’s a place for you to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in buying, selling, or investing in real estate, feel free to reach out to me. We’re here to help you make the right moves every step of the way. I hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/is-homeownership-the-key-to-your-financial-future.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://insideocrealestate.com/is-homeownership-the-key-to-your-financial-future.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s There to Love (and Hate) About Buying in Spring?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hU9PTpMoL-I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring is here, and if you’re a buyer, there are plenty of things to love about buying a home right now. However, there are also a few things to hate about the spring buying season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently came across an article from Realtor.com that outlines all the major positives and negatives you need to be aware of before taking the plunge. To read the full article, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.realtor.com/advice/buy/things-youll-love-hate-buying-a-home-in-spring/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, here are some of the main points to take away from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things you’ll love:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased inventory.&lt;/strong&gt; There are more homes to choose from, so you need to focus your time effectively and distinguish between areas you love and areas that are less desirable. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More open houses.&lt;/strong&gt; As more and more homes hit the market, there are more and more open houses taking place that give you a great opportunity to match what you see online with what you see in person and size up the competition from other buyers. As always, use your time effectively when sightseeing open houses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need to focus your time effectively and distinguish between areas you love and areas that are less desirable.%20http://insideocrealestate.com/whats-there-to-love-and-hate-about-buying-in-spring.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You need to focus your time effectively and distinguish between areas you love and areas that are less desirable.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things you’ll hate: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More competition.&lt;/strong&gt; This means you need to fine-tune what you’re looking for and make your choices quicker. In an active market, new listings don’t even make it to their first open house before they’re snatched up. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-related pressure.&lt;/strong&gt; Like I said above, you’ll have to make decisions quicker in this market. If you have to sleep on it, odds are, you won’t get to sleep in it. Doing as much prep work up front as possible while working with an agent who has their finger on the pulse of the market will help tremendously in this regard. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased prices.&lt;/strong&gt; It all boils down to supply and demand. If there’s a lot of demand and many different buyers vying for the same homes, prices will go up. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about buying in the spring or you have any other real estate needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/whats-there-to-love-and-hate-about-buying-in-spring.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://insideocrealestate.com/whats-there-to-love-and-hate-about-buying-in-spring.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Developments in the Orange County Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SHePqwheKAw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the onset of Daylight Saving Time, the times have changed, and so has the spring market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are currently 44% more homes on the market than there were last year at this same time, increasing from 4,420 to over 6,000 homes. Overall, demand for housing has picked up, rising 91%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A big portion of that increase can be attributed to our interest rates&lt;/strong&gt;, which are directly entangled with housing demand in the market. Interest rates peaked during the worst time in 2018—right around the holidays, rates hit 5.05%. As of this video recording, rates are only at 4.45%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For buyers, it means you have 10% more buying power than you did just four months ago.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our current market is different from previous years, but that also means there are different opportunities to take advantage of.%20http://insideocrealestate.com/the-latest-developments-in-the-orange-county-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our current market is different from previous years, but that also means there are different opportunities to take advantage of.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For sellers, it means that your home is a little more marketable and, more importantly, more affordable to potential buyers at the same time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t say for sure what will happen this year, but we do expect that market times will continue to decrease as spring approaches and that inventory will continue to grow. The current average days on market is 140 days, which means we’re in a different market entirely compared to last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In past years, there was a quick run-up of multiple offers on every home, but these days, you’ll need to be a little bit more selective: &lt;strong&gt;Market aggressively, but also be sure to price your home in a way that will get the most attention from buyers in the shortest amount of time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter if you’re looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate this year, feel free to reach out to us. We’d be happy to provide you with all the information you need to make the right moves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 11:40:06 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/the-latest-developments-in-the-orange-county-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://insideocrealestate.com/the-latest-developments-in-the-orange-county-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
