<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calgary Real Estate Video Blog with Eric Mortimer</title>
    <description>Our mission at Eric Mortimer &amp; Associates is to be your best resource for Calgary real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Eric Mortimer &amp; Associates, your professional Calgary Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 10:43:36 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 10:43:36 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your Market Recap for 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/54er1c21B6c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;From annual price growth to interest rates, I&amp;rsquo;m covering it all; here&amp;rsquo;s what the market did in 2019 and where I think we&amp;rsquo;re headed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Are you surprised by the tax assessment you just received in the mail? Maybe you’re sitting on the sidelines waiting for real estate prices to be just right so that you can get into the market. Making sense of it all can be pretty confusing; the markets across the country have varied significantly, and media outlets are blasting all kinds of information. Today I’m helping you get a grasp on things as we head further into 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:24 - Year-over-year change in benchmark prices across Canada&lt;br /&gt;1:34 - Summary of the Calgary Real Estate Board’s annual forecast event held on Jan. 14&lt;br /&gt;3:35 - Annual sales and price growth for Calgary in 2019 (residential, detached, attached, apartment)&lt;br /&gt;5:10 - Price growth prediction for 2020&lt;br /&gt;5:40 - The impact of interest rates, crude oil, and employment on the market in 2020&lt;br /&gt;6:30 - Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or real estate in general, please feel free to reach out by phone or email. I would love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/your-market-recap-for-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/your-market-recap-for-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020 Calgary Real Estate Predictions, Pains, &amp; Profits</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/otF5NPoCgOo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have several predictions to make for our 2020 real estate market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Happy New Year! It’s time for my 2020 real estate market predictions. A lot of people have been asking for this forecast lately because, quite often, it’s contrary to what other experts have to say and it comes straight from the market trenches. If you want to know what’s happening with your home’s equity or you have some life changes happening next year that involve buying or selling a home, this message is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:41 - The chances of selling your home within 90 days are 28.5%—will that go up or down?&lt;br /&gt;2:07 - The difference between one of our team’s upcoming listings and a home across the street that hasn’t sold yet&lt;br /&gt;3:03 - How our team staged the home&lt;br /&gt;3:37 - How far I expect prices to drop and where our economy is headed&lt;br /&gt;4:34 - Where vacancy rates are headed&lt;br /&gt;5:00 - Which types of homes will be in high demand in 2020 and which won’t&lt;br /&gt;5:57 - Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious about your home’s value or you have any more questions about our future market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/2020-calgary-real-estate-predictions-pains-profits.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/2020-calgary-real-estate-predictions-pains-profits.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Determine the Best Time to Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/27jylgKt9hw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;To know the best time to sell your home, there are several factors to consider.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When is the best time to sell your home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question was recently asked by a viewer of my video blog named Neil who benefited from my home selling advice earlier in 2019. Neil was preparing his home for the market, but he was flexible in terms of when to list it. When he sought my advice, I ran the numbers and figured out that the best time to put his property on the market was in February. Inventory would be low and I foresaw more competition hitting the market and prices dropping after February was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Neil did list his home, it generated multiple offers and he got a great deal. Afterward, prices declined, more homes hit the market, and inventory increased—just as I predicted. A lot of people would’ve assumed in this case that it would be better to wait until spring to list, but that wouldn’t have done anybody any good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February might not be the best time to put your home on the market, but &lt;strong&gt;if you list during the winter months, you know that buyers are serious&lt;/strong&gt;. Nobody looks at properties in freezing weather just for decorating ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you decide what’s best, it’s important to know your type of home’s recent sale history—look at the days on market, the level of inventory, and the selling history of your neighborhood in general. If you look at the statistics at 4:21 in the video above, you’d be surprised at how many sales are spread throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’re not ready to make a move and are overly attached to your home, buyers will know, and you’ll probably sabotage your sale.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-determine-the-best-time-to-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re not ready to make a move and are overly attached to your home, buyers will know, and you’ll probably sabotage your sale.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another factor to consider before deciding when to list is life changes&lt;/strong&gt;. We real estate agents are agents of change, and we understand that life happens. People are born; people die. Marriages begin and end. Job situations change. When one of these life changes take place, that could be your best time to move. It’s important that you’re ready to change, as well. If you’re not ready to make a move and are overly attached to your home, buyers will know, and you’ll probably sabotage your sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re still in the early stages of planning your sale, please give me a call. I’ve seen many people overdevelop their homes and spend too much money preparing it for the market. Then, once they did list it, they had to chase down the market and ended up losing whatever investment they put into the home. If you schedule a consultation with me, I can advise you on what you should and shouldn’t do to prepare your home for the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we’ve just launched a new home selling program that removes a lot of the hassle of selling a home that we’d love to share with you. To learn all about it, visit &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://guaranteedsales.ca/&quot;&gt;guaranteedsales.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about when to sell your home, feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-determine-the-best-time-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-determine-the-best-time-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Respond to Lowball Offers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OImOEPxHm6o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;How should you respond to receiving a lowball offer? Here are a few tricks and tips for navigating this sometimes awkward situation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you receive an offer, respond promptly and keep the momentum going. When receiving an offer, sellers have the option to accept it, reject it, or counter it, and there is a time to do each of these things. Most of the time I don’t recommend rejecting an offer right off the bat since the buyers have shown an interest in your property and have gone to the time, effort, and expense to put it together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s what you do when you receive an offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A. Make sure it is a lowball offer versus a fair offer&lt;/strong&gt;. One of the first things you have to determine is whether it’s a lowball offer at all. Sometimes they could be right and you could be off on your pricing. I have seen many occasions where people have turned down offers in the beginning only to eventually reduce their list price lower than what they could have sold it for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. Don’t take it personally&lt;/strong&gt;—this is a good reminder for everyone, whether you are buying or selling real estate or not. I recommend that you read or re-read Don Miguel Ruiz’s book “The Four Agreements.” One important lesson is to not take the actions of others as personal attacks against you. When we get emotional, it can cloud our reason and cause us to make silly mistakes. This is another reason it’s important to have a great agent as a buffer. It’s one of those things that can be simple, but not necessarily easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C. Contact other people that have expressed interest in the property&lt;/strong&gt;. If other people have viewed the property, make sure your agent lets them know what’s happening; they may want to put in an offer, too. If that happens, you may end up having multiple offers. I have negotiated numerous times with people that started out with lowball offers and they ended up getting more than asking price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming that you don’t have multiple offers going, here are some ways that you can respond to a lowball offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Have a sense of humour&lt;/strong&gt;. Bear in mind that you should build a little rapport before trying this, though. For example, if a buyer submitted an offer of $75,000 under your $300,000 asking price, you respond with a number that’s $75,000 over your asking price. If they react in the ways I expect they might, you can tell them you thought that was the game you were playing—throwing silly numbers out. Then suggest meeting in the middle at $300,000. Have some fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Ask them to start with something better&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s tough to cover all of the nuances of this point, but sometimes it’s possible to get people to come up on their own without countering their offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Counter, but stick close to the asking price&lt;/strong&gt;. Going back to the earlier example of the $300,000 house: If someone gives you a lowball offer, you could counter with $298,000. You can also go straight to this tactic and skip the humour; sometimes keeping tight and coming down slowly can bring people up in larger steps. Also, remember that there is more to a transaction than just the price. There are conditions, terms, deposits, possessions, and goods included. Price often isn’t the thing that holds up a negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Adjust your list price for another buyer&lt;/strong&gt;. A lot of people won’t do offers substantially lower than the list price, so if it is evident that you are overpriced, you may be missing out on buyers. If your asking price is $300,000 and your last offer was $260,000 but you can’t seem to move any higher, it may be a good idea to put this negotiation on hold and, for example, reduce your list price to $280,000. This could potentially get offers for around $270,000, $275,000, or even full price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Sometimes, keeping tight and coming down slowly can bring people up in larger steps.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-respond-to-lowball-offers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Sometimes, keeping tight and coming down slowly can bring people up in larger steps.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is one bonus tactic that is useful in any financial negotiation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite often, people will come to a point where neither party wants to give an inch on a particular detail. In these cases, one or both parties might say, “Why don’t we just be fair and split the difference?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, suppose you are at $280,000 and the other party is offering $260,000. They might say, “Okay, let’s be fair—we are willing to split the difference and meet at $270,000 and have a done deal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a potential counter to this situation: “Wow, splitting the difference is a great idea. I appreciate your creativity. We were at $300,000, and we have now come down to $280,000. You are offering $270,00. Let’s split the difference and do $275,000!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ve enjoyed these tips from the vault of a certified negotiation expert, and I hope you can make or save yourself some money with them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about dealing with lowball offers, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-respond-to-lowball-offers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-respond-to-lowball-offers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Make It a Fun, Safe Halloween With This Spooktacular Guide</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mFD8loLuEaE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halloween will be here before you know it, so today I&amp;rsquo;ll share some quick tips that will help you and your family have a fun, safe holiday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skeletons, spiderwebs, and Jack-o’-lanterns galore are popping up all over our neighborhoods, and that can only mean one thing: Halloween is just around the corner. If your preparations so far have involved stocking up on candy and choosing the perfect costume for yourself or your children, you’re on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting in the Halloween spirit is great, but decking out your yard with spooky decor and buying sweets for trick-or-treaters isn’t the only thing you should be doing to get ready for the holiday ahead. &lt;strong&gt;Ghouls and goblins might be nothing more than fun, fictional frights, but there are some real dangers to watch out for on Halloween night&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, by following a few simple safety tricks, you can help make this Halloween a fun and safe treat for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. If you’re a homeowner expecting trick-or-treaters, make sure you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep your home, yard, and sidewalks brightly lit (and shoveled if applicable)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clear debris and obstacles from your yard, steps, and walkways&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep pets kenneled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Park your car in the garage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use LED candles instead of real candles inside Jack-o’-lanterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tone down extra-scary decor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep a close eye on your front door&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. If you’re a parent with children who plan to trick-or-treat, make sure you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always accompany young children to each house they visit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visit neighborhoods with sidewalks to avoid walking in the street&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always use crosswalks and look both ways before crossing the street&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add reflective tape to your child’s costume&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep masks at home, as they can obstruct your child’s vision&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have your child carry a flashlight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish a curfew for older children venturing out on their own&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remind older, unsupervised children to call 911 in case of emergency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell unaccompanied children to never enter a stranger’s home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can help make this Halloween a fun and safe treat for everyone.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/make-it-a-fun-safe-halloween-with-this-spooktacular-guide.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can help make this Halloween a fun and safe treat for everyone.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. If you’re going to be driving on Halloween night, make sure you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stay alert and watch for children in the street&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eliminate any distractions within your vehicle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drive slowly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be especially cautious at intersections and corners&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be mindful when pulling in or out of driveways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Halloween holding such a high risk of accidents involving child pedestrians, following these safety tips will be essential. Still, even after your children have made it home with their Halloween haul, there is one more important safety concern you’ll need to address: their candy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Check candy for the following red flags before letting your trick-or-treaters dig into their treats:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An unusual or discolored appearance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoiled or unwrapped items&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tears or holes in wrappers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to following these tips, you should also &lt;strong&gt;be wary of homemade items or baked goods&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don’t personally know who made them, these should be discarded. As a general rule for any treat: When in doubt, throw it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents should also be mindful of treats that could pose a choking hazard. Hard candies, gum, peanuts, and small toys should only be given to older children. If you have any additional questions regarding tainted or unsafe candy, you can contact Poison Control or your local police department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By following these tips, you and your trick-or-treaters will be all set to have a safe and happy holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fangs for reading and sharing this. Happy Halloween!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 16:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/make-it-a-fun-safe-halloween-with-this-spooktacular-guide.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/make-it-a-fun-safe-halloween-with-this-spooktacular-guide.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winter Is Coming: Is Your Home Ready?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FR8tnXjfGuM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today Barry Malesh from A Buyer&amp;rsquo;s Choice Home Inspections joins me to provide you with some tips on how to prepare your home for the winter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Calgarians are getting ready for winter—they’re preparing their cars and their garages are swamped with snow tires. But what about their houses? Barry Malesh from A Buyer’s Choice Home Inspections is here to give you some tips about what you should be doing to prepare your home for the coming winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Service your furnace&lt;/strong&gt;. Now’s the time of year that you’ll start needing your furnace the most. Make sure you get it serviced and have your ducts cleaned out because you don’t want to have any problems with it when the temperature is 40 below. Cleaning your unit and changing the filters will also help you avoid carbon monoxide leaks, keep the air in your home clean, and keep your bill lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Check your smoke detectors every time you change your clocks&lt;/strong&gt;. This includes carbon monoxide detectors, as well. Change out the batteries regularly, and replace your units once about every five years, since they don’t last forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Reduce the inside temperature when you’re gone to save heat&lt;/strong&gt;. Many people think that if they lower the temperature at night, they’re just wasting money reheating the house the next day. Tests on this scenario have been done, and it’s actually been proven that the larger the temperature differential between the inside of the house and the outside of the house, the more heat is lost. So, if you do lower the temperature in the house when you’re gone more than four hours, you can save on heating costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Make sure the attic is the same temperature as the outside of your home&lt;/strong&gt;. Here’s a great tip for keeping the heat in your home from leaking out of your attic: seal off your attic hatch with vapor barrier, and be sure to weather strip it, as well. Make sure that the vents for your bathroom and kitchen range lead to the outside, too; that air is warm and moist, so the condensation could freeze and cause damage if it isn’t vented outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat escaping from the attic will also cause melting on your roof and create ice dams. Barry has seen homes where, because of ice damming, water seeps under the shingles and the melt runs down the interior walls, shorting the electrical system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Change out smoke and carbon monoxide detector batteries regularly.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/winter-is-coming-is-your-home-ready.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Change out smoke and carbon monoxide detector batteries regularly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Always shut off your outside taps&lt;/strong&gt;. Disconnect your garden hoses, turn off the water shutoff valve, and then go back outside and open the tap so that the air can escape. It’s the compressed air in water lines that causes them to break, not the ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Have your downspouts extended at all times&lt;/strong&gt;. If ice on the roof melts and runs down your house without proper drainage, the water will pool at the foundation. Here, it can freeze, crack your foundation, and let more water in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. When going away for winter vacation, shut off the main water to the home&lt;/strong&gt;. This way, if anything starts to leak, you won’t have any water issues. The valve for this is in the basement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, have someone walk through your house while you’re gone. Your insurance might have a clause that mentions this as well: Every three days to once a week, someone should walk through the house to make sure the heat’s on and that there aren’t other issues with the home. Failure to do this might allow for problems to go unnoticed, and your insurance may not cover it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like more tips about how to protect your home in the winter, reach out to me. I’ll send you a free report that includes a checklist you can follow every fall and spring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/winter-is-coming-is-your-home-ready.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/winter-is-coming-is-your-home-ready.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top Secret Listings &amp; Agents You Should Know About</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YGImXFgXuaU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our team has access to a secret set of listings that you won&amp;rsquo;t find on the MLS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am going to share with you, not one but three of our top coming soon listings before they are out on the MLS and available for purchase to anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you been, or do you know someone who is, frustrated because you keep just missing out on the best deals? You find a place you love and go to the open house or call the agent and it’s already gone. This can feel like a waste of time and be heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you be surprised to know that you are probably missing places that were actually perfect for you because they were gone so fast? &lt;strong&gt;It happens to people every day, particularly in the styles, communities, and price ranges with the highest demand&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often this happens because somebody else heard about it either before it hit the market or the instant it came on. Our coming soon inventory is constantly changing, so make sure you let us know if you are looking for anything in particular, and we can keep you updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have access to a number of other agents and their coming soon listings. &lt;strong&gt;This not only gives you a secret advantage over other buyers, but it also makes sure you don’t miss out on some of the best places&lt;/strong&gt;. All three of these properties are in desirable areas in the fastest moving price range of $375,000 to $475,000. As you’ll see, these homes are going to see a lot of action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These will get scooped up quickly.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/top-secret-listings-agents-you-should-know-about.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These will get scooped up quickly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our first property is a bungalow in the SW neighbourhood Westgate&lt;/strong&gt;. It is currently being painted, so it’s going to look even better than it does now. People just love the mature trees and the easy access to bow trail and downtown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The next property is a 1,400 square foot bungalow with hardwood floors in the NW neighbourhood Dalhousie&lt;/strong&gt;. This is located on a great crescent and close to sought-after schools. This really has some great potential for somebody that is willing to do a little bit of work and updating. Do you want to build some sweat equity? This is an opportunity to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third secret deal is a nearly 1,600 square foot two-story with a double-attached garage and a fully developed basement for under $375,000&lt;/strong&gt;. It is currently being painted inside and the huge back decks are being stained. This one will get scooped up quickly. It’s also close to schools, shopping, transit, and the Stoney and Deerfoot trails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more information on these, other properties, or our other unique home marketing systems and strategies, give us a call or send us an email today. We’d be happy to put our particular set of skills to work for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/top-secret-listings-agents-you-should-know-about.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/top-secret-listings-agents-you-should-know-about.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Let These Common Buyer Fears Wreck Your Home Search</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6QjuPqURuNQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;To have a successful home purchase, there are certain buyer fears you need to overcome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, if you can acknowledge your fears about the home buying process, you can overcome them and move forward with your purchase with clarity, courage, and commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of fears do buyers usually have? Here are four of the most common:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Fear of loss&lt;/strong&gt;. In this case, buyers will come across a property and get scared that they have to buy it soon or someone else will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Fear of missing out&lt;/strong&gt;. Here’s where the analytical brain kicks in and tells you that, even though you really love this house, it’s only the third one you’ve looked at, and there are thousands of more listings on the market you should look at too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Fear of overpaying&lt;/strong&gt;. Nobody wants to look like they overpaid for something. If you think a house is overpriced, the tendency is to not want to pay too much for it, wonder why someone else hasn’t bought it yet, and/or wonder whether you’d get a good deal or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Fear that something is wrong with the house&lt;/strong&gt;. What if there’s a structural defect and that’s why nobody has bought it? If it’s a condo, a structural defect might necessitate a special assessment or increased fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s not a perfect market out there, and a home’s list price might be either above or below its true value.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/dont-let-these-common-buyer-fears-wreck-your-home-search.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s not a perfect market out there, and a home’s list price might be either above or below its true value.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard the phrase, “What you think about, you bring about.” In other words, the fears you think about can manifest themselves in the form of mistakes because you overcompensate to avoid those fears. With that in mind, here are five common mistakes buyers make that are caused by the fears above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Not getting pre-approved&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s common for people to start searching for homes and making offers without knowing how much they can afford. This can cause you to lose out on the home you want or lead you to become “house poor.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Overpaying&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s not a perfect market out there, and a home’s list price might be either above or below its true value. Not everyone has access to records of previously sold listings, expired listings, or other statistics that indicate where the market is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Not having access to all properties&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition to the properties listed on the MLS, there are “coming soon” listings, “For Sale by Owner” listings, off-market properties, and other options available to buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Listening to the wrong people&lt;/strong&gt;. There are all sorts of people out there who claim to be real estate experts, so make sure you listen to an actual expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Not having your own agent&lt;/strong&gt;. Make sure you hire a proper buyer’s agent to represent you. They’ll have a fiduciary duty to you and only you, which will save you thousands of dollars in the long run. Also, make sure you hire the right agent—one who has a team of professionals behind them to look after all of your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, most agents average between zero and three deals per year. Our team, on the other hand, closed three deals just last week. I don’t say this to brag—I say it to assure you that we cover all our buyer clients’ needs. &lt;strong&gt;Here are some specific services we offer that you should look for when selecting your agent:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have a VIP buyer program that gives you access to all properties online and offline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We do a careful market analysis to make sure you never overpay for a property&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We supply competent affiliates and professionals (home inspectors, lenders, lawyers, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/dont-let-these-common-buyer-fears-wreck-your-home-search.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/dont-let-these-common-buyer-fears-wreck-your-home-search.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Tell if Your Home Is Overpriced</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XDND9P_8AzA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are three signs you need to watch out for to know whether your home is overpriced.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re putting your home on the market, it’s important that you price it correctly from the start. Overpricing it can cost you tens of thousands of dollars—not just in terms of carrying costs, but because you’ll end up chasing the market downward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people assume a buyer will eventually make an offer for less than what they ask, but that doesn’t happen very often. Think of the TV show “Shark Tank,” where people offer a percentage of their company in exchange for an investment: Some of those companies are amazing, but their founders will still walk away without a deal because they ask for too much of an investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same thing can happen to sellers in our Calgary market, so if you do overprice your home, you’ll need to adjust quickly. How can you tell if this is the case, though? Here are the three signs you should watch out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Your listing has expired&lt;/strong&gt;. If it’s been on the market for six months or more, it’s already gone through a lot of exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Overpricing it can cost you tens of thousands of dollars.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-tell-if-your-home-is-overpriced.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Overpricing it can cost you tens of thousands of dollars.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The Rule of 10&lt;/strong&gt;. In other words, for every 10 showings you have, you should get at least one offer—if you go 10 days without a showing, your home is overpriced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Feedback&lt;/strong&gt;. People will give you feedback after a showing if your Realtor is doing a great job. Make sure you listen to it. A lot of sellers try to block this feedback out, but if buyers give you feedback without wanting to buy your home, it means they’re trying to help you. A lot of their minor complaints can be solved once the price is right. If your price is right, the only feedback you want to hear is an offer or a clarifying question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your home has been sitting on the market and you want it sold soon, we specialize in fixing bad listings, so give us a call and we’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-tell-if-your-home-is-overpriced.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-tell-if-your-home-is-overpriced.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can Photography Do for Your Home’s Sale?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VGgYrv5m70o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Having great photos of your home is a great way to start the home sale process. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s competitive market, you need to do everything right in order to sell. One of those things is capturing the right photographs of your home. We look at bad real estate pictures every week, and that’s not where you want to be. We’re joined by a real estate photo expert today to answer some common questions about what he does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a big believer in the 80/20 rule that says 80% of our results come from 20% of our efforts. &lt;strong&gt;In real estate, photography comes within that 20% of work&lt;/strong&gt;. Danny Boutet of Visual Marketing knows a lot about this topic. He’s been in business for 11 years and has shot over 7,000 homes in and around the Calgary area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;According to Danny, the biggest mistake he sees homeowners make when it comes to photos is not having their spaces decluttered&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’re not using something, get it out of the way. Misplaced shoes, clothes, jackets, and trinkets should be out while photos are being taken. He also recommends double checking your lights, windows, and mirrors to ensure they are clean. HDR photos can pick up things that we didn’t have to worry about in the past, but it can also show your home off in a way that’s never been possible before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=80% of our results come from 20% of our efforts.%20http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/what-can-photography-do-for-your-homes-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“80% of our results come from 20% of our efforts.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Danny about how you can make your home’s photos sparkle, give him a call at (403) 470-4350 or send him an email to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#118;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#097;&quot;&gt;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#118;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#097;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to watch one of our previous videos on &lt;a href=&quot;https://calgaryvideoblog.com/how-to-focus-on-product-and-promotion-when-prepping-your-home.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;prepping your home&lt;/a&gt; as well. If you have any other real estate-related questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/what-can-photography-do-for-your-homes-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.calgaryvideoblog.com/what-can-photography-do-for-your-homes-sale.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
