<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Scott Fuller Team | BRE# 01334119 - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 11:07:18 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 11:07:18 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Buy and Sell a Home at the Same Time</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/A1ewUN6djec?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few different ways you can structure a contingent offer. To explain, let me lay out three different scenarios:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case No. 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Your house isn’t on the market yet, and you’re putting an offer on another property. A lot of sellers might say they’re not sure about your offer, especially if they’ve received other offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case No. 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Your house is on the market, but it’s not under contract. The seller will likely take that more favorably since it’s more likely that you’ll get your home under contract at some point soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case No. 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Your house is on the market and is under contract. From the seller’s point of view, this is almost as good as an offer from a person who isn’t writing a contingent offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are often opportunities in the East Bay area to get a contingent offer accepted.%20https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/how-to-buy-and-sell-a-home-at-the-same-time.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are often opportunities in the East Bay area to get a contingent offer accepted.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For case No. 1, you need to be prepared to put your house on the market and to show the seller of the house you’re looking to buy that you’re serious and ready to go.&lt;/strong&gt; These are some things you’ll need to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a listing agreement with a real estate agent and determine a list price that is going to get your home sold. Make it competitive; don’t test the waters here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have all of your seller disclosures completely filled out. That way, we have a paper trail we can track and you’ll be ready to show the house as soon as it goes on the market.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get past your home inspection and look into any repair items like dry rot, water damage, infestations, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get professional photos taken of your property.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider having a staging consultation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a fully underwritten loan approval. This is almost the same thing as having cash, from a seller’s point of view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have all these things done, you can put an offer on the home you’re looking to buy and you’ll let the seller and their agent know that you’re serious and your home’s sale won’t be viewed as a liability that would cause them to pass over your offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’re getting into a market that’s a little more balanced between buyers and sellers, there are often opportunities in the East Bay area to get a contingent offer accepted, even if your house isn’t yet on the market. You’ll need to demonstrate to the seller that it’ll be ready to go on the market within 24 hours of them accepting your offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this, please feel free to reach out to us. We know the process can be a bit overwhelming for sellers, but part of our service is having a consultation with you to show you exactly how it works and to create a strategy from start to finish that will make it happen for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/how-to-buy-and-sell-a-home-at-the-same-time.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/how-to-buy-and-sell-a-home-at-the-same-time.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Preparing for a Market Downturn</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yNibt44MZKw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’re into August, our market is slowing down and starting to soften a bit. If this means we’re headed for a downturn, there are four things you can do to prepare yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, take a look at your mortgage note and make sure you’re in a good position before rates go up.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have an adjustable rate mortgage, find out what your options are to get it fixed in case you plan on living in your property for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re an investor, &lt;strong&gt;evaluate your real estate portfolio and consider getting rid of any properties that aren’t performing well.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have one or more properties that aren’t doing well or have a lot of deferred maintenance attached to them, now’s the time to decide whether you’re better off selling them now before something potentially happens sometime down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Typically when property values decrease, so do rental rates.%20https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/preparing-for-a-market-downturn.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Typically when property values decrease, so do rental rates.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a landlord and you have tenants living in your property, put together some longer-term lease contracts so you can lock in the current lease rate.&lt;/strong&gt; Typically when property values decrease, so do rental rates. While you may not want to do this because of the possibility that rates will rise, think about what could happen if your tenants want to renew their leases in six months and rental rates have plummeted in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;check if you have any credit from your home equity line of credit that you can use.&lt;/strong&gt; Before the last downturn, a lot of people had credit from their home equity line that they were going to use but were prevented from doing so by their lender once the market started to turn. If you need access to those resources, talk to a CPA or your financial planner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about what you can do to prepare for a market downturn, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 14:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/preparing-for-a-market-downturn.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/preparing-for-a-market-downturn.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Affordability in the Bay Area</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/O8hWM7ACL5E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to share some staggering statistics regarding affordability in the Bay Area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app called Blind is used by many tech workers to communicate with each other anonymously. Recently, Blind sent out a survey to 2,326 tech workers across different companies, including Google, Facebook, Oracle, etc., to ask if they could afford a home here. Of those surveyed, 59% reported being unable to afford a home in the Bay Area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=59% of surveyed workers in the Bay Area reported being unable to afford a home here.%20https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/affordability-in-the-bay-area.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“59% of surveyed workers in the Bay Area reported being unable to afford a home here.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not surprising, given that the median home price in San Francisco is $1.6 million. At this price, &lt;strong&gt;only 12% of people in San Francisco can actually afford to buy a house.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not just the average worker who can’t afford to live in the Bay Area—59% of tech workers can’t either. This is exactly why we see so many people selling their homes and leaving the Bay Area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this or are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 15:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/affordability-in-the-bay-area.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/affordability-in-the-bay-area.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Townhome or Condo: How Do You Tell the Difference?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x00-ke1cgaQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between a condo and a townhome?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of confusion out there regarding these two types of property. People tend to assume that multiple units stacked on top of each other are classified as condos, and this is generally true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, most think of townhomes as being two-story homes with rentable upstairs and downstairs units. This is not necessarily the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it isn’t just prospective buyers who are confused about the how properties are classified. I recently spoke with a woman &lt;strong&gt;who owned a property she believed to be a townhome for years, only to eventually discover that her home is technically classified as a condo.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Terms and regulations can vary between townhomes and condos, so it’s important to be aware of how a property is classified.%20https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/townhome-or-condo-how-do-you-tell-the-difference.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Terms and regulations can vary between townhomes and condos, so it’s important to be aware of how a property is classified.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is such a thing as townhome-style condos, so it is important not to make uninformed assumptions about the classification of properties you encounter. I recommend double checking with your Realtor as to whether a property is a townhome or condo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point you may be wondering, &lt;strong&gt;“Why does the classification of a property matter in the first place?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it comes down to financing terms and regulations, as these can vary between property types. Whether you’re marketing a property as a seller or are looking to purchase a property as a buyer, being aware of how it’s classified will matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to condos, you will generally own the airspace between walls. But with townhomes, you will also often have ownership over the land the property sits on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 13:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/townhome-or-condo-how-do-you-tell-the-difference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/townhome-or-condo-how-do-you-tell-the-difference.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sellers: Keep an Eye out for This Sneaky Scam</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qHUxDXeQ_yM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every seller wants to get top dollar for their home, but it is important not to let this aspiration get in the way of your better judgment. &lt;strong&gt;Today I would like to go over a common appraisal scam that certain unscrupulous buyers have been employing lately.&lt;/strong&gt; To explain this scam, let me paint an example scenario for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you have a home with a market value between $780,000 and $820,000. You place this home on the market for a list price of $800,000, then a frustrated buyer comes along and makes an offer far above this figure—let’s say $900,000. Should you take this offer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It is best to not let dollar signs cloud your decisions.%20https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/sellers-keep-an-eye-out-for-this-sneaky-scam.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It is best to not let dollar signs cloud your decisions.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As tempting as it is, you shouldn’t. &lt;strong&gt;An offer that sounds too good to be true probably is.&lt;/strong&gt; This over-inflated offer may be part of an appraisal scam, which is where buyers submit an intentionally outrageous offer that they know won’t match the appraisal. They do this so that they can get you to the negotiation table and secure a much lower price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid having this happen, always consult with your Realtor. What our team does when faced with this circumstance is to insist that the buyer remove the appraisal contingency if they are serious about that high of an offer. This way, they cannot go through with their plan if it is a scam. &lt;strong&gt;If a buyer making an offer like this can provide proof of funds and is willing to waive the appraisal contingency, then everything is good to go.&lt;/strong&gt; Otherwise, it is best to not let dollar signs cloud your decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 13:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/sellers-keep-an-eye-out-for-this-sneaky-scam.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/sellers-keep-an-eye-out-for-this-sneaky-scam.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Things You Shouldn’t Overlook When Purchasing a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bxv82gM7WTE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the five things you shouldn’t overlook when purchasing a property in our East Bay market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The home’s surrounding neighborhood.&lt;/strong&gt; Take a look at the neighborhood at all times of the day. What does it look like at night, or during the morning, or during the afternoon? Is the neighborhood conducive to what you might be looking for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Your daily commute.&lt;/strong&gt; What’s your trip to work going to look like from your new property? If your commute might be a long one, you might want to take a look at it during the busiest commute hours in the morning and evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Is your home’s neighborhood conducive to what you’re looking for?%20https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/5-things-you-shouldnt-overlook-when-purchasing-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Is your home’s neighborhood conducive to what you’re looking for?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Whether or not the CC&amp;amp;Rs or HOAs limit what you can do with the property.&lt;/strong&gt; This means exterior enhancements, paint, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Whether or not you can rent out the property.&lt;/strong&gt; If you plan on purchasing the home for a short period of time and then renting it out, you might not be allowed to do so if the home is located in an HOA area. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Things you can’t change about the property later on.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t like the lot size, for example, you might be limited in making future enhancements to it, so take a look at that and decide whether you want to reconsider or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about buying a home in our area, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 04:22:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/5-things-you-shouldnt-overlook-when-purchasing-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/5-things-you-shouldnt-overlook-when-purchasing-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Know When It's Time to Replace Your Appliances?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FPpkz5aqcYI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re purchasing a property with existing appliances and home systems or you already own a home, it’s important to understand how long home systems and appliances truly last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things to realize is that &lt;strong&gt;even though systems or appliances may not be broken down, they still might not be as efficient as they could be.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If technology has advanced far past the level at which your current appliances and systems are functioning, you may want to consider making some repairs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Staying proactive about repairing or replacing systems and appliances will save you a lot of trouble.%20https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/how-do-you-know-when-its-time-to-replace-your-appliances.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Staying proactive about repairing or replacing systems and appliances will save you a lot of trouble.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, replacing systems and appliances altogether might also be necessary. Staying proactive about repairing or replacing systems and appliances will save you a lot of trouble down the line. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to know how long each of the systems and appliances in your home will tend to last. Knowing this will give you a better idea of where you should make investments toward a more efficient home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Air conditioners, water heaters, and stoves all last eight to 15 years. Refrigerators last between seven and 13 years, dishwashers last between nine and 15 years, and washers and dryers last five to 15 years. &lt;strong&gt;HVAC systems tend to last the longest—between 10 and 30 years. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 07:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/how-do-you-know-when-its-time-to-replace-your-appliances.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/how-do-you-know-when-its-time-to-replace-your-appliances.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Things You Should Know About Homeowners Associations</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/08wjyiFxVvg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homeowners associations can include single-family residences in a community or a townhouse or condo community. Before you purchase a property within a homeowners association, there are five things you should know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, what is the monthly cost of the HOA?&lt;/strong&gt; For condos and townhomes, that can range from $250 to $450 or even $500, depending on what the community offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What is covered by the HOA and what benefits are available?%20https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/5-things-you-should-know-about-homeowners-associations.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What is covered by the HOA and what benefits are available?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to be comfortable with that monthly payment. Plus, your lender will qualify you based on your mortgage payment, taxes, and HOA fees, so it’s important to know what that amount is in order to qualify to buy the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is covered in the HOA? Homeowners associations may cover general upkeep of the area, landscaping, pool maintenance, tennis court upkeep, and other amenities. Some HOAs cover trash removal, water bills, and insurance for the property—which is not the same as your personal policy. Figure out what the HOA offers and what benefits are available to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the rules and regulations in the HOA?&lt;/strong&gt; Different homeowners associations will have different rules, such as where you can park, how many people you can have over, and other things like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you happy with the outside of the house? The great thing about HOAs is the community will be uniform. There are specific colors for the outside of the house and the front door. There are also rules about mowing the lawn and landscaping. Some people may view these regulations as a downside because there is less freedom for what you can do with your property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, how can you get involved with the HOA?&lt;/strong&gt; You may want to get on the HOA board to make the rules and regulations and further improve the property and the community itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about homeowners associations or you would like to learn more about buying a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/5-things-you-should-know-about-homeowners-associations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/5-things-you-should-know-about-homeowners-associations.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Qualifying for a Home Mortgage Just Got Easier</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aouzj6Of5V0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been thinking of buying a home, you may be happy to know that the government has recently made it easier to qualify for a mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent changes announced by Fannie Mae will be great news for anyone who perhaps previously struggled to qualify for a home mortgage. First of all, the &lt;strong&gt;debt-to-income ratio has increased to 50%.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The government has recently made it easier to qualify for a mortgage.%20https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/qualifying-for-a-home-mortgage-just-got-easier.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The government has recently made it easier to qualify for a mortgage.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that you’re able to be qualified based on 50% of your income going toward your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;adjustable rate mortgages can be done with 5% down.&lt;/strong&gt; In the past, a higher percentage was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another key change is that you may now qualify using future primary employment income. What this means is that if you have a pay increase or new job coming up in the near future, that higher income can help you qualify for your purchase, today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-employed borrowers may now also qualify based on one year of tax returns.&lt;/strong&gt; In the past decade or so, self-employed people had very few options—so this is great news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, timeshares are no longer considered mortgages. So, if you’re attempting to qualify for a home purchase you will no longer have to worry about a timeshare counting as a current mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 05:53:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/qualifying-for-a-home-mortgage-just-got-easier.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/qualifying-for-a-home-mortgage-just-got-easier.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should Real Estate Be Part of Your Retirement Plan?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s4SO7FosQmE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should you invest in real estate as part of your retirement plan? It’s a good idea, but you need to make sure it’s right for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should real estate be part of your retirement plan?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, including real estate in your retirement plan is a great way to &lt;strong&gt;diversify your portfolio.&lt;/strong&gt; Most financial planners agree that diversification reduces the risk in your retirement plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, investing in real estate may not be right for everyone. It does require you to set a lot of money aside in case something happens in the property. For example, the air conditioning may go out, you could lose a tenant, or you may need to take care of deferred maintenance items. When you invest in real estate, you need to have an emergency fund to take care of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real estate is a big commitment.&lt;/strong&gt; Unlike other kinds of investments, real estate is not necessarily liquid. It can be difficult or expensive to get rid of your real estate investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=INVESTING IN REAL ESTATE IS A BIG COMMITMENT.%20https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/should-real-estate-be-part-of-your-retirement-plan.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“INVESTING IN REAL ESTATE IS A BIG COMMITMENT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, before you take the plunge, make sure you do your research. First, find out how much money you need to put down. Also, decide who will manage the property. If it’s a local property, you may be able to manage it on your own. If the property is in another city or state, then you need to find someone you trust to manage the property for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about investing in real estate, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 11:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/should-real-estate-be-part-of-your-retirement-plan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eastbayrealestatejournal.net/should-real-estate-be-part-of-your-retirement-plan.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
