<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Real Estate Video Blog with Ashley Carter</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carter Group Chicago - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://cartergroupblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 10:06:44 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 10:06:44 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>All About Trapped Equity</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KIno64eubUs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is trapped equity and why might it be holding you back? Let’s discuss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the amount of equity you’ve got built up in your property might contribute to your overall net worth, it doesn’t actively make you money. &lt;strong&gt;This is where the concept of “trapped equity” comes into play. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, trapped equity is personal wealth that is tied up in an asset, like your home, and can’t be “released” unless you sell or refinance. Even if you’re using the property as a rental instead of a primary residence and are therefore generating positive cash flow, selling or refinancing are still your only means of accessing the home’s full value. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Trapped equity is personal wealth that is tied up in an asset, like your home.%20https://cartergroupblog.com/all-about-trapped-equity.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Trapped equity is personal wealth that is tied up in an asset, like your home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, &lt;strong&gt;having trapped equity in a property isn’t a bad thing, but it definitely isn’t conducive to certain goals.&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to increase your net worth more quickly, then please reach out to us about how your property’s trapped equity might be holding you back from further growing your wealth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 11:34:52 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/all-about-trapped-equity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cartergroupblog.com/all-about-trapped-equity.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Can Help You With Your Real Estate Investment Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fzH1pD-Qc2A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re looking to invest in real estate, we can help you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you or someone you know interested in investing in real estate? Whether you’ve only briefly thought about it, you’ve already started the process and need help, or you’re a seasoned investor looking to access more properties, we want you to reach out to us. We come across off-market properties on a weekly basis, and we can’t always list these properties for sale, so we want to be able to contact you if you’re interested in these opportunities and adding to your portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, we have a property available right now we haven’t found a buyer for, so if you’d like to know more or you have any other questions, give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to speak with you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 18:00:41 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/we-can-help-you-with-your-real-estate-investment-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cartergroupblog.com/we-can-help-you-with-your-real-estate-investment-goals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Won’t a Buyer Make an Offer on Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8V7QmPrkTmQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your home is overpriced and you’re wondering why buyers won’t even pitch you a lowball offer, pay attention to today’s video.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, we’ll represent a seller who, despite having difficulty finding a buyer, chooses not to make a price reduction to their home. When no buyer comes along, they wonder, &lt;strong&gt;“Why won’t someone just make me an offer?”&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know the exact science behind the answer to this question, but as someone who’s been in this business for a long time, I can tell you that buyers (and people, for that matter) don’t think or act that way. If your home has sat on the market for quite some time and you’ve yet to adjust its price, you can’t expect a buyer to come in with an aggressive, but lower, offer. That’s simply not how the U.S. consumer is wired. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, how would you feel if a buyer was to make an offer between 10% and 20% below your asking price? You’d probably be so offended that you wouldn’t want to work or negotiate with them at all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If your home has sat on the market for quite some time and you’ve yet to adjust its price, you can’t expect a buyer to come in with an aggressive, but lower, offer.%20https://cartergroupblog.com/why-wont-a-buyer-make-an-offer-on-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If your home has sat on the market for quite some time and you’ve yet to adjust its price, you can’t expect a buyer to come in with an aggressive, but lower, offer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to understand that, &lt;strong&gt;as a rule, buyers won’t take a flier price on your home.&lt;/strong&gt; They know that the more time your home spends on the market, the more likely it is that you’ll reduce your price, and when you do, that particular buyer will strike.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to avoid these types of scenarios if we can help it, and &lt;strong&gt;a major part of that is making sure your home is well-priced and well-prepared from the very beginning. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know would like help in the buying, selling, or investing process, please let us know. My team and I would be happy to help!  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/why-wont-a-buyer-make-an-offer-on-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cartergroupblog.com/why-wont-a-buyer-make-an-offer-on-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Condo Building Helping or Hurting You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AT8BttrfY3E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a condo owner, certain factors can make or break your home sale—factors unrelated to your actual unit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have a question for condo and townhome owners: &lt;strong&gt;Is your building helping or hurting you? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re selling one of these properties, you’re inextricably connected to the entire building, and certain factors can affect your prospect of finding a buyer. Take a moment to look around. What kind of first impression does the building give off from the sidewalk, lobby, etc.? Does the building contain elevators? Put another way, what do you see as you make your way to your unit? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To buyers, the building your condo is situated in is a direct reflection of the unit itself. They’ll pass judgment on the building’s overall maintenance and whether it looks like a high level of care goes into the property. &lt;strong&gt;Before the buyer ever sets foot in your actual home, there’s a chance that they’ve already decided whether they’ll give it serious consideration just based on their perception of your building.&lt;/strong&gt; Needless to say, it’s very important that the building you choose to move into doesn’t work against your future sale. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=My advice is to be involved and do your due diligence along the way to ensure some easy wins when you go to sell your property.%20https://cartergroupblog.com/is-your-condo-building-helping-or-hurting-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“My advice is to be involved and do your due diligence along the way to ensure some easy wins when you go to sell your property.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the building’s appearance, &lt;strong&gt;buyers will want to know how much your condo association has in cash reserves and the property’s history concerning its maintenance schedule. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answering these questions will only help you as a future seller. Too often, condo sellers have to overcome buyers’ objections to the building’s mismanagement or its poor condition—the effects of which put you at a disadvantage right out of the gate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice is to be involved and do your due diligence along the way to ensure some easy wins when you go to sell your property.&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or if you plan to sell your condo sometime in the future and you’d like some help determining what you should be spending your time and money on, please reach out to the Carter Property Group. We’d be happy to counsel you in that effort, and we look forward to hearing from you! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/is-your-condo-building-helping-or-hurting-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cartergroupblog.com/is-your-condo-building-helping-or-hurting-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Data on Our Chicago Housing Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YYHBpw2BCWk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today we’ll look at some recent data from the end of August having to do with our Chicago market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end-of-August numbers are in for our Chicago real estate market. What do they tell us about the current landscape? Let’s pore over the numbers pertaining to single-family homes to find out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we do, note that we’ll analyze each data point by doing a 10-year, three-year, and one-year lookback. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to follow along in the video above or use the timestamps below to navigate this market update at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:37—An often-forgotten point about the economics of the housing market &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:00—Median sales price &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:53—Months’ supply of homes for sale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:46—Closed sales  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:46—Cause and effect of closed sales plus median sales price &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:10—The distinction between leading indicators and lagging indicators &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:45—My take on the overall state of the market &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:02—The key takeaways for homebuyers &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:54—The key takeaways for sellers &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:45—Wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what we covered today or about anything else real estate-related, please don’t hesitate to let us know. We’d look forward to hearing from you! &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/the-latest-data-on-our-chicago-housing-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cartergroupblog.com/the-latest-data-on-our-chicago-housing-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Does Home Staging Work?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vW4t28G7xm4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preparing your home properly is essential in having a successful home sale. Here’s why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we’re consulting with home sellers, one of the most common questions we hear is, “Is staging worth it? Does it really work?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are two things that we can do to most effectively sell properties.&lt;/strong&gt; The first is pricing competitively. The second is preparing the property for sale. Typically, staging is directly tied to both of these components. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a property has too much furniture, not enough furniture, or not the right size of furniture, staging can make a significant difference. If you have oddly shaped rooms, staging can really help there, too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Staging helps with small or oddly shaped rooms.%20https://cartergroupblog.com/does-home-staging-work.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Staging helps with small or oddly shaped rooms.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In an ideal world, your property should be cleaned, painted, and staged.&lt;/strong&gt; The staging is the icing on the cake of the final presentation that buyers are looking for. It’s a major factor in the home-selling process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about selling a home or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/does-home-staging-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cartergroupblog.com/does-home-staging-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are Fixer-Uppers Hot or Not?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/earZMpFsxVc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are homebuyers still eyeing fixer-uppers these days? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The short answer is no.&lt;/strong&gt; We live in an increasingly fast-paced world where people want what they want on demand, and real estate is no exception. Homebuyers are seeking move-in ready, hassle-free properties that they can swiftly close on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, the running joke has been that buyers are looking to have the moving truck show up at 10 a.m. sharp, so they can welcome guests to the cookout at their new home by 5 p.m. that evening. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buyers of today don’t want to have to tackle a long list of upgrades after closing on a home.%20https://cartergroupblog.com/are-fixer-uppers-hot-or-not.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buyers of today don’t want to have to tackle a long list of upgrades after closing on a home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this is meant to be hyperbole, but the fact remains: &lt;strong&gt;Buyers of today don’t want to have to tackle a long list of upgrades after closing on a home.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t emphasize enough how important it is for you, as a seller, to get your home in prime condition. Otherwise, buyers won’t even give it a second glance because they know they’ll have the ability to borrow more money for a home in better condition and at an exceptionally low interest rate.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;strong&gt;as a seller, you want to extract the most value out of your home sale, so we need to make a concerted effort to ensure your home is in turnkey shape.&lt;/strong&gt; For any questions related to real estate or if you or someone you know would like to make a move, please let us know today. We’d be happy to help!       &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/are-fixer-uppers-hot-or-not.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cartergroupblog.com/are-fixer-uppers-hot-or-not.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Is the Best Time to Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ka7j_Apj0wY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers often ask me when the best time to sell their home is in today’s market. The answer actually depends on one key thing: you. Ask yourself—are you ready to put in the time, money, and energy that’s necessary to prep your home for sale? In today’s competitive market, your home needs to look and feel perfect from the moment a buyer steps foot inside. So the best time to list is actually whenever your home is ready to show. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/when-is-the-best-time-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cartergroupblog.com/when-is-the-best-time-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Did You Miss Your Chance to Sell Your Home for Top Dollar?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iAQp6dE2tWg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers are often under the impression that there’s a particular time of year when they should be putting their home on the market—that time is, of course, spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve discussed in previous videos, the reality is that **the right time to sell your home is when it best suits your situation. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been doing this a long time, and we’ve found that it doesn’t make sense to wait an entire year for the spring market to come back around. Unless your goals specifically line up with that time of year, here’s something to consider: Buyers populate our Chicago market and are looking to make a purchase every week and month of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Why wait a whole year when you’re unsure of what the future will bring?%20https://cartergroupblog.com/did-you-miss-your-chance-to-sell-your-home-for-top-dollar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Why wait a whole year when you’re unsure of what the future will bring?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, you’re probably not doing yourself any favors by trying to sync up your home sale with a seasonal market. &lt;strong&gt;There’s no telling what market conditions will be like a year from now.&lt;/strong&gt; Home prices could very well flatten out or even go down and, given that the market is always shifting, that’s a real possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortening your time frame to a comfortable point gives us a chance to predict what the market will be doing and will lead to greater certainty in your sale. **Why wait a whole year when you’re unsure of what the future will bring? **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know would like an evaluation of a property or you’re thinking about making a real estate move, don’t hesitate to let us know. We look forward to speaking with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/did-you-miss-your-chance-to-sell-your-home-for-top-dollar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cartergroupblog.com/did-you-miss-your-chance-to-sell-your-home-for-top-dollar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recapping the U.S.’s 2018 Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/R-qZcxANBxc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to take the opportunity today to give you the full rundown of how our 2018 market fared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five central data points that drive real estate: home sales, home price, months’ supply of inventory, mortgage rates, and affordability. I’ll take a deep dive into these stats on the national scale.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National home sales for 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5.3 million total homes sold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Down from 2016 and 2017&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matched the number for 2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projected to fall slightly to 5.2 million in 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National home prices for 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished with a year-over-year appreciation of 5%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anticipated to increase in 2019&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase is projected to be in the 1% to 5% range&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National months&amp;rsquo; supply of inventory for 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished with four months’ worth of inventory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dating back to 2013, our seller’s market has persisted due to:  
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Number of new construction homes remaining low&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ever-increasing interest rates&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Homeowners staying put for longer&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National mortgage rates for 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased almost a full percentage point from early 2018 to year’s end&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Currently hovering at 4.5%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rates are still at historical lows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National affordability for 2018 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished slightly up, as compared to 2017’s market&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since 1970, we still sit below average affordability index&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do these numbers bear out for the future of our real estate market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All in all, the national housing market is relatively healthy and will remain stable in 2019&lt;/strong&gt;—homes are selling well and interest rates have stayed fairly moderate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for those looking to buy in 2019, we aren’t going to see homes flying off the market nor will they appreciate to an astronomical extent. If your real estate goals for this year include making a home purchase, a golden opportunity awaits you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in a conversation around what your options might be in any aspect of residential real estate, please give us a call. We look forward to having that conversation with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://cartergroupblog.com/recapping-the-u-s-s-2018-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cartergroupblog.com/recapping-the-u-s-s-2018-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
