<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The HBR Team Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The HBR Team - your professional Tracy Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 14:36:04 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 14:36:04 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Expectations For the 2021 Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zxZ-TDQI3mw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;re looking at what 2021 may bring to our market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What can we expect from our 2021 market? Like most real estate professionals in the market, we wish we had a solid answer to that question. However, we can say with some certainty that interest rates won’t be going up in the first quarter of the year. Ultimately, we don’t expect a ton of change at the beginning of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re still consistently bringing in buyers for our area, specifically the South Bay, East Bay, and San Francisco areas. However, &lt;strong&gt;we also still have a shortage of inventory&lt;/strong&gt;, which means that if you’re a homeowner on the fence about selling, you should reach out to us so we can discuss your situation and why it would be beneficial for you to enter the market. We can customize a program just for you so that you know all the options that are available to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t hesitate to reach out to us! We’d love to help you move on to the next stage of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-expectations-for-the-2021-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/our-expectations-for-the-2021-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is an As-Is Offer?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xe-LMfNh_l0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;A word on buying an &amp;lsquo;as is&amp;rsquo; property.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This question has been coming up quite a lot this week because buyers in our seller’s market are so anxious to have their offers on a property accepted. The term ‘as is’ is an important part of your negotiations and even after the fact when you’re in contract. &lt;strong&gt;A home that is sold ‘as is’ means the seller intends to sell the house without making repairs&lt;/strong&gt;; the property will be sold in its current condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your agent tells you that a home is being sold as is, &lt;strong&gt;you do have the option to have inspections done&lt;/strong&gt;. However, the seller should at least attach their disclosures and a pest/roof inspection for you to review. Even during an as-is sale, it’s important to have some kind of understanding about what kind of property you’re buying. It’d be a shame if you got so far into the contract only to find out that the home you were buying has a $10,000 roof issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about buying a home in our current market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-an-as-is-offer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-an-as-is-offer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Offering Real Estate Financial Checkups</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AYPXE_XZNLQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;A real estate financial checkup can prevent issues in your future.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With your physical health, you want to do preventative care to ensure you don’t have an emergency later. It’s the same for your real estate financial health. In both instances, &lt;strong&gt;you should get ahead of any issues&lt;/strong&gt; and take care of things. You need to know where you stand with your finances to prevent a disaster down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people who are in the best financial state do preventative checkups. They speak to their financial advisor regularly and talk to their tax accountant before the end of the year so they know what will benefit them in the coming year. We want to help you with this. Many people come to us after something has happened, but we usually can’t undo what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need to know where you stand with your finances.%20http://localhost:4000/were-offering-real-estate-financial-checkups.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You need to know where you stand with your finances.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s your will, your trust, financial planning for your child’s college education, retirement, downsizing, or something else, we can help you figure out a plan. We want to offer you real estate financial health checkups. &lt;strong&gt;Simply &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.homebuyersrealty.com/hows-your-real-estate-financial-health-get-your-checkup-now&quot;&gt;click this link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; and we can help you reach your financial goals&lt;/strong&gt;. Input your name, address, and what your goal is, and we’ll do our research into your specific needs. Then we’ll have a conversation either via Zoom or in person and discuss your next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about our real estate financial checkups or anything else concerning real estate, please call or email us. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/were-offering-real-estate-financial-checkups.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/were-offering-real-estate-financial-checkups.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Seen Our Latest Endorsement?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KixQgHXQom4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;John Tesh, national radio show host and musician, has endorsed our team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today we’re very excited to announce that we’ve been endorsed by John Tesh. Not only are we huge fans of John Tesh because he created “Roundball Rock,” the theme song for the NBA on NBC, but we also love his show “Intelligence for Your Life.” It’s broadcast locally on Sundays on 102.3 FM, and it gives us quality information that brings wisdom, peace, and satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We love his energy, his message, and his impact on this world&lt;/strong&gt;. We had the honor of meeting John a few years ago, and had plans to see him in concert this spring until COVID put a damper on things. We can’t wait to go back and see him in the future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take a listen to John’s endorsement of our team at 1:20 in the video above&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can’t wait to see John in concert in the future.%20http://localhost:4000/have-you-seen-our-latest-endorsement.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We can’t wait to see John in concert in the future.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/have-you-seen-our-latest-endorsement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/have-you-seen-our-latest-endorsement.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Are So Many Sellers Moving Out of the Bay Area?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bdGORa-cMV8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an eastward migration happening in our market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today’s topic can be summed up in one sentence: Go east, young man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, we’ve seen a lot of people moving from the Bay Area to the Central Valley due to more and more companies allowing their workers to work from home (and to a lesser extent, low interest rates). This has had a big impact on our market. We’ve seen a huge influx of young buyers who don’t have to live in higher-priced areas anymore—areas where they had previously been renters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a welcome improvement to our market because &lt;strong&gt;sellers are benefiting tremendously and home prices are rising&lt;/strong&gt;. Every property we listed the week before the recording of this video attracted multiple offers and sold above asking price. Additionally, many home sellers in our area are moving even further east and settling in the Midwest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ve seen a huge influx of young buyers who don’t have to live in higher-priced areas anymore.%20http://localhost:4000/why-are-so-many-sellers-moving-out-of-the-bay-area.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve seen a huge influx of young buyers who don’t have to live in higher-priced areas anymore.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been thinking about leaving California and moving to another state but are still on the fence about selling, give us a call. We’d love to talk more about why now’s an optimal time to sell. There are far more buyers than there are sellers out there, so &lt;strong&gt;it’s a great time to get top dollar&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other real estate questions, feel free to reach out to us. We’re here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-are-so-many-sellers-moving-out-of-the-bay-area.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-are-so-many-sellers-moving-out-of-the-bay-area.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are We Seeing More Activity as Things Open Back Up?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J8FnFRrXeF4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;More businesses are opening back up, and real estate is seeing a surge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We were pleasantly surprised at the response last week in the real estate market as more and more businesses opened back up. We listed four houses last weekend and had a total of 85 showings. We didn’t expect such a response so soon, and more people are getting anxious to take advantage of pent-up demand and low interest rates. &lt;strong&gt;We only expect it to get busier from here&lt;/strong&gt; as we continue to follow the state’s guidelines for our listings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-we-seeing-more-activity-as-things-open-back-up.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-we-seeing-more-activity-as-things-open-back-up.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Our Market Headed for a Recession?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LPD5DKWs3zU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are we headed for a recession like the one back in 2007? Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As we continue to keep our clients and friends up to date with the latest goings-on in our market, we’ve been hearing a lot of people asking if we’re headed into a recession. Our friends over at eXp just had their shareholder meeting, and they provided a lot of great data to help answer that question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back during the Great Recession of 2007 and 2008, 14.5% of homeowners had less than 10% equity in their homes. Today, that number has dropped to 6.6%. Back then, the number of active subprime loans hit 5.1 million, where today, it’s only at 1.98 million. Those were a huge factor in what caused the Great Recession, and &lt;strong&gt;today we simply don’t have the same issues&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-our-market-headed-for-a-recession.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/is-our-market-headed-for-a-recession.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Sell Your Home During COVID-19</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x66_WF46zTc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our goal is to help serve your real estate needs no matter what.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We received an amazing response regarding &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://hbrteamblog.com/the-relationship-between-recessions-and-the-housing-market.html&quot;&gt;our last market update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. While it’s a great time to sell, we’d like to ensure the process is being done correctly in order to get top dollar for your house. Those that went pending were priced right and cleaned inside and out, receiving multiple offers because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re aware that everyone has a friend or relative that sells real estate. We do, too, and they always want to offer their opinions. However, keep in mind that when you hire a real estate team like ours, &lt;strong&gt;we have your best interests at heart&lt;/strong&gt;. We want you to get your home sold quickly for top dollar and we appreciate your trust in us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-during-covid-19.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-during-covid-19.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Relationship Between Recessions and the Housing Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/94QG6Jyw2CA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re not being overly optimistic when we say a crash isn&amp;rsquo;t imminent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So many people expect that the housing market will fail as a consequence of what’s been going on with COVID-19 and its effect on the economy. Though some of us still bear the scars of 2008, there’s no reason to believe this new crisis will drag real estate down that same dark path again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are indicators that we may even come out of this ahead&lt;/strong&gt;; inventory is still low, and it’s still a seller’s market. We don’t see the world through rose-colored glasses, we tell it like it is. That being said, the numbers simply don’t indicate that we’re heading for housing market doom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-relationship-between-recessions-and-the-housing-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-relationship-between-recessions-and-the-housing-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Will There Be a Spring Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aXuw0TSrjJs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the shelter-in-place provisions across the country, will there even be a spring real estate market?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;People have been asking us over and over: What’s going on with the spring market? Are we even going to have one, or will COVID-19 cause us to bypass it completely? The answers we’ll provide today depend on when the shelter-in-place provisions will be lifted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, there are serious restrictions on showings; we can only show vacant homes in person, and we’ve been doing virtual home tours for sellers who still live in their homes. &lt;strong&gt;If restrictions are lifted, we anticipate a number of homes will enter the market&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/will-there-be-a-spring-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/will-there-be-a-spring-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
