<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hudson County Real Estate Video Blog with Steven Rosado</title>
    <description>Our mission at Keller Williams City Life Realty is to be your best resource for Hudson County real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Keller Williams City Life Realty, your professional Hudson County Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://rosadoblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rosadoblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 10:55:26 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 10:55:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Deadline to Appeal Your Property Taxes Is April 1</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iwadFOeypRU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here to talk to you about potentially saving thousands of dollars on your real estate taxes. &lt;strong&gt;You’ll need to get it done by April 1, so listen up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel as though your property is being taxed too high, then you may want to appeal your taxes in hopes of receiving a lower rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I go any further, let me just say that I’m not an attorney or a financial advisor. I can give you a good indication of the estimated value of your property but if you want to appeal your taxes, I can give you great recommendations for legal and financial advice. The best part about this process is that it doesn’t take much work. You just rely on us, and we’ll get the job done for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The way that the tax assessment office values properties is not a perfect system.&lt;/strong&gt;They are aware of this, which is why they are giving up to a 15% margin of error. That’s a big number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I can give you a good indication of the estimated value of your property.%20http://rosadoblog.com/the-deadline-to-appeal-your-property-taxes-is-april-1.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I can give you a good indication of the estimated value of your property.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works. Let’s say your home is assessed at $600,000 and the tax rate is 1.6%. If a similar home is assessed at $510,000 or less, it would fall outside of the 15% buffer zone. Your taxes would go from $9,600 down to $8,400. &lt;strong&gt;You’d save about $1,400 each year by winning that appeal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just went through this process on a property in Jersey City. I was being taxed on a rate more than 20% above what the property’s value was. It’s very likely I’ll win this one and save around $200 per month in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make sure I let you know about this before the deadline to appeal comes on April 1. No, this is not an April Fool’s joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions in the meantime or need any assistance, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 15:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://rosadoblog.com/the-deadline-to-appeal-your-property-taxes-is-april-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rosadoblog.com/the-deadline-to-appeal-your-property-taxes-is-april-1.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Process That Will Sell Your Tenant-Occupied Home Quickly  for Top Dollar</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/62RPNlSqN7Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our area, we have a lot of investment properties, and for the most part, those properties have renters in place. As you might expect, when you sell one of these homes, these renters don’t tidy up the place in the same way you would because they don’t own it and don’t care as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do in this situation? Do you have the home go vacant and carry the HOA and mortgage costs for however many months before it goes under contract and closes, or is there a way you can sell the home for top dollar with the tenants still in place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, there is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the tenants. They don’t care about the home as much as you do, and they’ve just been told they have to vacate the home in about 60 days, so they’re probably none too excited. &lt;strong&gt;I recommend you make a deal with them.&lt;/strong&gt; Show them that you care and that the process will be as easy for them as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I myself let them know that their privacy and their schedule are paramount and that we’ll be very strict on the showing schedule so there aren’t any that take place that they weren’t expecting—that’s usually one of their biggest worries. For example, we usually set aside two or three nights a week where showings are pushed to a certain timeline—say, 5 p.m. to 7:30 p.m. on weeknights and 12:00 p.m. to 3:00 p.m. on weekends. This works out great for everybody involved—it pushes all the traffic toward certain times and lets the tenants know we care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This process will bring you top dollar in the shortest amount of time.%20http://rosadoblog.com/a-process-that-will-sell-your-tenant-occupied-home-quickly-for-top-dollar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This process will bring you top dollar in the shortest amount of time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have the tenants on board, &lt;strong&gt;make the home look presentable.&lt;/strong&gt; I usually schedule a cleaning the day of photography. Since the home will probably revert back to the way it looked before after the cleaning and photography are finished, I schedule another cleaning the day of a showing or open house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;you must price the home to sell.&lt;/strong&gt; We usually list the home above asking price. This usually gets the home sold in less than 10 days so we don’t have to keep showing the home week after week. It’s very difficult to schedule multiple open houses when you have tenants in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process will bring you top dollar in the shortest amount of time. All the while, your tenants are paying your mortgage and HOA fees until the home closes. It’s not easy and it takes a lot of experience, but that’s where an agent such as myself comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about selling a home with tenants or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 15:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rosadoblog.com/a-process-that-will-sell-your-tenant-occupied-home-quickly-for-top-dollar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rosadoblog.com/a-process-that-will-sell-your-tenant-occupied-home-quickly-for-top-dollar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Take A Look At My Home-Flipping Project</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kH8sMxDHYT0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My promise to you in 2018. . . NO MORE BORING VIDEOS! I’m going to make it my top priority to show you how to yield the best results in our Hudson County Market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that 1 in 5 of my clients are interested in real estate investment, i figured i would LITERALLY put my money where my mouth is. So i decided and flip a home and bring you all along for the ride!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first rule of real estate is that the location of the property is paramount in mitigating your risk.&lt;/strong&gt; I chose a property in a good central location to New York City transportation. There are two bus stops, a light rail, a path station, and now there’s a new restaurant called Road that was just put in, making it a pretty hot up-and-coming spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=One man’s trash can be another man’s gold.%20http://rosadoblog.com/take-a-look-at-my-home-flipping-project.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“One man’s trash can be another man’s gold.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see the property and learn how one man’s trash can be another man’s gold, skip ahead to 1:15 in the video. Despite its ramshackle appearance, I believe there’s a lot of value in this property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought it for $315,000, and—factoring in the $110,000 for renovation, $25,000 for financing costs, and $5,000 for tax and utilities—the target sale price was a conservative $600,000. The total project is projected to take from nine to 11 months. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about flipping or real estate in general, please reach out to me. I’d love to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 04:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rosadoblog.com/take-a-look-at-my-home-flipping-project.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rosadoblog.com/take-a-look-at-my-home-flipping-project.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays From the Rosado's</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CZpGXiIxrzw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone that I had the opportunity to work with this year. Whether you relied on my services for buying, selling, or renting… or provided me with opportunities by referring my services to someone you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter if the referral bought, sold, or rented from me. It’s the opportunity that counts. I wanted to take some time this year (which was the most successful year thus far in my nine-year career) and directly thank each and every one of you.&lt;br /&gt;Collectively, we’re able to help brighten up the holiday for people in need. Not only giving thanks, but giving smiles and hope to people who need it the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, thank you, thank you all for giving us the opportunity to do this. I hope your holiday season just go brighter as well. Talk to you next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays from the Rosado’s!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 06:59:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rosadoblog.com/happy-holidays-from-the-rosados.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rosadoblog.com/happy-holidays-from-the-rosados.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Should Buyers and Sellers Expect From Our Holiday Hoboken Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eux7MeDt4HA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The holiday season in our Hoboken market means different things for buyers and sellers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a seller and your home isn’t ready to be on the market in the next 10 to 15 days, you should probably think about waiting until 2018 to list&lt;/strong&gt;. Generally speaking, the buyer pool decreases a tad from Thanksgiving to New Year’s and the market shifts away from you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, now is the perfect time to get started on your marketing for 2018, and there are a couple reasons why. First, fall is a beautiful time of year, meaning your home’s photography will look a lot better. Secondly, now is the time of year when people focus on hosting friends and family for the holidays, which means homes will be cleaner and look nicer. From a staging standpoint, you can take advantage of this by taking pictures of the interior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The buyer pool shrinks and homes tend to stay on the market longer this time of year.%20http://rosadoblog.com/what-should-buyers-and-sellers-expect-from-our-holiday-hoboken-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The buyer pool shrinks and homes tend to stay on the market longer this time of year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a buyer, this is one of the few times of the year that the market will work in your favor in our area&lt;/strong&gt;. As I said, the buyer pool shrinks and homes tend to sit on the market longer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a buyer or a seller, if you have any more questions about our Hoboken market or you’re thinking of making a move soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 08:33:32 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rosadoblog.com/what-should-buyers-and-sellers-expect-from-our-holiday-hoboken-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rosadoblog.com/what-should-buyers-and-sellers-expect-from-our-holiday-hoboken-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Long Does a Conventional Home Sale Usually Last?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_vk_AIU23Pc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In tabulating the total length of a conventional home sale, we must examine each separate phase of the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://rosadorealtor.blogspot.com/p/free-home-value-report.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://stevenrosado.kw.com/listings-search/#/398466887&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of timeline can buyers and sellers expect in a conventional home sale? For a comprehensive look, let’s break the process down into each separate phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first phase is the &lt;strong&gt;attorney review.&lt;/strong&gt; This takes place after an accepted offer has been put in place and both the buyer and seller sign off on the contract. The contract goes to both of their attorneys for review, after which the buyer’s attorney makes any revisions or recommendations they see fit and sends a rider to the seller’s attorney, which is basically a proposal in addition to the contract. The seller’s attorney then makes their own revisions and sends it back to the buyer’s side. Once both sides agree to the rider and sign off on it, you can exit attorney review. Phase length: five to seven days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, we move on to the &lt;strong&gt;inspection phase.&lt;/strong&gt; Generally, a buyer will have a right to an inspection where their inspector will look at the home and make any recommendations for repairs. That recommendation will go to both attorneys. They’ll then decide if any repairs need to be made by the seller, any credits are due from the seller, or if the buyer will accept the home as-is. Phase length: eight to 10 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the inspection is completed, the &lt;strong&gt;appraisal phase&lt;/strong&gt; begins. The appointed appraiser will reach out to the buyer or seller side and schedule the appraisal. They’ll measure the interior of the home and put a comparable report together to submit to the bank. Phase length: seven to 10 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is the &lt;strong&gt;mortgage commitment phase.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the phase in which the appraisal is sent to the bank and goes to underwriting for approval. The underwriting department examines all the financial factors and checks the buyer’s criteria to make sure everything lines up with the loan. Phase length: 14 to 21 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=CONVENTIONAL HOME SALES TAKE LONGER THAN CASH PURCHASES.%20http://rosadoblog.com/how-long-does-home-sale-last.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“CONVENTIONAL HOME SALES TAKE LONGER THAN CASH PURCHASES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the mortgage commitment has been issued, the &lt;strong&gt;title search phase&lt;/strong&gt; happens. The title company will take a look at the transfer history of the property and see if there are any additional parties that claim ownership of the property that haven’t been involved in the sale up until that point. Once those variables are settled and the title company deems the title clean and clear, they’ll issue title insurance. Phase length: seven to 10 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, we come finally to the &lt;strong&gt;clear to close phase.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the final review from the bank to make sure the buyer is financially stable. Phase length: five to seven days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the clear to close phase commences, each side is free and clear to complete the home sale. If you’ve been keeping your math at home, your total timeline for a conventional sale is &lt;strong&gt;46 to 65 days.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind, a conventional sale means having a mortgage involved. If the home sale is a cash purchase, the appraisal and mortgage commitment phases aren’t necessary. Subtracting them makes a cash sale timeline anywhere from 20 to 27 days. Generally, you’ll see closing dates for those transactions set anywhere from 30 to 35 days out. Cash sales are typically more attractive to sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 11:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://rosadoblog.com/how-long-does-home-sale-last.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rosadoblog.com/how-long-does-home-sale-last.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Sale Timeline</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Have Rising Mortgage Rates Impacted Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fbuM8Q64DJA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mortgage rates have risen lately, but as you’ll see, this shouldn’t stop both buyers and sellers from getting a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://rosadorealtor.blogspot.com/p/free-home-value-report.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://stevenrosado.kw.com/listings-search/#/398466887&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do rising mortgage rates mean for buyers and sellers in our market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you don’t remember, mortgage rates were historically low last year. In August, they were as low as 3.44%, and now they’ve risen up to about 4.12%. What does that mean in real terms?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, the same mortgage on a $250,000 house would’ve cost you about $100 per month less than it does this year. The overall term of that loan is also about $35,000 more on a 30-year mortgage. That’s a sizeable chunk of change, and I don’t want to downplay that, but &lt;strong&gt;it’s really not going to do too much harm to our market in the immediate future.&lt;/strong&gt; Why is this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at it in a historical context, the same loans 10 years ago averaged over 6.3%. If you go back to the 90s, they hovered anywhere between 7% to 10%. In the 80s, they rarely dipped below 16%. As you can see, they’re still extremely low compared to the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YES, MORTGAGE RATES HAVE RISEN LATELY, BUT THIS IS NOTHING TO BE SCARED OF.%20http://rosadoblog.com/the-effect-of-rising-mortgage-rates-in.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YES, MORTGAGE RATES HAVE RISEN LATELY, BUT THIS IS NOTHING TO BE SCARED OF.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a buyer, now is still a great time to buy.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll still get a great rate and there are plenty of loan products available to you. It’s just a matter of connecting with the right agent and finding the right home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a seller, now is a great time to sell as well.&lt;/strong&gt; Your home will very likely sell quickly and you’re very likely to get top dollar since there are so many folks interested in buying and we currently have a limited inventory. The market did slow down in December, but that was more due to a lack of inventory than mortgage rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a buyer or seller, if you have any questions or are thinking about making a move in our market soon, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you and I hope you have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 15:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rosadoblog.com/the-effect-of-rising-mortgage-rates-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rosadoblog.com/the-effect-of-rising-mortgage-rates-in.html</guid>
        
        <category>Mortgage Rates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Never Trust a Zestimate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pjfx5lhRiQc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a serious buyer or seller, you should never trust a Zestimate. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://rosadorealtor.blogspot.com/p/free-home-value-report.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://stevenrosado.kw.com/listings-search/#/398466887&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to tell why you should never trust a Zestimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To clarify, &lt;strong&gt;Zestimates can be helpful to people who are dabbling in real estate, but if you’re serious about buying or selling a home, it can be very misleading and cause you to leave a lot of money on the table.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve seen this happen many times, and here are three recent examples that I’ve been involved with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first involves a home we recently sold at 49 Chestnut Street in Weehawken. The Zestimate for this home was $700,353. If we listed it at that price, the property would’ve been on the market for years because it wasn’t worth anywhere near that amount. Instead, we listed the property at $410,000, and in less than 10 days, we had three offers and eventually sold it for $425,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second example involves a buyer I’m working with to close on a home on Lydia Drive in Guttenberg whose Zestimate is $632,407 but got listed at $609,000. We haven’t closed yet, but my buyer has negotiated the price down to $590,000, and you can be sure he’s happy the owner didn’t go off the Zestimate value because that may have led him to believe that $609,000 wasn’t a bad list price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=TRUSTING A ZESTIMATE CAN COST YOU A LOT OF MONEY IN A TRANSACTION.%20http://rosadoblog.com/why-you-should-never-trust-zestimate_17.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“TRUSTING A ZESTIMATE CAN COST YOU A LOT OF MONEY IN A TRANSACTION.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third example involves a single-family home in Hoboken that we recently helped sell. The Zestimate for it was $1.433 million, but we listed it at $1.525 million, received multiple offers, and sold it in less than 10 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, these are huge swings in prices. The reason for this is that &lt;strong&gt;a Zestimate is a tool that’s based solely off an algorithm.&lt;/strong&gt; In calculating the value of a single home, it takes into account the values of the surrounding homes but not much else. Crucial details like an upgraded kitchen or bathroom get left out of a Zestimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re serious about buying a home or getting an accurate value of a home you plan to sell, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 13:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rosadoblog.com/why-you-should-never-trust-zestimate_17.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rosadoblog.com/why-you-should-never-trust-zestimate_17.html</guid>
        
        <category>Zestimates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Does the 2017 Real Estate Market Look Like?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tyCX1IxGIOA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m explaining what influence Trump will have on the real estate market and going over my 2017 predictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://rosadorealtor.blogspot.com/p/free-home-value-report.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://stevenrosado.kw.com/listings-search/#/398466887&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the election over, I’m going to answer a couple questions about the future of the market. The first question is, “What kind of influence will the new president-elect have on the real estate market?” I’m also going to talk about my real estate market predictions for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what influence will the new President-elect have on the real estate market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is anything we know about Donald Trump, it’s that he has a weird hairdo, he sends out horrible tweets at three in the morning, and he really knows real estate. If there is a silver lining at all, it’s that &lt;strong&gt;he is a real estate mogul.&lt;/strong&gt; He is very good at predicting real estate markets and he understands our industry like nobody we have seen in office before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is going to put a $550 billion infrastructure and transportation plan into effect that will boost jobs and wages. This will allow people to purchase more homes. &lt;strong&gt;According to an article in The Wall Street Journal, only 63% of people own homes, which is the lowest in history&lt;/strong&gt; since the United States started tracking that statistic back in 1963.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He will also implement a lot of tax code changes, which are expected to be the largest tax code changes a President has introduced since Ronald Reagan. He is going to offer a $30,000 tax exemption to married couples, which will make the tax reduction for mortgage loan interest less lucrative. This means there will be less incentive to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=NEXT YEAR IS GOING TO BE A FANTASTIC YEAR FOR REAL ESTATE.%20http://rosadoblog.com/how-will-trump-affect-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“NEXT YEAR IS GOING TO BE A FANTASTIC YEAR FOR REAL ESTATE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the tax code changes are going to be a wash for real estate, but the infrastructure and transportation plan should give people more of their bottom line income to spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for my market predictions for 2017. Next year is going to be a fantastic year for real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real estate market in the United States is predictable and it goes in a cycle. If you look at the chart, you can see there are peak and valleys, and then a crash, and this repeats. Almost like clockwork, &lt;strong&gt;every 18 years there is a cycle that is repeated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a recovery phase which we have already experienced, then there’s expansion, which I believe we are about a quarter of the way into. We do not have hyper supply; in fact, one of the big things driving prices is the lack of supply, and we have interest rates going up a bit, which will ward off inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next crash in the market isn’t predicted to happen until 2024. That means the market has a lot of room to run. Sellers should be confident in selling, and buyers should be confident in buying. &lt;strong&gt;The rates are going to be fantastic for both.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here for the source of this information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about real estate, feel free to reach out to me by giving me a call or sending me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 15:22:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rosadoblog.com/how-will-trump-affect-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rosadoblog.com/how-will-trump-affect-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Seen Our Brand-New App?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7NCezJuz5S8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a few quick updates for you today about the technology we use and how it helps you in your home search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://rosadorealtor.blogspot.com/p/free-home-value-report.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Want to buy a home?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://stevenrosado.kw.com/listings-search/#/398466887&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got two quick updates for you today about some of the new technology we are using in our business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is our new iPhone and iPad app with Keller Williams. It’s much better than what you’ll find on Zillow and Trulia. You can search for nearby homes, nearby rentals, and more. &lt;strong&gt;You can see what open houses are going on this weekend, where all the homes are located, and even use a mortgage calculator to estimate your monthly payment.&lt;/strong&gt; Type &lt;a href=&quot;http://app.kw.com/KW2Q08TPW&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://app.kw.com/KW2Q08TPW&lt;/a&gt; into your iPhone browser to download app for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we had some problems with our home value tool, so we installed a new one! All you have to do is enter your address and a few details and it will provide you with a quick evaluation. If you want a more in-depth evaluation, we can help with that, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or are looking to buy or sell in the area, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 11:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://rosadoblog.com/have-you-opened-our-new-app.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rosadoblog.com/have-you-opened-our-new-app.html</guid>
        
        <category>New App</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
