<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journey with Jennie</title>
    <description>Jennie Wolek, a top Real Estate Agent in Tulsa, shares her own internal real estate agent training for free. Her Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 12:04:27 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 12:04:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Relationship Patterns Influence Our Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i7-TJKBaSQA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you keep track of relationship patterns, you’ll see that making one contact can lead to a windfall of transactions down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look in the video above, you’ll see I’m holding a piece of paper I’m really proud of that I want to share with you. It’s a flowchart of a relationship pattern my team and me have been tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this shows me is that &lt;strong&gt;making one contact, making one relationship, and helping one family with their relationship needs can lead to over 30 other transactions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take those 30 units and multiply them by our average commission of—let’s say—$5,000, that’s over $300,000 of gross commission income we can bring in as a team, all by being purposeful and having a database that applies systemized touches. And, it’s fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=GIVE THANKS TO THE PEOPLE WHO HELP YOU WITH YOUR BUSINESS.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-do-you-know-where-your-business-comes-from.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“GIVE THANKS TO THE PEOPLE WHO HELP YOU WITH YOUR BUSINESS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;strong&gt;make sure you notice relationship patterns.&lt;/strong&gt; The reason I was reminded to share this with you is that Nate, one of our sales associates, has been working with some new clients buy and sell homes, and we retraced those transactions to a friend I went to college with whom we helped buy and sell a home last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sign in the yard led to another listing across the street, which led to an open house guest, which led to four other families we now get to help. Celebrate these kinds of patterns and don’t forget to reward the people who help you with your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions or there’s anything else I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 15:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-do-you-know-where-your-business-comes-from.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-do-you-know-where-your-business-comes-from.html</guid>
        
        <category>#JustJennie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Train Your Referral Partners</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/47iQ0WJRfao?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure that your family, friends, and clients all know the best way to refer you to a potential client. Here are a few tips to help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you make sure that when people refer you, they’re doing it correctly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had a past client, friend, or family member tell you that they’ve given so-and-so one of your business cards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those situations, I’m always very appreciative. However, there is an issue with that sort of referral. If the person who received the card is anything like me, &lt;strong&gt;they’ll eventually lose the card.&lt;/strong&gt; I like to tell the friend or client who gave them my card to call, text, or email me. The last thing we would ever want is for that person to end up with a weak agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, we just need to remind our friends and family how they should refer us to them. One script that I love is Mick Hick’s “The Promise.” It’s a great foundation and piece to add to your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=SOMETIMES, WE JUST NEED TO REMIND OUR FRIENDS AND FAMILY HOW THEY SHOULD REFER US TO THEM.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-teaching-others-how-to-refer-your-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“SOMETIMES, WE JUST NEED TO REMIND OUR FRIENDS AND FAMILY HOW THEY SHOULD REFER US TO THEM.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• “The idea is, during the process of us working together, you will likely hear of other people talking about buying and selling real estate. In that time—between now and when we get to closing—we sure would appreciate if you would give me a call when you hear of anybody that’s thinking about buying or selling.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• “[…]What I’m asking for is for you to take the next step to make sure that I have the chance to help. In addition to giving my name out, please call, text, or email me their information, because then, I’ll know that there’s a 100% chance that I’ll get in touch with them. This could even be if they’re thinking about refinancing or if they have a general question about real estate. Let me be the real estate expert and reach out to them, because I love helping you and I sure love helping your friends, as well.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharing referrals is a great way to build our business. It’s what we do—we help people and build relationships. &lt;strong&gt;Make sure to gather the information of the referring person;&lt;/strong&gt; we’re not going to bug them. We’re just going to gently reach out and let them know that we heard they were looking for real estate help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to reach out to me. I’m happy to give you advice on how to improve your practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 11:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-teaching-others-how-to-refer-your-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-teaching-others-how-to-refer-your-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>#JustJennie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Being Accountable is the Key to Success</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cv6mwdaF75s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accountability is an essential quality for any successful real estate agent.
Take it from my friend, Ricky Cain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m at the Keller Williams Realty Southwest market center with Ricky Cain of The Cain Team of Austin. Today, Ricky is going to talk with us about being accountable as an agent. Accountability is the most important thing you can do to ensure your success, Ricky says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts by being accountable to a time-blocked schedule. &lt;strong&gt;That way, you can accomplish the things that you need to get done when you need to get them done.&lt;/strong&gt; If it’s not in your schedule, it doesn’t exist. That’s a big BOLD principle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to being accountable to your schedule, you need to be accountable to your goals. Break them down to weekly and monthly goals, starting with a “1-3-5” or a “GPS” where you are breaking down the one thing that you absolutely have to accomplish this year that will make it the best year you ever had, then breaking it down to those three primary actions and five secondary actions within those primary actions that you intend on completing. Then, create a 4-1-1 plan that incorporates your 1-3-5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=ACCOUNTABILITY IS THE MOST IMPORTANT TOOL FOR YOUR SUCCESS.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-how-to-hold-yourself-accountable.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“ACCOUNTABILITY IS THE MOST IMPORTANT TOOL FOR YOUR SUCCESS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That all sounds easy and good, but who is going to hold you accountable to staying on track?&lt;/strong&gt; For us, it’s our MAPS coaches, our family, and ourselves. You need all three to maximize your productivity. It’s better to stick to a plan and have your goals exceeded than try to fit everything else in on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This information all comes from “The One Thing” by Gary Keller. If you haven’t read it yet, stop what you’re doing and read it now. They also have some great podcast and webinars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Rick for joining us today. If you need any help in Austin, send him an email to Ricky@TheCainTeam.com. If you need anything else, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 10:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-how-to-hold-yourself-accountable.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-how-to-hold-yourself-accountable.html</guid>
        
        <category>#JustJennie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Removing Limiting Beliefs Can Change Your Life</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zdNeHzYB6Mw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By removing limiting beliefs, just like I did, you can live your life more productively and more fiercely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every single day, we make choices about what we’ll allow into our brains, what we absorb, and how we’ll react to life. When it comes to these choices, it’s important that we remove limiting beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember that my mind first expanded and adopted this concept back in 2010 at a BOLD class when I started thinking about the possibilities of living a life by design instead of default. That’s when I started thinking about life in terms of “I can,” and “I am,” and I started having daily positive affirmations to feed myself positive vibes and thoughts that allowed me to currently live more productively and more fearlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that, I had limiting beliefs about myself—either because I didn’t have the same experience as other agents, the same amount of money as them, or that certain “thing” that allowed them to be confident. I just didn’t feel the same thing inside me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember thinking the same thought so many other agents have every single day: I don’t want to bug them. &lt;strong&gt;Shifting my mind from “I don’t want to bug them” to “I’m really great at helping people—how many people do I get to help today?” changed everything for me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DO WHATEVER YOU HAVE TO DO DAILY TO REMOVE YOUR LIMITING BELIEFS.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-remove-limiting-beliefs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DO WHATEVER YOU HAVE TO DO DAILY TO REMOVE YOUR LIMITING BELIEFS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At my first BOLD class, I remember that the thought of talking to 20 people in a single day physically made me want to vomit. That’s because I was living in fear of what they might think about me or how I might be intruding on their day. Then I realized that after I connected with them, they were happy to hear from me! If they weren’t, that was OK too. That’s none of my business, and they don’t know me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you switch your thinking to “I don’t want to bug them” to “I’m great at helping people,” I promise you’ll be able to remove your limiting beliefs, at least in regards to helping people. After all, we’re in the business of helping people—the relationship-building business. If you don’t have relationships, you don’t have a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do whatever you have to do on a daily basis to remove your limiting beliefs,&lt;/strong&gt; whether it’s positive affirmations, journaling the things you’re good at, etc. Have accountability around those things as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about limiting beliefs our you’d like to talk with me about any “drunk monkeys” that get in your way, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 12:59:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-remove-limiting-beliefs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-remove-limiting-beliefs.html</guid>
        
        <category>#JustJennie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Are All Successful Agents Learning-Based?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XNSgl7KgbLU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s always more to learn as a real estate agent. Here are just a few examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to be joined today by my amazing friend, Jessica Starr, a Keller Williams agent out of Connecticut and Lower Massachusetts. I talked to her a little bit about why being learning-based is so important as an agent, as well as about some of the different trainings and learning opportunities that KW offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica’s favorite course is probably BOLD, judging by the fact that she’s taken it a dozen times. There are so many different opportunities out there for KW agents, though, that &lt;strong&gt;Jessica says you should start building a plan for all the events you want to attend in December or January.&lt;/strong&gt; Take a look at the training calendars in your office, then determine which ones you want to attend. Jessica advises booking KW Family Reunion and Mega Camp first. A few other courses that Jessica recommends are Quantum Leap and the Language of Sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=ALL SUCCESSFUL PEOPLE ARE LEARNING-BASED.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-the-benefits-of-being-a-learning-based-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“ALL SUCCESSFUL PEOPLE ARE LEARNING-BASED.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also make it a point to attend a few masterminds. They can be a game changer. &lt;strong&gt;When you’re working with people who are doing things at a high level, the conversations and relationships you build are huge and can help you out for the rest of your career.&lt;/strong&gt; Even though it’s a cost to attend, the referrals alone that you’ll get from other agents make it worth the price of admission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that all successful people are learning-based. Jessica and I actually filmed the video above at a Mastermind event in Chicago. If you or someone you know needs real estate assistance in Connecticut or Massachusetts, give her a call at (860) 761-3765 or send her an email to StarrRealtyGroup@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for me about your real estate career, give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 13:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-the-benefits-of-being-a-learning-based-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-the-benefits-of-being-a-learning-based-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>#JustJennie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Going From E to P Can Help You Burst Through Your Ceiling of Achievement</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/95OZodJH6wU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going from E to P changed Scott Klaas’ life for the better, and it can do the same for you.
Here’s how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at my latest mastermind trip, we’ve been talking about Keller Williams’ six personal perspectives. One of those perspectives I want to share with you is going from E to P, and I’m happy to be joined by fellow agent Scott Klaas from Wisconsin and have him explain how this perspective had a positive impact on him and his business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The E in this perspective means “entrepreneurial.” Your natural ability, energy level, and anything else you can naturally do has a ceiling of achievement, and &lt;strong&gt;the only way to bust through that ceiling of achievement is to go to P, which means “purposeful.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing that for the first time changed Scott’s life. Now everything he does has to have a system, a model, and it has to have leverage behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Those three things will break you through your ceiling of achievement,” he says. “And then that ceiling will become your new floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WHEN YOU KEEP BUSTING YOUR HEAD AGAINST THE CEILING, YOU NEED MORE LEVERAGE AND BETTER SYSTEMS AND MODELS.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-going-from-e-to-p-with-scott-klaas.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WHEN YOU KEEP BUSTING YOUR HEAD AGAINST THE CEILING, YOU NEED MORE LEVERAGE AND BETTER SYSTEMS AND MODELS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, you can move toward your next level of achievement. When you keep busting your head against the ceiling, you need more leverage and better systems and models. From there, you can keep going up and up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some ways to increase your ceiling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Scott, going from E to P is about having a better life. He was working nonstop 16- and 18-hour days with 10 to 20 deals always under contract. He was always dealing with something wrong, or some headache, or always putting out fires, and he was never present anywhere. &lt;strong&gt;When you get purposeful, you have other people take some of those responsibilities, and you time block extremely well. It frees up your nights and weekends and helps every area of your life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to get in touch with Scott or you’d like to send a referral his way, you can reach him on Facebook, call him at (414) 795-6675, or send him an email at sklaas@kw.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 13:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-going-from-e-to-p-with-scott-klaas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-going-from-e-to-p-with-scott-klaas.html</guid>
        
        <category>#JustJennie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prioritizing Your Time to Maximize Your Outcomes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m6RJrB1EhQE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the 80/20 principle, we can ensure that we’re prioritizing our time to be sure that our money-producing activities are handled before everything else, which sets us up for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to continue my discussion of the six personal perspectives by focusing on another of them: the 80/20 principle. It shows up time and time again in our lives and in our businesses, and I really believe that there’s so much truth behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pareto’s principle states that 20% of our activities will produce 80% of our results.&lt;/strong&gt; Simply put, not everything we do is equally as important. Because others have gone before us and done the research, we know that we need to &lt;strong&gt;do our most dollar-productive activities in the morning&lt;/strong&gt; to make sure those things get done because that will help determine our success in our business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate agents and salespeople of any kind all have the same job descriptions:
• Lead generation
• Lead follow-up
• Go on appointments and negotiate contracts
• Practice and roleplay&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually reword these and put them in the order of how my day usually goes. So instead, I would say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• 8:30 a.m.—Practice and roleplay
• 9:00 a.m. to 11 a.m.—Lead generate
• 11 a.m. to noon—Lead follow-up
• Afternoon—Go to appointments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=PARETO’S PRINCIPLE STATES THAT 20% OF OUR ACTIVITIES WILL PRODUCE 80% OF OUR RESULTS.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-the-80-20-principle-use-this-principle-to-change-your-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“PARETO’S PRINCIPLE STATES THAT 20% OF OUR ACTIVITIES WILL PRODUCE 80% OF OUR RESULTS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s crazy how this works and when you set accountability around it, it starts showing up, and your perfect calendar does start to come true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 2015, I took BOLD four times in a row. I did that because I knew I had to get into action and get things back on track for my business and for my team. During that time, I had five different role play partners, with a different partner to work with at 8:30 a.m. every morning in a different city. &lt;strong&gt;That really helped increase my ability to talk better, know my scripts, be better at objection handlers, and it’s also a great way to connect with agents across the country.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After practice and roleplay, I would go into my 9 a.m. to 11 a.m. lead generation. Early on with the new coach that I had, he required that I send him a text every morning at 9 a.m. when I got into my database. By sending that text every morning, I was certain to open my database to see who I needed to call to get into action and get busy. That one little text I sent every morning has changed my business over the past couple years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think about what you are spending your time on all day long.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re still a single agent, that’s super great—just make sure you’re doing your most dollar-productive activities in the morning. Everything else like setting appointments, making flyers, and doing inspections can all be done in the afternoon, after you’ve ensured that your money-making activities have been taken care of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know how you focus on your 20%; I’d love to hear about it. For any other questions, feel free to contact me by phone or email. Have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 09:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-the-80-20-principle-use-this-principle-to-change-your-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-the-80-20-principle-use-this-principle-to-change-your-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>#JustJennie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Adding Value to Your Own Life?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/y_iJ6I2seGI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are your schedule and general thought-process adding value to your life?
If not, switch things up so that they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about self-mastery. It’s one of the Six Personal Perspectives that Gary Keller, Co-Founder &amp;amp; Chairman of the Board for Keller Williams Realty, wrote about in his NY Times Best Seller, The Millionaire Real Estate Agent. &lt;strong&gt;He discovered that the most successful real estate agents have a similar mindset when it comes to success&lt;/strong&gt; and boiled this mindset down to six fundamental perspectives that are at the core of Keller Williams Realty’s education for its agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self Mastery is the mindset, process, and habits associated with making sound decisions for desired results &amp;amp; self growth. It’s the self control that comes from having a clear vision &amp;amp; the determination to see it physically manifest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, it’s “KAIZEN” a Japanese term and philosophy meaning “continuous improvement” or “change for better.” You’ve mastered “Self” when your thoughts, words, actions, and reactions all align with your goals/mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-mastery is to continue to work on, and ultimately master, you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about scenarios from my own life and business that I could share with you to help you understand what I mean. One of the things I’ve done for myself is created a habit of getting up early and having “me time” while exercising on the treadmill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was using that 30 minutes of walking on the treadmill in the morning to watch Netflix and TV series from Amazon Video that I normally never watched. It was just guilty-pleasure time, and I think it’s important to have that. However, I was noticing that I was filling my brain with silly stuff&lt;strong&gt;—things that didn’t matter or add value to my life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=SELF-MASTERY IS TO CONTINUE TO WORK ON, AND ULTIMATELY MASTER, YOU.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-self-mastery-is-the-path-to-growth.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“SELF-MASTERY IS TO CONTINUE TO WORK ON, AND ULTIMATELY MASTER, YOU.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I switched that routine. Instead of mindless shows, I started listening to audiobooks about growth, mindset, and leadership, or else inspirational and motivational videos with John Maxwell or Tony Robbins—anything that could add value to my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying that you shouldn’t take time for yourself and do some of those guilty-pleasure things, because those are fun and enjoyable as well. I just had found that I wasn’t growing. And by listening to these different thoughts on leadership, business, and life balance, I was able to trigger thoughts in my own mind that &lt;strong&gt;inspired me to think of new ways and ideas to better my family, business, friends, and community.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do these little things that tweak your mind and your schedule to where you’re adding some value to yourself so that you can continue to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know how you work on your self-mastery, and I can in return share some more ways to grow through this practice. Life is a journey; we’re continuing to grow every single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this or other topics, please feel free to reach out to us. Make it a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 09:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-self-mastery-is-the-path-to-growth.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-self-mastery-is-the-path-to-growth.html</guid>
        
        <category>#JustJennie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Better Way to Handle Your Buyer Listings</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rZgr00y_U9I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been able to do a much better job of handling our buyers
by adding one simple tool to our business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to share something cool with you. It’s a system our team uses for buyer listings that was developed by my friend Brian Inskip. It’s called My Buyer Listing. Essentially, it’s a website where you can post your buyer listing information and have a system behind it and a plan for how to share the listing with your network and your neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of us post seller listings all the time and share them with our networks. &lt;strong&gt;Why not do the same thing with our buyer listings?&lt;/strong&gt; I like to think of it as a dating game for houses. Maybe a homeowner isn’t thinking about selling until they see that there is a buyer on this site that is clearly looking for a home like theirs. Wouldn’t that be cool to match up with a buyer or seller in advance and not even have to list the home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IT’S LIKE A DATING GAME FOR HOUSES.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-how-do-you-treat-your-buyer-listings.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IT’S LIKE A DATING GAME FOR HOUSES.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to share this tool with you to help you get in front of more buyers. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 12:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-how-do-you-treat-your-buyer-listings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-how-do-you-treat-your-buyer-listings.html</guid>
        
        <category>#JustJennie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Gift of Giving</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DRftVyDZWJs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put it in your business plan for 2018 to give back to your community. We have some ideas about how you can do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to talk with you about giving—giving back to your community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving is awesome, and it feels great. &lt;strong&gt;Make sure you have it in your budget and your business plan for 2018 to be able to give back to your community.&lt;/strong&gt; The following are some ways that we like to give back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013, devastating tornadoes hit our neighbors in Moore, Oklahoma. They hit so close to home that at that point in May, &lt;strong&gt;we chose to, as a team, donate $100 of all the rest of our closings that year back to the relief efforts in that area,&lt;/strong&gt; including the food bank, the Salvation Army, United Way, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That felt really good; we got to give back about $4,000, which really makes a difference. As a team, we chose to continue with that feeling of giving and charity. &lt;strong&gt;Since then, for every closing that we have, we call up our client after closing and thank them so much for allowing us to help them choose which organizations we can give to in their name.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WHEN PEOPLE GIVE, IT MAKES THEM FEEL GOOD, AND THEN WE ALL FEEL GOOD.%20localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-giving-back-feels-great.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WHEN PEOPLE GIVE, IT MAKES THEM FEEL GOOD, AND THEN WE ALL FEEL GOOD.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, those are the best conversations ever. &lt;strong&gt;When people give, it makes them feel good, and then we all feel good.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way we give as a team is on our green sheets. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re with Keller Williams Realty, we have distribution authorizations that pull donations out of our money at closing automatically.&lt;/strong&gt; Our team gives to the Keller Williams Kids Can organization, as well as KW Cares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget that there are ways to give that are mindless and easy, and just feel great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know what ideas you come up with! I’d love to hear other ways that you’re giving. And guess what? If you already have this in your budget, when disaster strikes our country, you’ll be able to be first on call to give back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 13:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-giving-back-feels-great.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-giving-back-feels-great.html</guid>
        
        <category>#JustJennie</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
