<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>American Mortgage Group</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from American Mortgage Group - your professional San Diego Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://abeltejeda.blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 11:26:36 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 11:26:36 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Fall for These 5 Mortgage Misconceptions</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1RK__I2uV48?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homebuyers: there are five big mortgage misconceptions that could lead you astray if you believe them. Today I’ll name them and discuss the actual truth behind them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. You’ll get the best rate with your current bank.&lt;/strong&gt; Some banks offer discounts to their clients, but that’s not usually the case. You’re always better off shopping around and talking to different lenders so you can compare both the best rates and overall cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. You can’t get a mortgage loan for less than 20% down.&lt;/strong&gt; In reality, there are several mortgage loans you can get for less than 20% down. The FHA first-time homebuyer program, for instance, allows you to secure a loan for just 3.5% down. Additionally, conventional loans allow you to put down any amount less than 20%. Keep in mind, though, that if you put down less than 20%, you’ll have to pay mortgage insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You can only refinance your home loan once every 12 months.&lt;/strong&gt; Actually, you can refinance your home loan whenever you want. As a rule of thumb, though, you should only refinance when you can recover the cost of that refinance within two years or you can lower your rate by 1%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Credit shouldn’t stop you from buying a house.%20http://abeltejeda.blog/dont-fall-for-these-5-mortgage-misconceptions.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Credit shouldn’t stop you from buying a house.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. You need excellent credit to buy a house.&lt;/strong&gt; There are programs you can use that allow you to buy a home with a FICO score as low as 580. Remember, the beauty of credit is you can fix it right away. Our team offers free credit counseling, so if your credit score isn’t where you’d like it to be, we’d be happy to sit down with you and talk about what you need to do to raise it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. You can’t buy a house if you had a bankruptcy, short sale, or foreclosure.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, there are several programs that allow you to do just that. An FHA loan, for example, will allow you to buy a home within two years of your bankruptcy discharge, and conventional loans allow you to buy within four years after a foreclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what your situation, your best course of action is to talk to a mortgage professional such as myself so we can go over what you need to do to buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other mortgage questions or there’s anything else I can help you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 10:48:15 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/dont-fall-for-these-5-mortgage-misconceptions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abeltejeda.blog/dont-fall-for-these-5-mortgage-misconceptions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Finance Advice</category>
        
        <category>Home Loans</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Documents You’ll Need in Order to Get Pre-Qualified</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/M8NeJ9VIUjc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to provide you with a list of documents you’ll be required to have in order to get pre-qualified for a home loan if you’re going FHA, VA, or if you’re self-employed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With both FHA and conventional loans, you’ll need the same documents:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The two most recent pay stubs for both the main borrower and the co-borrower if there is one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tax returns for the past two years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two recent bank statements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A copy of your driver’s license&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A copy of your social security card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re in the military or are a veteran and you qualify for a VA loan, the documents you’ll need are slightly different:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your latest Leave and Earnings Statement (if you’re active duty)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your certificate of eligibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your tax returns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your most recent bank statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Remember that the first step in the home buying process to get pre-qualified—don’t start by looking at homes or going to open houses.%20http://abeltejeda.blog/the-documents-youll-need-in-order-to-get-pre-qualified.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Remember that the first step in the home buying process to get pre-qualified—don’t start by looking at homes or going to open houses.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re self-employed, there are two different options:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two years of tax returns, which allows us to base your income on how much you declare as profit at the end of the year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bank statements from the last 24 months, which allows us to determine your income based on the deposits you’ve made in the last two years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know the documents needed, what do you do with them? Well, we can set up an appointment where we’ll sit down face-to-face, or you can email or fax the documents to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that the first step in the home buying process to get pre-qualified—don’t start by looking at homes or going to open houses. You first need to determine what is the maximum amount you’d qualify for, what your options are, and how much your monthly payments would be at different price points. You only want to be looking at houses you can afford, and the only way to do that is to get pre-qualified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like to set up an appointment with me, please feel free to reach out. I’d love to discuss your situation and see how we can help you move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 09:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/the-documents-youll-need-in-order-to-get-pre-qualified.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abeltejeda.blog/the-documents-youll-need-in-order-to-get-pre-qualified.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Loans</category>
        
        <category>Finance Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Few Different Ways to Tap Into Your Home’s Equity</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cWCgoldBSpg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many different ways to tap into the equity of your home. We’re going to break it down for you today, whether you have VA, FHA, or conventional financing. &lt;strong&gt;We’ll also tell you how to cash into your equity without having to refinance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s talk about cashing out with a VA loan. A huge advantage of having a VA loan is that you are able to cash out up to 100% of your equity without having to pay taxes on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re self-employed, it doesn’t matter what type of loan you had in the past. With the new loans we have available, we can use your bank statements to qualify instead of having to use your tax returns. This lets you tap into that equity. &lt;strong&gt;You used to have to wait to cash out on that equity until you sell, but today we can help you cash out up to 90% loan-to-value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=VA homebuyers can cash out up to 100% of their equity.%20http://abeltejeda.blog/a-few-different-ways-to-tap-into-your-homes-equity.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“VA homebuyers can cash out up to 100% of their equity.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things you can do with an FHA loan. Once you start to build equity, you can get rid of mortgage insurance by tapping into it. Even though you are increasing your loan amount by cashing out, you are reducing your payment by removing the mortgage insurance. &lt;strong&gt;At the end of the day, even though you’re cashing out, you’ll end up saving money on your payment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, our bonus tip. How can you tap into the equity of your home and cash out without refinancing? The answer is simple. Take a home equity line of credit, or HELOC, out on your property. If you have a really good rate, you don’t even have to touch that loan. &lt;strong&gt;You can get a HELOC for whatever amount you need while keeping your loan payment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision of whether to refinance or get a second mortgage depends on a number of factors, including your rate and your credit, but the best thing for you to do to start the process is message me. If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 13:35:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/a-few-different-ways-to-tap-into-your-homes-equity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abeltejeda.blog/a-few-different-ways-to-tap-into-your-homes-equity.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Equity</category>
        
        <category>Finance Advice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are San Diego and Temecula in a Housing Bubble?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HS5RP0_qMQc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am going to discuss a couple questions that my clients keep asking me: Are we in a housing bubble? Will there be a downturn in home value prices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The economy is extremely strong in San Diego and Temecula and we are not following the same pattern of oversupply that we did in 2007. In fact, we are two years behind on new home construction and that is actually causing home prices to continue to rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think you can just wait for home prices to drop, you are in for a rude awakening. The only thing that can stop this rise in prices is interest rates. For the past seven quarters, interest rates have been going up. Every 1% increase in rates decreases your purchasing power by 10%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean if you are a buyer or a seller? Well, first of all, while I am not a real estate agent, I see the patterns since I lived through what happened in 2007. &lt;strong&gt;If you are looking to buy, go ahead and buy.&lt;/strong&gt; If interest rates and home prices both continue to increase, you are going to be priced out of the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you think you that you are just going to wait for home prices to drop, you are in for a rude awakening.%20http://abeltejeda.blog/are-san-diego-and-temecula-in-a-housing-bubble.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you think you that you are just going to wait for home prices to drop, you are in for a rude awakening.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are a seller and you are trying to time the market so you sell at the peak, I would advise that you sell now instead.&lt;/strong&gt; It is a really good time to sell and you never know what is going to happen to property prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So are Temecula and San Diego in a housing bubble? No— not even close. We are not even close to a housing bubble. Especially since we still have the huge problem of a lack of inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/are-san-diego-and-temecula-in-a-housing-bubble.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abeltejeda.blog/are-san-diego-and-temecula-in-a-housing-bubble.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Purchase</category>
        
        <category>Interest Rates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Our Awesome New Loan Program</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FaWaWjMP8_4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a real estate agent, an insurance agent, self-employed, or own your own business and haven’t been able to buy a house or refinance your current loan because of how much money you declare, then today’s topic is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like there are new programs and guidelines being introduced to the market almost every day, and that’s great news for you. In the past, if you were self-employed, the only way to show your income and be able to qualify for a home purchase (or to be able to refinance your property) &lt;strong&gt;was to show your past two years of tax returns.&lt;/strong&gt; We would then take the average of those 24 months and come up with your income; these are, after all, your expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This created a huge problem.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, say you’re a trucker who makes $200,000 a year, but after depreciating your truck, paying for gas and meals, you would only end up with, say, $40,000. That means we would only use $40,000 to help you qualify for a home purchase. Now, with the way that the real estate market is—especially here in San Diego—there’s not much you can qualify for. That’s why the new self-employed program, which is based on bank statements, was introduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We don’t take your expenses or business deductions into account, just a percentage of your deposits.%20http://abeltejeda.blog/the-benefits-of-our-awesome-new-loan-program.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We don’t take your expenses or business deductions into account, just a percentage of your deposits.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s so special about our self-employed loan?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, &lt;strong&gt;it’s not based on taxes.&lt;/strong&gt; We base your qualification on your deposits using your bank statements. Say that you get $20,000 a month—we use the average from 24 months, 12 months, or even just one month, depending on the program you qualify for. We don’t take your expenses or business deductions into account, just a percentage of your deposits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing about this loan is that &lt;strong&gt;you can come in with only 10% down, and you don’t need perfect credit.&lt;/strong&gt; The loan can also go up to $2 million, and the debt-to-income ratio is higher than traditional loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one of our newest home loans that we’ve rolled out, and we’ll have new ones coming out in the the next couple of weeks, to be discussed in future posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know someone needs a home loan to purchase a property, needs to refinance, or has any questions, you are absolutely encouraged to reach out to us. I’ll be sure to take care of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 12:46:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/the-benefits-of-our-awesome-new-loan-program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abeltejeda.blog/the-benefits-of-our-awesome-new-loan-program.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>All of Your Questions About VA Eligibility, Answered</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/G06sUYZrRDo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;People have approached me with a number of great questions about VA loan eligibility, so today I would like to highlight and address some of the things I’m most frequently asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“How do you get a VA loan?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; As simple as this question sounds, many people don’t know where to start this process. To get a VA loan, you’ll need to visit a financial institution, like a bank, or a direct lender that is qualified to handle VA loans. We at American Mortgage Group would be happy to assist you in this pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“What determines how much you can borrow from the VA?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Certificate of Eligibility (COE) will tell you how much you can borrow from the VA. A COE can be obtained directly from the VA or from your lender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“What qualifies as acceptable proof of military service?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to this question will actually vary depending on whether you are a veteran or are still active duty. Active duty military personnel will need to present a Statement of Service. Veterans, though, will need to present a DD 214.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Can you still obtain a VA loan if you are unable to present a Statement of Service or DD 214?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, yes. Another way to obtain a COE (and a VA loan) is to fill out a VA Form 26-1880. This will allow your lender to gather military records and determine how much you qualify for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Can you have a cosigner on a home purchase you’re financing with a VA loan?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a cosigner help you purchase a home when using a VA loan is acceptable, but the cosigner must be your legal spouse. You may have other people on the title of the property, but not on the VA loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can rest assured that when you purchase a home using a VA loan, you will be paying a fair price.%20http://abeltejeda.blog/all-of-your-questions-about-va-eligibility-answered.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can rest assured that when you purchase a home using a VA loan, you will be paying a fair price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“If someone already has a VA loan, can they get another one?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, but the amount you will qualify for depends on how much entitlement you have left after your previous purchase. Your COE will indicate this amount. Also, eligibility can be restored if the previously purchased home has been sold. A lot of people think they can only have one VA loan at a time, but this is not correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Can you get a VA loan if you had a bankruptcy in the past?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. It will need to be determined whether your bankruptcy was a Chapter 7 or a Chapter 13, though, because these will each be handled differently. More than anything, the most significant thing you will need to do is sit down and have a conversation about your current financial standing. And you will want to pay special attention to your FICO score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With these common questions out of the way, there is one more common concern I’d like to touch on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people fear that they will overpay for a home when making a purchase with VA loan financing. However, the VA appraisal process won’t allow you to do so. There are certain codes and conditions a property must meet to qualify for VA financing in the first place. You can rest assured that when you purchase a home using a VA loan, you will be paying a fair price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:19:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/all-of-your-questions-about-va-eligibility-answered.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abeltejeda.blog/all-of-your-questions-about-va-eligibility-answered.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Things First-Time Homebuyers Need When Purchasing a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/q9ug-W5jxY0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a first-time homebuyer, what’s required of you when purchasing a home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like most first-time homebuyers, you pretty much have three mortgage loan options to choose from: VA, FHA, and conventional. If you’re not a veteran or currently in the military, a VA loan doesn’t apply to you. As for FHA and conventional loans, there are three requirements that come with qualifying for these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is your &lt;strong&gt;credit&lt;/strong&gt;, and the difference with this factor between an FHA and a conventional loan is huge. With an FHA loan, you can qualify with a score as low as 580. With a conventional loan, it can depend on which program you choose and what payment you come in with. Even if your credit is not where it needs to be in order to purchase a home, that can be fixed. We have credit repair companies we partner with who we can refer you to, and we can also give you in-house credit counseling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second requirement is the &lt;strong&gt;down payment&lt;/strong&gt;. As with your credit, there’s a huge difference between an FHA loan and a conventional loan in terms of what you have to put down. With an FHA loan, you can go as low as no money down. There are plenty of down payment assistance programs out there, but you have to determine whether that’s something that’s conducive to your situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FHA program for first-time homebuyers only requires you to put down 3.5% of the purchase price, which translates into $3,500 for every $100,000. Keep in mind, you can tap into your 401(k), IRA, or retirement plan to pay for that down payment—it doesn’t have to be paid for with money you currently have in your bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a conventional loan, you can go anywhere from 3% down to 30% down. Many people assume that conventional loans require you to put down 20%, but that’s not true. However, if you don’t put at least 20% down, you’ll have to pay private mortgage insurance (or PMI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you meet these three requirements, there’s no reason you shouldn’t get approved for a loan.%20http://abeltejeda.blog/3-things-first-time-homebuyers-need-when-purchasing-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you meet these three requirements, there’s no reason you shouldn’t get approved for a loan.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third and final requirement is your &lt;strong&gt;income.&lt;/strong&gt; When it comes to this factor, you need to be employed within the same industry over at least the last two years. This doesn’t mean you have to be with the same employer, though. This comes into play once we start talking about your debt-to-income ratio (DTI). Again, there’s a big difference here between a conventional loan and an FHA loan, and you need to know your DTI to determine which route to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The situation is slightly different if you’re self-employed.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a lot of compensating factors, we can potentially take only one year’s worth of taxes. There are several loan programs for self-employed individuals that don’t require two years’ worth of taxes. Your loan can also be done with only bank statements, and that’s important because it means you don’t have to declare huge amounts to be able to qualify, and you only need one month’s worth of bank statements to determine where your income is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you meet these three requirements, there’s no reason you shouldn’t get approved for a loan.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about this topic or you’re thinking about buying a house, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 12:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/3-things-first-time-homebuyers-need-when-purchasing-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abeltejeda.blog/3-things-first-time-homebuyers-need-when-purchasing-a-home.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Ways to Pay Down Your Mortgage Faster</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nk94u-_LDEA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are like most people, you have a 30-year mortgage on your home to pay off. That might seem like an eternity, but there are a couple of different strategies that you can use to pay off that mortgage early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What most people are unaware of is that when you do get a mortgage, most of your interest is charged upfront.&lt;/strong&gt; Banks are in the business of making money, so they want to make sure they get their money upfront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first 18.5 years of that 30-year term, you’ll be paying more in interest than on the principal loan amount. When the average homeowner sells after seven years, they don’t even get to the portion where they’re actually knocking down the principle. Here are a few ways to pay off your 30-year mortgage a little sooner without a ton of extra effort:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Get a 15-year mortgage and a lower interest rate.&lt;/strong&gt; When you get a 15-year loan as opposed to a 30-year loan, you tend to get a lower rate. You also have less to pay in interest on the loan. At the end of the day, you end up saving thousands in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Making bi-weekly payments.&lt;/strong&gt; Grab your mortgage payment and look at the payment breakdown. Instead of making, one $1,000 payment, for example, you make two $500 payments each month. When you do this, you end up making 26 mortgage payments a year. That equates to 13 monthly payments instead of 12 without you even noticing. This will save you eight years of payments, on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The best strategy is whichever one fits your lifestyle and budget.%20http://abeltejeda.blog/4-ways-to-pay-down-your-mortgage-faster.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The best strategy is whichever one fits your lifestyle and budget.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Making an additional mortgage payment.&lt;/strong&gt; If you get a big tax refund or bonus at work, think about making an additional mortgage payment instead of going on a vacation or buying a new car. Make sure you note that the payment “Be applied directly toward the principle.” That will help you knock years off of your loan term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Refinancing for a lower rate or to remove mortgage insurance.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a $1500 payment and it goes down to $1,300 with a refinance, that’s $2,400 per year you’re saving. However, If you keep making the same payment of $1,500 after you refinance, you can pay down your mortgage much quicker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which strategy is the best? &lt;strong&gt;Whichever one fits your lifestyle and budget.&lt;/strong&gt; What is good for you is not necessarily good for your neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or want my help with this, please give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 13:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/4-ways-to-pay-down-your-mortgage-faster.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abeltejeda.blog/4-ways-to-pay-down-your-mortgage-faster.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 2 Most Popular Loan Programs for First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uw_0LEsCsxA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many different loan programs available for first-time-homebuyers (or homebuyers in general), but the two most popular that I want to talk about today are the FHA loan and the conventional loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the FHA loan. &lt;strong&gt;This loan allows you to purchase a property with a down payment of just 3.5%.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s equivalent to paying $3,500 for every $100,000 the home is worth. A $400,000 property, for example, would only require a down payment of $14,000. That’s an awesome deal! The FHA loan is also a government-secured loan, but the best thing about it is you can qualify for it with a FICO score as low as 580.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FHA loan does have its drawbacks, however. Since you’re not putting at least 20% down for it, you have to pay mortgage insurance. At the end of the day, though, the important thing is it allows you to buy a home without a large down payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Remember, these loans aren’t one-size-fits-all.%20http://abeltejeda.blog/the-2-most-popular-loan-programs-for-first-time-homebuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Remember, these loans aren’t one-size-fits-all.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conventional loan is the second-most popular among first-time homebuyers. People with high credit scores and a higher income make up the majority of those who qualify for a conventional loan. Unlike FHA loans, conventional loans are credit-driven. This means the higher your credit score is when applying for it, the lower your interest rate will be. Additionally, conventional loans aren’t as lenient as FHA loans when it comes to a person’s debt-to-income ratio. &lt;strong&gt;If you have an excellent credit score and you make good money, this might be a better option for you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A conventional loan allows a down payment as low as 3%, but as with an FHA loan, you’ll still be stuck having to pay mortgage insurance. The main difference between these two scenarios is that with an FHA loan, you have to pay that mortgage insurance until you refinance your loan. With a conventional loan, once your property appreciates to a 70% loan-to-value ratio, you can do a drive-by appraisal or simply contact your mortgage insurance company and have your mortgage insurance removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An FHA loan is a better option if your resources are limited or you have a low credit score,&lt;/strong&gt; but it’s not designed for you to keep it over a period of 30 years—it’s designed to get you into a house. Once that property appreciates, the smart move would be to refinance out of the FHA loan and into a conventional loan so you can get rid of your mortgage insurance and have a lower payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, these loans aren’t one-size-fits-all. If you have any more questions about which one is best for you, give us a call so we can determine where you stand and what you need to do to qualify for either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other mortgage questions, don’t hesitate to reach out. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/the-2-most-popular-loan-programs-for-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abeltejeda.blog/the-2-most-popular-loan-programs-for-first-time-homebuyers.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do VA Loans Work?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gynUOclRis8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often get questions about how VA loans work and what it takes to obtain one. The very first thing I’ll touch on is the VA lending limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The VA only allows you to borrow up to a certain amount. This amount will vary by county. In San Diego County, for example, you can borrow up to $649,750 for a single-family residence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important point to be aware of is the fact that &lt;strong&gt;there are different lending limits for single-family homes, duplexes, triplexes, and fourplexes.&lt;/strong&gt; In San Diego County, the VA lending limit is $831,800 for a duplex, $1,005,450 for a triplex, and $1,249,550 for a fourplex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Riverside, the VA lending limit is $453,100 for a single-family residence, $580,150 for a duplex, $701,250 for a triplex, and $871,450 for a fourplex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what happens if you want to purchase a home above the VA lending limit? You actually do still have options in this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can still purchase a home using a VA loan, even if that home is above the lending limit, so long as you pay 25% of the difference.&lt;/strong&gt; So if you want to purchase a $700,000 single-family home in San Diego, the $649,750 covered by the VA loan leaves a total difference of $50,250. Of that $50,250, you would only have to come up with $12,562.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, people also often ask me what kind of incomes qualify for VA loans. Well, if you’re active military, we can use every income source on your LES.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are no longer in the military or are retired, you can still use your current income so long as you have continued to do what you did while in the military. If in the military you were a mechanic and you are still working in that field, you can still use your new income to help you qualify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Remember that certain lending standards vary depending on county and income.%20http://abeltejeda.blog/how-do-va-loans-work.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Remember that certain lending standards vary depending on county and income.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, you cannot use your GI bill because that income won’t continue for three years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VA disability income, however, does qualify. In fact, you can use 120% of VA disability income toward a loan, and &lt;strong&gt;if you’re receiving at least 20% disability, you can have your VA funding fee waived.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some counties even offer property tax exemptions for veterans who are 100% disabled. This varies by county and depends on your income, so consult with your agent and your county recorder’s office for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this has answered some of your questions. Still, nothing compares to speaking with a lender about your specific circumstances. And to all veterans and active duty military members: Thank you for your service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 11:08:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/how-do-va-loans-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abeltejeda.blog/how-do-va-loans-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Loans</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
