<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cleveland's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Michael Kaim, a top Real Estate Agent in Cleveland, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 13:20:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 13:20:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Translate Your Schedule Into Success in Your Career</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4JLNgievmSw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One question that clients, friends, and other professionals in this industry always ask me is, “What does your typical day look like?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To tell the truth, the answer to this has not remained consistent over the years. My schedule has changed. So before I get into talking about where I am today, I’d like to discuss how I got here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of my career, I was up at 5 a.m. each morning. After spending one hour at the gym, I was in the office six days a week by 7:00 a.m. I had a 7:30 a.m. roleplaying call where I practiced my scripts, and then at 7:45 a.m. I would get on the phones to prospect for three to four hours straight. &lt;strong&gt;I was calling my sphere, prospecting FSBOs, reaching out to expired listings, and more.&lt;/strong&gt; This took me up until about lunch. I then prepared my afternoon schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, between 2 p.m. and 4 p.m., I would make phone calls and take care administrative work. If I had finished with that, I would work on following up with leads, instead. At last, I would end my day by scheduling appointments or doing more prospecting until 8 p.m. or 9 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My goal every day was to make between 50 and 75 contacts.&lt;/strong&gt; This was the schedule I had set for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since that time, I’ve had kids, I’ve built a team, and things have changed. Still, while my schedule may have been modified, this is still the same basic set of duties I work through each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Prospecting time is money time.%20localhost:4000/how-to-translate-your-schedule-into-success-in-your-career.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Prospecting time is money time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on the buyers’ side is a little different, though. That’s exactly why I’ve brought on Tina Hivnor to talk about her experience and schedule. One of the first things she emphasized was the importance of taking time off. And, according to her, this is something that holds true for buyer and seller agents alike. Our team likes to approach time off by looking at schedules a month at a time. &lt;strong&gt;We decide right away what time people will be taking off, so that everyone can “recharge their batteries” from time to time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, our team focuses more narrowly on what each week’s schedule will look like. We look at which days an agent will be in the office and which days will be marked off of their schedule. This way, appointments can be set with certainty and confidence. Our agents block off all the time they are not available so that they can be clear with their clients about when they are available. Our agents’ schedules are really formed around our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, of course, there’s also the matter of prospecting time. In Tina’s words, “Prospecting time is money time. This is the one block of time that if you ever erase it, you must replace it.” &lt;strong&gt;The reason that agents on our team are so successful is that they take the time to follow up&lt;/strong&gt; and make new contacts each and every day. My father used to say that if you did no prospecting in a day, you didn’t do any work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 06:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-translate-your-schedule-into-success-in-your-career.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-to-translate-your-schedule-into-success-in-your-career.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
