<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Real Estate in the Real World</title>
    <description>Jennie Wolek, a top Real Estate Agent in Tulsa, shares her own internal real estate agent training for free. Her Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://realestateintherealworld.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:31:59 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:31:59 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 5th and Final “S” of the Five-S Model: Sustain</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bGZSHKvER2M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s finally time to explore the fifth and final “S” of the Five-S model of customer experience: Sustain. At this point, you’ve set expectations, kept your clients updated along the way, you’ve surprised and delighted throughout the transaction, and now it’s over. &lt;strong&gt;Once you’ve done all of this, now it’s time to sustain the relationship in order to create a client for life. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to make them feel special, but it doesn’t require a ton of effort or planning. &lt;strong&gt;First off, make sure you call them a few days after closing to thank them for allowing you to help them.&lt;/strong&gt; This is also a surprise and a nice thing to do. It’s not a call for a referral; it’s purely a gratitude phone call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To properly sustain a relationship, you have to have a touch program in place.&lt;/strong&gt; If it’s already built out on your calendar, you won’t forget to keep those who are most important to you in the loop. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You have to have a touch program in place.%20https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-5th-and-final-s-of-the-five-s-model-sustain.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You have to have a touch program in place.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many people think that real estate agents are just money hungry. When you don’t call someone after closing or maintain your relationship with them, you’re essentially proving their point. I know that’s not who you are, so that’s why you need to take steps now to make sure you stay in touch with all of your clients in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let me know some of the ways that you stay in touch with past clients.&lt;/strong&gt; We use a lot of events and giveaways to increase engagement, but we’d love to hear about what you’re doing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-5th-and-final-s-of-the-five-s-model-sustain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-5th-and-final-s-of-the-five-s-model-sustain.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Five-S Model of Customer Experience: Surpass</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/w01tZO9N_Oc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest installment of our video series on the Five-S Model of customer experience, we’ll talk about the fourth S: &lt;strong&gt;surpass.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that the more I teach about customer experience, the more attuned to it I become as an observer—whether the experience was amazing or left much to be desired. In the real estate business, &lt;strong&gt;we should always be looking for ways that we can be better for our clients, &lt;/strong&gt;and the “surpass” component of the Five-S Model is an opportunity for us to surprise and delight them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides giving clients updates, checking in with them, asking for feedback, and satisfying all the basics of an overall great experience, it’s important to look for ways that we can go the extra mile and surpass expectations. As I travel around and meet with other agents, I continue to learn new ideas for doing this. Here’s one: &lt;strong&gt;As soon as your buyer or seller goes under contract, surprise them with a gift.&lt;/strong&gt; Perhaps you can deliver packing tape, champagne or wine, or some other small gesture that celebrates the occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The “surpass” component of the Five-S Model is an opportunity for us to surprise and delight our clients.%20https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-surpass.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The “surpass” component of the Five-S Model is an opportunity for us to surprise and delight our clients.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, rather than advising them to do this or that, &lt;strong&gt;look for opportunities to do certain things for your client.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, if the seller you’re representing is moving out of their home in the coming days, show them that you’re willing to go above and beyond by bringing in a professional carpet cleaner, mowing their lawn one last time, or helping to offset their costs if that’s part of your approach.   &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;your extra efforts should have the element of surprise and need to be carried out in a systematic, organized fashion.&lt;/strong&gt; The best way to do this is to set reminders so that no matter how busy you get in your life and career, you don’t forget this important part of bolstering your customers’ experience. Of course, just because you have a system, it doesn’t mean you can’t personalize your gifts as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t even have to reinvent the wheel. Whether it’s other real estate teams or leaders in entirely different industries like Nordstrom’s, Southwest, Disneyworld, or anyone you notice providing a world-class customer experience, there are other models out there that you can look to.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or if you’d like to share with me the unique ways in which you surprise and delight your clients, please give me a call at 918-706-9845 or send me an email at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#074;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#084;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#087;&amp;#111;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#107;&amp;#071;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#117;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#074;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#084;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#087;&amp;#111;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#107;&amp;#071;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#117;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-surpass.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-surpass.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rockstar Agent Haro Setian Shares His Secrets to Success</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KqgiuownMFI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the latest episode of Agent Success Secrets, I had the pleasure of speaking to Greenville, South Carolina Realtor Haro Setian. Haro came to Keller Williams in 2009, when the market was, of course, not in the best state. Despite entering the industry at a difficult time, Haro has absolutely thrived since then. Now, he’s going to explain how he did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;01:12 - Haro shares the story of how he got to where he is today&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;08:40 - How Haro finds agents who share his mission, vision, and values&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13:21 - Three mistakes Haro has learned from in order to “fail forward” in his career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20:19 - How Haro avoids “shiny objects” as a real estate professional&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21:59 - Haro shares what he thinks holds most agents back from achieving their potential&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;26:06 - Wrapping up our interview with one of Haro’s most difficult moments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30:01 - How you can get in touch with Haro&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give my team or me a call or send us an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/rockstar-agent-haro-setian-shares-his-secrets-to-success.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://realestateintherealworld.com/rockstar-agent-haro-setian-shares-his-secrets-to-success.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Five-S Model of Customer Experience: Survey</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QLcnzz_NBWI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another episode of “Your Journey with Jennie.” Today we’re continuing our look at the Five-S model of customer experience with the third “S”: Survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you have set up expectations with your clients and are in an agreement together, you’re going to survey with them along the way to figure out how you’re doing. &lt;strong&gt;This includes checking in with them and getting feedback.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re implementing “The Promise” into your business, this is going to be part of your plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we don’t ask, we don’t know and we won’t be able to correct any communication problems or errors to get better as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If we don’t ask, we don’t know.%20https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-survey.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If we don’t ask, we don’t know.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are plenty of different ways to survey.&lt;/strong&gt; One way is with a system to measure and survey your clients after closing. Another way is to use surveys and reviews online post-closing. This could be done through apps, websites, or you could create your own. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback is so important because you never want to assume how you did. You want others to tell you. &lt;strong&gt;If you do a great job and they leave a great review, that will attract even more business to you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about surveying or want to tell me about how you check this box in your business, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-survey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-survey.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Valuable Conversation With Wendy Papasan of Papasan Properties</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JPxF9odyU-Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s such an honor to have Wendy Papasan, owner of Papasan Properties, her with me again. We’ve gotten to know each other over the years, and I loved so much about her story. Wendy’s insight has so much value that can be shared with other agents across the country. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Wendy and I will chat about how she got into this business, what her team looks like, how much she produces, and much, much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For your convenience, I’ve cited timestamps below that will direct you to various points in the video above. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:48—Introducing Wendy and her team&lt;br /&gt;2:10—How do you grow your business as a mom, a spouse, and as a community-giver?&lt;br /&gt;4:41—The systems and models that Wendy followed to allow for this level of success&lt;br /&gt;5:55—Balancing motherhood and a career&lt;br /&gt;8:07—Wendy’s guide to time blocking&lt;br /&gt;11:40—What Wendy has learned from her failures &lt;br /&gt;14:41—Besides her family and her team, what else drives Wendy?&lt;br /&gt;17:42—Where Wendy learned that she loved to give back to the community&lt;br /&gt;20:00—What Wendy is most proud of&lt;br /&gt;22:03—How Wendy discovered her talent for empowering the leaders of her team&lt;br /&gt;24:11—Wrapping up our discussion&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you would like to contact Wendy, visit her website at &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://papasanproperties.com&quot;&gt;www.PapasanProperties.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, or else find her on Facebook and Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, I’d be delighted to hear from you. Don’t hesitate to give me a phone call or send me an email. Hope to hear from you soon!&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/a-valuable-conversation-with-wendy-papasan-of-papasan-properties.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://realestateintherealworld.com/a-valuable-conversation-with-wendy-papasan-of-papasan-properties.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Five-S  Model of Customer Experience: Serve</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XHD_vqcXyR0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to serve our clients?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means that whatever we told them we were going to do, we must do. People conduct business with people they trust, and it’s our job to make sure we live up to the way we present ourselves in our listing consultations or buyer presentations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, &lt;strong&gt;we must be the person we promised we would be.&lt;/strong&gt; If we don’t do something we said we would do, people lose trust in us. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are standards when it comes to building and maintaining communication, and these standards apply to our teams as well as our clients. What are your communication standards in terms of how often you reach out to your clients? It has to at least be weekly, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have to communicate with our clients in other ways, and this will be leveraged through technology. This can include your CRM and other client management systems that allow you to touch base with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If we don’t do something we said we would do, people lose trust in us.%20https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-serve.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If we don’t do something we said we would do, people lose trust in us.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you’ll leverage through people. Perhaps you have people on your team who’ll be in touch with your clients, so you want to make sure they’re properly set up and introduced to them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, you’ll leverage though your vendor partners. During the home buying or selling process, you’re working with other people who are actually a part of your team as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, &lt;strong&gt;there are four tips you need to remember to facilitate great communication with your clients:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell them what you’re going to do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask lots of questions and listen intently.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communicate with them weekly—I encourage this to be at least a phone call attempt. If they don’t answer, follow up with a text or email reiterating your message.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never put off bad news. No matter how bad it is, you have to get it over with, and if you have any part in this bad news, you have to own up to it and move forward. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this aspect of the Five-S  model of the customer experience, don’t hesitate to call or email me. In the meantime, stay tuned for future videos where I’ll spotlight the other S’s so that you can have a better understanding of how to boost the quality of your customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any other questions or comments you may have, feel free to reach out to me and my team. We’d love to have a conversation with you.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-serve.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-serve.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Did Rockstar Realtor Sarita Dua Find Her Success in Real Estate?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7sxtPFmiqwE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Realtors, some of the best ways we can grow in our profession is by looking to the example of successful individuals in our industry. That’s why in today’s episode of Agent Success Secrets, I’ve brought on the very talented Sarita Dua for an interview about her story. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the interview. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;00:25 - Introducing today’s guest: Sarita Dua&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;01:00 - Sarita shares her story&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;06:30 - How Sarita found success working with buyers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:15 - What helped Sarita to understand the value of effective team structures and relationships&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:06 - The importance of using written agreements with buyers and sellers alike&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:14 - Sarita clarifies how she uses showing agents within her business&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17:31 - How Sarita compensates her agents&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18:42 - Sarita shares her perspective on personal and professional growth, and why she’s going back to school as an adult&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24:22 - Sarita speaks about the “Opportunities” software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28:11 - Why Sarita believes overpreparing is better than underpreparing in the midst of a shifting market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28:54 - How to get in touch with Sarita&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/how-did-rockstar-realtor-sarita-dua-find-her-success-in-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://realestateintherealworld.com/how-did-rockstar-realtor-sarita-dua-find-her-success-in-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Special Services Do You Offer Clients?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u46vpT5PSNE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have heard, The Wolek Group has recently made a few additional services available to our seller clients. On top of this, we also occasionally run special offers—one of which being our offer to pay for a pre-listing inspection and appraisal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re already seeing awesome results from this, which is why I wanted to share this update with all of you today. &lt;strong&gt;Yesterday, for example, we helped a client close who had been on the market for seven months without any offers prior to meeting us.&lt;/strong&gt; They were financially and emotionally stressed, so when we were able to offer to pay for a pre-listing inspection and appraisal before re-listing their property, they couldn’t have been happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Open your mind to new ways you can serve your clients.%20https://realestateintherealworld.com/what-special-services-do-you-offer-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Open your mind to new ways you can serve your clients.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the appraisal came in, we discovered that their house had been overpriced by about $57,000 during their previous listing attempt. This might not be what the seller wanted to hear, but it was important in helping them succeed. &lt;strong&gt;This is exactly why pre-appraisals are so valuable. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this message has helped open your mind to new ways you could potentially serve your clients. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/what-special-services-do-you-offer-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://realestateintherealworld.com/what-special-services-do-you-offer-clients.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are Some of Ruthy Taylor’s Secrets to Success?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S7zCMPdpQN4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a fellow KW agent hailing from Tacoma, Washington, Ruthy Taylor has plenty of advice to give to other agents seeking guidance in their careers, and I’m pleased to be able to sit down with her today and delve into the secrets to her success. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the timestamps of our conversation so you can jump ahead to any section(s) that interest you the most:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0:48 - How Ruthy got started in her career, what her production was for last year, and what her goals are for this year &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2:33 - How she’s achieved success in her career&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6:21 - Her advice for other agents &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8:08 - Why it’s important for new agents to find time to pursue the things they enjoy outside of real estate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9:39 - Her advice for older agents who are feeling burnt out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12:10 - What her original group looked like and what she would do differently with it this time around&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;13:54 - Are the people in her group automatically entered into her MET database? Does she start marketing them as a real estate professional?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15:48 - What she has in store for the future of her group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;20:11 - Other lead sources she maintains for her business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or referrals for Ruthy, you can give her a call at (206) 718-3933 or email her at ruthytaylor@kw.com. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions for me, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Ruthy has been able to get a lot of business without actively pursuing it.%20https://realestateintherealworld.com/what-are-some-of-ruthy-taylors-secrets-to-success.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Ruthy has been able to get a lot of business without actively pursuing it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 13:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/what-are-some-of-ruthy-taylors-secrets-to-success.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://realestateintherealworld.com/what-are-some-of-ruthy-taylors-secrets-to-success.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The First “S” in the Five-S Model of Customer Experience is Set</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qvo4xuSxJMY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of experience do you give your clients? Is it good? Could it be great? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but &lt;strong&gt;every day I think about ways to provide a better customer experience&lt;/strong&gt; for everyone that I meet out in the community or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the customer experience class that I’ve been teaching, &lt;strong&gt;I use the Five-S model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; and today, I’ll demonstrate what the first of those five S’s means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first S stands for “set.”&lt;/strong&gt; We know that in providing a great customer experience (and having an awesome business), we first need to know our own value proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Whenever you’re in the process of delivering a great customer experience, you first present your value proposition to your clients and set your expectations.%20https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-first-s-in-the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-is-set.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Whenever you’re in the process of delivering a great customer experience, you first present your value proposition to your clients and set your expectations.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year after year, I sometimes find myself struggling to figure out what makes me unique. What helps us, as a team, stand out from other agents in town? &lt;strong&gt;In my class, we really dig deep into discovering your own personal value proposition, as well as one for your team.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you’re in the process of delivering a great customer experience, you first present your value proposition to your clients and set your expectations. To set expectations, listen to your client’s needs, understand what their expectations are, and then verify that you’re both on the same page. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future videos, I’ll walk you through the other four S’s so that you can have a better understanding of how to boost the quality of your customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more about the customer experience, you can find my class on &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.kwconnect.com/search?q=jennie+wolek&quot;&gt;KWConnect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. I also have developed a shortened version, so contact me if you’re interested in that coming to your city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any questions or comments you may have, feel free to reach out to me and my team. We’d love to have a conversation with you.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-first-s-in-the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-is-set.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://realestateintherealworld.com/the-first-s-in-the-five-s-model-of-customer-experience-is-set.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
