<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Anew Real Estate Team - your professional Austin Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://austinhomesupdate.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 10:40:21 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 10:40:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Down Payment Assistance Programs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtHVCH-y-FA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down payment assistance programs are an invaluable tool in helping some homebuyers with their down payment. With that in mind, I’ve invited Alejandro Juarez of AMEC Home Loans to answer a few questions you may have about these programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s important to understand about down payment assistance programs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down payment assistance programs allow you to obtain a mortgage loan and skip the down payment aspect of it. A lot of times, you’ll hear down payment assistance loans get referred to as “zero down” loans because lenders take care of the down payment and build it into the loan itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of flexibility with down payment assistance loans, and you can receive up to 5% worth of financial assistance from them. If you have a $200,000 loan, for instance, you can get $10,000 worth of assistance, which can cover both the down payment and the closing costs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the requirements of qualifying for a down payment assistance loan?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit is a very important thing to keep in mind in terms of qualifying for a down payment assistance loan because they don’t have the flexibility of a normal loan. You need a credit score of at least 620, and you’ll need to fit certain income requirements. In the Austin metroplex and the greater central Texas area, your annual income can’t exceed $93,000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing you need to think about in terms of qualifying for one of these loans is whether it fits your needs. A normal loan and a down payment assistance loan look very different, so you’ll need to compare how each option benefits you. Interest rates are generally higher with down payment assistance programs, so make sure the assistance you’re getting is worth the higher interest rate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Alejandro, most clients are happy with this tradeoff because it allows them to get into their very own home, and they always have the option to refinance into a normal loan later on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Think about whether a down payment assistance program really fits your needs before you decide to apply for one.%20http://austinhomesupdate.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-down-payment-assistance-programs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Think about whether a down payment assistance program really fits your needs before you decide to apply for one.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any prepayment penalties attached to these programs? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Some down payment assistance programs have what’s called a “recapture tax.” If, for example, you get an MCC credit and it goes toward your taxes and you sell your home within six months, you may have to repay the tax amount you saved with that program. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the down payment assistance programs that don’t have this tax, Alejandro favors the T-Shack loan the most. This loan allows you to provide that assistance in the form of a grant. As long as you live in the home for six months and don’t refinance, you don’t have to pay the amount back. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also other loan programs that aren’t grants. Rather, they’re loans attached to the larger mortgage loan, and eventually they will have to be paid back. They’re usually 0% interest loans, but they still get attached to the total balance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What other ways can you take advantage of these programs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use these programs to save money when you buy a house, as long as you’re buying the house as a primary residence. I brought a client to Alejandro not too long ago who didn’t necessarily need help with his down payment, but he was able to take advantage of the program anyway. His income was just below the limit for the county he was purchasing in and he had a huge amount of savings. Because of this, he was able to use the funds from the program and keep his out-of-pocket savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down payment assistance programs are always changing, so if you’re interested in using one or you have any other questions about them, you can call Alejandro at (512) 710-9456 or email him at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#106;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#046;&amp;#106;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#122;&amp;#064;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#099;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#106;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#046;&amp;#106;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#122;&amp;#064;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#099;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other questions or real estate needs, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 14:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-down-payment-assistance-programs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhomesupdate.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-down-payment-assistance-programs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learn How to Grow Your Business With: Kyle Whissel</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v_euf3rhqLg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a new entrepreneur who is wishing to grow your business but unsure how? I recently hosted a Facebook Live video where I interviewed my friend Kyle Whissel from San Diego. We spoke about the reasons he decided to start working with a broker after years of independent success, the significance of video marketing, and the importance of balancing your work life and home life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kyle told us that the biggest reason for the change was his desire to get off the hamster wheel where you have to continually run or you do not earn income. With a brokerage, he was able to get more support and tools as well as revenue shares for not only him but his entire team. His clients even benefited from the transparency his new brokerage, eXp Realty, offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Kyle and why he thinks video marketing and balance are so crucial, watch my latest video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 14:49:43 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/learn-how-to-grow-your-business-with-kyle-whissel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhomesupdate.com/learn-how-to-grow-your-business-with-kyle-whissel.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Detailed Q&amp;A About Austin Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kRXxevIpMCo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to take some time to answer a range of real estate questions that people continually ask me. I recently sat down for a Q&amp;amp;A session where I addressed some important, commonly asked real estate quandaries. I’ll be answering these questions in detail, so for convenience’s sake, I’ve provided timestamps below. This way you can skip around to the sections that most interest you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0:45—“Which homes in the Austin market are the hottest?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5:45—“Which homes are not hot in the Austin market?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8:45—“What do median prices look like in Austin?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11:45—“Where should people start if they’re thinking of entering the market to buy or sell?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for taking the time to listen to our discussion. If you have any questions about the market, buying or selling a home, or how find out your home’s value, you can visit our website at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.ANewRealEstate.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.ANewRealEstate.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, or feel free to reach out to us by phone or email. We’d be glad to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 15:24:54 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/a-detailed-qa-about-austin-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhomesupdate.com/a-detailed-qa-about-austin-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Installed Your Home’s Carbon Monoxide Detector Yet?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/09u0Pgndrls?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of April 1, &lt;strong&gt;it is now required of all Austin homes that have gas- or fuel-burning appliances to have a carbon monoxide detector installed in a proper location.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes any homes that have an attached garage, so if your home is powered solely by electricity, this ordinance is still required. Specifically, the ordinance states that “A CO detector must be installed near a bedroom if there’s anything in your home that uses fuel or gas, as well as inside the bedroom, if the room has or connects to a room that has fuel or gas.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Association of Fire Protection takes it a step further by recommending that you install your CO detector in a central location outside each sleeping area and on each level of the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This ordinance is about you and your family’s safety.%20http://austinhomesupdate.com/have-you-installed-your-homes-carbon-monoxide-detector-yet.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This ordinance is about you and your family’s safety.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re getting your home ready for sale and you don’t have a CO detector installed, that will come up on an inspection report once you get an offer. More importantly, this is about you and your family’s safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’d like more information about this ordinance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abor.com/new-carbon-monoxide-ordinance-effective-april-1/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; will provide you with all the details.&lt;/strong&gt; These detectors aren’t expensive, and you can pick one up at Home Depot or just search for one on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for me about this ordinance or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 14:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/have-you-installed-your-homes-carbon-monoxide-detector-yet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhomesupdate.com/have-you-installed-your-homes-carbon-monoxide-detector-yet.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Filed for Your Homestead Exemption?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wTHD2VpC8A4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you bought a home in 2017 and you haven’t done so yet, please make sure that you file your homestead exemption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are living in your primary residence in the state of Texas, you can get a discount on your taxes by filing for the homestead exemption. &lt;strong&gt;You have to file by April 30.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There is no fee to file your homestead exemption.%20http://austinhomesupdate.com/have-you-filed-for-your-homestead-exemption.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There is no fee to file your homestead exemption.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the websites for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.traviscountytx.gov/&quot;&gt;Travis County&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wilco.org/&quot;&gt;Williamson County&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.co.hays.tx.us/&quot;&gt;Hays County&lt;/a&gt; to get the direct links to these forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get scammed by any junk mail sent to your home that asks you to pay a fee to file for your exemption. &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;t’s free to file! There is no fee.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 15:25:13 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/have-you-filed-for-your-homestead-exemption.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhomesupdate.com/have-you-filed-for-your-homestead-exemption.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Austin Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aaWUZ7WHxAA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new year is a time for changes in the market. I wanted to reach out today with a few tips about some changes that you should be aware of. I also wanted to give you a quick look at the current state of the market for buyers and sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first thing you should be aware of in this market is some tax law changes that have taken effect.&lt;/strong&gt; Before I go any further, let me just say that I’m not a CPA and you should most certainly check with one before filing your taxes, especially regarding the changes to the mortgage interest rate decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, it’s time to file your homestead exemption if you purchased a home in 2017. The time frame you have to file the exemption goes from now until April 30. You can learn more about the process of how to do that in this video that I recently did on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This hot market makes it an incredible time to sell.%20http://austinhomesupdate.com/austin-real-estate-market-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This hot market makes it an incredible time to sell.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For buyers out there, we still have a hot market where we’re seeing multiple offers. &lt;strong&gt;I’m working with several buyers right now who are having a hard time finding properties to meet their needs.&lt;/strong&gt; Hopefully, more sellers will list their homes as we move into the spring. If you’re buying, you need to have all your ducks in a row and be ready to make an offer when you find the property that suits your needs. There will probably be several other buyers competing for the home as well. If you need any advice on how to win out in multiple offer situations, let me know and I’d be happy to give it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for sellers, this hot market makes it an incredible time to sell for top dollar. I think the market will continue to climb and continue to be strong for the foreseeable future. With the growth that we have here in the Austin metro, everything is looking strong.** I’d be happy to share some of the strategies that I like to implement with sellers to increase demand and create a multiple offer atmosphere.**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the Austin real estate market or if you’re thinking about buying or selling, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 08:28:07 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/austin-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhomesupdate.com/austin-real-estate-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One-Time Only Open House - 767 Dews Rd, Leander, TX 78641</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-saturday-january-13th-11am-to-2pm&quot;&gt;Open Saturday, January 13th, 11AM to 2PM.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t miss your only chance to see this property up close&lt;/strong&gt;. Nature and wildlife abound on this serene two acre lot studded with oak trees and tucked peacefully among many more natural acres of Leander/Williamson County ETJ and private land—&lt;strong&gt;all just minutes from all the modern day conveniences of Austin, TX.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kb7FmLtU7dc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This 3 bed, 2 bath home is Texas white stone on 4 sides and features bright large rooms, polished concrete floors, updated kitchen with stainless appliances, breakfast bar and a charming wrap around porch with panoramic country views and a covered breezeway. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Saturday, January 13th, 11AM to 2PM.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3BD, 2BA 1,734 sq.ft. - built in 2001 - Only $325,000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;MLS# 5203702&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/kurt-duffeck---1-of-29-1---x----725-543x---.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/kurt-duffeck---12-of-29-1---x----725-483x---.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/kurt-duffeck---21-of-29-1---x----725-483x---.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/kurt-duffeck---19-of-29-2---x----725-478x---.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/kurt-duffeck---8-of-29-1---x----725-483x---.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 10:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/one-time-only-open-house-767-dews-rd-leander-tx-78641.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhomesupdate.com/one-time-only-open-house-767-dews-rd-leander-tx-78641.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can We Help You Achieve Your Real Estate Dreams? </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L-gvyA5Rezc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you looking to buy, sell, or rent a home? No matter what your real estate dreams are, we can help.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Austin Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://anew.exprealty.com/sell/default&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Want to buy an Austin Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://anew.exprealty.com/search&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to reach out to you and see what we can do to help you with your dreams of moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I know that moving can seem like an overwhelming task.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether you’re renting or buying a new place, gearing up for a move is a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I can help you through this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are buying a home, my services are free. I know what it takes to coordinate a big move. I can even help you sell your current home and move at the same time; a lot of buyers need to sell before they can buy another property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have developed some proven strategies over the past 17 years&lt;/strong&gt; that will help you get top dollar for your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I HAVE DEVELOPED PROVEN STRATEGIES TO HELP YOU GET TOP DOLLAR FOR YOUR HOME.%20http://austinhomesupdate.com/how-can-we-help-you-achieve-your-real.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I HAVE DEVELOPED PROVEN STRATEGIES TO HELP YOU GET TOP DOLLAR FOR YOUR HOME.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you are renting in today’s market, I can help you out. Rentals are pretty hard to come by these days, unless you are looking for an apartment. If you’re looking for a smaller home to rent, that market is as hot as the sales market, and those homes go pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We also have a great network of real estate agents around the country,&lt;/strong&gt; so we can help you whether you are moving locally or out of the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you happen to know of anyone or you yourself are thinking of moving, just give us a call. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 10:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/how-can-we-help-you-achieve-your-real.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhomesupdate.com/how-can-we-help-you-achieve-your-real.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Tips and Tricks</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's Going on in Our Market Today?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JMQWKn6q7Mc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now that we’re halfway through the year, it’s time for a market update.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Austin Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://anew.exprealty.com/sell/default&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Want to buy an Austin Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://anew.exprealty.com/search&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m out at the Play Shop, where I’ve just found some real estate statistics for our Austin, Texas area for the month of June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in Austin, the median home price has gone up 4% year over year from last June. The price that homes are selling for, on average, is now $303,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to think of this number as a halfway point — &lt;strong&gt;half of homes will sell above this price, and half will sell below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE’RE SEEING A FEW NUMBERS THAT HAVE GONE UP FROM THIS TIME LAST YEAR.%20http://austinhomesupdate.com/whats-going-on-in-our-market-today.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE’RE SEEING A FEW NUMBERS THAT HAVE GONE UP FROM THIS TIME LAST YEAR.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, we’re seeing a few numbers that have gone up from this time last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, our average days on market is 16 days—meaning that number is up 14% from what we saw this time last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total sales, though, are down 3% from last year—$3,656 for the month of June. But, the &lt;strong&gt;average price per square foot is currently $182, and some new builders are doing even better than that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or want more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/whats-going-on-in-our-market-today.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhomesupdate.com/whats-going-on-in-our-market-today.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Get Your Home Sold If You Have a Pet</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PlJ7_E3qcMs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have a pet and you’re looking to sell your home, then read on for some helpful advice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to sell your Austin Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://anew.exprealty.com/sell/default&quot;&gt;Get a FREE home value report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Want to buy an Austin Home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://anew.exprealty.com/search&quot;&gt;Search all homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is, many homebuyers are looking for a pet-friendly home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two out of three of us have a pet, and 61% of pet owners say they have trouble finding a home that is a good match for their pet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, a recent survey estimates that 31% of animal owners frequently don’t put in an offer because a home would not suit their pet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that if your home is a good match for a pet, it will be attractive to a large pool of dedicated animal owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, 67% of Realtors also estimate that actually having a pet in your home can make it harder for you to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can you do? Here are three things I typically recommend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Repair any damage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Floors, walls, doors, the yard — these are some typical areas that pets love to chew, scratch, and dig up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repairing this damage is an investment that will pay for itself many times over in terms of a higher selling price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=PET OWNERS ARE LESS SENSITIVE TO ODORS IN THEIR HOME THAN PROSPECTIVE BUYERS ARE.%20http://austinhomesupdate.com/how-to-get-your-home-sold-if-you-have.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“PET OWNERS ARE LESS SENSITIVE TO ODORS IN THEIR HOME THAN PROSPECTIVE BUYERS ARE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Get a professional to remove pet odors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many pet owners are less sensitive to odors in their home than prospective buyers will be.
That’s why you should hire a professional cleaning crew to clean any carpets, rugs, or upholstery that have absorbed pet odors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re done with the cleaning, ask a friend or your Realtor for a sniff assessment to make sure the job is really complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Take your pet out during showings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people are afraid of animals. Others are allergic. And regardless of the time, money, and effort you’ve put in to clean and repair your home, many buyers will be prejudiced by knowing that a pet currently lives there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I recommend taking your pet out during showings and also removing any pet objects such as toys, food bowls, or scratching posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By following these three simple guidelines, &lt;strong&gt;you will be able to sell your home for top dollar, whether the buyer is a pet owner or not.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case you have any questions or concerns about preparing your home for a sale, give me a call. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 12:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://austinhomesupdate.com/how-to-get-your-home-sold-if-you-have.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://austinhomesupdate.com/how-to-get-your-home-sold-if-you-have.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
