<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Real Estate Video Blog with Kevin Langan</title>
    <description>Our mission at real broker, LLC is to be your best resource for  real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The real broker, LLC, your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 15:13:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 15:13:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Major Ways Our Market Is Changing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WoCYcKH_FSo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;These factors are changing as the housing market continues to shift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you weren’t aware, the real estate market is changing. We’re moving away from an extreme seller’s market, and things are slowly becoming more normalized. Today I’ll tell you about the three biggest changes that I’ve noticed lately:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Inventory.&lt;/strong&gt; In March, the Phoenix area MLS had about 4,000 listings, but we now have about 18,000. That shows demand has fallen below the rate of new listings, which is causing our supply to rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Interest rates.&lt;/strong&gt; Interest rates are currently around 6% for a well-qualified buyer who puts 20% down. That impacts affordability, meaning fewer people are willing to purchase a property at our current prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Things are slowly becoming more normalized.%20http://localhost:4000/3-major-ways-our-market-is-changing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Things are slowly becoming more normalized.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Expectations between buyers and sellers.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers are noticing that the market is shifting, while some sellers are still clinging to the dynamics of the past market where they were getting 25 offers in one weekend. Those days are over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re moving toward a more normal market cycle. As things settle down, it’s very important to work with a great agent that understands the local market, pricing and marketing strategies, and negotiation tactics. If you have any questions about buying or selling a home, please give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to set up a free consultation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-major-ways-our-market-is-changing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-major-ways-our-market-is-changing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Invest in Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ijrnxse1Z9Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are three key benefits to using real estate as an investment vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t invested in real estate yet, why not? There are so many great benefits to doing so. Here are my top three:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Cash flow.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the measure of the income a property will generate after all expenses are covered. It’s monthly income you can use to pay your bills or put into other savings and investments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Equity.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the difference between the value of the property and the amount you owe on the mortgage. As renters pay rent, you’ll use that money to pay off your mortgage, and your loan balance will decrease. Real estate appreciates about 3% to 5% per year historically, although we’ve seen double-digit appreciation over the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Tax benefits.&lt;/strong&gt; As an investor, you’re able to depreciate the value of that property over time to offset your active income. Many high-earning, self-employed individuals pay a lot in taxes. A way to shelter themselves is to purchase investment properties and use the IRS tax rules to depreciate those assets over time and offset their income tax burden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ve seen double-digit appreciation over the last few years.%20http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-invest-in-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ve seen double-digit appreciation over the last few years.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in exploring your investment options or just have any real estate-related questions, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 10:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-invest-in-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-invest-in-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways You Can Profit From Inflation</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g87ZGXI3nTg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Three ways inflation can benefit homeowners and real estate investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does inflation affect real estate? As an agent and investor, I study how inflation impacts both me and our market. I follow Keith Weinhold and his podcast, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getricheducation.com/&quot;&gt;“Get Rich Education.”&lt;/a&gt; He talks about three ways inflation benefits both investors and homeowners: price appreciation, debt debasement, and cash flow enhancement. Let’s talk about what he means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Home prices will appreciate.&lt;/strong&gt; The price of your home will go up in an inflationary environment because there’s more capital available to bid up the value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Inflation benefits both investors and homeowners.%20http://localhost:4000/3-ways-you-can-profit-from-inflation.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Inflation benefits both investors and homeowners.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Your loan will be easier to pay off.&lt;/strong&gt; The dollars you’re bringing in will be less valuable than the dollars you spent to get the loan on your home. Likely, inflation will outpace your mortgage’s interest rate, so it will be easier to pay off your mortgage with those less valuable dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You will get more cash flow from investments.&lt;/strong&gt; Rents typically rise during inflationary times. However, if you have a 30-year mortgage, your payments will stay the same. That means your monthly net income will increase over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or want to profit from inflation using real estate, call or email me. I’d be happy to schedule a free consultation with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-ways-you-can-profit-from-inflation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-ways-you-can-profit-from-inflation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Inspections Are Key for Buyers and Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YG2WaWer99M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Whether you’re a buyer or seller, you need a home inspection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking about buying or selling a home soon? If so, you should probably get an inspection; yes, even the sellers. Today I want to talk about why inspections are important to both parties in a real estate transaction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, &lt;strong&gt;every seller should get a pre-inspection before they list.&lt;/strong&gt; This way, you can address any issues before you go on the market. This will ensure your transaction runs smoothly and your buyer doesn’t walk away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For buyers, the benefits of an inspection are a little more obvious. Often, your seller will be willing to help pay for any items on your inspection report. The cost of those repairs almost always exceeds the cost of the inspection. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t be scared of the inspection report.&lt;/strong&gt; Properties deteriorate over time, and a report is just a tool you can use to make the best purchase you can. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about this topic or anything else real estate-related, please call or email me. I am always willing to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 09:17:08 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-inspections-are-key-for-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-inspections-are-key-for-buyers-and-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Will Rising Rates Do To Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NSe1WILEzmM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Interest rates will affect our market but not as soon as you might think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates are going up, so what will that do to our market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically speaking, &lt;strong&gt;the market does not immediately soften when rates rise.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, we see a rush of buyers who fear that they may be priced out of the market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Federal Reserve has indicated that they plan to raise short-term rates, which will indirectly impact the mortgage bond market. Because of that, we’ll likely see higher mortgage rates throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying or refinancing this year, &lt;strong&gt;I would do it sooner rather than later.&lt;/strong&gt; Our market still has short supply and high demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to call or email me. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-will-rising-rates-do-to-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-will-rising-rates-do-to-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Easy Ways To Improve Your Credit Score</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eeSQk64ATQM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;These are my three tips to help you improve your credit score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a good credit score can be the difference between getting a loan for your dream house or not. Here are three easy ways to improve your credit score:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Pay down balances on credit cards.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a balance that’s over 50% of your max, that’s going to negatively impact your score. You may not be able to pay it off in one payment, but start making progress and get the balance under 50%. Ideally, you should get it under 30%. You can also call your credit card company and ask for a credit limit increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Get a credit card if you don’t have one.&lt;/strong&gt; Be very responsible with your use of it, and don’t go over 30% of your max credit limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Set up automatic payments.&lt;/strong&gt; This way, you’ll never miss a payment by over 30 days and get a late report on your credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about buying or selling a home, give me a call or send an email. I’d be happy to get you scheduled for a free consultation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-easy-ways-to-improve-your-credit-score.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-easy-ways-to-improve-your-credit-score.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Top 3 Valentine’s Day Dinner Recommendations</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y9qo-mOS6sU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;If you need a dinner reservation for Valentine’s Day, try these spots first&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a restaurant recommendation for Valentine’s Day, you’re in luck. Here are my top three recommendations for the Phoenix area:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pomopizzeria.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Pomo Pizzeria.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; It’s an authentic Neapolitan pizza shop. It reminds me of the places I’ve visited in Naples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themissionaz.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The Mission.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; It’s a gourmet Mexican restaurant. Get your reservation in now before it’s too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tapatiocliffshilton.com/dining/different-pointe-of-view/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. A Different Pointe of View.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; It’s on top of a mountain at the Pointe Hilton Tapatio Cliffs Resort, and the food is just as good as the views. It’s an A+ experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need any more dinner recommendations or have a quick real estate question, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-top-3-valentines-day-dinner-recommendations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/my-top-3-valentines-day-dinner-recommendations.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Ways to Benefit From Homeownership Via Taxes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fj9jxg0xx0A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are some tax-related benefits to homeownership you might not know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a CPA or tax attorney, so before I begin, know that this advice is just a general guideline. Please consult with your CPA or tax attorney before you make any real estate transactions based on this advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, there are two exclusions in the IRS code that allow you to avoid or defer paying taxes on the sale of real estate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first is the primary residence exemption.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve lived in a home as your primary residence for two of the last five years and sell it, you can claim up to $250,000 in capital gains if you’re single or $500,000 if you’re married.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second exemption is for investment properties.&lt;/strong&gt; A 1031 exchange has a couple of rules. First, it has to be an investment property, and you have to have owned it for more than one year. If both conditions are met, you can exchange that property for another one of equal or greater value without paying capital gains taxes. The money from your sale goes to an intermediary, then you identify another property to purchase with those funds. You can then defer all your taxable liability on that money and use it to buy another, more expensive piece of real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about this topic or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2-ways-to-benefit-from-homeownership-via-taxes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2-ways-to-benefit-from-homeownership-via-taxes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I Expect From Our 2022 Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KuaQJHiaVEk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s what I believe we’ll see in our Phoenix real estate market in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will happen in the 2022 Phoenix real estate market? Today I’m sharing my market predictions for next year. &lt;strong&gt;We’ve been in a seller’s market with low inventory and high demand throughout 2021, and I expect the same from 2022.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also foresee single-digit appreciation despite 2021’s appreciation exceeding 20% for the median sale price. One reason I predict more mild appreciation next year is because I expect interest rates will increase by the end of 2022. Something to keep in mind about the real estate market is that it’s very stable. The stock and crypto markets can be incredibly volatile and rise or fall 20% within a day, whereas if there’s a shift in supply and demand, it’ll take months (if not a year or two) to impact the real estate market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe our market will stay strong and consistent in 2022. If you have any questions about the market or buying or selling a home, please give me a call or send an email. I’d be glad to schedule a free consultation with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-i-expect-from-our-2022-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-i-expect-from-our-2022-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays! </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UiFQQUUY8i0/?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;From our team to your family, we want to wish you a happy holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The holiday season has officially arrived. We hope you enjoy this wonderful time of year and make some fantastic memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We wanted to take a moment to thank you for your continued support&lt;/strong&gt;. We love helping people make their real estate dreams come true, so thank you for working with us and supporting our business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be a busy time of year, but we are always here to help you and answer any questions you may have. Give us a call or reply to this email; we’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case we don’t hear from you until 2022, have a happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 05:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/happy-holidays.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/happy-holidays.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
