<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mississippi Gulf Coast Real Estate Video Blog with Bryan David</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Bryan David Group - your professional Mississippi Gulf Coast Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://bryandavidgroup.tv/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 11:53:57 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 11:53:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is 2018 the Year to Step Into Homeownership?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GEOGYPDksWo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can you expect from our market in 2018? To answer that, we must look at three key factors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first is &lt;strong&gt;inventory.&lt;/strong&gt; For the past several years, we’ve seen an all-time low level of inventory. It’s a seller’s market across most of the Gulf Coast. There are a lot of buyers out there looking for housing and a lot of sellers that have been sitting on the sidelines waiting for spring to list their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’re considering becoming a homeowner, 2018 is a great year to do it.%20http://bryandavidgroup.tv/is-2018-the-year-to-step-into-homeownership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re considering becoming a homeowner, 2018 is a great year to do it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;mortgage interest rates remain low.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re still in the low 4% range, and we expect that to continue through at least the first part of 2018. A lot of buyers are entering the market to take advantage of this. This means that we’ll have a lot of both sellers and buyers entering the market this spring, which makes now a great time to list your house before everyone else does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;homeownership is still a quality investment.&lt;/strong&gt; The next tax reform bill kept many things unchanged in our market, so if you’re considering becoming a homeowner, 2018 is a great year to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know are looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 06:04:16 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/is-2018-the-year-to-step-into-homeownership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bryandavidgroup.tv/is-2018-the-year-to-step-into-homeownership.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is a New Construction Home Right for You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_0RZarqZ0es?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been thinking of buying a new construction home, there are a few pros and cons to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about purchasing a new construction property is all of the amenities that come with it. &lt;strong&gt;Because new construction homes are highly customizable, you don’t have to worry about what any previous owner might have liked or wanted in their home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all up to you to choose the things you want included. This includes everything from the faucets to the flooring. Everything is new and it’s all yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Everything is new and it’s all yours.%20http://bryandavidgroup.tv/is-a-new-construction-home-right-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Everything is new and it’s all yours.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, new constructions have another key benefit: being new. This factor will save you a lot of money on things like home maintenance. Additionally, you will have warranties on all of the major systems. You won’t need to worry about any systems going down in the first few years you’re living there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is a downside. &lt;strong&gt;You must consider the amount of time a home will take to be built.&lt;/strong&gt; This can be a few months. But, if all of the things fall into place properly, you should be done. Still, it can be very frustrating to plan a move when delays come up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a new construction home without the wait, there’s always the option of buying a spec (or speculative) home. These homes are usually already built and ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 09:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/is-a-new-construction-home-right-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bryandavidgroup.tv/is-a-new-construction-home-right-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Benefits Associated With VA Loans</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_eiIa9ryDXo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to cover four points about VA loans and the benefits associated with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VA loans don’t require a down payment.&lt;/strong&gt; Military service people and veterans can go to the closing table with zero down, which is a great benefit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They don’t require mortgage insurance.&lt;/strong&gt; Both FHA and USDA loans require mortgage insurance for the life of the loan. As a member of the military, you won’t have that requirement with a VA loan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Veterans can go to the closing table with no money down%20http://bryandavidgroup.tv/4-benefits-associated-with-va-loans.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Veterans can go to the closing table with no money down”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VA loans aren’t restricted to single-family residences.&lt;/strong&gt; Essentially, you could buy a duplex, triplex, or quadruplex, live in one of the units and rent the others out. This allows you to have your unit paid for by someone else.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a disabled veteran, you don’t have to pay the funding fee.&lt;/strong&gt; This could save you anywhere from 1% to 3% on the cost of the loan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know is in the market to buy, sell, or invest in real estate, definitely give us a call or send an email. I’d be glad to sit down and speak to you, your friends, or your family and help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 04:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/4-benefits-associated-with-va-loans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bryandavidgroup.tv/4-benefits-associated-with-va-loans.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Military Relocation Professionals Help Active Service Members</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pu7Eqh4h_Wk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help educate you about military relocation professionals, I’m going to answer a few common questions relating to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between a Realtor that’s certified as a MRP and one that is not?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A military relocation professional has certified knowledge of what a service member does and what they have to go through when they move. There are a lot of things that have to be done and certain timelines they have to meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any other benefits to using a military relocation professional?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Being part of the military relocation program keeps you up to date on any new regulations or other changes.%20http://bryandavidgroup.tv/how-military-relocation-professionals-help-active-service-members.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Being part of the military relocation program keeps you up to date on any new regulations or other changes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being part of the military relocation program keeps you up to date on any new regulations or other changes. When I was in the military, I went through a lot of moves, but that was many years ago. Being an MRP, though, allows me to stay updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some of the nice things about relocating to the Gulf Coast?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keesler Air Force Base is a wonderful base that’s only a block away from the beach, and the Seabee base isn’t very far from the beach either. There are lots of activities and plenty of quality housing nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will release a military relocation guide this month on our website. In the meantime, if you have any other questions about MRPs or any other real estate topics, don’t hesitate to give us a call. We’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 04:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/how-military-relocation-professionals-help-active-service-members.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bryandavidgroup.tv/how-military-relocation-professionals-help-active-service-members.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Heard of 203(k) Loans?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bb9BJNpGGvE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a broker associate with Keller Williams here on the Mississippi Gulf Coast, I’d like to talk to you a little bit about the 203(k) loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a 203(k) loan? This type of loan is a renovation loan that &lt;strong&gt;works in tandem with your regular lending and allows you to make renovations to the house during the purchase.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the terms of the loan, you have about six months to make those renovations, and you’ll be required to use an approved contractor. It’s a little bit of extra paperwork, but it’s definitely worth doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This type of loan is a renovation loan that works in tandem with your regular lending and allows you to make renovations to the house during the purchase.%20http://bryandavidgroup.tv/have-you-heard-of-203k-loans.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This type of loan is a renovation loan that works in tandem with your regular lending and allows you to make renovations to the house during the purchase.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two versions of the 203(k) loan: a full version and a streamlined version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go into a house and you love everything about it except that maybe the kitchen is just not right, ask your agent about a 203(k) loan. You can have the entire kitchen renovated to be just the way you want it so that you can own the perfect house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is interested in buying, selling, or investing in real estate, please give us a call. We’d love to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 07:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/have-you-heard-of-203k-loans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bryandavidgroup.tv/have-you-heard-of-203k-loans.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things to Avoid When Buying Your First Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WALL9fppeRc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I asked the buyer’s agents on my team what they found most gratifying about their jobs, they told me how much they love working with first-time homebuyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, my agents enjoy helping these buyers understand and navigate the home buying process for the first time, and then watching them succeed in doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason this is so gratifying is because these agents realize just how much goes into the process of searching for and purchasing a home. There are a lot of steps, which means a lot of room for error. For that reason, today I wanted to go over some of the most common mistakes first-time homebuyers make, so that you don’t repeat these mistakes yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not considering the cost of the home, beyond just the mortgage payment.&lt;/strong&gt;There’s a lot more to the cost than principal and interest. You also need to consider insurance and taxes. Also, the maintenance of owning the house over the years is going to add up. It’s important to consider these kinds of costs that will come down the line, including any upgrades you may do. These upgrades may add value to the house, but remember that you might not see that money back when you sell.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure you understand your price range and that you are pre-approved ahead of time.%20http://bryandavidgroup.tv/things-to-avoid-when-buying-your-first-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure you understand your price range and that you are pre-approved ahead of time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shopping for a home without being pre-approved.&lt;/strong&gt; Imagine finding your dream home only to watch someone else buy it out from under you while you’re at the lender trying to get pre-approved. Make sure you understand your price range and that you are pre-approved ahead of time. This will prevent any unpleasant surprises.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changing your debt-to-income ratio, causing your lender to deny you the loan.&lt;/strong&gt;Watching your new house go down the drain is a terrible feeling. You may not realize it, but going out and making expensive purchases on credit can have a huge impact on your ability to receive your loan. Wait until after closing before you do anything that could change your credit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or are interested in having a buyer consultation with us, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 07:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/things-to-avoid-when-buying-your-first-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bryandavidgroup.tv/things-to-avoid-when-buying-your-first-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Inspection Tips for Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pYLWWLrqIC4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time for part two of our video series on home inspections. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bryandavidgroup.tv/what-to-expect-during-a-home-inspection.html&quot;&gt;Last time&lt;/a&gt;, I talked to homebuyers but today, I have a few inspection tips for sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on selling your house, &lt;strong&gt;why should you consider getting a home inspection before you put your house on the market?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The No. 1 reason to get an inspection before listing your home is that you can take care of all necessary repairs before your home hits the market. An inspection costs about $300, and you will be able to know exactly what condition your home is in and take care of about 90% of those repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every home inspector is a little different. One may find something that another one doesn’t, but you can get most of those repairs taken care of. If there are any major repairs, you can get most of that done on your own time prior to getting an offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you get a great offer on your house without taking care of the inspections and repairs, then the buyer will order their own inspection. On occasion, we see buyers get scared off by an inspection report because they cannot deal with the number of repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Take care of all necessary repairs before your home hits the market.%20http://bryandavidgroup.tv/home-inspection-tips-for-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Take care of all necessary repairs before your home hits the market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the buyer backs out of the contract after the inspection, you will have to put your house back on the market. Your next offer will probably not be as good as the first offer you had, so you could end up selling your house for thousands of dollars less than the original sale price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also consider the time involved in this process. When you have to put your house on the market, you lose weeks or even months due to those repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultimately, you will have to do the repairs anyway to get the house sold.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of going back on the market and making two or three additional mortgage payments, order that $300 home inspection before your home is on the market. Doing so will save you a lot of time, money, stress, and heartache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buyers see that you have already ordered an inspection on the home, they may accept your inspection report. From there, the contract just flies through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about home inspections or preparing your house for the market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 04:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/home-inspection-tips-for-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bryandavidgroup.tv/home-inspection-tips-for-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Expect During a Home Inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KTjrCvNNH4s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve gotten a lot of questions about home inspections, so I decided to start a video series to cover everything you need to know. Today, I’ll go over a few key points for homebuyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.  When?&lt;/strong&gt; As soon as we get a contract on your house, one of the very first things we’ll do is order a home inspection. The contract generally has a short period to get your inspection done and request repairs from the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.  Who?&lt;/strong&gt; There are a lot of home inspectors out there. You can do a search on the Internet or we can recommend a few inspectors who have helped our clients in the past. That said, you need to make sure that the home inspector has an active license. Check out this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrec.state.ms.us/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to make sure your home inspector’s license is active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure that your inspector has an active license.%20http://bryandavidgroup.tv/what-to-expect-during-a-home-inspection.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure that your inspector has an active license.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.  How&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;much does it cost?&lt;/strong&gt; Home inspections tend to start around $250. The majority of home inspections cost about $300 to $350, and very large homes will cost $400 or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.  What&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;do you get for your money?&lt;/strong&gt; You will receive a lengthy report detailing any issues with the home, including major concerns, minor concerns, safety hazards, and maintenance items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also determine what will happen if the inspector misses a major problem in the home. Is the inspector insured, what is the procedure, and how is the inspector covered?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about home inspections or are interested in buying a home, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 11:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/what-to-expect-during-a-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bryandavidgroup.tv/what-to-expect-during-a-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Key Tips for Buying or Investing in Waterfront Properties</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_kLRZa0QN8U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down here on the Mississippi Gulf Coast, we have plenty of waterfront property for you to choose from, be it river, bay, bayou, or beachfront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of interest these days in waterfront property. However, there are four things you should consider before buying or investing in a waterfront property:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;What is your intention or expectation for the property?&lt;/strong&gt; If your plan is to sit on the deck and sip your coffee while the sun rises over the bayou, that’s fine. There are a number of properties out there that fit that bill. If you intend to fish off the pier and catch trophy trout, or if you have a boat, that requires further discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. If you do have a boat, what is the draft of the boat?&lt;/strong&gt; How big is the boat? We need to determine if you require a property with deep water access so that you can utilize the property the way you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What is your intention for the property?%20http://bryandavidgroup.tv/4-key-tips-for-buying-or-investing-in-waterfront-properties.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What is your intention for the property?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Inspect any existing bulkheads or piers on the property.&lt;/strong&gt; We don’t want you to buy something that’s been eaten up by worms or is starting to cave in. It can be costly to get those torn out or replaced.  Also, if you require a new bulkhead or pier we want to make sure it is planned into your budget. It can cost anywhere from $150 to $250 per linear foot to replace, depending on how deep the water and how extensive the job is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. What is the build elevation on the lot that you intend to purchase?&lt;/strong&gt; You need to get down to the planning department to find out. You should also look for other restrictions that may come with building on a waterfront property, as that can wind up being extensive and costly as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about waterfront property or would like some help in finding the right one for you, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 08:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/4-key-tips-for-buying-or-investing-in-waterfront-properties.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bryandavidgroup.tv/4-key-tips-for-buying-or-investing-in-waterfront-properties.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Going on in the Gulf Coast Real Estate Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/upUuihYcUbI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time we gave you an update on how the Gulf Coast market was in the spring, but now we are in the dead of summer. Here’s what we’ve been seeing over the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inventory is still down. We only have about six months on average across the coast. Some areas, like Ocean Springs, have only four months. That signifies a seller’s market. In a seller’s market, we see increased prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Case in point, the average price for a home along the coast is $150,000. That number jumps up near $190,000 in Ocean Springs. Those are just the average prices, though. &lt;strong&gt;There are certainly options for every budget.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homes in Biloxi are selling in just 70 days, on average.%20http://bryandavidgroup.tv/whats-going-on-in-the-gulf-coast-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homes in Biloxi are selling in just 70 days, on average.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Homes are spending an average of 104 days on the market along the coast, but there are pockets where they are selling much faster. Ocean Springs, of course, has an average around 80 days. Biloxi has dropped from 90 to 70 days. On the other end of the spectrum, Gulfport’s average rose to 135 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall, we’ve had a really good run with housing lately.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have been thinking about buying or selling, now is a great time to get in the market while there is high demand for your home and you can buy a new home with a low interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 05:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://bryandavidgroup.tv/whats-going-on-in-the-gulf-coast-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bryandavidgroup.tv/whats-going-on-in-the-gulf-coast-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
