<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Stern Team: Home Page</title>
    <description>Salt Lake City Utah best Realtors are on The Stern Team, led by Joshua Stern. Follow us for latest market info and be prepared to buy or sell real estate.</description>
    <link>http://sternteam.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sternteam.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 14:24:57 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 14:24:57 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Keep Your Home Decluttered Forever</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qHA4bqArFcM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to decluttering, Marie Kondo is all the rage right now. She’s the Japanese lifestyle celebrity who has the miraculous ability to help people declutter their homes for good. What’s her trick? Only keep the things that spark joy or keep you happy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are three tips based on that principle that you should follow when decluttering:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, collect all of the same things around the house (e.g. all the books), touch each object once, and ask yourself whether it sparks joy. If it doesn’t, it needs to go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=At the end of the day, you’ll find that you only keep things that make you happy.%20http://sternteam.org/3-tips-to-keep-your-home-decluttered-forever.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“At the end of the day, you’ll find that you only keep things that make you happy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, remember to follow the right order when tidying up. Start with clothing, move on to books, papers, and other miscellaneous items, and then focus on mementos. By the time you get to mementos, you’ll understand the method. Don’t keep things because you think they might come in handy. The likelihood that they will come in handy is low, and you can always buy a newer version of an item that does spark joy in the off-chance that you’ll need it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;get rid of the clutter before buying storage containers&lt;/strong&gt; or other oversized products to organize your space. Take it slow and don’t stress over the process too much. You want to make sure you do it right and on your own time. At the end of the day, you’ll find that you only keep things that make you happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/3-tips-to-keep-your-home-decluttered-forever.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/3-tips-to-keep-your-home-decluttered-forever.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Is How Long a Pre-Approval Usually Lasts</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T93hCpM58DI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re hoping to buy a home, it’s smart to ponder the question, “How long does a pre-approval last?” Even after you’ve received a lender’s stamp of approval for your financing, weeks or even months could pass before you actually buy a house. Will that pre-approval you receive still be valid by then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since lenders realize that buying a house does take time, pre-approval dates have a shelf life, but not a definite one.&lt;/strong&gt; While the length of time varies, in general, a pre-approval is good for about three months. Here’s what homebuyers need to know to make the most out of this time frame, and what to do if your pre-approval is at risk of running out before you buy a home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step to buying a home should be to prove that you have the financial means to do so through a pre-approval. &lt;strong&gt;This is a process through which a mortgage professional examines a loan application to determine whether a potential buyer will qualify for a mortgage. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A pre-approval is usually good for anywhere from 90 to 180 days.%20http://sternteam.org/this-is-how-long-a-pre-approval-usually-lasts.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A pre-approval is usually good for anywhere from 90 to 180 days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To obtain a pre-approval, buyers need to provide a mortgage lender with information like their employment history, credit score, income, and debts. During this process, the lender will want to see bank statements, pay stubs, and tax returns. &lt;strong&gt;It can feel invasive, but lenders are looking to protect their interests by not loaning money to someone who could be considered “high-risk.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are people who have high, outstanding debts, inconsistent income, or a history of late payments. Once a lender reviews your finances, they will give you a pre-approval letter, detailing a good-faith willingness to extend mortgage financing based on its preliminary examinations of your assets, income stream, and creditworthiness. &lt;strong&gt;This letter will also detail the actual loan amount that you qualify for. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How long does a pre-approval last? Although there is no definite duration, the custom within our industry is that a pre-approval is good from anywhere for 90 to 180 days, but many may consider it “too old” after three months. The reason? In three months, your financial life can change drastically. You can buy appliances, a car, or do plenty of other things to affect your home buying prospects. &lt;strong&gt;Since pre-approvals do have a shelf life, it’s best to not get one until you’re seriously looking for a home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this information has been useful to you. If you have any other real estate questions or needs, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email today. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/this-is-how-long-a-pre-approval-usually-lasts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/this-is-how-long-a-pre-approval-usually-lasts.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Sellers Must Disclose About Their Listing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0RSN-pqF9rE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’ve lived in your home for a few years or a few decades, you know all about its quirks, its best features, and its flaws. When you decide to sell your home, some of this information might be necessary for you to share with buyers in the form of a seller disclosure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Including certain flaws in this document can feel uncomfortable; however, it’s best to be open and honest during the process.&lt;/strong&gt; Failing to disclose certain issues could land you in legal trouble or, at the very least, create significant hurdles for your home sale. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially true since buyers will find out through a home inspection, anyway, if any problems (major or minor) are present in your home. Alternatively, if a problem does manage to escape their notice, but they ultimately discover it after closing, you could be subject to a lawsuit if they believe you intentionally hid the issue during your deal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While different states have different laws about what you must disclose, federal laws do make it necessary for sellers across the nation to be forthcoming about one hazard in particular: lead paint. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Failing to disclose certain issues could land you in legal trouble or, at the very least, create significant hurdles for your home sale.%20http://sternteam.org/what-sellers-must-disclose-about-their-listing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Failing to disclose certain issues could land you in legal trouble or, at the very least, create significant hurdles for your home sale.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your home was built in or before 1978, you are legally responsible for ordering an inspection to check for lead paint.&lt;/strong&gt; You are also required to issue the results of this inspection to the buyer in the form of a seller disclosure document. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for what disclosure requirements you might be subject to in your specific area, these regulations change too rapidly for us to list any specifics here. Instead, we recommend that you speak to your agent directly about current local regulations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, though, problems that sellers should disclose regardless of local regulations include water damage, mold, pests, or any other major structural, mechanical, or safety-related issues. Buyers will also likely ask to see evidence that these problems have been resolved, so save all applicable receipts and paperwork from applicable repairs or insurance claims you’ve made. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some states even require sellers to disclose any risk of natural hazards like wildfires, earthquakes, or flooding, if these are common to the area.&lt;/strong&gt; So, again, check with your Realtor to see how you should proceed when it comes time to make your own disclosures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or would like to discuss your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/what-sellers-must-disclose-about-their-listing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/what-sellers-must-disclose-about-their-listing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why List During the Holidays?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qMzpKo1SOxU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer is now in the rear-view mirror but despite what some believe, the end of warmer weather does not mean our market has completely cooled off. Selling your home over the holiday season is often a smart move for sellers savvy enough to take advantage. Not only is there less competition during these later months, but the buyers who are out looking also tend to be much more serious about finding the right home. And these are just a couple of benefits sellers can enjoy when listing at this time of year. Homes also show well during the holidays thanks to seasonal decor and the warm-and-fuzzy feelings that tend to crop up as the year draws to a close. The bottom line is that if you want to sell in 2019, it isn’t too late. Our team would be happy to help you sell quickly and for top dollar this holiday season. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/why-list-during-the-holidays.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/why-list-during-the-holidays.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What All Homebuyers Must Know About New Construction Properties</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HsII9hjglcM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you thought about buying a new construction home? If so, there are five points you need to be aware of: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. New construction homes aren’t always listed on the MLS.&lt;/strong&gt; Quite often, home builders have agents working as on-site salespeople in order to increase their control of the transaction while reducing total costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. New construction homes are often sold before they’re built.&lt;/strong&gt; Builders will generally line up financing and line up the construction and sales process before a property is even built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The first buyers within a subdivision may get the greatest discounts.&lt;/strong&gt; As the saying goes, “the early bird gets the worm.” Acting quickly when a new subdivision is being built could lead to financial rewards. These rewards also come with the risk of being committed to a process before much is known about how it will play out, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Builders put a lot of emphasis on numbers.&lt;/strong&gt; Since a builder isn’t a traditional seller, they don’t have an emotional attachment to the home(s) they’re selling, and will therefore be more focused on making sure you’re qualified and ready to purchase than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Discounts may be available in the form of upgrades.&lt;/strong&gt; If the property is close to the end of the sales cycle, builders may be willing to offer you an upgrade package that would reduce the overall cost of purchasing the home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Acting quickly when a new subdivision is being built could lead to financial rewards.%20http://sternteam.org/what-all-homebuyers-must-know-about-new-construction-properties.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Acting quickly when a new subdivision is being built could lead to financial rewards.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/what-all-homebuyers-must-know-about-new-construction-properties.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/what-all-homebuyers-must-know-about-new-construction-properties.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Real Estate Numbers Along the Wasatch Front</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QEi7lveDkDI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re back with another update on the Wasatch Front real estate market. In the third quarter of 2019, we saw a significant jump in sales. &lt;strong&gt;Year to date, we’re up 2.1% with over 37,700 homes sold so far in 2019.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average price for all home types is over $383,000. At the same time last year, our average price was just over $354,000. That’s an 8.2% year-over-year increase, which is &lt;strong&gt;great news if you’re a homeowner looking to capitalize on your equity by selling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our average days on market along the Wasatch Front is 47 days—a 20% increase from the 39-day average we saw at this time last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Prices are rising, but so is our supply of homes.%20http://sternteam.org/the-latest-real-estate-numbers-along-the-wasatch-front.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Prices are rising, but so is our supply of homes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our overall inventory for all housing types is at a 3.8-month supply. Anything less than six months is considered a seller’s market. The market is still very good, but homes are taking slightly longer to sell. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third quarter also brought us some of the lowest interest rates we’ve seen in a few years. As we finish the third quarter, rates jumped up a bit, but are still fantastic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prices continue to go up, but there’s more inventory available.&lt;/strong&gt; Couple that with solid interest rates and we have a good market for buyers and sellers right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/the-latest-real-estate-numbers-along-the-wasatch-front.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/the-latest-real-estate-numbers-along-the-wasatch-front.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Becoming More Financially Responsible</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bBq3TlcsE_Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to improve your finances? Many do, but maybe you don’t know where to start. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, promoting your own financial health all starts with measuring some basic skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;learn how to budget.&lt;/strong&gt; Budgets can be boring, but they are the cornerstone of financial responsibility. They can help you no matter what the situation is, be it paying the bills, chipping away debt, saving for retirement, or buying a home. Budgeting can help you answer the dreaded question, “Where did all my money go!?” that you may ask yourself at the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you can’t afford it, don’t buy it.%20http://sternteam.org/5-tips-for-becoming-more-financially-responsible.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you can’t afford it, don’t buy it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;use credit cards correctly.&lt;/strong&gt; Credit cards can be a valuable financial tool that can help you build credit or repair poor credit. Just be sure to avoid getting caught in a bad cycle with credit cards; only buy what you can afford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;strong&gt;pay yourself first.&lt;/strong&gt; This seems impossible, but it’s incredibly important that you make sure to pay yourself first by transferring money into your savings account before paying any of your bills. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll also want to learn how to &lt;strong&gt;invest wisely.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether you invest in a small stock portfolio or you own your own home, learning how to invest is a keystone of your financial health and wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;live within your means.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t compare yourself to others, and if you can’t afford it, don’t buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about becoming more financially responsible or about real estate, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be glad to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/5-tips-for-becoming-more-financially-responsible.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/5-tips-for-becoming-more-financially-responsible.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Things to Remember When Building a New Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gDBCTOjy1BE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inventory has been shrinking recently, which has a large number of&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;buyers building new homes, instead. When buyers do this, though, they need to ensure that they’re being well-represented. There are three reasons this is so important: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The on-site agent is working for the builder.&lt;/strong&gt; The person you meet when you visit a model home may be perfectly pleasant and knowledgeable, but they aren’t there with your best interests in mind. Rather, they’re there to protect and advocate for the builder. So, given that the builder has an agent on their side, why wouldn’t you want one on yours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Many builders use their own purchase agreement.&lt;/strong&gt; Without professional training, interpreting such documents (which are often upwards of 30 to 40 pages long) can be difficult. This is yet another reason why having an agent working on your behalf is so critical. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The builder has an agent on their side, so why wouldn’t you want one on yours?%20http://sternteam.org/3-things-to-remember-when-building-a-new-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The builder has an agent on their side, so why wouldn’t you want one on yours?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Agents can offer a neutral perspective&lt;/strong&gt;. Buying a home is an emotional decision. After all, this is the place where you’re going to make memories and put down roots. With all of these things on your mind, trying to parse out the logistics of the purchase itself can be hard. An agent not only brings a high level of knowledge and experience to the table, but also a neutral perspective, which will help ensure you get the best possible deal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about this or any other real estate subject, or would like to learn how we can help you meet your own buying, selling, or investing goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/3-things-to-remember-when-building-a-new-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/3-things-to-remember-when-building-a-new-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Buy a New Home or Sell Your Old Home First?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9OYipvuTpO8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most home sellers are also homebuyers. Because of this, the inevitable dilemma of which transaction to complete first comes up. Buying first is ideal because it allows you to take your time and there are much fewer hoops to jump through. Most people can’t afford two mortgages at once, however, so selling first is a reality for many. In either case, there are plenty of different options that will lead to a smooth process. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/should-you-buy-a-new-home-or-sell-your-old-home-first.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/should-you-buy-a-new-home-or-sell-your-old-home-first.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who’s Responsible for Keeping a Property Show-Ready?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rG726jGGmT8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home sellers and their agents want their properties to remain show-ready at all times while they’re on the market; but ensuring that this is the case can be a chore—especially if said sellers have already moved out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whose job is it to pick up the newspaper, shovel the driveway, and keep the grass trimmed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it usually isn’t feasible for a seller who has already moved away to take care of these daily or weekly tasks. So whose shoulders does this home maintenance fall on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Until the property has sold, its condition remains the responsibility of the seller.%20http://sternteam.org/whos-responsible-for-keeping-a-property-show-ready.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Until the property has sold, its condition remains the responsibility of the seller.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, until the property has sold, its condition remains the responsibility of the seller. Buyers will lose interest and neighbors will become testy if your home becomes an eyesore. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t assume your real estate agent is your gardener or maid.&lt;/strong&gt; Even though they also have a vested interest in making sure your home sells quickly and at a high price, it isn’t their job to stay on top of its general upkeep. Some agents may be up to the task, but you shouldn’t presume this to be the case until you’ve had a candid discussion about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some agents may refuse to take responsibility for these tasks not because they mind doing the work, but because they don’t want to be blamed in case anything goes wrong. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, &lt;strong&gt;the best way to ensure a vacant home is well-maintained while its on the market is to hire relevant contractors or a property manager to take care of the necessary tasks.&lt;/strong&gt; Your agent will likely be happy to help coordinate the fine details so long as you, the seller, are the one taking bids and making payments. A good agent will also often have a network of vendors with whom they can connect their seller, if necessary. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that, &lt;strong&gt;no matter the situation, a quality real estate agent will have your best interests at heart&lt;/strong&gt; and will be more than willing to guide you through whatever obstacles you encounter during your home selling experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sternteam.org/whos-responsible-for-keeping-a-property-show-ready.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sternteam.org/whos-responsible-for-keeping-a-property-show-ready.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
