<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Central Pennsylvania Real Estate Video Blog with Andrew Kronenberg</title>
    <description>Central Pennsylvania real estate agent, Andrew Kronenberg, has the best resources for all things real estate. Whether you are buying, selling, or investing in real estate, Andrew Kronenberg is here to guide you through the process. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Keller Williams of Central PA, your professional Central Pennsylvania Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /</link>
    <atom:link href="http://Kronenbergreg.com /feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 15:22:01 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 15:22:01 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Will Rising Interest Rates Impact Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/huSg6bADwaw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had a lot of growth in our economy in general over the last couple of years, and today we’ll be touching on one specific aspect of it: Interest rates. Before we get into our discussion, though, I’d like to clarify an important term: Basis points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basis points are used to describe changes to interest rates. &lt;strong&gt;A single basis point is a hundredth of a percentile, so, therefore, 25 basis points would be equivalent to 0.25%. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you hear someone say that the Federal Reserve met and raised interest rates by 25 basis points, this means there was an increase of 0.25%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, let’s move on to our main topic. Interest rates can have a significant impact on buyers and sellers alike in our market. And given that the Fed meets four times per year to discuss these rates, it’s important to understand how this may impact your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Even after the most recent increase, rates are still low compared to historical averages.%20http://Kronenbergreg.com /how-will-rising-interest-rates-impact-buyers-and-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Even after the most recent increase, rates are still low compared to historical averages.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rates have been steadily rising in recent times, but even after the most recent increase in September, they are still low compared to historical averages. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can see this point illustrated in an extremely powerful graphic we’ve featured in today’s video (at 1:24).&lt;/strong&gt; This graphic shows precisely how interest rate hikes correlate with drops in affordability. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what does the current trend of rising rates ultimately mean for buyers and sellers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sellers, the good news is that recent appreciation has left homeowners with higher levels of equity. For buyers, these changes mean that it may be better to purchase a home as soon as possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 12:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /how-will-rising-interest-rates-impact-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Kronenbergreg.com /how-will-rising-interest-rates-impact-buyers-and-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When You Should Consider Investing in a Starter Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/webp-net-resizeimage-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends and Clients —&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you invest in a starter home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or is it a better idea to wait and save for your “forever” home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, let’s make sure we’re talking about the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economists often define a “starter home” as being in the lower third of a specific market’s value range (as opposed to trade-up homes and luxury homes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many homeowners, however, a starter home isn’t about price. Instead, &lt;strong&gt;it’s about how long they plan to stay there&lt;/strong&gt; — typically, only a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s where the dilemma really occurs. That’s because buying and selling a home, as well as moving in and out, all have costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, since the bulk of the mortgage payments for those first years goes to interest, you’re also &lt;strong&gt;unlikely to build up much equity if you only own the home for a short while.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In fact, according to one estimate, &lt;strong&gt;the break-even point for a starter home is somewhere from 5 to 7 years.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, if you’re planning to stay in the home for just a few years, then it might not make sense to buy it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A starter home can help you save money and build equity and net worth.%20http://Kronenbergreg.com /when-you-should-consider-investing-in-a-starter-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A starter home can help you save money and build equity and net worth.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So am I telling you to buy a starter home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope. There are, however, good situations in which a starter home makes perfect sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;strong&gt;if you’re planning on staying put for 5 or more years, a starter home will save you money on rent,&lt;/strong&gt; will help you build up equity and create net worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, if the home has long term potential, and you can imagine it becoming your forever home with the right renovations or additions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option, is &lt;strong&gt;if you are open to keeping the home and renting it out as an investment property.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, creating more net worth if your global financial picture will allow this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately though, this will be a decision that’s based on your own unique preferences and circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you weigh all of that in, if you do decide that a starter home might make sense for you, then here’s something important you should know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best time to buy a starter home is fast approaching.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s because fall is the season when starter home inventory peaks and listing prices drop, according to the real estate portal Trulia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means &lt;strong&gt;you should have the most choices, at the most affordable prices during the fall.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are curious what kinds of homes are becoming available around Central Pennsylvania area right now, take a look at this complete listing inventory:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://akronenberg.kw.com/search-homes/#/-650372487&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here for all available Central Pennsylvania homes for sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more detailed infromation about the current Central Pennsylvania real estate market and additional inventory, including whether a starter home is right for your unique circumstances, contact me at (717) 609-8265 or Andrew@kronenbergREG.com. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 17:03:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /when-you-should-consider-investing-in-a-starter-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Kronenbergreg.com /when-you-should-consider-investing-in-a-starter-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer 2018 Central Pennsylvania home price update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/webp-net-resizeimage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends and Clients —&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer is here, which means the high season for real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been thinking of selling your home, &lt;strong&gt;you might be in for a golden moment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But be aware &lt;strong&gt;it might not last long.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me explain why, with a few &lt;strong&gt;nationwide details&lt;/strong&gt; of the current real estate market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, &lt;strong&gt;homes are selling in record time.&lt;/strong&gt; This May, it took just 34 days for a home to go under contract, which broke last year’s record of 36 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home prices also continue to rise.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, they’ve been rising for six straight years, and for the past two years, this growth has been accelerating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, 27.6% of the homes sold in May sold above their listing price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this is due to a woefully &lt;strong&gt;short supply of homes on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, the total supply of homes is 5.4% lower this year than the same time last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the real estate market might be on the cusp of change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one thing, &lt;strong&gt;mortgage rates have been rising,&lt;/strong&gt; and now stand near their highest levels in seven years. As a result, pending home sales were down as of April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More worryingly, a Redfin survey found &lt;strong&gt;a drop in customers touring homes&lt;/strong&gt; for the first time in 27 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The real estate market might be on the cusp of change.%20http://Kronenbergreg.com /summer-2018-central-pennsylvania-home-price-update.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The real estate market might be on the cusp of change.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s going on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;home price surge might be nearing its end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, &lt;strong&gt;home affordability is dropping:&lt;/strong&gt; Over the past 6 years, there has been a 48% increase in average home prices, while wages increased only 14%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while some sellers are still managing to sell at higher prices than listed, nearly a quarter of sellers actually had to lower their prices this April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this all mean for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you do decide to sell right now, you would have an easy time of it,&lt;/strong&gt; and you could get a top price for your home. That’s because demand and prices are both still high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you decide to wait, things might go south quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s because the market may be reaching the limits of price growth,&lt;/strong&gt; and may be stalled by higher mortgage rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are considering selling your home, you can get started with an estimate of what your home is worth in the current market. Simply use this calculator, which takes into account recent Central Pennsylvania sales:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://akronenberg.kw.com/selling/&quot;&gt;Enter your street address here to find out what your home is worth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you want an even more accurate estimate, then give me a call at (717) 609-8265. I have my finger on the pulse of the Central Pennsylvania real estate market, and I can tell you how quickly — and for how much — you could sell your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 12:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /summer-2018-central-pennsylvania-home-price-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Kronenbergreg.com /summer-2018-central-pennsylvania-home-price-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Real Estate Scams You  Need to Know About</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/webp-net-resizeimage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying or selling a home can be an intimidating experience and trusting real estate “professionals” may be daunting. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Unfortunately, like any industry, there are some bad actors. Don’t become a victim!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some real estate scams that we’ve seen recently. If you know what to look out for, you can protect yourself with that knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The mortgage closing scam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular scam is spreading across the country. It’s become so prevalent that the FBI estimates it has &lt;strong&gt;led to more than $1 billion in stolen or diverted funds in 2017 alone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts when hackers gain access to a real estate agent’s email account. Then, when it’s time to close a particular deal, the hackers, posing as the real estate agent, send instructions to the homebuyer on where to wire the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it’s only after the buyer has sent thousands of dollars to an unknown bank account that the truth comes out - the real estate agent wasn’t actually the one reaching out, and the buyer has been scammed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prevention. Select a reputable title company. A real estate agent should NOT be involved in the transfer of funds and your title company should never accept, nor follow, wire instructions from a real estate agent. Additionally, title companies should be insured against such fraudulent activities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Fake real estate attorneys&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scam is similar to the first one, in that the scammers will impersonate somebody legitimately involved with a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the hackers will impersonate a real estate attorney who is associated with a particular transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, at the time of closing, they will &lt;strong&gt;contact the buyer, either by email or over the phone, and tell them the wire destination has been changed.&lt;/strong&gt; If this scam works, the homebuyer could again be out thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prevention. Again, selecting a reputable real estate law firm is critical. Your real estate agent will be able to recommend a well-established attorney who is properly insured against such fraudulent activities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=FIND A REAL ESTATE AGENT YOU TRUST TO REPRESENT YOUR BEST INTERESTS.%20http://Kronenbergreg.com /3-real-estate-scams-you-need-to-know-about.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“FIND A REAL ESTATE AGENT YOU TRUST TO REPRESENT YOUR BEST INTERESTS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The bait-and-switch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the first two scams, this scam targets sellers. It also doesn’t require any hacking or impersonation—just a dishonest buyer. Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A buyer makes an offer that’s well above the listed price.  The seller happily agrees, and the contract is signed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the buyer starts procrastinating, making excuses, and dragging out the process for months or even a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, the seller continues to pay costs for the home, and is getting more and more emotionally worn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, the unscrupulous buyer flatly says they can only buy the home at a lower price, usually under the listed price. And the seller, desperate by now, frequently agrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how can you protect yourself against these and other scams?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;don't send account information over email.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confirm everything over a phone call to a number that you already know to be valid…or even better, in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, finding a real estate agent that you can trust to represent your best interests is critical. I’d be honored to serve in that role, so please give me a call at (717) 226-0819. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve facilitated real estate transactions in Central Pennsylvania for more than a decade, and I will happily provide contact information for my previous clients as references.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re only just considering selling your home, you might be interested in finding out what your home is worth in the current Central Pennsylvania market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://akronenberg.kw.com/selling/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Find out what your home is worth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you’re looking to buy, take a look at all the great homes that have recently come on the market in Central Pennsylvania:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://akronenberg.kw.com/search-homes/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for all available Central Pennsylvania homes for sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Have a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 12:23:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /3-real-estate-scams-you-need-to-know-about.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Kronenbergreg.com /3-real-estate-scams-you-need-to-know-about.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I’m pumped, EXCITING NEWS!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed--3-.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends and Clients —&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hooke, Hooke &amp;amp; Eckman Realtors is constantly striving to bring our clients the highest quality of service and the most useful tools to maximize their home buying and selling experience. When pursuing the best for your clients and agents, change is inevitable. I am excited to announce that Hooke, Hooke &amp;amp; Eckman Realtors has formally affiliated with Keller Williams of Central PA!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keller Williams is the #1 real estate company in the world! We are confident that the tools, training and resources available from KW can only improve on the already outstanding service that we are committed to providing our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Hooke, Hooke &amp;amp; Eckman Realtors has formally affiliated with Keller Williams of Central PA!%20http://Kronenbergreg.com /im-pumped-exciting-news.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Hooke, Hooke &amp;amp; Eckman Realtors has formally affiliated with Keller Williams of Central PA!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please know, as an existing or prospective buyer or seller, there is nothing you need to do. This email is intended to make sure you are among the first to know about this exciting new partnership. The terms of your listing and/or buyer representation will not change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please don’t hesitate to contact me directly with any questions. Thank you for your continued trust and I look forward to striving to provide you with an exceptional buying and selling experience!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 12:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /im-pumped-exciting-news.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Kronenbergreg.com /im-pumped-exciting-news.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Can Help You Buy or Sell a South Central Pennsylvania Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-3vSbiDsDQM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Andrew Kronenberg at Hooke, Hooke &amp;amp; Eckman Realtors here in South Central Pennsylvania. &lt;strong&gt;We serve clients up and down the I-81 corridor from Hershey to Chambersburg.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying a new home or selling your current home, we can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our market is moving quickly.&lt;/strong&gt;We have tools that are exclusively available to Realtors to give you the advantage in today’s marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our market is moving quickly, but we have the tools to give you the advantage.%20http://Kronenbergreg.com /how-we-can-help-you-buy-or-sell-a-south-central-pennsylvania-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our market is moving quickly, but we have the tools to give you the advantage.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For buyers, we can provide faster notifications of new homes to the market and get you into showings sooner. For sellers, we offer free maximum value consultations and expansive marketing to get the most effective exposure for your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about real estate, would like to tour a property, or learn about the value of your home,  please don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. My team and I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 09:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /how-we-can-help-you-buy-or-sell-a-south-central-pennsylvania-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Kronenbergreg.com /how-we-can-help-you-buy-or-sell-a-south-central-pennsylvania-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Update on Winter Home Prices in 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cgJeLsyC7fI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This winter is likely to be a very important moment for many home sellers. That’s because three big trends are coming together to affect Lancaster County home prices right now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Housing inventory remains extremely tight. &lt;/strong&gt;The total number of homes on the market fell 10% year over year in the last quarter. This is the biggest drop since 2013, and it’s part of a consistent pattern of very limited and decreasing housing supply. Of course, &lt;strong&gt;the fewer homes there are on the market, the easier it is to sell, and the higher the price you can expect to get.&lt;/strong&gt; Home prices have increased almost 6.5% nationally since last year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Buyers are increasingly optimistic. &lt;/strong&gt;Despite the tight inventory, homebuyers are increasingly optimistic and continue to look for homes. Some of this has to do with the recent growth in income and job stability. Loosening lending standards are also making &lt;strong&gt;many homebuyers eager to take advantage of current mortgage rates, &lt;/strong&gt;which slipped under 4% recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s the perfect time to get in the real estate market.%20http://Kronenbergreg.com /a-quick-update-on-winter-home-prices-in-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s the perfect time to get in the real estate market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The new tax reform bill will impact the market.&lt;/strong&gt; The federal government recently passed the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act, which majorly overhauled our tax code. While it’s unclear how this will affect the real estate market as a whole, &lt;strong&gt;there are some changes that do not favor home sellers.&lt;/strong&gt;  As a result of the changes made to the tax code, the National Association of Realtors now projects slower growth for home prices in 2018, with an appreciation rate of 1% to 3%. By doubling the standard deduction, Congress has significantly reduced the value of mortgage interest and property deductions as tax incentives for homeownership. On the bright side, no changes were made in the rules surrounding capital gains for home sales, which is good news for home sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you put all three of these trends together, two big conclusions emerge. First, &lt;strong&gt;now is a very favorable moment for home sellers,&lt;/strong&gt; thanks to the shortage in the market, the many eager buyers, and the high and rising prices. On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;higher cost, higher tax areas will likely see prices decline&lt;/strong&gt; as the result of new restrictions on mortgage interest and state and local taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to take advantage of the present moment to sell your home, please reach out by giving us a call or sending us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 06:30:49 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /a-quick-update-on-winter-home-prices-in-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Kronenbergreg.com /a-quick-update-on-winter-home-prices-in-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips to Streamline Your Move</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SQzRUm93Pik?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to share five important tips about moving that you can use to make your next move as smooth as possible.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently moved into a different home. I learned quite a bit during the transition. As Realtors, we tend to focus on the technical aspects of real estate. We are professionals in negotiation and marketing. We try to offer extensions of service through different contractor recommendations and different providers for services associated with real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not very often that we go through a full move ourselves. As a result of my recent experience, &lt;strong&gt;I want to share some tips that I learned through the process with the hope that it will make your move a little easier.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, &lt;strong&gt;begin packing and purging as early as possible&lt;/strong&gt; so that you don’t have the stress of a last-minute scramble! We tend to collect things over time, whether they’re hand-me-downs or extra things you’ve outgrown or don’t use anymore. Get rid of those things. Rooms you don’t use should be packed as early as possible so when it comes down to the 11th hour of your move, you’re not scrambling or throwing things in boxes. The purge and the move can happen simultaneously; you can donate or toss things along the way when you’re cleaning up and packing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Secondly, you can hire a moving company. Treat yourself. &lt;strong&gt;Trust when I say that a moving company is worth every dollar.&lt;/strong&gt; They can be expensive, but they offer a whole spectrum of services such as hauling your already-packed belongings to your new home or helping you pack your things in addition to helping you move them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Trust me when I say that a moving company is worth every dollar.%20http://Kronenbergreg.com /5-tips-to-streamline-your-move.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Trust me when I say that a moving company is worth every dollar.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third tip is to contact all your utility companies in advance, usually about two weeks before the move. &lt;strong&gt;Make sure that all your payments and obligations are settled with them.&lt;/strong&gt; You can also schedule installations around the same time for your new home, to save you the hassle of juggling those appointments at the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth, &lt;strong&gt;take off more time from work than you think you need.&lt;/strong&gt;There’s more to moving than getting your stuff from point A to point B. You also have to make time to unpack, organize, decorate, tear down boxes, and a general clean-up. If you try to do it over one weekend, you’ll find that you needed an extra day, and you might dwell on what you have left to do once you’ve returned to work. Before you know it, you’re spending your evenings and weekends for months at a time on finishing those things you didn’t get done initially. So just take a little bit more time and get things finished up.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fifth and most valuable tip is to enjoy it.&lt;/strong&gt; Laugh about it. Things will go wrong, appointments will be missed, installations will be missed, things will break, and certain other things won’t line up the way you imagined. But make the best of it and exercise some humility.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions or have a move coming up, we can help recommend different service providers and moving companies. Feel free to give us a call; helping you move is just an extension of the service that we as real estate agents provide to you. We hope you had a great holiday season, and we wish you health and prosperity in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more tips to make your next move a piece of cake, watch my latest video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 08:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /5-tips-to-streamline-your-move.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Kronenbergreg.com /5-tips-to-streamline-your-move.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Things to Think About When Buying a New Construction Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BFoQmd3gOmE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are going the route of building a home instead of purchasing a resale property, there are three things you need to keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timing your move.&lt;/strong&gt; When you buy a new construction home, your move will not be the simple 30-day or 90-day closing process you would find with resale homes. The process of building a new construction home can take between four and seven months, and sometimes even longer. So, if you’ve got a specific time frame in mind for your move, be sure to account for the time construction will take.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financing.&lt;/strong&gt; There are different financing packages between resale and new construction purchases. Sometimes, new construction loans come with a slightly higher interest rate as well as a few more fees. There are bundle loans available where there is a single settlement, much like you would find with a resale purchase. But oftentimes in new construction loans, there are two settlements: one on the land and one on the total package once construction is complete. My team and I would be happy to partner you with a lender who can help.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Whatever you choose, make sure it is right for you.%20http://Kronenbergreg.com /3-things-to-think-about-when-buying-a-new-construction-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Whatever you choose, make sure it is right for you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The construction process.&lt;/strong&gt; This is what I find most people really struggle with. When you’re looking at building a home, there are two ways you can go about it. You can work with a full custom contractor, which will allow you to control and customize every aspect of the home, or you can work with a volume builder. Volume builders have a set number of home plans that they work with. You can choose between these plans, but you will have limited control over customization. Outside of customization, the main difference between these two options is time. With a full custom home, you have to go to vendors and pick out everything. This can be extremely time-consuming, and the longer you wait on decisions, the longer construction can be set back. Working with a volume builder will generally expedite the process. Whatever you choose, make sure it is right for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 06:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /3-things-to-think-about-when-buying-a-new-construction-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Kronenbergreg.com /3-things-to-think-about-when-buying-a-new-construction-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New housing development in Carlisle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//d1qmdf3vop2l07.cloudfront.net/tall-octopus.cloudvent.net/compressed/440c7dae52612dc019b29cc63333df90.JPG&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; alt=&quot;Click here to read the full article&quot; data-cms-original-src=&quot;/uploads/versions/capture-article-1---x----1000-583x---.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed, there are fewer homes available on the market this year compared to last year, and buyer demand is still very strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, new construction housing is beginning to accelerate. If you are unable to find an existing home, new construction may be an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was recently featured in an article by the Central Penn Business Journal that explores new housing developments in the Carlisle area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Andrew+Kronenberg+/Westward+Homes+Final.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can find the full article here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cumberland Valley School District boasts some of the highest home prices in the county, causing buyers to look elsewhere. Large-scale projects in areas like Silver Spring and Hampden are also winding down. Land in those municipalities are at a premium. &lt;strong&gt;Developers and builders are finding opportunities in the greater Carlisle area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New construction properties won’t satisfy all of the housing demand that we’re seeing right now, but it will provide new options for frustrated homebuyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Builders who historically haven’t explored Carlisle are now looking at the area to find projects, potentially helping boost our inventory over the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I am &lt;strong&gt;currently working on a residential subdivision off Meeting House Road in Carlisle to develop 18 single-family lots.&lt;/strong&gt; These 18 lots will be available for construction in early 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or are interested in a new construction property, just give me a call at (717) 609-8265 or  email me at AndrewK@HHandE.com. I would be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 08:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://Kronenbergreg.com /new-housing-development-in-carlisle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://Kronenbergreg.com /new-housing-development-in-carlisle.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
