<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Spring Mortgage Team is to be your best resource for  real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Spring Mortgage Team, your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://thespringmortgageteam.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 16:35:17 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 16:35:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Are My Property Taxes Calculated?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nhKSxaNUNv8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to talk a little bit about property taxes. The big question people have is, “How are they calculated?” We’re going to answer that for you right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The county you live in assesses the value of your property every year, typically in late spring/early summer. There are also taxing entities that are associated with your property, such as the school district, community hospital, community college, and sometimes a water district. Each of these entities taxes at its own rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The county assesses your property’s value each year.%20https://thespringmortgageteam.com/how-are-my-property-taxes-calculated.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The county assesses your property’s value each year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To determine which entity taxes your property or a property you want to buy, you can go to your county’s assessor’s website (ex. &lt;a href=&quot;Dcad.org&quot;&gt;Dcad.org&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;dentoncad.com&quot;&gt;dentoncad.com&lt;/a&gt;). This will help you figure out what the taxes will be on your current property or on the property you are thinking of buying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about this topic or anything else related to the real estate or mortgage worlds, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 17:18:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/how-are-my-property-taxes-calculated.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thespringmortgageteam.com/how-are-my-property-taxes-calculated.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Know Why Your Mortgage Rates Fluctuate?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i7Sx2rCdWAI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about mortgage rates. What makes them go up? What makes them go down?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I want to start with who owns mortgages. Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, and Ginnie Mae fund virtually all of the traditional mortgage loans in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They sell securities to investors such as private investors, corporate investors, insurance funds, and even foreign governments to fund loans that we write. These places buy these securities because they are backed by the full faith and credit of the U.S. Department of the Treasury. &lt;strong&gt;What causes the rates to go up and down is the demand for those securities.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If investors are buying the securities, then the yields that they pay are going down. This would mean that your interest rates decrease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, and Ginnie Mae fund virtually all of the traditional mortgage loans in the United States.%20https://thespringmortgageteam.com/do-you-know-why-your-mortgage-rates-fluctuate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, and Ginnie Mae fund virtually all of the traditional mortgage loans in the United States.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, if the demand for those securities decreases, then they raise the yield to encourage them to buy more. This, then, would increase the interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about it in terms of the stock market, if your 401(k) is going well, then interest rates are probably going up. If your 401(k) is not doing well, interest rates are probably going down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions about this or anything else that is mortgage related, please feel free to give us a call. We would be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 10:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/do-you-know-why-your-mortgage-rates-fluctuate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thespringmortgageteam.com/do-you-know-why-your-mortgage-rates-fluctuate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Know How Much Home You Can Afford?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B5pFXVc7Ru0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know how much home you can afford? Depending on the loan type you’re using, whether it’s FHA, VA, or a conventional loan, 43% to 50% of your gross monthly income can be used to cover the cost of the home purchase and any associated credit liabilities. The home purchase itself will be comprised of expenses such as taxes, insurance, and, potentially, homeowners association dues. To hear my full message on this subject, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 15:24:14 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/do-you-know-how-much-home-you-can-afford.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thespringmortgageteam.com/do-you-know-how-much-home-you-can-afford.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Document FHA Gift Funds</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pGtm046IFCQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to receiving gift funds for non-conventional loans, there are certain requirements you need to be aware of and restrictions that are placed on the donor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;full account ownership of the donor must be documented and the donor’s ability to gift the money must be verified.&lt;/strong&gt; A full bank statement from your donor must be provided, showing their name, address, account number, and their account balances before and after the gifts funds are taken out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a variety of ways the donor can transfer you the funds in this scenario, but if the money is being transferred to you directly, then we need to document your receipt of that money with an updated transaction history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are a variety of ways the donor can transfer you the funds in this scenario.%20https://thespringmortgageteam.com/how-to-document-fha-gift-funds.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are a variety of ways the donor can transfer you the funds in this scenario.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;if the donor has large deposits on the monthly statement that they provide, they have to document where that money came from&lt;/strong&gt;, as stated in the Patriot Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about the requirements of gift funds for non-conventional loans or you have any other questions, please feel free to reach out to us. We would be more than happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 10:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/how-to-document-fha-gift-funds.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thespringmortgageteam.com/how-to-document-fha-gift-funds.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Escrow Accounts: What They Are and How they Work</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MBw39jdntaY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is an escrow account? How does it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, &lt;strong&gt;an escrow account is put in place during a home purchase to keep the recurring costs associated with homeownership.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you use a mortgage loan to buy a home and you put down less than 20%, federal law requires that there be an escrow account involved in the transaction. Escrow accounts are also required whenever you use an FHA or VA loan to purchase a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you use a mortgage loan to buy a home and you put down less than 20%, federal law requires that there be an escrow account involved in the transaction.%20https://thespringmortgageteam.com/escrow-accounts-what-they-are-and-how-they-work.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you use a mortgage loan to buy a home and you put down less than 20%, federal law requires that there be an escrow account involved in the transaction.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essentially, you “escrow” the future tax and insurance payments of that home.&lt;/strong&gt; One-twelfth of your tax bill is added to your monthly mortgage payment and held in the escrow account so that when your tax bill is due, the mortgage company has enough funds to pay it. The same goes for your insurance bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The due dates for each payment don’t always align—your insurance payment is typically due on the anniversary of your mortgage, and your property tax payment is typically due in December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about escrow accounts and how they function, don’t hesitate to get in touch with me. I’d be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 10:23:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/escrow-accounts-what-they-are-and-how-they-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thespringmortgageteam.com/escrow-accounts-what-they-are-and-how-they-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Would You Need an Access Letter?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kBvyFomZ1BE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ve got questions; we’ve got answers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would we need a letter from someone who’s not on the loan documenting access to an account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this example: A husband and wife have a joint account, but the wife is the only person on the mortgage. There can be a lot of reasons why this may happen—maybe only she has an income, he has bad credit, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The account owner must give the other person access to those funds.%20https://thespringmortgageteam.com/why-would-you-need-an-access-letter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The account owner must give the other person access to those funds.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we do not have both account owners on the loan, however, the account owner must give the other person access to those funds. &lt;strong&gt;We will need an access letter to do this.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, please contact us. We look forward to speaking with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 14:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/why-would-you-need-an-access-letter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thespringmortgageteam.com/why-would-you-need-an-access-letter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Look at How to Start the Mortgage Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sAI-Vx02N-E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to take a quick look at how to get started with the mortgage approval process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start by collecting your name, social security number, address, residence history, and employment history. This information helps complete the base of the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=However you prefer to submit your information, I would be happy to assist you.%20https://thespringmortgageteam.com/a-quick-look-at-how-to-start-the-mortgage-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“However you prefer to submit your information, I would be happy to assist you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three different ways you can provide this information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Face-to-face.&lt;/strong&gt; You are more than welcome to come into my office. I would love to see you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Over the phone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Online.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whichever you prefer, I would be happy to assist you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to let me know by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 10:45:14 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/a-quick-look-at-how-to-start-the-mortgage-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thespringmortgageteam.com/a-quick-look-at-how-to-start-the-mortgage-process.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Quickly Can We Close Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Oz56nemxYkQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How quickly can we close your home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Closing speed largely depends on you, the appraiser, and the terms of the loan.%20https://thespringmortgageteam.com/how-quickly-can-we-close-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Closing speed largely depends on you, the appraiser, and the terms of the loan.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some federal regulations that require waiting periods from the date of the application to the first eligible closing date. There is also a waiting period for the appraisal, as well as for when you receive the initial closing disclosure. We’ve closed loans in eight days, but most between 20 and 25 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ultimately, it’s up to you. If you have further questions about this or anything else real estate related, please give me a call. I would be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 06:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/how-quickly-can-we-close-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thespringmortgageteam.com/how-quickly-can-we-close-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What All Is Included in Closing Costs?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-eo3nvfwyVo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are answering your questions about closing costs. &lt;strong&gt;First, w&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hat are closing costs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the closing table, the three kinds of expenses buyers can expect are the down payment, one-time closing fees, and pre-paid items. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin by talking about down payments. A down payment is a deposit made toward the cost of the home, and usually amounts to a specific percentage of the total list price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The amount of money that you bring to closing will vary based on several factors.%20https://thespringmortgageteam.com/what-all-is-included-in-closing-costs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The amount of money that you bring to closing will vary based on several factors.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next, closing costs are one-time fees associated&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;with the home purchase.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes the appraisal fees, the survey fees, the lender costs, and the cost of title insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, prepaid items are recurring charges. These are things which you will pay continually as a homeowner, such as homeowners insurance, property taxes, or mortgage insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of money that you bring to closing will vary based on the price of the house, your down payment, and your creditworthiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have further questions about this or anything else real estate related, please give me a call. I would be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 09:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/what-all-is-included-in-closing-costs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thespringmortgageteam.com/what-all-is-included-in-closing-costs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rapid Rescoring Your Credit Report</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bj82E8Q9-Mk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is rapid rescoring and what does it do for your credit report? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain circumstances where people have high-revolving credit balances, but are on 0% interest so they don’t feel like it’s a problem to have a high limits-to-balance ratio. They may also have a furniture account that they’re paying monthly installments on, but it’s being reported as a revolving account. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These kinds of situations can have a negative impact on your credit score, but if you have the ability to pay those account balances, &lt;strong&gt;we can help you print off a new statement that shows what your updated balance is and “force-report” those account balances through rapid rescoring.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can do these rapid rescores in usually four or five days.%20https://thespringmortgageteam.com/rapid-rescoring-your-credit-report.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We can do these rapid rescores in usually four or five days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, creditors only report to the credit scoring models only once a month, and if you have a 25- or 30-day timeline for your mortgage approval or closing, you need the ability to do these rapid rescores to get your score up and save money. We can do these rapid rescores in usually four or five days, depending on which creditor you’re paying off. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about how rapid rescoring works or you’re in need of a rapid rescore, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. If you have any other questions, I’d be happy to answer those too. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 10:06:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://thespringmortgageteam.com/rapid-rescoring-your-credit-report.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thespringmortgageteam.com/rapid-rescoring-your-credit-report.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
