<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Kati Spaniak, a top Real Estate Agent in Chicago, shares her own internal real estate agent training for free. Her Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>http://realestategrit.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://realestategrit.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 10:47:22 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 10:47:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Set Boundaries With Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PLB2Wthuk-Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest complaints among those working in real estate is that it’s a 24/7 job. In truth, though, it doesn’t have to be. In fact, it shouldn’t be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found yourself up in the middle of the night texting or emailing a buyer or seller? If so, then it’s time to establish some boundaries. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do you do so? What’s the best way to establish boundaries with your clients?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three main steps you need to take: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Think about what you want your life to be like.&lt;/strong&gt; For some, this means being off-the-clock by a certain time of night. If you don’t want clients to text you at 11 p.m., then make it clear from the beginning that you’re only available until 6 p.m. Making a clear distinction between which points in your day (and your week) are dedicated to clients and which points are dedicated to your personal life will be essential to maintaining a good work/life balance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Sticking to your boundaries will improve your well-being both on and off the clock.%20http://realestategrit.net/how-to-set-boundaries-with-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Sticking to your boundaries will improve your well-being both on and off the clock.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Figure out how much you want to work on weekends.&lt;/strong&gt; Many showings occur on the weekends, but this doesn’t mean you have to be available at every waking minute of every day. If a client calls you and wants to see a house, simply tell them when you’re available. Keep that window of time consistent so that you still have time for yourself and your loved ones. Everyone needs time off, after all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Don’t break your own boundaries.&lt;/strong&gt; If you give an inch, people will take a mile. For your own sake (and for your family’s sake), make sure that you stick to the boundaries you set for yourself. Doing so will improve your well-being both on and off the clock. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 10:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-to-set-boundaries-with-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestategrit.net/how-to-set-boundaries-with-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is It Like to Be an Agent?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BgMMT_aTpqs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often at the end of a particularly difficult deal, clients will ask me, “How do you do it?” Well, the more I think about it, this is an interesting question. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And now that I’ve taken some time to consider my answer, it’s really quite simple: I do this because I love helping people.&lt;/strong&gt; Buying or selling a home is much more than just a simple, run-of-the-mill business transaction. There’s a lot of emotion that goes along with it. And, as an agent, I know that I need to play a much greater role than just that of a salesperson. I have to be someone who they can trust to guide them through a massive step in their life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The job of an agent is often much more than just a job.%20http://realestategrit.net/what-is-it-like-to-be-an-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The job of an agent is often much more than just a job.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are a real estate agent, being communicative, patient, and open-minded is a must. Buyers and sellers give their agents a window into some very personal aspects of their lives, so having these qualities is essential. Buyers and sellers deserve to know that their agent will keep private matters private. Honesty, confidentiality, and respect are very important. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With that said, though, I also find it important to be honest even when it’s uncomfortable. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, the job of an agent is often much more than just a job. And, personally, I wouldn’t have it any other way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like to speak in greater detail on this topic, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 14:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/what-is-it-like-to-be-an-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestategrit.net/what-is-it-like-to-be-an-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Should Agents Select Homes to Show Clients?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LOPQTnz6FAQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are working with a buyer, you should really only show them a maximum of eight to 10 homes. If you are providing services like a buyer consultation up front, you should not have to show them more properties than this. &lt;strong&gt;Buyers these days are very busy, so it is important not to waste their time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I like to streamline the process by having a conversation with my clients about what non-negotiable features their future home must have. It is essential that you find out what a client needs and wants in a home. Knowing what is important to them will guide you in selecting viable properties. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it is also important to be honest with your clients. If their list of wants and needs isn’t feasible, you have to tell them that. Your buyers should have a realistic expectation of the kinds of homes that are available. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As agents, we know what is available. &lt;strong&gt;Our clients shouldn’t have to tour 50 different homes to learn something we already know. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Knowing what is important to your clients will guide you to selecting viable properties.%20http://realestategrit.net/how-should-agents-select-homes-to-show-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Knowing what is important to your clients will guide you to selecting viable properties.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if a client says they have a non-negotiable budget of $500,000 or less, but they also demand to see homes of a specific size and in a specific location, you must be honest with them about their prospects. And as you explain their options, make sure you continually check in with whether they are comfortable with the choices you are laying out for them. Clients should understand that you are not going to show them homes that do not fit their criteria. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet this does not mean clients will not ask you to show them homes that do not make sense. This is why you, as their agent, should do your research before taking them to any property they suggest. &lt;strong&gt;If the property they are pushing you toward truly is not a good fit, I would advise you to steer them away from it. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you may have to reevaluate their preferences and needs later on in the process. If you have toured dozens of homes with no results, something is wrong. At this point, it is time to go back to basics and get to the bottom of what your clients are looking for in a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 16:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-should-agents-select-homes-to-show-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestategrit.net/how-should-agents-select-homes-to-show-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Build Relationships With Potential Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3joo0aZ5Bag?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it interesting to watch how people work with their clients. So, I decided that today I am going to talk about how to build relationships with potential clients.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;I have found that &lt;strong&gt;coming across as a consultant results in people trusting and valuing you.&lt;/strong&gt; Years ago, I took a sales training class where they talked about how you cannot go into a situation feeling like you need the money. If you go in thinking that you are financially secure, you are going to build a relationship with that potential client.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;I come from a place of giving back to my clients. When you meet someone, you really want to listen to what they are looking for and decide if you are really able to help them. &lt;strong&gt;If you are not able, tell them.&lt;/strong&gt; You will get much further in life with your client by being honest.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Sometimes this means that you must be a little confrontational. I am personally not great at being confrontational, so I try to tone it down. For agents who have a really hard time with needing to be liked by everyone, this can be a little challenging.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The client needs to understand that they will not necessarily get everything that they want.%20http://realestategrit.net/how-to-build-relationships-with-potential-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The client needs to understand that they will not necessarily get everything that they want.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An example of this is when you have a client who has specific wants. They want a 3-bedroom, 3-bathroom home within walking distance to downtown and is completely updated for $500,000. This is not possible, but some agents will neglect to tell their clients this and instead tell them they will find it.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The client needs to understand that they will not necessarily get everything that they want. When they start their home search and discover that nothing is matching well, that is a problem. &lt;strong&gt;It is your job to guide them using your communication skills.&lt;/strong&gt; You must have those uncomfortable conversations so you don’t end up showing them 20 homes and none of them match. If this happens, they will eventually go to another agent.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You really have to understand what a client is looking for and be honest with them.&lt;/strong&gt; You need to guide them and communicate with them that they may not get exactly what they want. Being honest may lead to you not getting the sale, but the client will view you as trustworthy.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;So, when I am working with people, I really try and connect with them as a consultant. I provide them information about the real estate industry and am sure to be myself. I enjoy hearing their story and deciding if I can help them or not.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;To find out more about how to build relationships with your clients, please feel free to contact me. I would be happy to speak with you further about this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 14:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-to-build-relationships-with-potential-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestategrit.net/how-to-build-relationships-with-potential-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Looking for New People to Sell Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ov1f553QeRo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does anyone in your circle of family, friends, co-workers, or acquaintances want to sell real estate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are always looking for great additions to the team, and we’re not just searching for people with experience in real estate—&lt;strong&gt;we’re looking for anyone who is personable, authentic, great with sales, hard-working, and self-accountable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at the Spaniak Team, &lt;strong&gt;we offer the opportunity to learn, grow, get leads, and start out your career using a base of people you know.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=On our team, we think that you should be making at least $50,000 in your first year.%20http://realestategrit.net/were-looking-for-new-people-to-sell-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“On our team, we think that you should be making at least $50,000 in your first year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of times, agents get into the business and it takes a few years in order for them to start making money. However, on our team, we think that you should be making at least $50,000 in your first year. In your second year, we hope that you can even make as much as $150,000 or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So think about it: Do you know anyone who would be a great fit on our team? If so, please forward this email to them. &lt;strong&gt;You can access the information about how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://realestategrit.net/join-our-team&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;apply here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s okay if you don’t know of anyone right now—but keep this in mind for the future. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 11:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/were-looking-for-new-people-to-sell-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestategrit.net/were-looking-for-new-people-to-sell-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Slowly but Surely Built a Successful Real Estate Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9EwEnPP1CHk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People ask me all the time, “How did you get started in real estate?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to tell you the answer to this question. So, let’s take a look back at how I got my start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I entered this industry back in 2003 when I got my license and began working as part of a real estate team. This chapter in my career lasted until about 2008, when I left the team and took a few years off from this path. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, though, I did come back. I got a new license in 2012 and started up the team that I am still leading today. Since then, &lt;strong&gt;I have built my business to be among the top real estate professionals on the North Shore of Chicago and the Number One Team in Northbrook. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, actually, being in the business prior to founding my current team proved to be a great benefit as I re-entered the industry. It gave me time to really focus on my business plan, as well as my plan for daily activities. Immediately after re-entering real estate, I was very committed to dedicating certain days and times to being in the office working on my business plan. From the very beginning, my goal was to be the No. 1 agent in Northbrook. I wanted people in this community to think of me as their go-to real estate professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, once I had developed a plan, I began reaching out to people. I started sending out emails, I took out a little bit of advertising space, and I began providing market evaluations for community members. And I did this because whether people are moving or not, everyone loves real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I wanted people in this community to think of me as their go-to real estate professional.%20http://realestategrit.net/how-i-slowly-but-surely-built-a-successful-real-estate-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I wanted people in this community to think of me as their go-to real estate professional.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diving deeper into real estate was a slow-going process, but I kept going.&lt;/strong&gt; I continued to put my name out there and provide services for the community, knowing that it would eventually pay off. After about six months of doing this, people began to notice. They would say things like, “You’re everywhere!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In actuality, I wasn’t everywhere. I was just making sure to stay visible in the places that mattered. I kept my focus small and found my niche. Doing this, in my opinion, is one of the keys to building a business. &lt;strong&gt;Being persistent without making people feel as though they are being constantly sold to is what put me on the path to success.&lt;/strong&gt; If you hope to build a business, you have to show people what kind of value you can provide for them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if someone has no immediate real estate need, it is good to establish yourself as a resource. That way when the time does come for them to make a move, they know who to reach out to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way I got my start and established myself within the community was by hosting roundtable discussions about Northbrook. Doing this allowed me to meet a lot of people without spending a lot of money in the process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything you do as an agent should be done with a certain question in mind: &lt;strong&gt;“What do people need and want from you as a real estate agent?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an agent is not about being a salesperson&lt;em&gt;—&lt;/em&gt;it is about being someone who the community can turn to for their real estate needs. If you work toward this and do so consistently, you are sure to find success in your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 12:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-i-slowly-but-surely-built-a-successful-real-estate-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestategrit.net/how-i-slowly-but-surely-built-a-successful-real-estate-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Generate Leads</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GzI0K9vS8kM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generating leads is a huge part of growing your business. You can get started by simply picking up the phone and making some calls—and it works great! &lt;strong&gt;But the reasoning behind why this works goes much deeper.&lt;/strong&gt; What you’re really doing is nurturing a relationship with your database of contacts, so today I’ll be sharing with you how to find those leads and turn them into future clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For your convenience, I’ve included timestamps of the video topic. Feel free to navigate to the section(s) you’re most interested in viewing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What you’re really doing is nurturing a relationship with your database of contacts.%20http://realestategrit.net/how-to-generate-leads.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What you’re really doing is nurturing a relationship with your database of contacts.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;00:12— Introduction to today’s topic: How to get leads&lt;br /&gt;00:57— The best way to get leads&lt;br /&gt;01:54— Cultivating relationships is more important than finding leads&lt;br /&gt;02:55— How to position yourself as a valuable source&lt;br /&gt;03:50— If they choose someone else, it’s nothing personal&lt;br /&gt;04:36— The ultimate goal: Connecting on a personal level&lt;br /&gt;05:50— Anyone can be a lead&lt;br /&gt;06:10— Summary of today’s topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need further information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 13:54:40 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-to-generate-leads.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestategrit.net/how-to-generate-leads.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Should Sellers Approach Our Spring Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KAZcuGNziBM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should we expect from our spring market in 2019? Specifically, what should sellers do to prepare for it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started 2019 with a great spike in activity, and my team and I sold a handful of properties that had been on the market for months. With that in mind, my advice for sellers as we move toward spring is to &lt;strong&gt;list your house as soon as possible.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s true that the weather is better come springtime, buyers are out shopping for homes all year long. You may need to work around bouts of extreme cold, but it’s important for your home to be on the market even if the market isn’t great.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Buyers can be difficult, and they like to look at houses online before seeing them in person, so your first order of business should be to &lt;strong&gt;make your home’s online listing photos look perfect.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, don’t go overboard with how many photos you use. When I take photos of a home, I usually don’t use more than 15 or 20 shots unless it’s a luxury home or a new construction home. Why? You don’t need to document every inch of your house, and if a buyer sees a bathroom that needs to be redone, they’ll count that as a reason not to look at the house in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=My advice for sellers as we move toward spring is to list your house as soon as possible.%20http://realestategrit.net/how-should-sellers-approach-our-spring-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“My advice for sellers as we move toward spring is to list your house as soon as possible.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing you can consider doing is &lt;strong&gt;virtual staging&lt;/strong&gt;. I don’t always do this with my sellers because I find it to be a little deceptive, but it does help attract buyers. For example, one of my sellers has a house with carpeted floors, but underneath the carpet is hardwood, so that’s what we showed in the home’s pictures. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with every other time of year, &lt;strong&gt;you also need to make sure you price your home correctly&lt;/strong&gt;. If your home is still unsold when June or July rolls around because it’s priced too high, you might end up in a race to the bottom with other panicked home sellers who have to slash their prices and ride the market down. The trick is to get under the market—not ride it down. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I predict that we’ll see the same type of spring market this year that we saw last year. In the meantime, we’re off to a pretty good start and we’ll see how the rest of February goes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about our upcoming spring market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 11:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-should-sellers-approach-our-spring-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestategrit.net/how-should-sellers-approach-our-spring-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Most Important of the 20 C’s: Coachable</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g4q-elARbnI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to separate yourself from all the other agents out there and take your career to the next level, you need to remember the 20 C’s. In time, I’ll share all of these with you and explain why each one is important, but for today I’ll start with the most important C: coachable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an agent, &lt;strong&gt;you have to be coachable.&lt;/strong&gt; This isn’t about needing to hire a coach; it’s about opening your eyes to the opportunities that are out there to learn from. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can sit down with anyone, even those who don’t have as much experience as me, and learn something from them. Why? Because my eyes are open. I’m willing to listen to them, and I believe that everybody has something to provide me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This isn’t about you getting a coach; it’s about you opening your eyes to the opportunities that are out there to learn from.%20http://realestategrit.net/the-most-important-of-the-20-cs-coachable.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This isn’t about you getting a coach; it’s about you opening your eyes to the opportunities that are out there to learn from.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Along with being coachable, you have to continue your education.&lt;/strong&gt; In real estate, education means learning about the real estate industry and learning how to sell. You have to do these things if you want to be successful, and that’s why being coachable is so valuable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So open your mind and keep education at the forefront of your life. Every day I educate myself, and ever since I started doing this, my business has taken off. And don’t forget to learn from other people—even if you think they don’t know anything, they probably do, and you can identify bits and pieces of information that can help you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To register for my next agent seminar where I’ll talk more in depth about the 20 C’s, &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://quaxel2.net/v1/track/click/498ad698-b2a2-8be0-021e-7c3c05f6bd18/gm%3A5b8faa64-67bd-46c3-9ce3-ac36a4037325/jarodd%40getvyral.com/?https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eventbrite.com%2Fe%2Fhow-to-sell-more-homes-this-winter-and-make-money-before-the-spring-market-by-kati-spaniak-tickets-52107645370=&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you want to talk more about the relationship between coachability and success or you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 09:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/the-most-important-of-the-20-cs-coachable.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestategrit.net/the-most-important-of-the-20-cs-coachable.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Benefits of Joining a Real Estate Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7thtErq2wgo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should you join a real estate team? I hear this question a lot. Our team has five licensed agents in addition to myself, and here’s what I think about real estate teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A team environment is not for everyone.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s for agents who want to make good money, who want to sell, and who don’t necessarily need to have their name out there in lights. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s how my team is set up.&lt;/strong&gt; I have five buyer’s agents and I take care of all the listings. In addition, I have a director of operations, a listing manager, and am currently hiring a transaction coordinator. I also have three unlicensed assistants, as well as a full-time runner. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a full-service team with our own office and we work pretty independently. &lt;strong&gt;Our goal is to make life awesome for our agents by providing leads, transaction coordination, and other support.&lt;/strong&gt; If you like working with a team and like the camaraderie, we provide a ton of value.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=100% of nothing is still nothing.%20http://realestategrit.net/what-are-the-benefits-of-joining-a-real-estate-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“100% of nothing is still nothing.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agents on my team have minimal expenses. They pay for their MLS fees and dues, but we pay for all the leads, marketing expenses, and office expenses that they might have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of agents get hung up on the splits. What I’d say to that is that &lt;strong&gt;100% of nothing is still nothing.&lt;/strong&gt; On a team, you can make more money than you can as a regular agent, and it’s much more consistent too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being on a team isn’t easy, especially if you’re an agent on my team. I want people who are dedicated and focused on their careers and who want to work hard. I listen to what agents want and take it very seriously. If you tell me you want to make $150,000 per year and you aren’t taking the necessary steps to get there, I will let you know that and push you to reach your goals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My team members don’t have to pay for coaching because I am their coach.&lt;/strong&gt; I provide resources, support, and a full CRM for our agents. I also hold them accountable to their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, that’s what it’s like to be on a team like mine. I’m always looking for great team members so if you think you have what it takes based on what you’ve heard, feel free to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 12:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/what-are-the-benefits-of-joining-a-real-estate-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://realestategrit.net/what-are-the-benefits-of-joining-a-real-estate-team.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
