<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Real Estate Video Blog with Ashley Carter</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carter Property Group - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 12:34:11 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 12:34:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Condo Building Helping or Hurting You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AT8BttrfY3E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a condo owner, certain factors can make or break your home sale—factors unrelated to your actual unit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I have a question for condo and townhome owners: &lt;strong&gt;Is your building helping or hurting you? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re selling one of these properties, you’re inextricably connected to the entire building, and certain factors can affect your prospect of finding a buyer. Take a moment to look around. What kind of first impression does the building give off from the sidewalk, lobby, etc.? Does the building contain elevators? Put another way, what do you see as you make your way to your unit? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To buyers, the building your condo is situated in is a direct reflection of the unit itself. They’ll pass judgment on the building’s overall maintenance and whether it looks like a high level of care goes into the property. &lt;strong&gt;Before the buyer ever sets foot in your actual home, there’s a chance that they’ve already decided whether they’ll give it serious consideration just based on their perception of your building.&lt;/strong&gt; Needless to say, it’s very important that the building you choose to move into doesn’t work against your future sale. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=My advice is to be involved and do your due diligence along the way to ensure some easy wins when you go to sell your property.%20http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/is-your-condo-building-helping-or-hurting-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“My advice is to be involved and do your due diligence along the way to ensure some easy wins when you go to sell your property.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the building’s appearance, &lt;strong&gt;buyers will want to know how much your condo association has in cash reserves and the property’s history concerning its maintenance schedule. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answering these questions will only help you as a future seller. Too often, condo sellers have to overcome buyers’ objections to the building’s mismanagement or its poor condition—the effects of which put you at a disadvantage right out of the gate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice is to be involved and do your due diligence along the way to ensure some easy wins when you go to sell your property.&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or if you plan to sell your condo sometime in the future and you’d like some help determining what you should be spending your time and money on, please reach out to the Carter Property Group. We’d be happy to counsel you in that effort, and we look forward to hearing from you! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/is-your-condo-building-helping-or-hurting-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/is-your-condo-building-helping-or-hurting-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Data on Our Chicago Housing Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YYHBpw2BCWk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today we’ll look at some recent data from the end of August having to do with our Chicago market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end-of-August numbers are in for our Chicago real estate market. What do they tell us about the current landscape? Let’s pore over the numbers pertaining to single-family homes to find out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we do, note that we’ll analyze each data point by doing a 10-year, three-year, and one-year lookback. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to follow along in the video above or use the timestamps below to navigate this market update at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:37—An often-forgotten point about the economics of the housing market &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:00—Median sales price &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:53—Months’ supply of homes for sale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:46—Closed sales  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:46—Cause and effect of closed sales plus median sales price &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:10—The distinction between leading indicators and lagging indicators &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8:45—My take on the overall state of the market &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:02—The key takeaways for homebuyers &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:54—The key takeaways for sellers &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:45—Wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what we covered today or about anything else real estate-related, please don’t hesitate to let us know. We’d look forward to hearing from you! &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/the-latest-data-on-our-chicago-housing-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/the-latest-data-on-our-chicago-housing-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Does Home Staging Work?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vW4t28G7xm4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preparing your home properly is essential in having a successful home sale. Here’s why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we’re consulting with home sellers, one of the most common questions we hear is, “Is staging worth it? Does it really work?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are two things that we can do to most effectively sell properties.&lt;/strong&gt; The first is pricing competitively. The second is preparing the property for sale. Typically, staging is directly tied to both of these components. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a property has too much furniture, not enough furniture, or not the right size of furniture, staging can make a significant difference. If you have oddly shaped rooms, staging can really help there, too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Staging helps with small or oddly shaped rooms.%20http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/does-home-staging-work.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Staging helps with small or oddly shaped rooms.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In an ideal world, your property should be cleaned, painted, and staged.&lt;/strong&gt; The staging is the icing on the cake of the final presentation that buyers are looking for. It’s a major factor in the home-selling process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about selling a home or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/does-home-staging-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/does-home-staging-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are Fixer-Uppers Hot or Not?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/earZMpFsxVc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are homebuyers still eyeing fixer-uppers these days? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The short answer is no.&lt;/strong&gt; We live in an increasingly fast-paced world where people want what they want on demand, and real estate is no exception. Homebuyers are seeking move-in ready, hassle-free properties that they can swiftly close on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, the running joke has been that buyers are looking to have the moving truck show up at 10 a.m. sharp, so they can welcome guests to the cookout at their new home by 5 p.m. that evening. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buyers of today don’t want to have to tackle a long list of upgrades after closing on a home.%20http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/are-fixer-uppers-hot-or-not.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buyers of today don’t want to have to tackle a long list of upgrades after closing on a home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this is meant to be hyperbole, but the fact remains: &lt;strong&gt;Buyers of today don’t want to have to tackle a long list of upgrades after closing on a home.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t emphasize enough how important it is for you, as a seller, to get your home in prime condition. Otherwise, buyers won’t even give it a second glance because they know they’ll have the ability to borrow more money for a home in better condition and at an exceptionally low interest rate.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;strong&gt;as a seller, you want to extract the most value out of your home sale, so we need to make a concerted effort to ensure your home is in turnkey shape.&lt;/strong&gt; For any questions related to real estate or if you or someone you know would like to make a move, please let us know today. We’d be happy to help!       &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/are-fixer-uppers-hot-or-not.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/are-fixer-uppers-hot-or-not.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When Is the Best Time to Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ka7j_Apj0wY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers often ask me when the best time to sell their home is in today’s market. The answer actually depends on one key thing: you. Ask yourself—are you ready to put in the time, money, and energy that’s necessary to prep your home for sale? In today’s competitive market, your home needs to look and feel perfect from the moment a buyer steps foot inside. So the best time to list is actually whenever your home is ready to show. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/when-is-the-best-time-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/when-is-the-best-time-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Did You Miss Your Chance to Sell Your Home for Top Dollar?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iAQp6dE2tWg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers are often under the impression that there’s a particular time of year when they should be putting their home on the market—that time is, of course, spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve discussed in previous videos, the reality is that **the right time to sell your home is when it best suits your situation. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been doing this a long time, and we’ve found that it doesn’t make sense to wait an entire year for the spring market to come back around. Unless your goals specifically line up with that time of year, here’s something to consider: Buyers populate our Chicago market and are looking to make a purchase every week and month of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Why wait a whole year when you’re unsure of what the future will bring?%20http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/did-you-miss-your-chance-to-sell-your-home-for-top-dollar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Why wait a whole year when you’re unsure of what the future will bring?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, you’re probably not doing yourself any favors by trying to sync up your home sale with a seasonal market. &lt;strong&gt;There’s no telling what market conditions will be like a year from now.&lt;/strong&gt; Home prices could very well flatten out or even go down and, given that the market is always shifting, that’s a real possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortening your time frame to a comfortable point gives us a chance to predict what the market will be doing and will lead to greater certainty in your sale. **Why wait a whole year when you’re unsure of what the future will bring? **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know would like an evaluation of a property or you’re thinking about making a real estate move, don’t hesitate to let us know. We look forward to speaking with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/did-you-miss-your-chance-to-sell-your-home-for-top-dollar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/did-you-miss-your-chance-to-sell-your-home-for-top-dollar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recapping the U.S.’s 2018 Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/R-qZcxANBxc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to take the opportunity today to give you the full rundown of how our 2018 market fared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five central data points that drive real estate: home sales, home price, months’ supply of inventory, mortgage rates, and affordability. I’ll take a deep dive into these stats on the national scale.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National home sales for 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5.3 million total homes sold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Down from 2016 and 2017&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matched the number for 2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projected to fall slightly to 5.2 million in 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National home prices for 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished with a year-over-year appreciation of 5%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anticipated to increase in 2019&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase is projected to be in the 1% to 5% range&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National months&amp;rsquo; supply of inventory for 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished with four months’ worth of inventory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dating back to 2013, our seller’s market has persisted due to:  
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Number of new construction homes remaining low&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ever-increasing interest rates&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Homeowners staying put for longer&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National mortgage rates for 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased almost a full percentage point from early 2018 to year’s end&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Currently hovering at 4.5%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rates are still at historical lows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National affordability for 2018 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished slightly up, as compared to 2017’s market&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since 1970, we still sit below average affordability index&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do these numbers bear out for the future of our real estate market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All in all, the national housing market is relatively healthy and will remain stable in 2019&lt;/strong&gt;—homes are selling well and interest rates have stayed fairly moderate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for those looking to buy in 2019, we aren’t going to see homes flying off the market nor will they appreciate to an astronomical extent. If your real estate goals for this year include making a home purchase, a golden opportunity awaits you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in a conversation around what your options might be in any aspect of residential real estate, please give us a call. We look forward to having that conversation with you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/recapping-the-u-s-s-2018-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/recapping-the-u-s-s-2018-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q_aN_rriDzk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Happy holidays!%20http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/happy-holidays.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Happy holidays!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe that 2018 is almost over. As the holidays are fast approaching, we want to take a moment to wish you and your family a warm and safe holiday season. It’s the season of giving, and we’d like to give you some insight into fun events going on in the area. Check out the list below to see our recommendations for ways to spend the season:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christkindlmarket.com/chicago/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CHRISTKINDLMARKET&lt;/a&gt; - Now through December 24th, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msichicago.org/explore/whats-here/exhibits/christmas-around-the-world/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Christmas Around the World, Museum of Science &amp;amp; Industry&lt;/a&gt; - Now through January 6th, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lpzoo.org/pressroom/lincoln-park-zoo-announces-24th-annual-zoolights-events-and-activities&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zoolights at Lincoln Park’s Zoo&lt;/a&gt; - Now through January 6th, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cityofchicago.org/city/en/depts/dca/supp_info/millennium_park10.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ice Skating in Millennium Park&lt;/a&gt; - December 14th 2018-March 10th, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mortonarb.org/events/illumination-tree-lights-morton-arboretum&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Illumination: Tree Lights at Morton Arboretum&lt;/a&gt; - Now through January 1st&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodmantheatre.org/carol&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Christmas Carol at Goodman Theater&lt;/a&gt; - December 14th 2018 - December 30th 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chicagobotanic.org/wonderland&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wonderland Express at Chicago Botanic Garden&lt;/a&gt; - November 23 – December 21, 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://navypier.org/event/fifth-third-bank-winter-wonderfest-2018/all/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Winter Wonderfest at Navy Pier&lt;/a&gt; - Now through January 6th, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon. Happy Holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/happy-holidays.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/happy-holidays.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Take Exterior Home Photos Now Before Winter Arrives</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/taDl6x7eCSE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall will be over before you know it, and with winter will come plenty of snow. This is why, if you plan on selling your home sometime between now and next spring, it’s an opportune time to take exterior photographs of it now before the white stuff comes down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Because 92% of homebuyers see homes online first, it’s important that you have photographs that leave a good impression&lt;/strong&gt;. If you take photos now, potential buyers will see a home bathed in autumnal colors instead of a white winter wasteland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We will come and take professional photos for you.%20http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/take-exterior-home-photos-now-before-winter-arrives.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We will come and take professional photos for you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you make this great first impression, we will come and take professional photos for you if you’re planning on selling this spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to take advantage of this offer, have any questions, or would like some more information, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/take-exterior-home-photos-now-before-winter-arrives.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/take-exterior-home-photos-now-before-winter-arrives.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Have What It Takes to Join Our Growing Team?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HNdQlv1fuhE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got an exciting announcement to make today. We’re looking to make a key addition to our team. We want a talented individual to come be the heartbeat of our day-to-day business operations. We’re looking for someone who loves to build and manage systems, wants to have a high level of client interaction, and wants to accomplish goals on behalf of our clients and our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This opportunity has a lot of upside potential to take on more responsibility and make more money as responsibilities and results accrue.%20http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/do-you-have-what-it-takes-to-join-our-growing-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This opportunity has a lot of upside potential to take on more responsibility and make more money as responsibilities and results accrue.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This opportunity has a lot of upside potential to take on more responsibility and make more money as responsibilities and results accrue. To learn more about the position and what we’re looking for, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;if-you-or-someone-you-know-is-interested-and-wants-more-details-about-the-position-click-herehttpss3amazonawscomvyralmarketingashleycarterashleycarternowhiringpdf-targetblank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you or someone you know is interested and wants more details about the position,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Ashley+Carter+Now+Hiring.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/do-you-have-what-it-takes-to-join-our-growing-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/do-you-have-what-it-takes-to-join-our-growing-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
