<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carbutti &amp; Co Realtors - your professional New Haven &amp; Fairfield County Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 14:28:28 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 14:28:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Storm N Norman of WEBE108 Stands by Our Professional Service</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m-mMT7ok9wI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why choose Carbutti &amp;amp; Co for your real estate needs? Find out from radio personality Storm N Norman from WEBE108.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may already be familiar with the smooth voice of radio personality Storm N Norman from WEBE108. &lt;strong&gt;We’re well-acquainted with him, as he’s been coming to us for all of his real estate needs for years.&lt;/strong&gt; He even recommends us to friends, family members, and listeners who are looking to buy or sell homes — that’s how much he trusts the professional service we offer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like help with your real estate needs, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 12:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-storm-n-norman-of-webe108-stands-by-our-professional-service.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-storm-n-norman-of-webe108-stands-by-our-professional-service.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Marketing in a Successful Real Estate Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/j3xY32TB8g0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A career in the real estate business is also a career in the marketing business. Here’s why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re almost into 2020, but before we get there, I have a message for you. Everybody wants to get into the real estate business, but &lt;strong&gt;if you’re getting into the real estate business right now, you’re actually getting into the marketing business as well.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, when you’re thinking about a career in real estate, you’re entering one of the most competitive businesses out there. This means that you don’t want to look like everyone else. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to stand out from the crowd. &lt;strong&gt;The best way to stand out is through your marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether it’s through radio, TV, advertising, social media, you have got to look different than every other agent and you’ve got to make an impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You want to stand out from the crowd in this business.%20http://localhost:4000/the-importance-of-marketing-in-a-successful-real-estate-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You want to stand out from the crowd in this business.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Carbutti and Co., we’re committed to having a social media manager, along with different marketing strategies and value propositions. If you’re thinking about a career in real estate and you don’t want to go it alone, give us a call or send us an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 09:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-importance-of-marketing-in-a-successful-real-estate-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-importance-of-marketing-in-a-successful-real-estate-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Does Jessica Durbin Recommend Carbutti &amp; Co.?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nFfpBcu80I0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jessica Durbin has known our team for years and has even referred family to us. Here’s why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica Durbin has worked for Connoisseur Media for a little over three years and has been in the radio business for over two decades. As someone who used to have a license, she appreciated the business that we have built even more after getting to know us for the past eight years. We put tons of marketing and support into our agents to help them succeed, and that’s just one of the reasons that Jessica has referred us to her family and friends over the years. “If I were looking to buy or sell my home, I would absolutely refer Jonathan Carbutti and Carbutti and Company Realtors,” Jessica said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ever have any questions about real estate, please feel free to reach out to us by phone or email. We would love the chance to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 14:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-does-jessica-durbin-recommend-carbutti-co.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-does-jessica-durbin-recommend-carbutti-co.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer 2019 Market Update</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KBsi2yGyWqM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Summer is winding down, but our market isn’t. Let’s discuss what’s happening now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re in the dog days of summer, but don’t think because the weather is set to cool down soon that our market is, as well. Homes are still selling, and many are getting multiple offers. We’re still in desperate need of inventory, so if you’re thinking of listing, don’t delay. Whether you’ve got plans to buy or sell, it’s a great time to make a move. And our team here at Carbutti Real Estate would be happy to help you make the most of your goals. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 11:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/summer-2019-market-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/summer-2019-market-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Nominated for the Reader’s Choice Awards!</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rmlio6_L8A8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carbutti &amp;amp; Co. has been nominated for best real estate company and best real estate!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to announce that Carbutti &amp;amp; Co. has been nominated for best real estate company and best real estate team for the 2019 Record-Journal Readers Choice Awards. We’re honored by the nomination, and we’d be humbled if you would show your support for us by &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://GetCarbutti.com&quot;&gt;voting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. To learn more about the contest, watch this short video. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 14:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/were-nominated-for-the-readers-choice-awards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/were-nominated-for-the-readers-choice-awards.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now Is the Time to Buy a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E-nP10Yk85c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all potential homebuyers: If you are curious about taking a look at some properties that interest you, or if you’re wondering whether or not you qualify for a mortgage, I want you to reach out to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you meet with me or one of our team’s real estate professionals, we’ll:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walk you through the whole home buying process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer all of your questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show you all the mortgage products available to you, including no-money-down loans, VA loans (for veterans), and FHA 203k rehab loans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get you pre-approved for a mortgage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many different options for buyers in today’s marketplace. In fact, I’d even argue that &lt;strong&gt;there’s never been a better time to buy a home&lt;/strong&gt;—so many different conditions in the market are working in your favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=So many different conditions in the market are working in your favor.%20http://localhost:4000/now-is-the-time-to-buy-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“So many different conditions in the market are working in your favor.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never bought a home before, or haven’t in a few years, I encourage you to reach out to me. Let’s set up a buyer consultation where we can discuss your options and help to get you into the home of your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 13:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/now-is-the-time-to-buy-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/now-is-the-time-to-buy-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your Update on the Spring 2019 Marketplace</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lsDsApTxBiI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a seller who has been thinking about putting your home on the spring market, now is the time to get a move on and actually do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our market, we can’t keep these properties long enough. &lt;strong&gt;There is so much pent-up demand from buyers&lt;/strong&gt; who have been in the marketplace for three to six months and haven’t yet seen anything they like. They’re just waiting for something new to come on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is the time to put your home on the market and take advantage of all this demand from buyers in the marketplace.%20http://localhost:4000/your-update-on-the-spring-2019-marketplace.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is the time to put your home on the market and take advantage of all this demand from buyers in the marketplace.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago, we were in a situation where we put a nice 3-bedroom, 2.5-bathroom, colonial starter home with a one-car garage on the market at 9 a.m. on a Friday morning. &lt;strong&gt;We had seven requests for showings in just the first 24 hours!&lt;/strong&gt; In the first 48 hours, we had six offers on the property. We ended up listing it for $329,000, and we ultimately put the property under contract for $350,000. &lt;strong&gt;We were able to create a multiple-offer situation that only benefited our seller.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pent-up demand stems from a number of different factors, but one of the main reasons for it is that &lt;strong&gt;there’s been a real shortage of good inventory on the market&lt;/strong&gt;. With interest rates holding as low as they have been, there are a lot of buyers who are looking to purchase homes right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So again, now is the time to put your home on the market and take advantage of all this demand from buyers in the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you’re thinking of selling your home and would like to get top dollar for it, reach out to me. Let’s set up an appointment for us to come down to your house so we can give you an honest, realistic estimate of what your home would sell for, and so we can generate a marketing plan and a time-frame that works for you. I hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-update-on-the-spring-2019-marketplace.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/your-update-on-the-spring-2019-marketplace.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Ready to Buy Your Next Home? Let Us Help</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qxZJgCiCZ-8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of a real estate agent, you probably think of someone who’s working on behalf of a seller. However, having representation as a buyer is equally important. When it comes time to buy a home, having an agent by your side will be essential to your success. You need someone to stand in your corner—someone to answer your questions, guide your decisions, and negotiate on your behalf. We would love to offer these services to you. Our team would like to set you on the path to home buying success, so please reach out. To learn more, watch this short video. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 16:58:04 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-ready-to-buy-your-next-home-let-us-help.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-ready-to-buy-your-next-home-let-us-help.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Branford Office Is Open for Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7KIATabCW0k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to officially announce the opening of our brand-new office right here in the heart of Branford, CT. As of December 1, we are officially open for business. We’re going to have a grand-opening party at our beautifully renovated office. We will get details out to you shortly. To learn more about the opening of our new office, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 10:50:36 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-branford-office-is-open-for-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/our-branford-office-is-open-for-business.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Is Now a Great Opportunity for Home Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/y610y0_pmfY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re over at a 4-bedroom, 3-bathroom colonial in the Fairlawn Farms section of Wallingford. We’re getting the house ready for the market, having professional photography done, and doing a bit of professional home staging to enhance the buyer experience. There’s a surprising misconception in the marketplace that home sales are slower in the fall market, but it’s just not true. In fact, there’s a real shortage of homes like this one and there are a lot of buyers out there that are just waiting for something like this. If you have any doubts about putting your home on the market or any questions about what it might be like, I want you to reach out and give me a call or send me an email today. To learn more about the fall market, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 15:04:52 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-is-now-a-great-opportunity-for-home-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-is-now-a-great-opportunity-for-home-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
