<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1000 Calls A Day | Done-For-You Outbound Teleprospecting</title>
    <description>We offer done-for-you calling of your database or cold list, up to 1,000 attempts a day, to identify new, missed or unconverted opportunities for your sales team.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 13:45:41 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 13:45:41 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Ways To Improve Your Campaign</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HRDOf7u_7V0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What gives our clients the best results? Here are a few of the common denominators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to talk about the two best ways to get better results from your outbound prospecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first thing you need to understand is that the prospect list that you’re putting into the system matters.&lt;/strong&gt; Not all data is created equally. Certain data is more valuable, and it will absolutely play a role in the results that you get. When you work with us, we use a company called Exact Data, who has done a great job with predictive analytics to help our clients purchase data (prospect lists and contacts). &lt;strong&gt;Predictive analytics can actually give us an idea of if a person is right for you.&lt;/strong&gt; After we go through hundreds of different data points to come up with your perfect client, they can further classify that list with predictive analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Having great data makes this process easier and more profitable.%20localhost:4000/2-ways-to-improve-your-campaign.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Having great data makes this process easier and more profitable.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having great data makes this process better and, in turn, makes you more money and gets you more leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second thing you need to know is that a nurture campaign is essential.&lt;/strong&gt; Once we start bringing you these strong leads, we’re passing them on to you. However, maybe they aren’t ready to do business quite yet. That’s why there needs to be a nurture campaign in place. It could be with a CRM, a text message campaign, or follow-up phone calls. The bottom line is that you need to have something in place. Once you bring a prospect into your funnel, it’s important to stay in touch with them so that you are top of mind when it comes time for them to hire someone. Having a solid campaign will help you close business and your ROI will go through the roof in year two. If you’re nurturing your leads properly, your ROI should increase every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious about what a great nurture campaign looks like, we have one that we can send on over to you. &lt;strong&gt;If you want a copy or if you have any other questions for us, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email.&lt;/strong&gt; We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 13:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/2-ways-to-improve-your-campaign.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/2-ways-to-improve-your-campaign.html</guid>
        
        <category>Prospecting calls</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Does Our Startup Process Look Like?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KgQ6uvDkOOg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our startup and hiring processes are detailed for a few reasons. Here they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today we wanted to answer a few questions we hear all the time:&lt;/strong&gt; “What is your startup fee?” “What does the process of hiring a VA look like?” and “How long does it take to get started?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a business owner, it can be extremely frustrating and time-consuming to hire somebody. If you’re hiring a regular employee, there is way more money and responsibility involved. That’s why it’s our goal to have you hand this VA work off to us and we’ll handle it completely from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have a staff of recruiters that are out there right now recruiting the top talent in the Philippines.&lt;/strong&gt; We search for talent here because they generally speak great English, and there are a large number of prospects to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see hundreds of resumes each day and sift through them ourselves. You probably don’t have the systems and processes in place to be able to do this yourself. That’s where we come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we find a candidate that meets our strict criteria, we bring them in for basic testing. If they pass that, we then bring them into an intense, two-week training program. &lt;strong&gt;Once they go through this, they have to test out of the program in order to show that they’re fully qualified for this job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=They will know your business, your team, and your market inside and out.%20localhost:4000/how-we-hire-va-assistants.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“They will know your business, your team, and your market inside and out.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we put them on the phones for a week or two to see how they do on the job. We closely monitor their performance throughout. If they pass all of our training and tests, we invite them to come on board and we hire them for one of our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you were trying to replicate this process on your own, it would be nearly impossible.&lt;/strong&gt; With our help, we can put candidates through this process, pick out three or four of the best-suited candidates for you, and share their video resumes with you. Then you can determine if any of them would be a good fit for your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recruiting, resume sifting, candidate interviews, and testing are all included in our startup fee. We will also specifically train each VA for your company. They will know your business, your team, and your market inside and out. Additionally, we will get your technology set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason our process is so detail-oriented is that we want to hire the right talent every time. The startup process can take up to four to six weeks as a result. In the long run, following this process can save you a ton of time and money and ensure we get you the best VA caller who can get you the best leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us or want to learn a little more about what we do, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 13:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-we-hire-va-assistants.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-we-hire-va-assistants.html</guid>
        
        <category>1000CallsADay</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Hire 1000 Calls a Day Instead of a VA Caller?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RmA4dw_nOdU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the advantages you get from hiring us instead of a VA caller add up to you having more time to call leads and grow your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why use 1000 Calls a Day instead of hiring a VA caller directly? Your decision ultimately depends on your situation and your budget, but there are certain advantages that come with hiring us and letting us handle the process from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we’re certainly not the cheapest, if you go to a site like Upwork.com or another virtual assistant site and hire a caller for $5 to $8 an hour, you’ll have to train that person, put all the technology in place, manage the campaigns, handle all of the troubleshooting, etc. It’s a vigorous, frustrating process, and it can take you away from your core competency and your most important revenue-producing activities. It’s our job to take that off your plate and help you generate leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first advantage is &lt;strong&gt;we can go out and get better talent for you.&lt;/strong&gt; We have full-time recruiters out there looking at 200 to 400 resumes a day. We test our VAs to make sure they’re legitimate, and we bring them up to speed with our testing processes. You don’t have to do any training either. We take care of all the scripts and campaigns ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;we take the risk of losing an employee off your plate.&lt;/strong&gt; Oftentimes, you can hire an employee, train them, spend a ton of time with them, only to have them leave in a couple months and make you start all over again. We, on the other hand, can replace the VA should they decide to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We take other tasks and processes off your plate so you can focus on calling leads.%20localhost:4000/the-advantages-of-hiring-us.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We take other tasks and processes off your plate so you can focus on calling leads.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we manage that VA for you. We have one supervisor for every 10 callers we manage, so our supervision of the caller involves helping them with the analytics and making sure they’re doing the right things. Our supervisors are also listening in on calls and giving the callers feedback and coaching on how to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, and perhaps most importantly, &lt;strong&gt;you get a whole team of people.&lt;/strong&gt; In addition to the caller and the supervisor, you get access to our executive staff who have a lot of experience managing outbound calling campaigns. It’s important to be able to put the data and/or prospects into the system and write or tweak the scripts, but what happens if the campaigns aren’t performing? We have over 100 callers we’re currently managing, so we can look at the exact same campaigns with other people around the country and compare your results. If your results aren’t meeting our expectations, we know that something needs to change, and we have the expertise to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to get you 40 to 50 pre-qualified leads on a monthly basis so you can convert those leads into more business and make more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions about how we can put an outbound prospecting campaign in place an help you grow your business, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-advantages-of-hiring-us.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-advantages-of-hiring-us.html</guid>
        
        <category>1000CallsADay</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Do We Get Our List to Call?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wx-JInZV4Kc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common question clients ask me is: Where do we get our list to call? There are actually two options I want to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common question clients ask me is: Where do we get our list to call?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are actually two options I want to talk about. Most people are familiar with purchasing access to expired, canceled, or withdrawn listings. But there’s also a way you can purchase premium lists to get better results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, you are going to pay a premium rate for those lists. Depending on the type of list and the amount you’re purchasing, &lt;strong&gt;these can run anywhere from seven cents to 30 cents per record.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Premium lists will help you weed through to find people who are the most likely to sell their home in the next 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you give us access to your expired service, we’ll pull from that list every two weeks. That way, your virtual assistant can give them a call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we don’t want to contact any brand-new expired listings. Those homeowners are getting anywhere from 60 to 70 phone calls a day in some markets. We don’t want to compete with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to pick up calling where other agents have stopped. After that point we’re persistent, but aren’t going to be calling the same neighborhood multiple times per day or week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 14:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/where-do-we-get-our-list-to-call.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/where-do-we-get-our-list-to-call.html</guid>
        
        <category>1000CallsADay</category>
        
        <category>Lead Follow Up</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Keep Remote Employees Accountable </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/y3cMA6VVAXw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at 1000 Calls A Day, how do we keep our remote employees accountable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most of our employees work remotely, I want to explain how we keep our virtual assistants accountable and help them with their time management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, we have a &lt;strong&gt;workforce monitor.&lt;/strong&gt; We just hired our second workforce monitor, and she is amazing. She is in charge of all tech support for our auto dialer and sending performance audits to our clients every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of our clients and VAs also have a &lt;strong&gt;Google chat thread running.&lt;/strong&gt; The VA uses the chat to clock in for the day, and we keep track of their breaks from there, depending on which auto dialer we use. If you use some of the professional call center software, then the VA has to insert a reason code if they want to pause the auto dialer for any reason. For example, they can enter codes in for a huddle session, coaching session, or restroom break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there are times when a virtual assistant goes MIA. When that happens for the first time, we issue a verbal warning. If it happens a second time, the VA will be removed. &lt;strong&gt;We do not tolerate employees that aren’t accountable virtually.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a very fine line that you have to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The management staff has their own chat thread where they keep in touch with one another, team leaders, and the operations staff. They let us know if someone has texted or called in because they are going to be late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In the event of a hurricane or typhoon, I will let you know why your VA isn’t available.%20localhost:4000/how-we-keep-remote-employees-accountable.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In the event of a hurricane or typhoon, I will let you know why your VA isn’t available.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a large-scale event like a typhoon or earthquake can make VAs unavailable. If that happens, I will personally go on our Facebook page and email all of our clients to let you know that some of their VAs might be affected by this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how we keep everyone accountable at 1000 Calls A Day. If you have any other questions or would like to learn more about 1000 Calls A Day, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 16:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-we-keep-remote-employees-accountable.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-we-keep-remote-employees-accountable.html</guid>
        
        <category>1000CallsADay</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Ways to Create Predictable Revenue</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/F6YsC-rPy4E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the best way to build predictable revenue? According to one of my favorite books, it all boils down to systematizing your sales process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Predictable Revenue” is a fantastic book by Aaron Ross and Marylou Tyler. I recommend it to all of my clients. One of the main lessons I’ve learned from this book is &lt;strong&gt;how to systematize your sales process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to grow your business exponentially, you need to delegate certain duties and replace yourself in certain roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you don’t like prospecting, hire someone to do that for you. Not into lead follow-up? Find someone to take care of that for you. That way, you can dedicate all of your time to meeting with clients and closing deals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your lead follow-up system should be systematized to the point where it reads like a recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of clients have trouble letting go of managing every part of the sales process. However, it’s important that you trust your team members and &lt;strong&gt;hire people who will do the things you don’t like to really well.&lt;/strong&gt; Look for a detail-oriented person who complements you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t like cold calling and finding new opportunities, or you don’t enjoy following up with leads, find someone who is really good at following instructions and systematizing their day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, it can be difficult for you to delegate at the beginning. However, once you see your calendar stacked with appointments and your business starts doubling—or even tripling—it will get easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’ll handle outbound prospecting so you can focus on growing your business.%20localhost:4000/the-best-ways-to-create-predictable.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’ll handle outbound prospecting so you can focus on growing your business.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you work with 1000 Calls A day, we handle the outbound prospecting for you. We call thousands of numbers a week to get those verbal opt-ins to add to your sales pipeline. I always recommend that you hire one person inside your office to take care of the lead follow-up. They will be more focused and able to convert leads at a higher level than you could on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, systematizing your sales process will give you more time to do what you do best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like to learn more about 1000 Calls A Day, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 14:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-best-ways-to-create-predictable.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-best-ways-to-create-predictable.html</guid>
        
        <category>1000CallsADay</category>
        
        <category>Predictable Revenue Model</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Whats the Difference Between a VA and an ISA?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YK-ztHprUsQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the difference between a VA and an ISA? Can’t one person handle both duties?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between a virtual assistant, also known as your dedicated outbound prospector, and an inside sales agent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I speak with a number of business owners who think that it’s best to combine the ISA and the VA role. However, there are a few reasons why that’s not the best idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very common for people to get VAs and ISAs mixed up, but &lt;strong&gt;they are actually two very different roles.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some business owners want to do their own lead follow up while producing, and others want the VA to handle lead follow up for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is, neither of those options are sustainable if you want to systematize your sales process and create predictable revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your VA will identify opportunities to keep your ISA busy.%20localhost:4000/whats-difference-between-va-and-isa.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your VA will identify opportunities to keep your ISA busy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do lead follow up on your own or have your VA handle it, there is usually a point of diminished returns about three to six months later. Why? Your prospector isn’t prospecting because they do lead follow up 90% of the time, or you’re not doing your lead follow up because you would rather be out in front of consumers to grow your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In order to truly systematize your sales process, you need these two separate roles.&lt;/strong&gt; VAs will identify the opportunity, add it to your sales pipeline, find the motivating fact, get them to verbally opt-in to be contact by an agent, and market-qualify the lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ISA is the person who spends the bulk of their time on the phone with your leads, teeing them up so that you can sign a contract with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ISA’s job is to build rapport. They spend more time with your leads than anyone else in the sales process. I always recommend that our clients have an ISA in the office responsible for nurturing, educating, and converting leads. At 1000 Calls A Day, we take care of adding new opportunities to your pipeline and keeping your ISA busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like to learn more about 1000 Calls A Day, just give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 13:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-difference-between-va-and-isa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/whats-difference-between-va-and-isa.html</guid>
        
        <category>Virtual Assistants vs. ISAs</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Only the Best Virtual Assistants Work With Our Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YH0Qt3SLpkQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We put our virtual assistants through rigorous screening to ensure that we only provide the best help to our clients. Out of every 60 applicants, only about five will pass our test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we at 1000 Calls A Day find the best virtual assistants for our clients?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, we hold our applicants to a very high standard of quality. &lt;strong&gt;Out of the 60 applications we receive every day, only about five typically make it past this initial screening.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, we show the remaining applicants what to expect out of a typical day-in-the-life of one of our virtual assistants. By showing them what to expect, giving them basic scripts and roleplay assessments, as well as having them shadow our tenured virtual assistants, we do all we can to ensure that they are fully equipped to do the most for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We truly only take the best applicants to work for our clients.%20localhost:4000/only-best-virtual-assistants-work-with.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We truly only take the best applicants to work for our clients.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once applicants have made it this far, we like to make sure that they have updated software and computer systems as well as a stable Internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They then move on to a more difficult segment of our roleplay assessment. After they pass that, they become one of our virtual assistants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We truly only take the best applicants to work for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about how to grow your business, or if you have any questions, feel free to give us a call or email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 09:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/only-best-virtual-assistants-work-with.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/only-best-virtual-assistants-work-with.html</guid>
        
        <category>1000CallsADay</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do We Define Success at 1000 Calls A Day?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wpwk80THin0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we measure success at 1000 Calls A Day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, we want each one of our virtual assistants to pass over 40 to 60 nurturing opportunities a month to their clients. Our goal is to &lt;strong&gt;build you a balanced sales pipeline&lt;/strong&gt; so that you have a ladder portfolio filled with opportunities to create predictable income. To achieve that, we are consistently adding short-term, mid-term, and long-term nurtures to your pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to add more short-term or long-term nurtures to your sales pipeline, just reach out to us. We are in constant communication with our clients so that we can consistently add the leads you need to keep your income predictable. For example, if you need more short-term nurtures, then we will call more expireds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our goal is to build you a balanced sales pipeline.%20localhost:4000/how-do-we-define-success-at-1000-calls.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our goal is to build you a balanced sales pipeline.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the surest ways our clients can see ROI is to &lt;strong&gt;add additional VAs to your team to maximize that effort.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also make sure we keep our VAs extremely happy, but we’ll go into more detail on that later. In the meantime, if you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 10:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-do-we-define-success-at-1000-calls.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/how-do-we-define-success-at-1000-calls.html</guid>
        
        <category>Defining Success</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Happens After Your VA Identifies a Lead?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/peNfgGZUTSw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens when your virtual assistant identifies an opportunity or a lead for your sales pipeline?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First of all, your VA will send you an email.&lt;/strong&gt; Depending on the dialing system you choose to work with, that email is either sent out automatically or your VA will pause their dialer and manually send you an email. Either way, you get an immediate, real-time notification that a lead has been identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also share a Google Sheet with you to keep track of every lead that you get once you start the program. These sheets start out basic but as the system and the program mature, they can get pretty complicated. You can integrate the Google Sheet with your ISA or inbound lead follow up person, who can then provide feedback to your VA within the spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens if you don’t have a CRM? You can use the tracker we provide as a rudimentary way to utilize and work the leads like you would in a CRM. However, we definitely recommend that you get a CRM as soon as possible to streamline your follow up process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We definitely recommend getting a CRM as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our VAs also send you a daily report&lt;/strong&gt; explaining what they did for you that day and list your leads at the bottom of the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after your VA identifies a lead, you will get an immediate notification, the VA will add the lead to your Google Sheet, and your VA will make a list of all of the leads they identified in their daily report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about this process or if you would like to learn more about 1000 Calls A Day, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 15:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-happens-after-your-va-identifies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/what-happens-after-your-va-identifies.html</guid>
        
        <category>1000CallsADay</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
