<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HI Pacific Property Management</title>
    <description>Our mission at HI Pacific Property Management is to be your best resource for Hawaii real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The HI Pacific Property Management, your professional Hawaii Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 12:00:44 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 12:00:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Are the 2 Best Upgrades You Can Make to Your Property?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/W3x7OpsMyNk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are the two best upgrades a property owner can make.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a homeowner looking to spruce up your unit a bit, what updates offer the best bang for your buck? The average home in Hawaii is usually anywhere from 40 to 60 years old—wow, that’s my age; I need an update! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jokes aside, you can’t just take your 60-year-old unit and put it on the market for rent. It won’t rent, and if it does, it won’t rent for a lot of money. So where should you invest your time and money? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Flooring.&lt;/strong&gt; Always put some vinyl product down in your house (tile is also an option, but it’s a little more expensive). If your carpet is weathered or your laminate is old, put down some vinyl; it’s not that costly and has a 25-year shelf life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Air conditioning.&lt;/strong&gt; People that come from the mainland cannot take our humidity. Trust me, I know this from experience: I lived on the mainland for a while, and when I moved back home, I simply couldn’t sleep without air conditioning. Here in Hawaii, there’s a roughly 50/50 shot that you’ll find a home equipped with air conditioning. In my experience, the houses without air conditioning rent last. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions on these two updates, or would like us to put in contact with some of our talented in-house handymen or trusted contractors, give us a call or send an email. We’re happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 11:20:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-are-the-2-best-upgrades-you-can-make-to-your-property.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-what-are-the-2-best-upgrades-you-can-make-to-your-property.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Is Our Eviction Guarantee?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ccTAgzOVpPM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;We offer owners an eviction guarantee. Here’s what that means.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at HI Pacific Property Management, we offer you an eviction guarantee. This states that &lt;strong&gt;if you choose to put a tenant we approve of in your unit and they later need to be evicted, we will pay for the legal eviction costs.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re the only property management group that offers this guarantee. I stand by our work, and we do such a great job with background checks that we’ve only had to use this guarantee once. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been in business for 10 years, have tons of units, and all we do is property management. Yes, even with all that, we’ve only had to pay for an eviction once. In fact, we offer three guarantees to owners: eviction, rent, and communication guarantees, which you can read more about on our website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give us a call or send an email if you have any questions about the eviction guarantee or property management. We would love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 12:58:57 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-is-our-eviction-guarantee.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-what-is-our-eviction-guarantee.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Why Are Walk-Throughs Necessary?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SS2bNaPBhOA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m explaining why walk-throughs are crucial and how we do them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a walk-through? Why would we need to walk through your property? The truth is, several rental owners have switched to us because no one has walked through their property in years. How would anyone know what’s going on there if someone doesn’t walk through it? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Walk-throughs are crucial.%20http://localhost:4000/q-why-are-walk-throughs-necessary.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Walk-throughs are crucial.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a property manager, this is the most important part of my job. When I do walk-throughs, I’m looking for damage, illegal tenants, and abuse. I’m looking for all these things in about a 10-minute walk-through with your tenants twice a year. If you allow pets in the house, we’ll walk through it three times per year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walk-throughs are crucial because &lt;strong&gt;we can tell if the tenant is living according to the rules, if they’re overly dirty, if there’s drug use, illegal alterations, and more.&lt;/strong&gt; These are great times to catch whether any of these things are happening and protect your property. You will get a report from us with pictures stating how the property is doing, how it looks, and what we saw from the tenants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about walk-throughs or property management in general, please call or email me. I would be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 11:29:07 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-why-are-walk-throughs-necessary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-why-are-walk-throughs-necessary.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Should I Replace the Carpet?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/puSLzc-MX3Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have carpet in your rental property, it may be time to replace it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get asked all the time by rental owners if they should replace the carpet in their properties with wood, vinyl, or tile. My answer to these questions is always yes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The average life of carpet is two to three tenants.%20http://localhost:4000/q-should-i-replace-the-carpet.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The average life of carpet is two to three tenants.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carpet has gone out of style over the last decade.&lt;/strong&gt; Many tenants with children ask if we have houses available without carpet because they can’t be sure of what kind of care was taken with the carpet before they moved into the house. Also, children will usually be much harder on carpet than adults. A lot of owners will have damage or wear and tear, and the average life of carpet is two to three tenants. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today many floor products are being made harder, water-resistant, or waterproof. I believe vinyl is the best flooring for rental properties; it has the most variation, a 25-year warranty, and it’s often waterproof. You can have a huge water spill in your house and have no damage or wood issues like bowing of the edges. &lt;strong&gt;Tile is also great, but it’s very expensive to lay,&lt;/strong&gt; though it has a shelf life of about 50 years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recommendation is to switch to waterproof vinyl if it’s time to change the flooring in your house. There are many products out there, so you can choose what’s best for your property. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about flooring or property management, please call or email us. We would love to speak with you. Aloha!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 11:49:38 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-should-i-replace-the-carpet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-should-i-replace-the-carpet.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Are We Keeping Clients Safe?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r2rGG3rROi4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m sharing our methods for keeping clients healthy amid COVID-19.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m sharing some of the protocols we’ve put in place to combat the pandemic. We’re doing showings via video on a variety of platforms so tenants don’t need to be there in person. However, if they insist on seeing it physically or with an agent, we open the doors for them, walk away to give them privacy, and everyone wears masks and gloves. We try not to do face-to-face interactions, but if for some reason we need to, we keep six feet of distance between us. All the property managers that work for us know our protocols and will enforce them. To learn more about how we’re keeping everyone healthy, watch the short video above. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 15:05:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-are-we-keeping-clients-safe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-are-we-keeping-clients-safe.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Do I Handle Insurance Claims?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WF9V7U9tIlw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s how to handle insurance claims as a rental property owner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s message is all about insurance claims and what to do if damage happens. If you’re turning your house into a rental property, you should have renters insurance, homeowners insurance, and loss of rent insurance. Water damage is the most frequent type of damage to a home, and it usually happens when there’s a leak. A valve could fail, or a tub or toilet overflows and then you have a water problem. However, water damage isn’t the only type to be concerned about. To learn more about insurance claims and damage, watch the short video above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 11:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-i-handle-insurance-claims.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-i-handle-insurance-claims.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Has Covid-19 Changed Our Business?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jrKFqgZ43Ms?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Curfews have been invoked in Hawaii; here’s how our business has changed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 protocols are going to change the way that we do business. Unfortunately for us here in Hawaii, a curfew was just implemented, meaning that no one is allowed on the roads between 11 p.m. and 5 a.m. on Friday, Saturday, and Sunday. We’ve already sent out information regarding how homeowners can expect our business practices to change with quarantine rules in mind, and new tenants coming into our system can expect to sign some extra paperwork. To learn more about how we’ve had to adapt to these recent challenges, watch the short video above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 10:54:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-has-covid-19-changed-our-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-has-covid-19-changed-our-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Effects Will This Pandemic Have on Real Estate?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lQQTBzsQc88?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although the March real estate numbers were not significantly affected by the coronavirus pandemic, I believe that we will see some repercussions in the months to come.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve actually had a good year so far and we hope you have too. During this pandemic, it has been so complicated to do business in all sectors of the economy, but especially in real estate. The good news is that real estate and property management have been deemed essential businesses and we’re working our hardest to ensure that we keep moving forward and doing business. There are going to be some effects on the real estate market, but we may not know what those effects are for the next six months or so. To learn more about how I think COVID-19 might affect the real estate market, watch the short video above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 11:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-effects-will-this-pandemic-have-on-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-what-effects-will-this-pandemic-have-on-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can We Expect for Our Summer Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MJLrgkEVtgg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s in store for us in the coming summer? Here are my thoughts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the stay-at-home orders in place to combat the spread of the pandemic, it brings up a very important question: What is this summer going to look like? Typically, as schools let out for the summer, the market tends to heat up. However, this year is sure to be a little different from the typical summer; the pandemic is going to shake everything up. To learn what that will mean for our market, watch the short video above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 11:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-can-we-expect-for-our-summer-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-can-we-expect-for-our-summer-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do Our Owners or Tenants Pay for Pest Control?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pMy85izemmY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For our properties, pest control is the tenant’s responsibility, except when they first move into the house.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any property owners who decide to leave their homes under our care, we always tell them the same thing regarding pest control: &lt;strong&gt;It’s the tenant’s responsibility, except when they first move into the property. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, if they find pests within the first 10 to 20 days of moving in, the problem has to be taken care of at the owner’s expense. After the initial move-in period, it shifts to the tenant’s expense. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, our last video blog was about termites, and oftentimes, the cabinets that are brought into condos or townhomes come from outside Hawaii. The walls and grounds of those properties can be treated, but any outside furniture and the moving boxes encasing them can carry termites. We’ve seen plenty of infestations occur after tenants move in because of this, so it’s something you need to know. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any other property management topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 13:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/do-our-owners-or-tenants-pay-for-pest-control.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/do-our-owners-or-tenants-pay-for-pest-control.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
