<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Homebound Team - your professional Colorado Springs Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 13:00:48 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 13:00:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways to Succeed in Real Estate &amp; Life In This New Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EyHGw0LoCdo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re sharing three ways you can succeed in real estate and life during the pandemic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today we’re coming to you from our basements to discuss three ways to succeed in real estate and life amid a quarantine market. We’ve been in a seller’s market here in Colorado Springs for a long time, but we’re going to see it shift into a buyer’s. &lt;strong&gt;You can still buy and sell in this market!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are moving more into the virtual world, but if you need to conduct real estate business, now’s the time. Interest rates are projected to be great throughout the year and even into next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-ways-to-succeed-in-real-estate-life-in-this-new-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-ways-to-succeed-in-real-estate-life-in-this-new-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The New Normal &amp; the Adaptability of the Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1B4GgTsbrE0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;The real estate market has adapted well to the new normal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What’s happening with the real estate market in the wake of the coronavirus pandemic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re anything like us, you’re stuck indoors trying to juggle things like homeschooling, working in close quarters next to your spouse, and new cooking recipes (sometimes succeeding, sometimes failing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the new normal, but the good news is, &lt;strong&gt;the real estate industry is moving right along&lt;/strong&gt;. Frankly, we’re surprised at how well consumers and agents have adapted to an industry that’s gone virtual. We have sellers showing buyers homes via Zoom, Skype, etc., inspectors showing up to houses wearing gloves and hazmat suits, and more. We have a responsibility to protect each other while continuing on with life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought there would be a drop in activity, but virtual showings, meetings, open houses, notary signings, etc., have kept opportunities readily available for buyers and sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re surprised at how well consumers and agents have adapted to an industry that’s gone virtual.%20http://localhost:4000/the-new-normal-the-adaptability-of-the-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re surprised at how well consumers and agents have adapted to an industry that’s gone virtual.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do the Pikes Peak MLS numbers say specifically? In the week leading up to the recording of this video, 329 new listings hit the market. &lt;strong&gt;Out of all the homes already on the market, 1,057 went under contract, and 1,218 sold&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about our market or aren’t sure how to navigate the new normal, give us a call and we’d be happy to help. More importantly, if you know someone who’s going through financial hardship and may have to sell their home or is in need of supplies, please reach out to us as well. We have the resources to help, and we’re here to serve our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our home to yours, we hope you stay safe and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-new-normal-the-adaptability-of-the-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-new-normal-the-adaptability-of-the-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Really Should Know About iBuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T6awqDvHdik?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the truth behind iBuyers and their automated valuation models.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An iBuyer is a real estate investor that often buys the home quickly using cash. They use an AVM, or automated valuation model, popularized in the form of Zillow’s Zestimate. Typically, an iBuyer will purchase the home without ever having seen it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having someone offer cash for your house sight unseen seems easy, but &lt;strong&gt;watch out for scams&lt;/strong&gt;. There’s a lot of fraud that floats around in the real estate industry, like wire transfer fraud. If you do decide that an iBuyer is the best route for you, make sure you go with a reputable one and close only at a local escrow or title company; never, ever, ever wire your money out somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The average consumer that takes an offer from these iBuyers takes 13% to 15% less than the value of their home.%20http://localhost:4000/what-you-really-should-know-about-ibuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The average consumer that takes an offer from these iBuyers takes 13% to 15% less than the value of their home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The reality of the iBuyer program is that it’s not as sexy as it sounds&lt;/strong&gt;. According to Forbes, the average consumer that takes an offer from these iBuyers takes 13% to 15% less than the value of their home. That’s massive! These iBuyers will also order an inspection, point out all of the issues they want fixed, and if you refuse, they’ll take even more off of their offer. It’s not a great deal. It’s important to be educated about what really occurs in these transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If 13% to 15% less than your home’s value sounds appealing, go for an iBuyer’s offer. Then again, you could go with a trusted team of professionals to represent you. Don’t leave money on the table! Reach out to us by phone or email anytime if you have further questions about iBuyers or are interested in buying or selling soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-really-should-know-about-ibuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-you-really-should-know-about-ibuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons to Buy in Fountain, Colorado</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/l5Y2njwf5U8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re sharing three great reasons you may want to consider buying a home in Fountain, Colorado.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We love Fountain, Colorado! Here are three great reasons you should consider buying a home in Fountain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Personality of a small town, convenience of a city&lt;/strong&gt;. Fountain has the personality of a small town but is close to anything you may want. It’s just down the road from downtown Colorado Springs, a quick drive to the Colorado Springs airport, and minutes away from Fort Carson’s Gate 20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Fountain has wonderful opportunities to build wealth and become a homeowner at a great value.%20http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-buy-in-fountain-colorado.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Fountain has wonderful opportunities to build wealth and become a homeowner at a great value.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Location, location, location&lt;/strong&gt;. Fountain is close to everything, the median list price is $298,000, and the average house size is over 2,100 square feet. You get a ton of bang for your buck. Homes are currently staying on the market for just eight days, so you have to move quickly if you want to buy in the Fountain area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Investment opportunity&lt;/strong&gt;. There’s a reason houses in Fountain are only on the market for a short time. You currently have to pay an additional $29,000 to buy a home in Colorado Springs, which is just 10 minutes away. Fountain has wonderful opportunities to build wealth and become a homeowner at a great value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s crucial to do your research no matter where you want to buy a house in Colorado. The first thing you should do is start with a team you trust to help you with the process. Start with us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about Fountain or real estate in general, please contact us via phone or email. We would love to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-buy-in-fountain-colorado.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-buy-in-fountain-colorado.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Things to Never Do When Buying a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gkiQzgxxjAI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are the three things you should &lt;u&gt;never&lt;/u&gt; do when buying a home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When it comes to purchasing a home there are three mistakes you should always avoid making during the process if you want to succeed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Go on vacation&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’re going on a vacation to Greece during the process of buying a home it will be very hard to complete the purchase. We can’t do everything on your behalf, and being far away makes coordination difficult. Wait to go on vacation until after you’ve closed on your home if you want to avoid undue stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Don’t pay off any debts&lt;/strong&gt;. This may sound crazy, but it’s not. If you pay off a debt entirely, that will impact your credit—for better or worse, we don’t know. Consult your loan officer before you pay off anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Don’t finance any large purchases&lt;/strong&gt;. Be it a new car or furniture for your new home, don’t take out any additional lines of credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can’t do everything on your behalf.%20http://localhost:4000/3-things-to-never-do-when-buying-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We can’t do everything on your behalf.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re careful to avoid these mistakes, your home purchase may go off without a hitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out to us with any questions you have about the home buying process. We’d be glad to give you our professional advice and help you end up in the home of your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-things-to-never-do-when-buying-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-things-to-never-do-when-buying-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Key Things to Know About Our 2020 Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0olsLY22V-k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re buying or selling in our Colorado Springs market in 2020, here are three insider tips to keep in mind.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As we begin 2020, there are three key points to know about our Colorado Springs market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;there &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be an inventory shortage&lt;/strong&gt;, which means we’ll see more multiple-offer situations. America’s Space Force is coming to town, and with it, its 15,000 personnel and their families. We don’t know where they’re going to live, but our team is ready to help all of them! In any case, be ready for this shortage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;the forecast remains good for interest rates&lt;/strong&gt;. 2019 ended with fantastic rates, so you might expect that they can only go up from here, but they’re predicted to stay low. This means that even though home prices are rising, buyers will still be able to afford more house and make competitive offers for the houses they’re looking at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Contact your real estate professional to ensure you’re in good hands going into 2020.%20http://localhost:4000/3-key-things-to-know-about-our-2020-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Contact your real estate professional to ensure you’re in good hands going into 2020.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;whether you’re a buyer or seller, it’s important to be prepared&lt;/strong&gt;. We know that interest rates are low, so buyer demand will be high, but we have no inventory. What does that mean? As we said above, there will be a lot of multiple-offer situations. If you’re a buyer, it’s important to have an agent on your side to help guide you through these situations. If you’re a seller, it’s important to know where you’ll go &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; you sell. As with buyers, it’s crucial to have an agent by your side to help with your preparation and guide you through the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact your real estate professional to ensure you’re in good hands going into 2020. If you don’t have an agent, give us a call and we’d be happy to assist with all your real estate needs. We’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-key-things-to-know-about-our-2020-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-key-things-to-know-about-our-2020-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Loan Limits Are Increasing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hLNoAZfO9fI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loan limits are increasing in 2020 for conventional, FHA, and VA loans. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Loan limits are increasing in 2020. What does that mean? First, there’s a difference between your purchase price and your loan limits. For instance, conventional loans have increased; in 2019 the limit was $484,000, and in 2020, the limit is $510,400. &lt;strong&gt;That’s over a 5% boost in just one year&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have the 20% down for a conventional loan, an FHA product is an excellent option. It’s 3.5% down and those limits are increasing, too. In 2019, they were $339,250. In 2020 they are $356,500, a 5% escalation. This helps your buying power when you’re purchasing a new home with an FHA loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, let’s talk about the VA product. The VA loan limits have had a 247% increase from last year. In 2019, the limit was $484,350. In 2020, it is $1.2 million (that’s 100% financing up to $1.2 million)! That also works if you have multiple VA houses, meaning you can go up to that number collectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The VA loan limits have had a 247% increase from last year!%20http://localhost:4000/loan-limits-are-increasing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The VA loan limits have had a 247% increase from last year!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to think about with VA loans: They allow up to $1.2 million, but not every bank will allow that high of a number. Check with your loan officer to confirm they have the product to get you all the way to $1.2 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re in the market and you’re looking to buy in 2020, go explore your options with your local lender&lt;/strong&gt;. Happy home hunting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for us about loan limits, please don’t hesitate to reach out by phone or email. We would love to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/loan-limits-are-increasing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/loan-limits-are-increasing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Breakdown of Your Monthly Mortgage Payment</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m83fCqd8r8s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your monthly mortgage payment includes a few different costs. Here&amp;rsquo;s how they break down.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to talk to you about what exactly is included in your monthly mortgage payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you pay rent, you’re essentially paying all interest every single month because you don’t own the property. &lt;strong&gt;When you do own a property, your monthly mortgage payment can be thought of in four categories that make up an acronym: PITI&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “P” stands for principal. It’s like an investment made to yourself every month. The first “I” stands for interest, because the bank has to make something on the money they loaned to you. The “T” and the last “I” stand for taxes and insurance, which cover the home in case of disaster. &lt;strong&gt;All of this is lumped into one monthly payment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you put less than 20% down, you’ll also have to pay mortgage insurance.%20http://localhost:4000/a-breakdown-of-your-monthly-mortgage-payment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you put less than 20% down, you’ll also have to pay mortgage insurance.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to PITI, you’ll also have MI, or mortgage insurance. If you put less than 20% down on your home, you have to pay this because you’re at a higher risk of going to default, unless you have a VA loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about PITI, buying a home, or anything else, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email today. We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-breakdown-of-your-monthly-mortgage-payment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-breakdown-of-your-monthly-mortgage-payment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Costly Sewer Repairs Stink: Try These 3 Plumbing Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZnaoF-eYvKw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today we have a special guest with us&amp;mdash;Jennifer from Bill&amp;rsquo;s Plumbing and Drain Service&amp;mdash;to help give you three tips that homeowners should know about their plumbing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What is the best solution for tackling smelly drains?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when I go into a home, I register a smell coming out of the drains. My first instinct is to pour some Drano in them to try to get rid of whatever is causing the odor. Jennifer , our expert from Bill’s Plumbing and Drain Service, says that Drano is a pretty harsh chemical; if you pour it down the drain, it will eat away at whatever is clogging the pipes, but it will also eat away at the pipes themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better solution is actually just water, Jennifer says. You can fill a big pitcher with warm water and throw a little bit of lemon juice or vinegar in there, then pour the solution down your drains—especially unused drains like your floor, guest bathroom, and laundry drains. Sometimes those don’t get wet, causing the P-trap to dry out and create an odor. Sealing the drain with a bucket of warm water will help take care of the smells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Why is it important to have a sewer scope when you purchase a home?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennifer says its importance is for checking the integrity of the sewer line to make sure there aren’t any issues with it. Spending around $150 dollars for peace of mind is well worth it when the alternative is an $8,000 to $10,000 repair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it necessary for newly constructed homes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennifer says there’s a common misconception that, for new homes, everything is new, so why check it? But actually, it’s always a good idea to check for potential issues, even in new homes.  A sewer scope can help you discern if debris from the construction process is causing problems in your system. You’d be surprised what can get in your sewer lines; you don’t want to buy a home and move in only to discover a costly issue. Make sure to check it out before signing those papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Drano is a pretty harsh chemical; if you pour it down the drain, it will eat away at whatever is clogging the pipes, but it will also eat away at the pipes themselves%20http://localhost:4000/costly-sewer-repairs-stink-try-these-3-plumbing-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Drano is a pretty harsh chemical; if you pour it down the drain, it will eat away at whatever is clogging the pipes, but it will also eat away at the pipes themselves”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What’s the difference between a sewer scope and an actual clean-out of a sewer line?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sewer clean-outs are done when you have such problems as root intrusions or other blockages in your sewer lines. Though many people think that a sewer scope is the only thing they need to do, you do need to make sure that the lines down to the sewer main are clear. It’s important to do an annual maintenance check, especially if you live in an area with lots of trees, to be sure you won’t have any backups. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying on top of your drain maintenance with these tips should help make your life as a homeowner easier, safer, and cheaper, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Jennifer at Bill’s Plumbing and Drain Service, be sure &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.billsplumbinganddrainservice.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;visit their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other questions about real estate, feel free to reach out to the Homebound Team. We’d be happy to answer any questions you have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/costly-sewer-repairs-stink-try-these-3-plumbing-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/costly-sewer-repairs-stink-try-these-3-plumbing-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Listing For Sale By Owner a Good Idea?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GSx7_k-bH0s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s hot market, is hiring an agent really necessary? Actually yes, and today we&amp;rsquo;ll explain why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a fantastic market like the one we’re in right now, why would someone need the help of a listing agent to sell their home? Actually, the truth is that a lot more goes into listing a home than simply sticking a sign in the yard and waiting for buyers to flock in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the average real estate transaction, there are usually about 50 people involved in getting the deal from contract to close. &lt;strong&gt;Inspectors, appraisers, Realtors, and a number of other professionals all play a role in making sure things go smoothly&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, it’s no wonder why trying to take on all of the work alone is a poor choice. When you forgo the help of a professional agent, you’re doing more work and earning less money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Listing alone is no replacement for selling under the guidance of a professional agent.%20http://localhost:4000/is-listing-for-sale-by-owner-a-good-idea.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Listing alone is no replacement for selling under the guidance of a professional agent.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you work with our team, we’ll have your home cleaned, staged, and professionally photographed—all to make sure you see the best results possible for your listing&lt;/strong&gt;. We also use a number of advertising tools in order to attract maximum exposure. All in all, listing alone is no replacement for selling under the guidance of a professional agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-listing-for-sale-by-owner-a-good-idea.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/is-listing-for-sale-by-owner-a-good-idea.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
