<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tulsa Real Estate Video Blog with Jennie Wolek</title>
    <description>Our mission at Keller Williams Realty Advantage is to be your best resource for Tulsa real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Keller Williams Realty Advantage, your professional Tulsa Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 16:26:17 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 16:26:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Us Know How We Can Help</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rc9TN7qb26M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you all doing well? It’s important to all of us at The Wolek Group that we connect with our friends, family, and community to make sure you’re safe and that we’re providing you with all the resources we possibly can. &lt;strong&gt;If you need anything at all, please reach out to us.&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve already sent you helpful resources, but we want to be doubly sure you have everything you need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a Facebook page called &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/tulsalooksgoodonyou/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tulsa Looks Good on You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which was created to share all the wonderful things Tulsa has to offer, and during this time we’re being extremely deliberate about adding helpful things to it to assist our community. We look forward to seeing you soon and giving you a real hug or handshake—for now, it’s virtual. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With interest rates still low, there is plenty of activity.%20http://localhost:4000/let-us-know-how-we-can-help.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With interest rates still low, there is plenty of activity.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do want you to know we’re still doing business. People are still buying and selling homes. We’re watching the numbers every day, and believe it or not, with interest rates still low, there is plenty of activity. For those that need to buy or sell, we’re taking extra steps to be cautious during this health crisis. For example, &lt;strong&gt;we’re conducting tons of virtual open houses, home tours, and appointments via Zoom&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and FaceTime.&lt;/strong&gt; Still seeing each other sometimes is critical during this distancing period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions or need anything, please contact us via phone or email. We look forward to seeing and talking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/let-us-know-how-we-can-help.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/let-us-know-how-we-can-help.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 411 on 473: Tulsa’s Awesome New Bar</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/56-NWENbWt0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love Tulsa, we love food, and we really love new bars in town! We’re so excited to introduce you to Niki and Andrew Layson, the owners of Bar 473 here in Kendall Whittier district. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bar’s name is an homage to the building it occupies, which was once a nationally registered historic place: Phillips 66 gas station No. 473, one of the early businesses in the first suburban development of Tulsa. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Andrew, the location was also unique in that it allowed for more patio space, creating &lt;strong&gt;a more organic social atmosphere.&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond being nestled in a lovely neighborhood, 473 draws in patrons with well-crafted, affordable cocktails. Providing a venue for local acts—comedy, music, poetry, etc.—also means that 473 is truly a community gathering space. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niki and Andrew were able to accent the neutral colors of the World War II-era building and create a clean, inviting space. The bar’s minimalist approach to decor ensures that the smaller inside area never feels too overcrowded. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Beyond being nestled in a lovely neighborhood, 473 draws patrons in with well-crafted, affordable cocktails.%20http://localhost:4000/the-411-on-473-tulsas-awesome-new-bar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Beyond being nestled in a lovely neighborhood, 473 draws patrons in with well-crafted, affordable cocktails.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right across the way from American Slayer and Cabin Boys Brewery, &lt;strong&gt;473 is yet another testament to the increasing vibrancy of our Tulsa community!&lt;/strong&gt; Though the many bars and breweries in this district cooperate more than compete, 473 aims to separate itself from the pack by having a deeper commitment to the city’s blossoming music scene. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Andrew put it, “We need to pay more attention to those local artists that are creating real, raw music and who are trying to put themselves out there as artists.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow 473 on Instagram (@four.seven.three) and Facebook (@bar473), or visit their website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bar473.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.bar473.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the wonderful ways in which Tulsa is growing, or you’re interested in buying or selling soon, give us a call. We’d love to talk with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 11:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-411-on-473-tulsas-awesome-new-bar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-411-on-473-tulsas-awesome-new-bar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why the Garman Family Chose the Wolek Group</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ulycl992XDU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year, our team has the privilege of helping hundreds of families make their real estate dreams come true. We know buying and selling a home can be stressful, but if you work with us, we make it easy on you. Through these incredible experiences, we create friendships and memories that last a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With that in mind, I want to share a testimonial from one of our clients that speaks to our mission in this business. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We know buying and selling a home can be stressful, but if you work with us, we make it easy on you.%20http://localhost:4000/why-the-garman-family-chose-the-wolek-group.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We know buying and selling a home can be stressful, but if you work with us, we make it easy on you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We helped the Garman family sell their old home and buy a new one. They interviewed three Realtors before reaching out to us, but once they did, they described it as “a dream come true.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, they already had enough stress they could handle, so they wanted the buying and selling process to be as stress-free as possible. After staging their old home, we managed to sell it in just three days. We also staged their new home after helping them purchase it so they could settle in more comfortably. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the video above in its entirety to see their full testimonial and why they’d recommend the Wolek Group to all of their friends and family. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ever have any real estate needs, don’t hesitate to call or email me. My team and I would love to help. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 16:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-the-garman-family-chose-the-wolek-group.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-the-garman-family-chose-the-wolek-group.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet Teresa Brockwell: Insurance Agent Extraordinaire</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ET4EMJWuim0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our latest video, we have another special guest joining us: Teresa Brockwell, The Wolek Group’s insurance agent extraordinaire! Teresa’s always been a great supporter of our business and a great help to all of our clients, and today we’ll have a quick chat about how she can help you with your insurance needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch it in its entirety or use these timestamps to browse specific points at your leisure: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:24—The importance of meeting with your agent and discussing your options &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:31—How Teresa and her team specialize in helping busy professionals &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:19—Why it’s never a bad idea to get a second opinion on your policy &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:28—Wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to get in touch with Teresa and discuss your insurance options, give her a call or text her at (918) 496-1800. As always, if you have questions about any real estate topic or are thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 16:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/meet-teresa-brockwell-insurance-agent-extraordinaire.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/meet-teresa-brockwell-insurance-agent-extraordinaire.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Agent’s Experience With Transitioning to Our Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/d1vA31_Rmp4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I sat down for a chat with Nate Araskog, an agent here at The Wolek Group. He’s here to share his experiences as an agent on our team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before coming to The Wolek Group, Nate Araskog had obtained his real estate license and worked with Daniel Sprik, a Realtor and good friend of his who had encouraged him to get into the industry in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I helped him to sell a couple of his properties before, so one day Nate and I met for coffee. It was supposed to have been a short introduction, but it ended up becoming a two-and-half-hour meeting. During that conversation, Nate saw my experience and the opportunities that lay in the foundation of my team’s structure and he decided he wanted to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my part, the conversation over coffee had originally been about real estate in general, but toward the end, something clicked within me. I asked him, &lt;strong&gt;“Are you asking me all these questions to join Keller Williams or to join my team?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s fun to be on the front end of change within the real estate industry at large.%20http://localhost:4000/an-agents-experience-with-transitioning-to-our-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s fun to be on the front end of change within the real estate industry at large.”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a smile on his face, Nate responded, “I don’t know—maybe both.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I recommended that he and I set up another time to get back together. We did, and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve grown so much since then, &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;his experience with our team and with Keller Williams has been fabulous overall.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s fun to be on the front end of change within the real estate industry at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time Nate and I met for that fateful coffee meeting, he was already a go-getter who found success as a single agent. What was he missing that helped him see the value of joining a team?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For him, &lt;strong&gt;the biggest factor was the opportunity to learn from someone who had experience.&lt;/strong&gt; He knew that our team would provide the ability to help people as a part of an organization, not just a single agent. He knew from the first time we met that the partnership we could create by being in business together was going to be hugely successful for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about starting career in real estate or would like to contact us about joining The Wolek Group yourself, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to hear from you and discuss why making the switch to Keller Williams and The Wolek Group would be a great decision for the trajectory of your career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 10:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-agents-experience-with-transitioning-to-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/an-agents-experience-with-transitioning-to-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Unique Approach to Health With Deneen Natural Health</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VcshdW9Jq6g?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deneen Natural Health offers supplemental solutions for health and wellness. Here’s what you should know about their approach.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so excited to introduce you to Dr. Shana Deneen with Deneen Natural Health. I wanted to talk to her because she does something quite special that I think everyone should know about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At Deneen Natural Health, Shana brings a more natural approach to health, wellness, and disease prevention by practicing naturopathic medicine and acupuncture.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People come in for a variety of reasons. Maybe they’re trying to get pregnant, going through side effects of cancer treatment, or simply have some back or neck pain. &lt;strong&gt;What makes Deneen Natural Health different is that they offer supplemental solutions to improving the health of their patients.&lt;/strong&gt; There are a lot of natural ways to promote health through nutrition, acupuncture, and herbal medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Eating legumes can help prevent heart disease.%20http://localhost:4000/a-unique-approach-to-health-with-deneen-natural-health.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Eating legumes can help prevent heart disease.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as diet and nutrition go, she’s a big promoter of eating legumes like lentils, split peas, and beans. &lt;strong&gt;These foods are really healthy and can help prevent heart disease, promote gut health, and help with the prevention of many different kinds of cancer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those with cancer undergoing treatments with a lot of side effects, acupuncture is a great way to mitigate those effects and improve their overall quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more about Dr. Shana and Deneen Natural Health, visit her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deneennaturalhealth.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;or give her a call at (918) 884-6005.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions for me about real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 16:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-unique-approach-to-health-with-deneen-natural-health.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-unique-approach-to-health-with-deneen-natural-health.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where You Can Find Authentic Wood-Fired Pizza</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iCN3yop7TjA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have a craving for wood-fired pizza, I have just the place to introduce you to on the latest episode of “Tulsa Foodie.”
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the latest episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” I want to introduce you to one of my favorite restaurants: the East Village Bohemian Pizzeria. Joining me for a quick sit-down is Amy McMillin, who co-owns the restaurant with her brother. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amy and her brother have been involved in the food industry since they were teenagers, and they share a special love of Italian food. Amy got her first taste of wood-fired pizza 15 years ago when she got the chance to visit Naples, and after she did, she decided that she had to recreate the same taste back home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secret to their pizza’s amazing taste, according to Amy, &lt;strong&gt;is their dedication to cooking everything fresh and authentic, just like they do in Italy. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I learned the hard way that you need a reservation on most nights if you want to get a table here.%20http://localhost:4000/where-you-can-find-authentic-wood-fired-pizza.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I learned the hard way that you need a reservation on most nights if you want to get a table here.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Every morning,” she says, “we come in and light the fire in our wood-fired oven, which has no gas—we’re stacking the wood and making the fire—and we’re roasting all the fresh vegetables every day. All the meats are getting roasted. We make our dough from scratch. We import our flour from Italy. And we’re doing that fresh every single day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the great food, they have a fun, cool vibe inside their restaurant. Their five-year anniversary at their current location in downtown Tulsa is coming up on December 19, and in those five years, they’ve built a wine room and a second kitchen which makes handmade pasta daily. They also have an amazing patio (which I’m a big fan of), where guests are known to wine and dine year-round—even when the temperature is nearly freezing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned the hard way that you need a reservation on most nights if you want to get a table here, and I can’t wait to try my next Bohemian pizza. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about the East Village Bohemian Pizzeria, &lt;strong&gt;visit their website at&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eastvillagebohemian.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;www.eastvillagebohemian.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;or check out their Instagram feed @bohemianpizzatulsa.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions for me or there’s anything I can help you with, give me a call or shoot me an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 16:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/where-you-can-find-authentic-wood-fired-pizza.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/where-you-can-find-authentic-wood-fired-pizza.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Story Behind My Career in Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p1xHi8MDt1o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often ask me how I got into real estate, and so I’d like to share that story with all of you today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’m originally from Tulsa and attended the University of Oklahoma just a couple hours away from there (Boomer Sooner!). I spent a lot of those years in school being average and only just barely getting by. I think that’s because, like a lot of college-aged kids, I didn’t know my passion or purpose in life. Finally, I got into classes that I cared about and I realized that I was a good student after all. I went on to get my master’s degree in Human Relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that time, I was still waiting tables at the mall in Norman. &lt;strong&gt;I really think that a lot of the best real estate agents are those who have been servers.&lt;/strong&gt; A friend of mine from high school who had just gotten into real estate reached out to me, asking if I needed to buy a house. At the time, I didn’t have any money, so how was I supposed to buy a house? To that, he responded, “You should get into real estate; a friend in my office just made $100,000 last month.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flexibility and lucrative nature of the real estate industry was very appealing to me at that age. &lt;strong&gt;After a while, though, I realized that there was a lot more hard work necessary than just selling lots of houses and raking in the money.&lt;/strong&gt; I realized that my work ethic, which I somehow just had in me, was starting to pay off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began working for a small brokerage with just five people in the office. I was learning how to be a property manager and how to be an office manager; I partnered with a broker and got to go on listing appointments and worked with homebuyers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After four years of working in real estate in Norman I knew that I was getting to the age where I wanted to be able to get back home to my family. I sold the two houses that I had bought in those four years and moved back home to Tulsa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re always looking for more people to come into our world so that we can help more families, have fun, give back to the community, and live large.%20http://localhost:4000/the-story-behind-my-career-in-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re always looking for more people to come into our world so that we can help more families, have fun, give back to the community, and live large.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I did, I signed on with a local, traditional real estate company. I was doing well at the time, but I didn’t know how to be anything other than a lead receiver, which means that I would show up to open houses and smile and be nice to people—over time, they would open up and let me help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then, I discovered a company called Keller Williams.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s when everything changed for me in my business and my personal life. Once I signed on with Keller Williams, I just ate up all of the available training, coaching, and mentoring that I could get my hands on. That really opened my mind; I started to dream big and realized that with Keller Williams, I could achieve those dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as a single agent, I was starting to get overwhelmed. I was working all kinds of crazy hours, and when I reached a breaking point, I knew that I needed help. That’s when the idea of building a team entered my mind. &lt;strong&gt;I didn’t want to build a team to crush the faces off the Tulsa, Oklahoma real estate market, but rather because I wanted to hold on to my sanity!&lt;/strong&gt; I wanted to be a good wife, mother, and agent, and building a team allowed me to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s fun about growing a team is that you get to help others do the same. It’s such an amazing experience. We’re always looking for more people to come into our world so that we can help more families, have fun, give back to the community, and live large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever thought about starting a career in real estate, or if you’re currently in the business but you’re not finding the success that you want, reach out to me. I’d love to chat with you about an amazing opportunity to join our team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 11:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-story-behind-my-career-in-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-story-behind-my-career-in-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why This Happy Client Recommends The Wolek Group</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tqUffqwgNsg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why does Katherine Fondren recommend The Wolek Group to anyone interested in buying or selling real estate? Today, she can tell you herself:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I had a home that I needed to sell. I had known Jennie Wolek over the years through mutual friends, and I was definitely looking for something different… something outside of the box. I was a Realtor in Louisiana when I lived there, so I thought I knew everything about the real estate business, but that was a long time ago, before the age of social media and all kinds of new marketing things.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“That’s why I loved about Jennie and what her company was doing: They were doing some outside-the-box marketing. Jennie would come over; we sat at my kitchen table and discussed what our goals were. She asked me what I liked best about my home and what prospective buyers should know about it. I was happy to share that information and she definitely used it in her marketing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I felt she really wanted to do what was best for me and my family, as well as the people buying my home.%20http://localhost:4000/why-this-happy-client-recommends-the-wolek-group.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I felt she really wanted to do what was best for me and my family, as well as the people buying my home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Then we immediately started the buying process. I met with one of her buyer’s agents and we discussed what we were looking for and needed in a home. And throughout the process, there was a lot of feedback, which I really value; being a former Realtor, I know that’s really important. A lot of my friends who are looking for Realtors always want feedback. If someone looked at your house, what did they think? How can we improve? What do they like? What do they not like?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“When we finally did get a buyer, I was really excited. Jennie did everything she could to walk us through the process. She was great from beginning to end, and I felt she really wanted to do what was best for me and my family, as well as the people buying my home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We found this beautiful house that we’re standing in right now in a neighborhood we didn’t even know about. It’s a new home from a builder I didn’t know; Jennie’s team had the knowledge of the market, so they knew what was going on even in new construction. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I’m thankful to The Wolek Group for helping steer us in the right direction and helping us find our dream home. It’s a wonderful process from beginning to end, very stress-free with a lot of communication, and I definitely, definitely recommend them!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you, like Katherine, ever need any help with your real estate needs, please feel free to reach out to us here at The Wolek Group. We’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-this-happy-client-recommends-the-wolek-group.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-this-happy-client-recommends-the-wolek-group.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thanks to You, We’ve Served Over 100 Families in 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L4Ypgwat2gE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce that we’ve served over 100 families in 2019. Because of our amazing clients, we’ve been able to help more, give back, have fun, and live large. With every home sold, we’ve been able to give back a portion of our proceeds to Keys to the City—a non-profit dedicated to giving back to our Tulsa community. We wouldn’t be able to do any of this without the amazing support of our family, friends, the people who help our team, and our clients. Thank you from the bottom of our hearts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you need help with anything real estate related, don’t hesitate to give us a call. We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/webp-net-resizeimage-10-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;220&quot; height=&quot;97&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/thanks-to-you-weve-served-over-100-families-in-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/thanks-to-you-weve-served-over-100-families-in-2019.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
