<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Roth Team is to be your best resource for Greater Milwaukee real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Roth Team, your professional Greater Milwaukee Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 12:36:55 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 12:36:55 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How the COVID-19 Pandemic Has Affected Our Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jyw3-cWk-fM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Despite the COVID-19 pandemic, buyers are still buying and sellers are still selling in our market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How have the COVID-19 pandemic and subsequent stay-at-home ordinances (which have been extended until the end of May) affected the real estate market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate has been deemed an essential service, and obviously, the health and safety of our clients is our top priority. We can still show homes by appointment only and list them, and while showing homes, we do our utmost to practice social distancing. We can’t, however, host open houses or have more than five people inside a house at the same time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t buy into the myth that homes aren’t selling. &lt;strong&gt;From April 1 to April 17, 727 new listings hit the market in the Greater Milwaukee area, and 594 homes went under contract.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers are still buying, too—especially with interest rates this low. Home sales last March increased by 8% to 10% in most areas compared to March 2019. This makes now a good time to sell. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can still show homes by appointment only and list them, and while showing homes, we do our utmost to practice social distancing.%20http://localhost:4000/how-the-covid-19-pandemic-has-affected-our-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We can still show homes by appointment only and list them, and while showing homes, we do our utmost to practice social distancing.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prices haven’t dropped, either. If anything, we’re seeing multiple offers for homes &lt;em&gt;over&lt;/em&gt; their asking price. We just sold a home in the Sussex/Lisbon area that generated four offers, all of which were over asking price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will they eventually go down? Considering everything that’s happening with the economy. If I were a gambling man, I’d say, yes, eventually they will go down, given everything that’s happening with the economy. Everything is based on supply and demand. &lt;strong&gt;Right now, supply is low and demand is high, but after the stay-at-home ordinances are lifted, there will be a lot more people listing their homes.&lt;/strong&gt; When supply rises faster than the demand, that’s when prices drop, and I predict this drop to happen in three to six months. How far prices will drop is anyone’s guess. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready to sell or have questions about our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. My team and I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 12:28:54 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-the-covid-19-pandemic-has-affected-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-the-covid-19-pandemic-has-affected-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trust a Seasoned Agent, Not an Algorithm</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/G6c9RIrntzY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what you should know about how Zillow determines the value of your home and why it’s flawed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the growing popularity of Zillow and other instant offer sites like it comes one important question: Can you trust Zillow’s estimate of your home’s value? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For perspective, Zillow has only been around since 2007; I’ve been in real estate since 1981, so I think I have a leg up on Zillow. In most cases, when Zillow comes up with its valuation (known as a Zestimate), they don’t even step foot into your home, they just crunch marketplace data. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=To be honest, I don’t even think Zillow knows why it changes its figures.%20http://localhost:4000/trust-a-seasoned-agent-not-an-algorithm.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“To be honest, I don’t even think Zillow knows why it changes its figures.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zillow uses an algorithm to estimate home value, and there’s no way for that algorithm to factor in any improvements you’ve made to the property.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve had several people ask me, “Well, why did Zillow raise my price,” or, “Why did Zillow lower my price?” To be honest, I don’t even think Zillow knows why it changes its figures. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is this: Don’t trust Zillow. What you need to do is get an experienced agent to look at the inherent benefits of and improvements to your home. Here at the Roth Team, we compare what homes like yours have recently sold for with what’s currently on the market. Then, based on your competition, we position your home so you get the highest price possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, don’t fret if Zillow gives you an estimate that seems leagues lower than what you feel is right. It almost certainly &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; too low, so seek out a professional opinion. If you’re thinking of selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me or someone else on the Roth Team. We’d be happy to sit down with you and figure out how to get you the most money for your home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 15:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/trust-a-seasoned-agent-not-an-algorithm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/trust-a-seasoned-agent-not-an-algorithm.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What the Real Estate Market Will Do in 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_85UwoPuDGA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I’m sharing my predictions regarding prices, inventory, interest rates and average days on market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring you up to speed on our current real estate market, interest rates are still low, and we’re looking at fixed-rate mortgages as low as 3% to 3.5%. Here are my predictions on what the market will do in this new year: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Interest rates will stay low.&lt;/strong&gt; The government said it wants to hold interest rates, so I think for at least the next six months you can expect them to stay low, but after that—you never know. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Inventory will increase.&lt;/strong&gt; As of the beginning of January, we’re seeing the lowest level of single-family homes for sale in the Milwaukee area, less than 4,000. For reference, compare this number to roughly 9,000 homes in January 2015. However, as we head into the spring and summer months, I do expect that we will see an increase. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I predict that in 2020 we will see a 3% to 5% increase in prices.%20http://localhost:4000/what-the-real-estate-market-will-do-in-2020.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I predict that in 2020 we will see a 3% to 5% increase in prices.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Median sale prices will continue to go up.&lt;/strong&gt; The rise likely won’t be as high as what we saw recently in the Milwaukee area, where prices in some cases increased by 8% to 10%. I predict that in 2020 we will see a 3% to 5% increase in prices. If inventory levels get higher, prices may even level out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The average days on market will increase.&lt;/strong&gt; In most market places, the average days on market is about 30 days. The higher price-range homes (anything from $500,000 to $1 million-plus) are still taking longer to sell and aren’t going up in value as much. The average days on market in 2020 will be lengthened by an increase in inventory. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a great time to buy a home when you consider how low the interest rates are; if you need pre-approval, contact us and we can get you set up with a lender. Sellers: take advantage of what will be the seventh year of a strong seller’s market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to get a valuation on your home, give me a call or reach out to anyone at the Roth Team. We’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 11:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-the-real-estate-market-will-do-in-2020.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-the-real-estate-market-will-do-in-2020.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Dangers of Overpricing Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IO53bln7Ij0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All sellers want to get the most they can out of their home sale. However, there are some issues associated with listing your home for too high of a price. Today, I’ll be discussing the five dangers of overpricing your property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An overpriced home will lead to fewer showings.&lt;/strong&gt; The fewer showings you have, the fewer chances you have to get an offer on your home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An overpriced home will attract the wrong buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers seek out homes based on their price brackets. If your home is missing the features and amenities of other homes within the price range you’ve placed it in, buyers are going to notice. Buyers who are looking in a given price range know what they want and expect from homes. You must price your home according to its true value so that you can capture buyers who will be legitimately interested.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Overpricing your home when you put it on the market can be a huge mistake. Today, I’ll explain why.%20http://localhost:4000/5-dangers-of-overpricing-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Overpricing your home when you put it on the market can be a huge mistake. Today, I’ll explain why.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An overpriced home helps your competitors.&lt;/strong&gt;If a buyer looks at your home and then visits another that is priced the same but comes with more features, your competitor’s home will look like a much better deal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An overpriced home takes longer to sell.&lt;/strong&gt; In some cases, overpriced homes may not sell at all.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An overpriced home that is later reduced won’t have the same impact.&lt;/strong&gt; If you lower your home’s price after it has already been sitting on the market, it will lack the impact of a new home coming onto the market that was priced correctly from the start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 12:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-dangers-of-overpricing-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-dangers-of-overpricing-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Questions To Ask Your Potential Realtor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HQ_FdNJuyDQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before saying, “You’re hired,” when interviewing a real estate agent to represent you, you’ll want to be sure they possess the hallmarks of a worthy candidate. To that end, today I’m sharing three questions you should ask any potential hire:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your list-to-sales-price ratio?&lt;/strong&gt; In our local market, this figure varies considerably—it could be anywhere from 93% to 95%. On average, our team’s ratio is at about 97%, which means we’re helping sellers net 2% to 4% more on their sale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you going to do differently to get my home sold?&lt;/strong&gt; Get an idea of the kind of unique touch they’ll give to marketing your home. It’s not enough for them to simply put your home on the MLS, stick a sign in your front yard, and hold an open house. You need to know, in no uncertain terms, what they’ll do to sell your home with a high degree of competency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How many homes have you sold so far this year?&lt;/strong&gt; Believe or not, the average agent has sold a paltry total of three homes on the year. Unlike the average agent, we at the Roth Team have sold 200 homes and counting in 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need to know, in no uncertain terms, what the agent will do to sell your home with a high degree of competency.%20http://localhost:4000/3-questions-to-ask-your-potential-realtor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You need to know, in no uncertain terms, what the agent will do to sell your home with a high degree of competency.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that this is the largest financial transaction of your life, it’s infinitely important for you to be happy with the agent you choose to go with. If you have any questions you’d like to ask us, go ahead and give us a call. We’d be happy to serve your real estate needs!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 17:28:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-questions-to-ask-your-potential-realtor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-questions-to-ask-your-potential-realtor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Handle the Issue of Buyer Repair Requests</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bu0-J4qipZU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers often ask me, “What should I do if a buyer finds a defect in my home? Should I fix the defect, give the buyer a credit, or can I sell the home as-is?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;strong&gt;the answer to that question is best determined by you and the buyer&lt;/strong&gt;. When the buyer hires a professional inspector, that inspector must cite everything they see; if they do find a defect, that must be disclosed on their report to not only that buyer, but also to any other buyer you’re selling to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most instances as a seller, you’ll likely have to fix that defect because most buyers aren’t willing to assume that problem, unless you inform them upfront and they have the ability to fix it before they close. Cash buyers may be able to do it after closing, but &lt;strong&gt;most lenders will require the defect to be fixed before they actually close.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In most instances as a seller, you’ll likely have to fix that defect because most buyers aren’t willing to assume that problem.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-handle-the-issue-of-buyer-repair-requests.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In most instances as a seller, you’ll likely have to fix that defect because most buyers aren’t willing to assume that problem.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what happens if sellers don’t have the funds to fix the problem before closing? We have contractors we can work with who will figure out where the repair would be done, and then &lt;strong&gt;the cost would be taken out of your closing proceeds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your other option, besides fixing the defect, would be to &lt;strong&gt;offer a credit to the buyer&lt;/strong&gt;. That way, you could proceed with the sale and the buyer could make the repair after closing, assuming their lender will accept them taking that credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about inspections and the defects that are likely to come up on the inspection reports, feel free to reach out to us anytime. We’d be happy to address any concerns you have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 15:30:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-handle-the-issue-of-buyer-repair-requests.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-handle-the-issue-of-buyer-repair-requests.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Need to Attend Your Home’s Showings?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gBwd3bpv5vY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I thought I’d answer a question that I’m often asked by sellers: &lt;strong&gt;“Should I be present during my home’s showings?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some times, sellers think they know their home more than their agent and can share that information with the buyer. &lt;strong&gt;However, when the seller is present at a showing, it can and does make the buyer a little uncomfortable.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re not there, they’ll be more comfortable, honest, and open. If you’re there, the buyer might be afraid to give that honest feedback because they don’t want to offend you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Let the agent handle the selling of your home.%20http://localhost:4000/do-you-need-to-attend-your-homes-showings.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Let the agent handle the selling of your home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to be gone when they get there, but leave during the showing for a half hour or hour. &lt;strong&gt;You also want to make sure all the lights are on and all the blinds are open so you get as much natural daylight as possible in the house.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, let the agent handle the selling of your home. If they’re an experienced professional, it will be no problem and will lead you to happy results. If you have any other questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 15:07:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/do-you-need-to-attend-your-homes-showings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/do-you-need-to-attend-your-homes-showings.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Really Don’t Want to Make Any of These 10 Homebuying Blunders</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KWxsO1CHa-E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The homebuying process can be complicated, but it’s compounded when the buyer acts without the proper knowledge of what they’re doing. They may seem like common sense to avoid, but believe it or not, the following 10 mistakes to avoid have actually happened in transactions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financing new purchases after applying for a mortgage.&lt;/strong&gt; You absolutely do not want to make any other major purchases while you’re in the process of getting a mortgage for a home, including a car, furniture, or the like. This will affect your credit, possibly damaging your chances of getting a mortgage altogether.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applying for new credit.&lt;/strong&gt;  Do not apply for any other type of credit during the process, be it for a different loan or a new credit card.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Racking up credit card debt.&lt;/strong&gt; Avoid increasing your current debt on your credit card(s) or risk sending up red flags in your mortgage lender’s eyes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changing jobs or reducing your hours.&lt;/strong&gt; Keep your current job and hours, if at all possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switching banks or making large transfers.&lt;/strong&gt; Your down payments will need to be verified at the bank you had when you applied for your home loan; switching banks will derail the process. Large transfers can also be suspicious to lenders.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making late credit card, installment, or utility payments.&lt;/strong&gt; The key to great credit is consistent, timely payments; late payments bring your score on your report down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-signing on a loan for anyone.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if that other person is a family member or a loved one, co-signing on a loan while you’re in the mortgage process will affect your ability to get a loan yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neglecting to list your debt on your loan application.&lt;/strong&gt; It will show up on your credit report regardless, so be upfront when you apply for your loan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making large deposits into your bank account.&lt;/strong&gt; Your lender will need to verify where those funds came from.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spending your closing money…before closing.&lt;/strong&gt; Believe it or not, this happened to a buyer during a transaction. That money needs to be set aside for the purchase of the home and spending it early defeats the purpose and only hurts your ability to buy that home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can avoid these 10 home buying mistakes once your offer is accepted and you begin applying for financing, the entire process should go over smoothly for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Avoid increasing your current debt on your credit card(s) or risk sending up red flags in your mortgage lender’s eyes.%20http://localhost:4000/you-really-dont-want-to-make-any-of-these-10-homebuying-blunders.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Avoid increasing your current debt on your credit card(s) or risk sending up red flags in your mortgage lender’s eyes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For any questions about these mistakes or about home financing in general, please feel free to reach out to us. We’d be more than glad to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 09:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/you-really-dont-want-to-make-any-of-these-10-homebuying-blunders.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/you-really-dont-want-to-make-any-of-these-10-homebuying-blunders.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Will Our 2019 Market Look Like?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_DB3BqPCx4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve entered the new year, let’s take a moment and share our predictions for what lies ahead. There are four main things we can expect moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What’s happening now in our local real estate market, and how will things play out through the rest of this year? Find out in today’s message.%20http://localhost:4000/what-will-our-2019-market-look-like.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What’s happening now in our local real estate market, and how will things play out through the rest of this year? Find out in today’s message.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest rates will probably rise.&lt;/strong&gt; Though rates are still historically low, they are set to go up at least twice in 2019. Now may be the time to lock in rates while they’re still between 4.5% and 5%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inventory will increase.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s likely that more homes will soon hit our market, meaning buyers will have greater choice in the near future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The average days on market will go up.&lt;/strong&gt; Even in hot price ranges, the increase in inventory will likely cause homes to sit on the market for longer periods of time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;prices are going to level out or flatten.&lt;/strong&gt; Brokers throughout the country have already reported this trend, and our midwest market is sure to see similar conditions soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 04:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-will-our-2019-market-look-like.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-will-our-2019-market-look-like.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summing Up the 2018 Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/z_1zsKQT36s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;we saw the number of homes that actually sold in the Greater Milwaukee area drop about 2.5%&lt;/strong&gt; compared to 2017. Interestingly enough, the number of listings that came on the market was also down almost 5%, meaning there were fewer homes available for buyers to choose from. Overall, in &lt;strong&gt;most marketplaces, we saw prices go up anywhere from 5% to 6%.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With all the buyers trying to lock in a home before the interest rates go up again, now is the time to put your home on the market, even before Spring.%20http://localhost:4000/summing-up-the-2018-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With all the buyers trying to lock in a home before the interest rates go up again, now is the time to put your home on the market, even before Spring.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With interest rates expected to rise again this year, we expect a lot more homes to come on the market, especially in the spring—&lt;strong&gt;there could be 25% to 30% more homes available.&lt;/strong&gt; With all the buyers trying to lock in a home before the interest rates go up again, now is the time to put your home on the market, even before Spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Roth Team had one of its best years in 2018—we closed on 245 homes, and our overall sales were up close to 15%. For that success, &lt;strong&gt;we thank you&lt;/strong&gt;, our past and current clients, for all your referrals and your business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 04:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/summing-up-the-2018-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/summing-up-the-2018-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
