<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your Journey with Jennie | Jennie Wolek</title>
    <description>Jennie Wolek, a top Real Estate Agent in Tulsa, shares her own internal real estate agent training for free. Her Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 16:09:25 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 16:09:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Passing the Baton?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OmT3TIguXPk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;With a team, you can pass the baton to win in a transaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Have you ever run track or seen a relay race? If so, then you know the necessity of passing the baton from one team member to another. A good track coach will tell you that &lt;strong&gt;a relay is won or lost in the transfer of the baton&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at The Wolek Group believe in the importance of passing the baton in real estate too. If you don’t have a team, you have no one to pass the baton to and must do all the work yourself. We pass three different batons during our real estate transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, when working with a seller, we pass a baton from the listing agent to the listing manager. The second baton is passed from the buyer agent to the transaction coordinator during pending or from the listing manager to the transaction coordinator when working with a seller. Third, &lt;strong&gt;between 24 and 48 hours before closing is when the baton is passed back to the real estate agent&lt;/strong&gt; from the transaction coordinator. This arms the agent with all the information they need to know before closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What truly matters is communication between team members.%20http://localhost:4000/are-you-passing-the-baton.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What truly matters is communication between team members.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When passing all these batons, what truly matters is communication between team members. Every time a baton is passed, it’s followed by a debriefing, a conversation between team members to ensure we completely understand all the intricacies and needs of the client. Anytime the ball is dropped it goes back to a lack of communication. We do our best to not allow that to happen; &lt;strong&gt;it’s our goal to win the relay!&lt;/strong&gt; We win by getting to closing with elated clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about how we pass the batons, I’m sharing the information in my closed Facebook group Your Journey With Jennie. Join today! If you ever have any questions about real estate, reach out to us via phone or email. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-passing-the-baton.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-passing-the-baton.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect at the &quot;Implement My Business&quot; Seminar?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/07nAD8x4_mI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to learn how to put our systems into action!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thank you to all the amazing real estate agents who joined me in June to learn how to “Mirror My Business!” I provided you with lots of systems, tools, and tips on how to build a big business, with much of it coming from your database. Today I’m excited to share with you a follow-up series and a deeper dive to teach you how to “Implement My Business,” launching in July!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For six weeks starting on July 7, we’ll hold 90-minute sessions in which we’ll discuss accountability and connect with like-minded agents who look forward to building a big business&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ll even throw in a extra systems and tools that I couldn’t fit into the “Mirror My Business” workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I’m excited to dive deeper and share with you how to Implement My Business!%20http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-expect-at-the-implement-my-business-seminar.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I’m excited to dive deeper and share with you how to Implement My Business!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/implement-my-business-6-week-series-tickets-106686466092&quot;&gt;sign up today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;! If you already attended the “Mirror My Business” workshop, simply &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;mailto:jennie@thewolekgroup.com?subject=%E2%80%9CImplement%20My%20Business%E2%80%9D%20seminar&quot;&gt;send me an email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;I’ll share the discount code with you&lt;/strong&gt;. If you didn’t, that’s okay, because you’ll receive all the same materials and documents as the other students as well as links to my Google Drive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out. I can’t wait to see you and share how to implement my business strategies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-expect-at-the-implement-my-business-seminar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-expect-at-the-implement-my-business-seminar.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Experience of Being Hacked &amp; Deleted From Facebook</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hXoFFdDlcOQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting your Facebook hacked stinks, but here&amp;rsquo;s what I learned from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Recently my Facebook account was hacked and deleted. Here’s what I learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. When we are a “serf on someone else’s digital land,”&lt;/strong&gt; as a friend of mine phrased it best, bad things can happen. Every day, we willingly give our thoughts, insights, and pictures to social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Facebook and Instagram are connected&lt;/strong&gt;—if you lose one, you lose them both! Ouch… again, it was not fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. We must own where we put our content&lt;/strong&gt;, or at least back it up, so that way if it’s lost, it’s not lost forever. I acted fast and reached out to my business coach and marketing friend for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. I had an addiction&lt;/strong&gt;. I used it to fool myself into thinking that I was always connecting with people and working when I was on those apps. I noticed that, on the first day of not having these apps, I still naturally kept going to the icons on my phone and clicking them. I finally deleted them and that helped a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Frustratingly, there is no way to contact a real human at Facebook for help.%20http://localhost:4000/my-experience-of-being-hacked-deleted-from-facebook.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Frustratingly, there is no way to contact a real human at Facebook for help.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. My mindset is strong&lt;/strong&gt;. Sometimes, there are things in life that I cannot control. It’s OK! Once I realized the likely fate of what happened, I accepted it and moved on quickly to find solutions for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. I’m still gun shy with social media&lt;/strong&gt;. Maybe I’m still a bit mad, too. Frustratingly, there is no way to contact a real human at Facebook for help. After a few days, I was able to create a new account, and I’m very slowly working through accepting new friend requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. We always need to find the silver lining&lt;/strong&gt;. I no longer have 5,000 Facebook friends, through which I must scroll to find someone to remove whenever I add a new friend. Though no longer publicly displayed on Facebook, all of my memories last within me and with my friends and family. I’ve left the Facebook and Insta apps on the last page of my phone, and the addiction has slightly subsided. I have been more present and focused on my work and family over the last five days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found this encouraging, whether you’ve suffered such an experience or not. As always, please feel free to reach out to the Wolek Group by phone or email if you have any questions about real estate. We’re here to help (and a live person will always be there to talk to you).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-experience-of-being-hacked-deleted-from-facebook.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/my-experience-of-being-hacked-deleted-from-facebook.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Starting the Day Off Great</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LTM7XoDIOlI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sharing my morning routine, hoping it helps you with yours.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I often get asked about my morning schedule, so today I’m sharing it with you. Years ago, I learned that the most successful people, at least in my business, all had one thing in common: they got up early. To me, early meant 5 a.m., so that’s when I started getting up every day. I quickly noticed that it was a great way to get ahead of my day. Since I enjoy a cup of coffee in the morning, I decided to wake up even earlier—around 4:45 a.m.—to have some coffee, think, and prepare for the day ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After my morning coffee and daily goal-planning, I exercise&lt;/strong&gt; by doing some yoga, using the treadmill, or even going outside for a walk or run—anything that allows me to feel good about myself, both mentally and physically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I take a shower and have a smoothie for breakfast. I’ve had the same smoothie almost every morning for at least five years. It’s packed with all kinds of good things: spinach, a frozen triple berry blend, protein powder, etc. At this point, my stomach is full, my mind is good, and my heart is strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’m the type of person who wears makeup and takes care of their hair, I’ll do that next before listening to a podcast or reading a book. Over time, I’ve learned that’s a way to think bigger and generate new ideas throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, &lt;strong&gt;I write a post in a closed Facebook group called &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/yourjourneywithJennie&quot;&gt;Your Journey With Jenny&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; every single morning&lt;/strong&gt;. Members can always tell what I’m working on, thinking about, and reading. Click on the above link to get permission to join if you haven’t already!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you plan out your morning with a powerful, intentional schedule, the rest of your day falls into place.%20http://localhost:4000/the-key-to-starting-the-day-off-great.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you plan out your morning with a powerful, intentional schedule, the rest of your day falls into place.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’m through with all that, I’ll connect with my team at 8:15 a.m. to share what we’re grateful for as well as what our intentions and goals are for the day. Then from 9 a.m. to 11 a.m., we work on lead generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that when you plan out your morning with a powerful, intentional schedule, the rest of your day falls into place and you’ll be more positive and ready to connect with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to reach out to me to share your morning routine!&lt;/strong&gt; If there’s anything I can do to help, don’t hesitate to ask. I’m here for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-key-to-starting-the-day-off-great.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-key-to-starting-the-day-off-great.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Want to Mirror My Business?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xgpeSgm7hWE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re hosting a &quot;Mirror My Business&quot; webinar, so come learn from us!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Want to mirror my business? Now you can! I’ve been in the real estate business for 19 years, and for the first time, &lt;strong&gt;I’m offering a three-hour “Mirror My Business” workshop&lt;/strong&gt;. I want to share our successful practices with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be sharing the systems, tools, and models that we use to help over 100 families each year. We’ll discuss mindset, mission, lead generation and conversion, marketing, setting appointments, listings and buyer presentations, agent and affiliate referrals, reviews, and ‘clients for life.’ I look forward to spending time with you in our small group webinar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To register, &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/mirror-my-business-workshop-with-jennie-wolek-tickets-104824745636&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the workshop or real estate in general, please reach out via phone or email. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/want-to-mirror-my-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/want-to-mirror-my-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <category>Listing Presentation</category>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Golden Handoff?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I5v34C_-fXc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many agents come and go in the real estate business. The Golden Handoff ensures their clients are taken care of after they leave.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have been in the real estate business for a very long time, and no matter what is happening in the market, many agents come and go constantly. What’s sad about this is that those &lt;strong&gt;Realtors have put time, energy, money, and often their love into developing and nurturing tons of relationships&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When agents leave the business for any reason, their clients are just left there, without a real estate agent to help them. I believe all real state agents should think like the businessperson they are and ensure that their clients are taken care of in the future. They should have a plan. That’s what the Golden Handoff is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Golden Handoff is entrusting a database to another agent and receiving a referral fee in return. That new real estate agent will have a plan and stay in touch with these clients. How smart and simple is that? This doesn’t cost the departing agent any time, energy, or money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Golden Handoff is entrusting a database to another agent and receiving a referral fee in return.%20http://localhost:4000/what-is-the-golden-handoff.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Golden Handoff is entrusting a database to another agent and receiving a referral fee in return.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please let me know if you’ve used the Golden Handoff in your business&lt;/strong&gt;, I’d like to hear about your experience with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the Golden Handoff or real estate in general, reach out to me via phone or email. I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-the-golden-handoff.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-the-golden-handoff.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <category>Reviews and Referrals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Implementing a Flexible Commission Plan</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KzbVmBwsDJ4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Implementing a flexible commission plan is a great way to compete against agents who adjust their commission in order to win listings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The market has shifted since the COVID-19 pandemic, and some agents are adjusting their commission in order to win listings. Even if your value proposition is much stronger to would-be clients than theirs, &lt;strong&gt;adjusted commissions are a hard thing to compete against&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s why today I’ll talk about the benefits of implementing a flexible commission plan into your business. This offers your would-be clients options instead of ultimatums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or suggestions, please reach out. We look forward to speaking with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-implementing-a-flexible-commission-plan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-implementing-a-flexible-commission-plan.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Stay Connected</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sv07TmjnqTw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the three ways we at The Wolek Group stay connected:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. We have a Google Hangout call every morning at 8:15 a.m.&lt;/strong&gt; This allows us to state our gratitude and share our intentions for the day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. We have a team meeting every Monday at 11 a.m.&lt;/strong&gt; This is an official meeting with an agenda. It also acts as a training session in case there are topics we need to cover. It’s a great way to keep an open dialogue about everything that’s happening. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. We use a communication tool called Slack.&lt;/strong&gt; This allows us to consolidate all of our communication into one place. We’ve found that information can get lost through text and emails. With Slack, every channel is a different category, and it’s a great place to store our team’s communication. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To accommodate our team and our clients during these trying times we are doing Zoom team meetings and virtual appointments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re always striving for success and making sure we deliver an amazing client experience, and communication is key.%20http://localhost:4000/how-we-stay-connected.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re always striving for success and making sure we deliver an amazing client experience, and communication is key.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication can separate the great companies from the not-so-great ones. We’re always striving for success and making sure we deliver an amazing client experience, and communication is key. Communicating as a team is very important. It’s also important that our clients see this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication with our people is just as important, and we ensure this by creating a GPS for each year. &lt;strong&gt;Our goals, priorities, and strategies are outlined inside our marketing plan.&lt;/strong&gt; Our goals are also placed inside our calendar so we can review them and send our 411s to each other every Monday morning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s lots to do and lots to stay on top of, but when you think big and break everything down, you see what the life of a very productive real estate professional looks like. Just take care of your most important items each day if you want to achieve greatness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to talk about how you can improve your team’s communication or have any questions about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 15:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-we-stay-connected.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-we-stay-connected.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <category>Listing Presentation</category>
        
        <category>Reviews and Referrals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I’m Sharing My Failures With You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3v6P8_i2mUs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re talking about failures. What a lovely topic, right? I actually used to do a “Fail Forward Friday” series where I would share my failures and I think it was a great way to share with other agents that failure is actually just feedback. &lt;strong&gt;I think I stopped doing it because I didn’t want to dwell on my failures.&lt;/strong&gt; However, I just heard a quote that changed my mind: “Success is just failure with enthusiasm.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I have noticed is that even though I look like I’m good at using leverage, it is something I’m not great at doing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I have a great team, but I don’t always leverage them properly.%20http://localhost:4000/why-im-sharing-my-failures-with-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I have a great team, but I don’t always leverage them properly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will find myself spending lots of focused time getting into the details of activities, especially when it comes to our database and administrative tasks. &lt;strong&gt;I like those things and am good at those things, but I often find that doing them uses up a lot of quality time that could have been used more efficiently in talking with people and finding people to help. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have agents on my team, and I have administrative rockstars, but I don’t always properly leverage them. &lt;strong&gt;The good thing is that I have awareness about this problem, which is something that all successful people have.&lt;/strong&gt; Those who are working and committing to self-mastery, like myself, know they must learn how to leverage through people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s my failure and I’m sharing it with you here because the first step to recovery is admitting you have a problem. &lt;strong&gt;I want to hear about your failures, too, so that we can all grow together.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for me, I’m always here to answer them. Just give me a call or send me an email today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 12:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-im-sharing-my-failures-with-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-im-sharing-my-failures-with-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <category>Listing Presentation</category>
        
        <category>Reviews and Referrals</category>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Date Night: Simple &amp; Effective Client Event</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nqEY76rjcQE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date night is a fun idea for a client event, and it's super easy to implement, too!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just in time for Valentine’s Day, the Wolek Group is hosting a Date Night event on Thursday, February 13. We’re offering take-and-bake pizzas and either a six-pack of beer or a bottle of wine to all those who RSVP for the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bring this up because date night is a fun and easy way to reach out to and connect with the people in your database. You can get all sorts of touches from this kind of event, like promotion through video, or partnership with a nonprofit to help promote their organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole week leading up to this year’s Date Night event, we’re also doing a reverse BOLD 100, where clients call in to register to win a giveaway. Bear in mind that these &lt;strong&gt;giveaways have to be big enough to entice people to call in.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can get all sorts of database touches from this kind of event.%20http://localhost:4000/date-night-simple-effective-client-event.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can get all sorts of database touches from this kind of event.”&lt;/a&gt;   When those interested in the giveaway do call in, we take that time to confirm their contact information and ask them if they know of anyone interested in buying, selling, or investing in real estate that we can contact; that way, we get a double entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We ALWAYS provide an Eventbrite link for them to RSVP for the giveaway&lt;/strong&gt;, which we cap in numbers. For example, on our upcoming Valentine’s Day Date Night event, we have 100 pizzas that clients need to RSVP for in advance. &lt;strong&gt;Set up a call day a couple of days before the event to confirm the client’s RSVP&lt;/strong&gt; and ensure they’re going to stop by for pick-up—people often forget to do that, so calling them ahead of time will help you adjust your numbers to avoid having extras. Be sure to partner with a vendor who can help you offset some of the costs, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are tons of ways to touch your database, but date night is simple and fun. If you want to implement this event idea yourself and have questions about doing so, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to hear how your event goes and/or advise you on setting one up properly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 15:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/date-night-simple-effective-client-event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/date-night-simple-effective-client-event.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
