<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- CLIENT BRAND --</title>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Jeff Cook Real Estate - your professional Charleston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jeffcooktv.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 17:11:31 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 17:11:31 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Real Estate Changed Whitney Muncey’s Life</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u21Zb8yU55s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whitney Muncey began her career with Jeff Cook Real Estate in 2017. Since that time, her life has changed in so many ways. Joining our team has not only lifted a big financial burden off her shoulders, but it has also allowed her to set her own schedule so she can be present with her family when she needs to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whitney is also a huge part of our training. &lt;strong&gt;During your first week, she will teach you how to prospect, how to manage your database, and how to present to buyers and sellers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her favorite thing about working on our team is getting to work with and meet so many different families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=She will teach you how to prospect, manage your database, and present to buyers and sellers.%20http://jeffcooktv.com/how-real-estate-changed-whitney-munceys-life.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“She will teach you how to prospect, manage your database, and present to buyers and sellers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re considering jumping into a real estate career, there are a few different questions you’ll need to ask your prospective employer,&lt;/strong&gt; including how they are investing in you and whether they offer any type of training. Finally, what is their culture like? Will people be there to help you become a better person and a better agent? If you’re interested in beginning the process of joining us, head on over to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jeffcookrealestate.com/c/Join-JCRE/&quot;&gt;website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/how-real-estate-changed-whitney-munceys-life.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffcooktv.com/how-real-estate-changed-whitney-munceys-life.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Make the Most Out of Small Spaces</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Gr0t0C6ZtTs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need ideas for something to do with a small space in your home? Try these three great, easy tips:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Choosing the right paint.&lt;/strong&gt; Using colors like neutrals, whites, creams, and grays can make a room feel larger than it really is. Pairing the right lighting and paint color is also very important; be sure to choose lighting that will enhance your colors, and avoid those bulbs and colors that cause glares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Be sure to choose lighting that will enhance your colors, and avoid those bulbs and colors that cause glares.%20http://jeffcooktv.com/how-to-make-the-most-out-of-small-spaces.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Be sure to choose lighting that will enhance your colors, and avoid those bulbs and colors that cause glares.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Use high shelving in closets for those rarely used items.&lt;/strong&gt; Also utilize high ceilings and walls for guitars, surfboards, or any item that can double as decoration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Use furniture for storage.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t have a lot of floor space? Use tables and benches with hidden storage compartments. Crates, boxes, and containers that are low in depth but wide are great for under-bed storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a new home, check out our inventory on &lt;a href=&quot;www.JeffCookRealEstate.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.JeffCookRealEstate.com&lt;/a&gt;, and feel free to reach out to us for any questions you have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 11:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/how-to-make-the-most-out-of-small-spaces.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffcooktv.com/how-to-make-the-most-out-of-small-spaces.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays, From Us to You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x6ht1dcq30M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to wish you a Merry Christmas and happy holidays! Thank you for everything you’ve done for us throughout 2018—we wouldn’t be where we are without you. We hope you’re able to share and receive plenty of joy with those you care about this holiday season. We’ll see you next year! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 13:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/happy-holidays-from-us-to-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffcooktv.com/happy-holidays-from-us-to-you.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Show Your Home During the Holidays</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/658UP318kKg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have a successful holiday home sale, you need to make sure you show your home in its best possible light. Here are a few tips to help you do just that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Create appealing aromas.&lt;/strong&gt; Scents like apple pie, cookies, and cinnamon are popular, but avoid using artificial fragrances like perfumes or candles that may affect a buyer’s allergies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Offer warm treats.&lt;/strong&gt; Follow up your delightful aroma with tasty treats like freshly baked cookies. This will allow the buyer more time in the home to feel welcomed and visualize how living there could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Comfort is truly the key to making a buyer feel as though they belong in your home.%20http://jeffcooktv.com/how-to-show-your-home-during-the-holidays.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Comfort is truly the key to making a buyer feel as though they belong in your home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Make the home bright.&lt;/strong&gt; A bright home is a sold home. Turn on the lights, open the curtains, and allow in as much natural light as possible. Amber-colored bulbs in your fixtures will also give a warm glow that’s perfect for fall and winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Play uplifting music.&lt;/strong&gt; Silence during the winter months can come across eerily to buyers and make your home seem empty. Play soft instrumental music in the background to make the buyer feel invited, and it may even trigger a “where do I sign” mood in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Emphasize comfort.&lt;/strong&gt; Luxurious blankets, tablecloths, and even soft pillows make a home seem a bit more inviting. Comfort is truly the key to making a buyer feel as though they belong in your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow these tips, you’re setting yourself up for a successful sale this holiday season. With a Jeff Cook Real Estate agent, you can also ensure that you’ll find the home you’ve always dreamed of. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jeffcookrealestate.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.jeffcookrealestate.com/&lt;/a&gt; to search available homes, and check out our home value tab to see what your home could sell for in today’s real estate market. Until then, feel free to reach out to us for any questions you have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 10:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/how-to-show-your-home-during-the-holidays.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffcooktv.com/how-to-show-your-home-during-the-holidays.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Could Joining Our Team Do for You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pVJZ7WxAWnQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re excited to introduce one of Jeff Cook Real Estate’s amazing team members: Brad Williams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brad usually starts his day bright and early at 6 a.m. with a hot cup of coffee and a trip to the gym to get his energy levels up. In his words, “coffee equals contracts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, even the most motivated individual still needs the right environment to thrive. Before coming to Jeff Cook Real Estate, Brad was working on his own. He was doing a few deals a year, sure, but he wasn’t seeing the level of success he knew he was capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he came to us in 2016, everything changed. He began producing at a much higher level almost right away. In fact, &lt;strong&gt;he sold over $12 million in sales volume and was named “Agent of the Year” within his first full year on our team.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better yet, Brad was able to do all of this without having to shell out any business expenses. Not having to pay money upfront for marketing is one of the things he loves most about working with us. We offer our agents the resources, support, and financial freedom they need to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’re ready to take control of your future and steer your life and career toward the success you deserve, don’t hesitate to reach out.%20http://jeffcooktv.com/what-could-joining-our-team-do-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re ready to take control of your future and steer your life and career toward the success you deserve, don’t hesitate to reach out.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is just a small glimpse into what sets us apart from the industry standard. Our agents are also highly knowledgeable about recent trends and statistics, meaning they’re able to help our clients earn the best possible deals as they navigate the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, &lt;strong&gt;Brad is living proof of what’s possible for real estate professionals who join our team.&lt;/strong&gt; He went from selling just a handful of homes to nearly 50 a year, and his career isn’t the only area of his life that’s been transformed. He’s also now a successful real estate investor, as well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joining us has allowed him to have the life he’s always dreamed of—living on a beautiful island, visiting Mt. Pleasant in his free time, and working at a great brokerage that makes it all possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of that said, we’ve got some great news: We’re hiring. If you’re ready to take control of your future and steer your life and career toward the success you deserve, don’t hesitate to reach out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, in Brad’s words, “Joining Jeff Cook Real Estate has opened a lot of doors for me, and it can for you too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can learn more about our team and the opportunity to join us by visiting&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinjcre.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.joinjcre.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, please give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 15:29:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/what-could-joining-our-team-do-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffcooktv.com/what-could-joining-our-team-do-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Thanksgiving to All of Our Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/c6jf8qATyFc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of the holiday noise and Black Friday messages flooding your inbox, I just wanted to take this opportunity to say &lt;strong&gt;Happy Thanksgiving from the Jeff Cook Real Estate Team.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I personally am so grateful for my amazing family: My incredible wife, Sarah, my two children, Ava and Jason, and our dog, Johnny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d also like to give you a challenge. It’s very easy to get caught up in everything going on during the hustle and bustle around this time of year, but &lt;strong&gt;I’d like you to pick one person you know and one person you don’t know and lift their spirits this Thanksgiving.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We are better together when we love and encourage one another.%20http://jeffcooktv.com/happy-thanksgiving-to-all-of-our-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We are better together when we love and encourage one another.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not everybody is as fortunate as we are to have a great holiday season, so it’s important to make sure everybody knows that they’re appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Jeff Cook Real Estate, this is our mission. This means that my job as the team leader is to empower my team so that we can empower the whole community. We are truly better together when we love one another and encourage each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I just wanted to say Happy Thanksgiving to all of you. Enjoy your time with your friends and family and don’t eat too much turkey!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 13:01:18 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/happy-thanksgiving-to-all-of-our-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffcooktv.com/happy-thanksgiving-to-all-of-our-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Joining Jeff Cook Real Estate Could Change Your Life</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TMVjQyKlLrc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting a career in real estate can be easier than you may think. If you’re tenacious, have a go-getter attitude, and are interested in taking your life and business to the next level, then entering the real estate industry might be the best next step for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In real estate, the sky’s the limit. You can make however much you like in this career, so long as you’re willing to put the time and energy into earning it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To illustrate what we mean, take the example of one of our team’s new agents: Rebecca West.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Even after having been with us for only just a little over a week now, Rebecca has already begun to see what a career with Jeff Cook Real Estate can provide.%20http://jeffcooktv.com/joining-jeff-cook-real-estate-could-change-your-life.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Even after having been with us for only just a little over a week now, Rebecca has already begun to see what a career with Jeff Cook Real Estate can provide.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after having been with us for only just a little over a week now, Rebecca has already begun to see what a career with Jeff Cook Real Estate can provide. “Joining Jeff Cook Real Estate has changed my life, because I’m excited to get up in the morning and go to work,” says Rebecca, adding that she “cannot picture a better agency to work for.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebecca’s success story has already been absolutely amazing, and, right now, we’d like to extend the opportunity for you to see the same life-changing results as she has. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re looking to get started on your own success story with Jeff Cook Real Estate, visit&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jeffcookrealestate.com/c/Join-JCRE/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.joinjcre.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 15:50:43 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/joining-jeff-cook-real-estate-could-change-your-life.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffcooktv.com/joining-jeff-cook-real-estate-could-change-your-life.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Need a Home Loan Approval? Here’s What You’ll Need</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RRJLz-sbSUc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When potential homebuyers are looking to be approved for a home loan, there are a few questions and concerns I often receive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“What about my credit score? My money saved? My down payment? Will I even be able to afford the monthly payment?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do these factors affect your chances of approval? Today, you’ll find your answers. You will typically need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employment by the same company for at least two years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$4,000 to $6,000 in savings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A credit score of at least 620&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you can only check off the first two boxes. There’s no need to worry, as banks can often provide you with a &lt;strong&gt;conditional loan approval.&lt;/strong&gt; With this, you’ll have time over the following months to work with your banker, raise your credit score, and eventually be issued your home loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A mixture of down payments, monthly payments, credit scores, and time employed influences how much of each factor is needed for home loan approval.%20http://jeffcooktv.com/need-a-home-loan-approval-heres-what-youll-need.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A mixture of down payments, monthly payments, credit scores, and time employed influences how much of each factor is needed for home loan approval.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have partners at &lt;strong&gt;Tabor Mortgage&lt;/strong&gt; who are more than happy to tailor a plan for your personal financial situation. They’ll put you on track toward homeownership—determining how large your home could be, what you can afford, what your down payments and interest will be, and ensuring you receive a safe, fixed-rate mortgage. You will find out exactly what you can afford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have extra money saved to go toward a down payment? This is a &lt;strong&gt;compensating factor,&lt;/strong&gt; which may mean you can lower the requirement of a two-year concurrent employment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These scenarios create many different outcomes—a mixture of down payments, monthly payments, credit scores, and time employed influences how much of each factor is needed for home loan approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s no one-size-fits-all answer, but if you have two out of three, there are definitely options for getting approved.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have any questions or need more information, feel free to contact me through phone or email. I look forward to helping you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 11:09:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/need-a-home-loan-approval-heres-what-youll-need.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffcooktv.com/need-a-home-loan-approval-heres-what-youll-need.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Joining Us Changed This Agent’s Life</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CmdrYbZAISg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’d like to share the amazing success story of one of our team members: Julia Umoren.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before coming to Jeff Cook Real Estate in March of 2018, Julia was working in one of the largest hair replacement centers in Atlanta. According to her, this transition has transformed her life and career for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the move to a successful career in real estate has propelled her toward personal real estate success, as well. &lt;strong&gt;Julia is about to purchase her own home, all thanks to her hard work with our team.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been day-to-day changes for Julia, too—like the fact that she now has more time with her family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With our top-quality training and a culture that is second-to-none, Jeff Cook Real Estate makes the transition into real estate seamless and simple for first-time agents.%20http://jeffcooktv.com/how-joining-us-changed-this-agents-life.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With our top-quality training and a culture that is second-to-none, Jeff Cook Real Estate makes the transition into real estate seamless and simple for first-time agents.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, while Julia says those entering a real estate career should have savings built up to draw on while they adjust to their new path, she also says that Jeff Cook Real Estate is one of the best places for new agents to dive into the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our top-quality training and a culture that is second-to-none, Jeff Cook Real Estate makes the transition into real estate seamless and simple for first-time agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even in just the few months Julia has been with us so far, she has already sold three homes and has two more currently under contract.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to know the families she works with and helping them find the perfect home is what Julia says is her favorite part of being an agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;if you, too, are looking to help families find homes, while working in a family atmosphere yourself, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinjcre.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.joinjcre.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 10:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/how-joining-us-changed-this-agents-life.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffcooktv.com/how-joining-us-changed-this-agents-life.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Easy Ways to Boost Home Value</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8emy_BTNFDo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Sometimes, homeowners may fail to notice the parts of their property that are outdated or in need of repair. It’s easy to overlook issues in one’s own home. However, when it comes time to list, homeowners should realize that the buyers they’re bringing in will certainly notice these flaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Thankfully, there are a few ways you can boost your home’s value before you sell, and today I’ll be sharing four of the most effective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Update the bathroom.&lt;/strong&gt; Changing out hardware like towel racks or the knobs on cabinets can be an inexpensive way to give your bathroom a facelift. Or, if money permits, upgrading your tile can be even more beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Even before stepping foot in your home, buyers will judge what they expect to find inside by how your property looks on the outside.%20http://jeffcooktv.com/4-easy-ways-to-boost-home-value.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Even before stepping foot in your home, buyers will judge what they expect to find inside by how your property looks on the outside.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Update your home’s lighting.&lt;/strong&gt; Good lighting can instantly make rooms appear larger and more welcoming. So before you list, take some time to assess the lighting fixtures throughout your home. Replace any burnt out bulbs, and, if necessary, swap out a few fixtures for newer, more luminous ones. Speaking of lighting, mounted lighting strips beneath cabinets can be a great addition. Buyers love this simple feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Repaint as needed.&lt;/strong&gt; Giving the home a fresh coat of paint will make it appear bright and clean. Even just the smell of fresh paint can help leave buyers with a positive impression of your home. However, make sure you stick to light, neutral colors, and that you also update your trim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Fix up the home’s landscaping and curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt; Even before stepping foot in your home, buyers will judge what they expect to find inside by how your property looks on the outside. A freshly mowed yard, well-trimmed landscaping, and the addition of darkly colored mulch will all go a long way in boosting your home’s curb appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 11:24:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffcooktv.com/4-easy-ways-to-boost-home-value.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffcooktv.com/4-easy-ways-to-boost-home-value.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
