<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Real Estate Podcast with Kati Spaniak</title>
    <link>http://realestategrit.net</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://realestategrit.net"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Real Estate Grit - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Kati Spaniak</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-05-31 09:48:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Kati Spaniak</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>kati@spaniakteam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Kati Spaniak</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://realestategrit.net/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Chicago Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Real Estate Grit - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Gaining Leads from an Open House</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/the-key-to-gaining-leads-from-an-open-house.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-29 12:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Open houses can go really well or really badly. In any case, there will be a lot of people walking through the house to check things out. 

So, how do you sit an open house to get leads? 

The first thing you need to focus on is having the right mindset. You’ve got to believe that the connections you make at the open house will either translate to a sale or to a new lead. After all, when you sit an open house you’re there for two reasons: To sell the house and to gain leads. 

Beyond simply having the correct mindset, it’s also important to have adequate signage. The more signage you have, the more traffic you’re going to see through the open house. Putting out a lot of signs can be time-consuming, but it will be well worth it in the end. 

Door knocking is another great way to generate interest in the open house. Even though the people you meet this way may not be looking for a home, it’s still good to make connections. They could make a great addition to your database. 

Now that we’ve discussed a few ways to prepare for the open house, let’s move on to what you should be doing the day of. First, make sure you arrive about 15 minutes early. There’s nothing worse than walking up to an open house to find people already waiting in the driveway. 

“The goal of an open house is to make connections and then follow up with them.”

It’s also important to have a sign-in sheet prepared and readily available to everyone who passes through. You can use anything from an iPad to pen and paper. All that matters is that you’re capturing the contact information of the people who attend. This includes their names, phone numbers, and email addresses. They should also provide the name of their agent. 

The goal of the open house is to connect with people on a personal level. Do not be overbearing as people tour the home. You want people to feel at ease. However, people who aren’t willing to fill out the sign in sheet shouldn’t be allowed to view the home. 

Once the open house is over, it’s good to take notes about the connections you made. And don’t forget to enter these people into your database. Of course, you should always keep in mind that you’re also there with the goal of helping to sell the home. If anyone visiting the home comes along with their agent, be sure to let the listing agent know. This creates a great opportunity to get some feedback about the house. 

So, in short, the goal of an open house is to make connections and then follow up with them. Open houses are a great way to get clients. Remember to keep your energy up and be yourself.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are two goals you should keep in mind when you sit an open house: selling the property and gaining leads.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are two goals you should keep in mind when you sit an open house: selling the property and gaining leads.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Kati Spaniak</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Kati Spaniak</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Real Estate Grit - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
