<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Tulsa Looks Good on You</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Keller Williams Realty Advantage - your professional Tulsa Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>The Wolek Group</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-04-09 13:42:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>The Wolek Group</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@TheWolekGroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>The Wolek Group</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Tulsa Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Keller Williams Realty Advantage - your professional Tulsa Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Us Know How We Can Help</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/let-us-know-how-we-can-help.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-31 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/March/Let+Us+Know+How+We+Can+Help.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you all doing well? It’s important to all of us at The Wolek Group that we connect with our friends, family, and community to make sure you’re safe and that we’re providing you with all the resources we possibly can. If you need anything at all, please reach out to us. We’ve already sent you helpful resources, but we want to be doubly sure you have everything you need. 

We have a Facebook page called Tulsa Looks Good on You, which was created to share all the wonderful things Tulsa has to offer, and during this time we’re being extremely deliberate about adding helpful things to it to assist our community. We look forward to seeing you soon and giving you a real hug or handshake—for now, it’s virtual. 

“With interest rates still low, there is plenty of activity.”

We do want you to know we’re still doing business. People are still buying and selling homes. We’re watching the numbers every day, and believe it or not, with interest rates still low, there is plenty of activity. For those that need to buy or sell, we’re taking extra steps to be cautious during this health crisis. For example, we’re conducting tons of virtual open houses, home tours, and appointments via Zoom and FaceTime. Still seeing each other sometimes is critical during this distancing period.

If you have questions or need anything, please contact us via phone or email. We look forward to seeing and talking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/March/Let+Us+Know+How+We+Can+Help.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/March/Let+Us+Know+How+We+Can+Help.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>During this challenging time, we’re here to help with whatever you need.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>During this challenging time, we’re here to help with whatever you need.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 411 on 473: Tulsa’s Awesome New Bar</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-411-on-473-tulsas-awesome-new-bar.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-10 11:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/January/SOI/February/The+411+on+473-+Tulsas+Awesome+New+Bar.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We love Tulsa, we love food, and we really love new bars in town! We’re so excited to introduce you to Niki and Andrew Layson, the owners of Bar 473 here in Kendall Whittier district. 

The bar’s name is an homage to the building it occupies, which was once a nationally registered historic place: Phillips 66 gas station No. 473, one of the early businesses in the first suburban development of Tulsa. 

According to Andrew, the location was also unique in that it allowed for more patio space, creating a more organic social atmosphere. Beyond being nestled in a lovely neighborhood, 473 draws in patrons with well-crafted, affordable cocktails. Providing a venue for local acts—comedy, music, poetry, etc.—also means that 473 is truly a community gathering space. 

Niki and Andrew were able to accent the neutral colors of the World War II-era building and create a clean, inviting space. The bar’s minimalist approach to decor ensures that the smaller inside area never feels too overcrowded. 

“Beyond being nestled in a lovely neighborhood, 473 draws patrons in with well-crafted, affordable cocktails.”

Right across the way from American Slayer and Cabin Boys Brewery, 473 is yet another testament to the increasing vibrancy of our Tulsa community! Though the many bars and breweries in this district cooperate more than compete, 473 aims to separate itself from the pack by having a deeper commitment to the city’s blossoming music scene. 

As Andrew put it, “We need to pay more attention to those local artists that are creating real, raw music and who are trying to put themselves out there as artists.” 

Follow 473 on Instagram (@four.seven.three) and Facebook (@bar473), or visit their website: www.bar473.com.

If you have any questions about the wonderful ways in which Tulsa is growing, or you’re interested in buying or selling soon, give us a call. We’d love to talk with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/January/SOI/February/The+411+on+473-+Tulsas+Awesome+New+Bar.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/January/SOI/February/The+411+on+473-+Tulsas+Awesome+New+Bar.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s what the owners of new Tulsa drinkery 473 have to say about what their passion project offers the community.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s what the owners of new Tulsa drinkery 473 have to say about what their passion project offers the community.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why the Garman Family Chose the Wolek Group</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-the-garman-family-chose-the-wolek-group.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-03 16:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/March/Why+the+Garman+Family+Chose+the+Wolek+Group.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Each year, our team has the privilege of helping hundreds of families make their real estate dreams come true. We know buying and selling a home can be stressful, but if you work with us, we make it easy on you. Through these incredible experiences, we create friendships and memories that last a lifetime.

With that in mind, I want to share a testimonial from one of our clients that speaks to our mission in this business. 

“We know buying and selling a home can be stressful, but if you work with us, we make it easy on you.”

We helped the Garman family sell their old home and buy a new one. They interviewed three Realtors before reaching out to us, but once they did, they described it as “a dream come true.”

At the time, they already had enough stress they could handle, so they wanted the buying and selling process to be as stress-free as possible. After staging their old home, we managed to sell it in just three days. We also staged their new home after helping them purchase it so they could settle in more comfortably. 

Watch the video above in its entirety to see their full testimonial and why they’d recommend the Wolek Group to all of their friends and family. 

If you ever have any real estate needs, don’t hesitate to call or email me. My team and I would love to help. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/March/Why+the+Garman+Family+Chose+the+Wolek+Group.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/March/Why+the+Garman+Family+Chose+the+Wolek+Group.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Why work with the Wolek Group? We’ll let one of our past clients explain.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why work with the Wolek Group? We’ll let one of our past clients explain.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet Teresa Brockwell: Insurance Agent Extraordinaire</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/meet-teresa-brockwell-insurance-agent-extraordinaire.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-10 16:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/February/Meet+Teresa+Brockwell-+Insurance+Agent+Extraordinaire.mp4</guid>
        <description>

For our latest video, we have another special guest joining us: Teresa Brockwell, The Wolek Group’s insurance agent extraordinaire! Teresa’s always been a great supporter of our business and a great help to all of our clients, and today we’ll have a quick chat about how she can help you with your insurance needs. 

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch it in its entirety or use these timestamps to browse specific points at your leisure: 

1:24—The importance of meeting with your agent and discussing your options 

2:31—How Teresa and her team specialize in helping busy professionals 

4:19—Why it’s never a bad idea to get a second opinion on your policy 

6:28—Wrapping things up 

If you’d like to get in touch with Teresa and discuss your insurance options, give her a call or text her at (918) 496-1800. As always, if you have questions about any real estate topic or are thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/February/Meet+Teresa+Brockwell-+Insurance+Agent+Extraordinaire.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/February/Meet+Teresa+Brockwell-+Insurance+Agent+Extraordinaire.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re a busy professional, it’s important to understand your insurance options, and Teresa Brockwell joins me today to discuss this topic.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re a busy professional, it’s important to understand your insurance options, and Teresa Brockwell joins me today to discuss this topic.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Agent’s Experience With Transitioning to Our Team</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-agents-experience-with-transitioning-to-our-team.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-14 10:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/January/SOI/January/An+Agents+Experience+With+Transitioning+to+Our+Team.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I sat down for a chat with Nate Araskog, an agent here at The Wolek Group. He’s here to share his experiences as an agent on our team.

Before coming to The Wolek Group, Nate Araskog had obtained his real estate license and worked with Daniel Sprik, a Realtor and good friend of his who had encouraged him to get into the industry in the first place. 

I helped him to sell a couple of his properties before, so one day Nate and I met for coffee. It was supposed to have been a short introduction, but it ended up becoming a two-and-half-hour meeting. During that conversation, Nate saw my experience and the opportunities that lay in the foundation of my team’s structure and he decided he wanted to be a part of it.

For my part, the conversation over coffee had originally been about real estate in general, but toward the end, something clicked within me. I asked him, “Are you asking me all these questions to join Keller Williams or to join my team?”

“It’s fun to be on the front end of change within the real estate industry at large.” 

With a smile on his face, Nate responded, “I don’t know—maybe both.”

With that, I recommended that he and I set up another time to get back together. We did, and the rest is history.

We’ve grown so much since then, and his experience with our team and with Keller Williams has been fabulous overall. It’s fun to be on the front end of change within the real estate industry at large.

By the time Nate and I met for that fateful coffee meeting, he was already a go-getter who found success as a single agent. What was he missing that helped him see the value of joining a team?

For him, the biggest factor was the opportunity to learn from someone who had experience. He knew that our team would provide the ability to help people as a part of an organization, not just a single agent. He knew from the first time we met that the partnership we could create by being in business together was going to be hugely successful for all of us.

If you have any questions about starting career in real estate or would like to contact us about joining The Wolek Group yourself, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to hear from you and discuss why making the switch to Keller Williams and The Wolek Group would be a great decision for the trajectory of your career.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/January/SOI/January/An+Agents+Experience+With+Transitioning+to+Our+Team.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2020/January/SOI/January/An+Agents+Experience+With+Transitioning+to+Our+Team.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I sat down for a chat with Nate Araskog, an agent here at the Wolek Group. He’s here to share his experiences as an agent on our team.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I sat down for a chat with Nate Araskog, an agent here at the Wolek Group. He’s here to share his experiences as an agent on our team.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Unique Approach to Health With Deneen Natural Health</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-unique-approach-to-health-with-deneen-natural-health.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-27 16:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/December/A+Unique+Approach+to+Health+With+Deneen+Natural+Health.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Deneen Natural Health offers supplemental solutions for health and wellness. Here’s what you should know about their approach.

I am so excited to introduce you to Dr. Shana Deneen with Deneen Natural Health. I wanted to talk to her because she does something quite special that I think everyone should know about.

At Deneen Natural Health, Shana brings a more natural approach to health, wellness, and disease prevention by practicing naturopathic medicine and acupuncture.

People come in for a variety of reasons. Maybe they’re trying to get pregnant, going through side effects of cancer treatment, or simply have some back or neck pain. What makes Deneen Natural Health different is that they offer supplemental solutions to improving the health of their patients. There are a lot of natural ways to promote health through nutrition, acupuncture, and herbal medicine.

“Eating legumes can help prevent heart disease.”

As far as diet and nutrition go, she’s a big promoter of eating legumes like lentils, split peas, and beans. These foods are really healthy and can help prevent heart disease, promote gut health, and help with the prevention of many different kinds of cancer.

For those with cancer undergoing treatments with a lot of side effects, acupuncture is a great way to mitigate those effects and improve their overall quality of life.

If you’re interested in learning more about Dr. Shana and Deneen Natural Health, visit her websiteor give her a call at (918) 884-6005.

If you have any additional questions for me about real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/December/A+Unique+Approach+to+Health+With+Deneen+Natural+Health.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/December/A+Unique+Approach+to+Health+With+Deneen+Natural+Health.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Deneen Natural Health offers supplemental solutions for health and wellness. Here’s what you should know about their approach.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Deneen Natural Health offers supplemental solutions for health and wellness. Here’s what you should know about their approach.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where You Can Find Authentic Wood-Fired Pizza</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/where-you-can-find-authentic-wood-fired-pizza.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-13 16:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/December/Where+You+Can+Find+Authentic+Wood-Fired+Pizza+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you have a craving for wood-fired pizza, I have just the place to introduce you to on the latest episode of “Tulsa Foodie.”


On the latest episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” I want to introduce you to one of my favorite restaurants: the East Village Bohemian Pizzeria. Joining me for a quick sit-down is Amy McMillin, who co-owns the restaurant with her brother. 

Amy and her brother have been involved in the food industry since they were teenagers, and they share a special love of Italian food. Amy got her first taste of wood-fired pizza 15 years ago when she got the chance to visit Naples, and after she did, she decided that she had to recreate the same taste back home. 

The secret to their pizza’s amazing taste, according to Amy, is their dedication to cooking everything fresh and authentic, just like they do in Italy. 

“I learned the hard way that you need a reservation on most nights if you want to get a table here.”

“Every morning,” she says, “we come in and light the fire in our wood-fired oven, which has no gas—we’re stacking the wood and making the fire—and we’re roasting all the fresh vegetables every day. All the meats are getting roasted. We make our dough from scratch. We import our flour from Italy. And we’re doing that fresh every single day.”

In addition to the great food, they have a fun, cool vibe inside their restaurant. Their five-year anniversary at their current location in downtown Tulsa is coming up on December 19, and in those five years, they’ve built a wine room and a second kitchen which makes handmade pasta daily. They also have an amazing patio (which I’m a big fan of), where guests are known to wine and dine year-round—even when the temperature is nearly freezing. 

I learned the hard way that you need a reservation on most nights if you want to get a table here, and I can’t wait to try my next Bohemian pizza. 

If you’d like to know more about the East Village Bohemian Pizzeria, visit their website atwww.eastvillagebohemian.com or check out their Instagram feed @bohemianpizzatulsa.

As always, if you have any questions for me or there’s anything I can help you with, give me a call or shoot me an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/December/Where+You+Can+Find+Authentic+Wood-Fired+Pizza+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/December/Where+You+Can+Find+Authentic+Wood-Fired+Pizza+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you have a craving for wood-fired pizza, I have just the place to introduce you to on the latest episode of “Tulsa Foodie.”</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you have a craving for wood-fired pizza, I have just the place to introduce you to on the latest episode of “Tulsa Foodie.”</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Story Behind My Career in Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-story-behind-my-career-in-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-22 11:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/November/The+Story+Behind+My+Career+in+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>
 

People often ask me how I got into real estate, and so I’d like to share that story with all of you today.I’m originally from Tulsa and attended the University of Oklahoma just a couple hours away from there (Boomer Sooner!). I spent a lot of those years in school being average and only just barely getting by. I think that’s because, like a lot of college-aged kids, I didn’t know my passion or purpose in life. Finally, I got into classes that I cared about and I realized that I was a good student after all. I went on to get my master’s degree in Human Relations.

During that time, I was still waiting tables at the mall in Norman. I really think that a lot of the best real estate agents are those who have been servers. A friend of mine from high school who had just gotten into real estate reached out to me, asking if I needed to buy a house. At the time, I didn’t have any money, so how was I supposed to buy a house? To that, he responded, “You should get into real estate; a friend in my office just made $100,000 last month.”

The flexibility and lucrative nature of the real estate industry was very appealing to me at that age. After a while, though, I realized that there was a lot more hard work necessary than just selling lots of houses and raking in the money. I realized that my work ethic, which I somehow just had in me, was starting to pay off.

I began working for a small brokerage with just five people in the office. I was learning how to be a property manager and how to be an office manager; I partnered with a broker and got to go on listing appointments and worked with homebuyers. 

After four years of working in real estate in Norman I knew that I was getting to the age where I wanted to be able to get back home to my family. I sold the two houses that I had bought in those four years and moved back home to Tulsa.

“We’re always looking for more people to come into our world so that we can help more families, have fun, give back to the community, and live large.”

Once I did, I signed on with a local, traditional real estate company. I was doing well at the time, but I didn’t know how to be anything other than a lead receiver, which means that I would show up to open houses and smile and be nice to people—over time, they would open up and let me help them.

Then, I discovered a company called Keller Williams. That’s when everything changed for me in my business and my personal life. Once I signed on with Keller Williams, I just ate up all of the available training, coaching, and mentoring that I could get my hands on. That really opened my mind; I started to dream big and realized that with Keller Williams, I could achieve those dreams.

However, as a single agent, I was starting to get overwhelmed. I was working all kinds of crazy hours, and when I reached a breaking point, I knew that I needed help. That’s when the idea of building a team entered my mind. I didn’t want to build a team to crush the faces off the Tulsa, Oklahoma real estate market, but rather because I wanted to hold on to my sanity! I wanted to be a good wife, mother, and agent, and building a team allowed me to do that.

What’s fun about growing a team is that you get to help others do the same. It’s such an amazing experience. We’re always looking for more people to come into our world so that we can help more families, have fun, give back to the community, and live large.

If you’ve ever thought about starting a career in real estate, or if you’re currently in the business but you’re not finding the success that you want, reach out to me. I’d love to chat with you about an amazing opportunity to join our team.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/November/The+Story+Behind+My+Career+in+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/November/The+Story+Behind+My+Career+in+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I wanted to share the story of how I got into the real estate business, including the lessons I learned along the way.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I wanted to share the story of how I got into the real estate business, including the lessons I learned along the way.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why This Happy Client Recommends The Wolek Group</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-this-happy-client-recommends-the-wolek-group.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-02 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/November/Why+This+Happy+Client+Recommends+the+Wolek+Group.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Why does Katherine Fondren recommend The Wolek Group to anyone interested in buying or selling real estate? Today, she can tell you herself:

“I had a home that I needed to sell. I had known Jennie Wolek over the years through mutual friends, and I was definitely looking for something different… something outside of the box. I was a Realtor in Louisiana when I lived there, so I thought I knew everything about the real estate business, but that was a long time ago, before the age of social media and all kinds of new marketing things.

“That’s why I loved about Jennie and what her company was doing: They were doing some outside-the-box marketing. Jennie would come over; we sat at my kitchen table and discussed what our goals were. She asked me what I liked best about my home and what prospective buyers should know about it. I was happy to share that information and she definitely used it in her marketing.

“I felt she really wanted to do what was best for me and my family, as well as the people buying my home.”

“Then we immediately started the buying process. I met with one of her buyer’s agents and we discussed what we were looking for and needed in a home. And throughout the process, there was a lot of feedback, which I really value; being a former Realtor, I know that’s really important. A lot of my friends who are looking for Realtors always want feedback. If someone looked at your house, what did they think? How can we improve? What do they like? What do they not like?

“When we finally did get a buyer, I was really excited. Jennie did everything she could to walk us through the process. She was great from beginning to end, and I felt she really wanted to do what was best for me and my family, as well as the people buying my home.

“We found this beautiful house that we’re standing in right now in a neighborhood we didn’t even know about. It’s a new home from a builder I didn’t know; Jennie’s team had the knowledge of the market, so they knew what was going on even in new construction. 

“I’m thankful to The Wolek Group for helping steer us in the right direction and helping us find our dream home. It’s a wonderful process from beginning to end, very stress-free with a lot of communication, and I definitely, definitely recommend them!”

If you, like Katherine, ever need any help with your real estate needs, please feel free to reach out to us here at The Wolek Group. We’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/November/Why+This+Happy+Client+Recommends+the+Wolek+Group.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/November/Why+This+Happy+Client+Recommends+the+Wolek+Group.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’ll allow Katherine Fondren to tell you all about her experience working with The Wolek Group.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’ll allow Katherine Fondren to tell you all about her experience working with The Wolek Group.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Thanks to You, We’ve Served Over 100 Families in 2019</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/thanks-to-you-weve-served-over-100-families-in-2019.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-06 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/October/We+Did+It-+Over+100+Families+Served!+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>
We’re excited to announce that we’ve served over 100 families in 2019. Because of our amazing clients, we’ve been able to help more, give back, have fun, and live large. With every home sold, we’ve been able to give back a portion of our proceeds to Keys to the City—a non-profit dedicated to giving back to our Tulsa community. We wouldn’t be able to do any of this without the amazing support of our family, friends, the people who help our team, and our clients. Thank you from the bottom of our hearts.

As always, if you need help with anything real estate related, don’t hesitate to give us a call. We’d love to hear from you.

 


</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/October/We+Did+It-+Over+100+Families+Served!+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/October/We+Did+It-+Over+100+Families+Served!+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’ve served over 100 families this year, and we wouldn’t have done it without you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’ve served over 100 families this year, and we wouldn’t have done it without you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Conversation with Luke Frazier of INSPiRE Financial Group</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-conversation-with-luke-frazier-of-inspire-financial-group.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-05 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/October/A+Conversation+with+Luke+Frazier+of+INSPiRE+Financial+Group.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m excited to introduce you to my friend Luke Frazier with INSPiRE Financial Group. I met Luke at a Tulsa Chamber of Commerce event and I was so inspired by him and how he runs his business as a financial planner.

Luke started this firm three years ago with what he calls “uncommon knowledge.” He felt that the industry as a whole was going in one direction, but not enough people were asking why. We’ve taken that knowledge and applied strategies and recommendations behind it to better our clients. As opposed to the stock market, they tend to focus on cash flow.

Products and services can only get you so far if you don’t have a strong “why.” For Luke, he believes that there are five core areas in which everyone is trying to improve: relationships with family and friends, career, finances, spiritual well-being, and physical well-being. 

Luke and INSPiRE feel like the financial aspect too often adds stress or negatively affect the other five areas. Their goal with their clients is to put strategies in place to turn the financial aspect into a positive and positively affects the other areas.

“Everybody has a different personality and mindset about finances.”

Way too many people are relying on Wall Street and big banks for their finances. Luke and his team promote investing in themselves instead of Wall Street or big banks. They work with a lot of small business owners and even real estate investors to produce cash flow instead of just putting money away and not ever seeing it for 30 years.

Their program is based on what the truly wealthy people in our country do. They go to work and make money, put their money to work for them, and use other people’s money to make even more money. They finance their own deals and use their own leverage, and Luke uses a lot of these types of strategies with his clients. As opposed to paying a lump sum for a boat, for example, you can take that amount and put it towards a rental property, for example. The income on the property can pay that mortgage and the loan on the boat. If we repeat that process over and over, it will create wealth.

Everybody has a different personality and mindset about finances. Where Luke and his team shine are with the clients with abundant mindsets who want to get wealthy now and not wait for it for later.

To learn more about Luke and what he does at INSPiRE, visit their website at www.planwithinspire.com or call Luke at (918) 500-2931.

Thanks so much to Luke for joining me. If you have any other questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/October/A+Conversation+with+Luke+Frazier+of+INSPiRE+Financial+Group.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/October/A+Conversation+with+Luke+Frazier+of+INSPiRE+Financial+Group.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>INSPiRE Financial Group is helping their clients create true, long-term wealth. Here’s how.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>INSPiRE Financial Group is helping their clients create true, long-term wealth. Here’s how.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>QL for Young Adults: Bridging the Gap Between Education and Life</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/ql-for-young-adults-bridging-the-gap-between-education-and-life.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-22 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/October/QL+for+Young+Adults-+Bridging+the+Gap+Between+Education+and+Life+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>
How do you know what your potential is? If you’re asking yourself this question, we can help you find the answer. As instructors for Quantum Leap for Young Adults (ages 18-30), we want to invite you to an upcoming life and leadership workshop on October 12. We’ll help you decide what you want your life to look like and create goals around that vision. Additionally, we’ll be offering two scholarships worth $500 that will go toward education and training. The scholarships are courtesy of our non-profit—Keys To The City.

To RSVP and save your seat, click here. If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/October/QL+for+Young+Adults-+Bridging+the+Gap+Between+Education+and+Life+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/October/QL+for+Young+Adults-+Bridging+the+Gap+Between+Education+and+Life+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Quantum Leap for Young Adults is hosting an upcoming workshop, and you’re cordially invited.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Quantum Leap for Young Adults is hosting an upcoming workshop, and you’re cordially invited.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are You a Seller With a Home in Need of Some TLC?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-a-seller-with-a-home-in-need-of-some-tlc.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-07 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/September/Are+You+a+Seller+With+a+Home+In+Need+of+Some+TLC_+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>
Today I’m driving to a listing appointment, and I just ran into a friend I’ve known since high school who is also in the real estate business as a house-flipper. She was talking about the challenge she’s been facing in the pursuit of great homes to buy, fix up, and resell. Another friend and client of ours who is in real estate as well has the same issue.

“We have a whole database for flippers, investors, and clients looking for an affordable home to fix up and resell.”

Given that, I thought today’s blog post would be a great opportunity to share this message:

If you have a home that needs a little love in the form of a few updates and repairs and you just don’t want to put the time, energy, or money into doing it, then go ahead and reach out to us at The Wolek Group: We have a whole database for flippers, investors, and clients looking for an affordable home to fix up and resell.

In addition, we can help with any kind of home or home buying needs you have, so don’t hesitate to reach out to us. Hope to talk to you soon! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/September/Are+You+a+Seller+With+a+Home+In+Need+of+Some+TLC_+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/September/Are+You+a+Seller+With+a+Home+In+Need+of+Some+TLC_+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Having issues selling a home that needs some work? I have a solution.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Having issues selling a home that needs some work? I have a solution.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Sellers Should Always Tidy Up Before Closing</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-sellers-should-always-tidy-up-before-closing.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-20 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/September/For+database-+reminder+to+leave+house+clean_Final+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Keeping on a tidy home while your property is on the market is no easy task, so if you’ve been feeling stressed out at the prospect of juggling your day-to-day cleaning chores with your responsibilities as a home seller, you aren’t alone. This is a very common feeling. Please know, though, that you don’t have to handle everything on your own. Our team is here to help. We have a vast network of service providers who would be happy to help you make your home shine before closing day comes. 

“The last thing any buyer wants is to find their new home in a state of disarray when moving day arrives.”

If you have any other questions or would like more information about today’s tip or any other real estate-related topic, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/September/For+database-+reminder+to+leave+house+clean_Final+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/September/For+database-+reminder+to+leave+house+clean_Final+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>No buyer wants to move into a dirty home, so sellers must always remember to tidy up before closing day arrives.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>No buyer wants to move into a dirty home, so sellers must always remember to tidy up before closing day arrives.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Local Nonprofit Spotlight: The Pencil Box</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/local-nonprofit-spotlight-the-pencil-box.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-10 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Local+Nonprofit+Spotlight-+The+Pencil+Box+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

As you know, we love giving back to the community and supporting local nonprofits. Since it’s almost back-to-school time, we want to take a break from real estate and share a quick video of all the amazing things The Pencil Box is doing for our local schools. We have testimonials from volunteers, public school teachers in Tulsa County, and Executive Director Nancy Bolzle as part of our spotlight. As Nancy says, “There is no greater investment than our youth.” 

If you have any questions about this organization or any real estate needs we can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Local+Nonprofit+Spotlight-+The+Pencil+Box+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Local+Nonprofit+Spotlight-+The+Pencil+Box+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we’re spotlighting a great local nonprofit dedicated to helping public schools: The Pencil Box.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we’re spotlighting a great local nonprofit dedicated to helping public schools: The Pencil Box.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Business Spotlight: Blue Jay Cleaning Services</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/business-spotlight-blue-jay-cleaning-services.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-27 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/august/Business+Spotlight-+Blue+Jay+Cleaning+Services.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Blue Jay Cleaning Services has been around in the Tulsa area and the Oklahoma City Metro area for about three years. They offer recurring residential services, as well as move-out cleaning and make-ready cleaning, which is done before your home goes on the market. In addition, they also do small office commercial services.

Here at The Wolek Group, we love helping our clients get their homes ready in the pre-listing period, and cleaning is no small part of that process. Whether you’re preparing to sell your home and move or you just want to simplify, Blue Jay’s owner Britt Greenwood says that decluttering is the way to go. This is especially important if you’re planning to sell your home. Look at your countertops in the kitchen—a good rule of thumb is to have no more than two or three appliances on them.

“A good rule of thumb is to have no more than two or three appliances on your countertops.”

In the bathroom, try not to have more than a handful of items on your surfaces, including your shower. When you sell your home, you need to live in it differently than you would if you weren’t planning to move.

As you’re decluttering the home, pack things in moving boxes to help speed up the moving process. When filled, these boxes can be stored in the garage or in an out-of-the-way storage area.

It’s also a good idea to make a list of things that need to be done in your home regarding renovations, repairs, and touch-ups. Be sure to have all those things done before you have a professional house cleaner visit your home, since trade workers can sometimes leave a mess.

If you’d like to contact Britt for an estimate, reach out to her by phone at (918) 277-3378, visit her website at www.BlueJayCleaning.com, or visit her Facebook page. One-time cleanings can be discussed over the phone, but if you have need of a recurring service, she or one of her staff members can come visit your home to see what needs to be done.

For any questions you have for me or the Wolek Group at large, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/august/Business+Spotlight-+Blue+Jay+Cleaning+Services.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/august/Business+Spotlight-+Blue+Jay+Cleaning+Services.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’m so excited to introduce you to my new friend, Britt Greenwood from Blue Jay Cleaning Services.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’m so excited to introduce you to my new friend, Britt Greenwood from Blue Jay Cleaning Services.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tulsa Foodie: The Rose District’s Nouveau Chocolates</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-the-rose-districts-nouveau-chocolates.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-03 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/July/Episode+6+-+Tulsa+Foodies+Latest+Feature-+Nouveau+Chocolates+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Welcome back to another edition of “Tulsa Foodie”. Today I’m super excited to introduce you to Melvin Piper, owner of Nouveau Chocolates. This Rose District shop is everything you’ve ever wanted in a chocolatier.

Melvin always wanted to own a business and food is one of his biggest passions. He fell in love with chocolate on a trip to Europe and started working at Nouveau about eight years ago. About a year ago, he bought the business from the previous owner and has put his own spin on some new classics while also maintaining the quality that people have always come to find at Nouveau.

They get a lot of foot traffic from the lunch and dinner crowds. There are some people that even come in for some coffee or tea every day or hot chocolate in the winter.

“Nouveau produces some of the finest Belgian chocolate around”

Nouveau produces some of the finest Belgian chocolate around. There are about 49 different selections in the showcase, which they are constantly adding to. They also serve delicious ice cream and chocolate-dipped cones. 

For all of you Tulsa Foodies out there, you can get 10% off of a 15-piece box for the entire month of July! Just make sure to mention us when you order!

Some of their most popular chocolates include maple bacon, key lime pie, and chili pepper flavors. Their oil-fire whiskey is infused with caramel and has a creamy liquid center. I tried one for myself and it was absolutely incredible. 

Come check out Nouveau Chocolates for yourself on 205 S. Main St. in Broken Arrow. You can also check them out on Instagram or Facebook @nouveauchocolates.

Thanks so much to Melvin for joining me and letting me take a look at some of his fantastic creations. If you have any questions for me in the meantime or any real estate needs that I can assist with, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/July/Episode+6+-+Tulsa+Foodies+Latest+Feature-+Nouveau+Chocolates+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/July/Episode+6+-+Tulsa+Foodies+Latest+Feature-+Nouveau+Chocolates+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>On this edition of Tulsa Foodie, we’re trying something a little sweeter. Let’s check out Nouveau Chocolates.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>On this edition of Tulsa Foodie, we’re trying something a little sweeter. Let’s check out Nouveau Chocolates.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Now Is a Great Time to Sell!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/now-is-a-great-time-to-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-24 08:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/Now+Is+a+Great+Time+to+Sell!.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Yesterday, I ran into one of my lender friends, and he happened to mention that interest rates are still crazy low. For a 30-year mortgage, rates are right around 4%!

Since it’s summer, now is the best time to make a move if you have a family and want to get settled in before school starts again in the fall.

“Now is the best time to make a move if you have a family and want to get settled in before school starts again in the fall.”

If you have any real estate needs at all, please reach out to the Wolek Group. We are very accessible—you can find us on Facebook and Instagram, you can always call or text me at (918) 706-9845, or you can email me at Jennie@thewolekgroup.com. Additionally, we’d love for you to download our free mobile app so that you can start searching for homes in your area, comparing prices, and just checking out what’s available. Finally, if you’re curious about the value of your home, visit www.TulsaHomeValue.com to get a free home value estimate.

We want to be your real estate resource. Hope to hear from you soon! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/Now+Is+a+Great+Time+to+Sell!.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/Now+Is+a+Great+Time+to+Sell!.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to give you a real quick update on the market. It’s a great time to be a seller! Find out why right here.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to give you a real quick update on the market. It’s a great time to be a seller! Find out why right here.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Take Advantage of our Certified Pre-Owned Home Program Today</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/take-advantage-of-our-certified-pre-owned-home-program-today.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-22 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Take+Advantage+of+our+Certified+Pre-Owned+Home+Program+Today.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Are you thinking about a move this spring or summer? Or maybe you are simply curious about the value of your home and the local real estate market. Either way—we need to talk!

“With this program, our listings sell in an average of just 14 days.”

We’re offering a FREE home inspection, staging consultation, and appraisal to clients who list with us through our Certified Pre-Owned Home Program!

Our Certified Pre-Owned Program allows you to:


  Sell your home FASTER
  Get MORE MONEY for your property
  Have LESS STRESS in the process
  Achieve SHORTER closing periods


With this program, we have seen our listings sell much faster, with an average of just 14 days on the market.

Our experienced team is here and ready to help with all of your real estate needs. We can’t wait to talk to you soon! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Take+Advantage+of+our+Certified+Pre-Owned+Home+Program+Today.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Take+Advantage+of+our+Certified+Pre-Owned+Home+Program+Today.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our certified pre-owned home program is perfect for homeowners who are looking to make a quick, profitable sale. Here’s how it works.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our certified pre-owned home program is perfect for homeowners who are looking to make a quick, profitable sale. Here’s how it works.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How We’re Giving Back to Families Affected by the Recent Floods</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-were-giving-back-to-families-affected-by-the-recent-floods.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-12 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/The+Wolek+Group-+How+Were+Giving+Back+to+Families+Affected+by+the+Recent+Floods.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our team is giving back to Oklahomans suffering from flood damage and we need YOUR help! ​Through our charity organization, Keys To The City, The Wolek Group is giving $500 to SIX families in need of flood relief!

Although cleanup has begun, we are far from finished. If you know someone in the Tulsa area whose home is severely damaged or was lost due to flooding, complete the nomination form below!

Nomination Form

We will be making selections on July 1st, so don’t wait to raise a hand!

Want to join our Flood Relief efforts? Email us at info@thewolekgroup.com to learn more about how you can donate! 

                                                                                                
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/The+Wolek+Group-+How+Were+Giving+Back+to+Families+Affected+by+the+Recent+Floods.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/The+Wolek+Group-+How+Were+Giving+Back+to+Families+Affected+by+the+Recent+Floods.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In an effort to help those affected by the recent flooding, our team is giving six lucky families a $500 donation. If you know anyone who you believe deserves this help, we’d like for you to nominate them today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In an effort to help those affected by the recent flooding, our team is giving six lucky families a $500 donation. If you know anyone who you believe deserves this help, we’d like for you to nominate them today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>If You’re Thinking of Making a Move, We Want to Help</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/if-youre-thinking-of-making-a-move-we-want-to-help.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-28 10:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/Making+a+MOVE+or+curious+about+your+HOME+VALUE_!+(2).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Having spent more than 18 years in the real estate industry, our team knows that making a move can be very stressful. We’d like to make this important step in your life go more smoothly by not only helping to guide you through the market but also listing your property as a certified pre-owned home.

Our team sends you through the inspection and appraisal process before your home ever goes live on the market. This will prevent certain issues from sinking your sale once you’ve got a buyer on the line.

“We know that when homes are priced correctly, in good condition, and are marketed well, they sell quickly and for top dollar.”

Along with these preliminary steps, our team also implements a “coming soon” marketing program that helps to build buyer interest in your property before it’s listed. 

We know that when homes are priced correctly, in good condition, and are marketed well, they sell quickly and for top dollar. When you’re ready to make a move, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to helping you sell for the most money, in the least time, and with as little hassle as possible.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/Making+a+MOVE+or+curious+about+your+HOME+VALUE_!+(2).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/June/Making+a+MOVE+or+curious+about+your+HOME+VALUE_!+(2).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we’d like to share just a few of the ways in which our team can help you sell.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we’d like to share just a few of the ways in which our team can help you sell.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Revitalize T-Town Is Keeping Tulsa Homes Safe and Sound</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/revitalize-t-town-is-keeping-tulsa-homes-safe-and-sound.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-21 10:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/MAY/How+Revitalize+T-Town+keeps+Tulsa+families+safe+and+sound.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently I had the opportunity to speak with Jennifer Barcus-Shafer of Revitalize T-Town to talk about her organization and what makes it so great. Having been in business for almost 22 years, Revitalize T-Town (formerly Rebuilding Together Tulsa) is an incredible force for good in our community. 

“Revitalize T-Town, or ‘RTT’ as we call it, makes homes safe, secure, and weather-proof for homeowners within the Tulsa city limits,” says Jennifer. The majority of RTT’s clients are seniors or individuals with disabilities, and these people generally find out about the organization through word of mouth. The more people RTT helps, the more their reputation grows in our community. And the more their reputation grows, the more effectively they’re able to achieve their mission: revitalizing Tulsa.

“The more their reputation grows, the more effectively they’re able to achieve their mission: revitalizing Tulsa.”

The first step RTT takes after receiving and reviewing an application is to assess the person’s home and determine what must be done to improve its condition. After that, the various improvement projects a given home needs are ranked by priority so that local contractors can handle the most urgent areas first. You can check out the video above at 1:13 for a slideshow of some before and after photos from RTT’s previous projects. 

Even more impressively, the money that funds RTT comes straight from our community. That said, monetary donations are always welcome. Still, there are many other ways to give back. If you’re a local contractor like an electrician or plumber, RTT would be happy to connect you with projects that fit your skill set. 

If you’re interested in helping out or learning more, please visit https://revitalizettown.org/. 

And, as always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/MAY/How+Revitalize+T-Town+keeps+Tulsa+families+safe+and+sound.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/MAY/How+Revitalize+T-Town+keeps+Tulsa+families+safe+and+sound.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Revitalize T-Town is truly a force for good here in Tulsa, so I’d like to share some insight into their story and mission today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Revitalize T-Town is truly a force for good here in Tulsa, so I’d like to share some insight into their story and mission today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Are Mortgage Rates Affecting Springtime Buyers and Sellers?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-are-mortgage-rates-affecting-springtime-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-18 15:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Mortgage+Experts+Take+on+Our+Spring+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are we seeing from the spring market so far? How are mortgage rates affecting buyers and sellers? 

Today I’ve invited Chris Padley of the Gateway Mortgage Group to join me for a quick chat so he can help answer these questions. Chris has been in the lending business for 16 years, and he’s one of the trusted lenders we work with here in the Tulsa area.

According to him, what we’re seeing from the market right now can be described as the normal springtime explosion. 

“Every single week is a new rush of pre-qualifications and contracts,” he says. “Every year it’s exciting, and I’m loving it.”

“If you’re a buyer and you’ve been on the fence the past few months, now’s a great time to take advantage of these conditions.”

The ups and downs of the real estate business can get crazy, so for Chris, staying positive when things get really busy means sticking to the systems he’s put in place—his scripts, daily phone calls, etc. He knows that letting the day in, day out craziness change his routine can cause everything else to fall apart. Every day, he’s on the phone and lead generating with potential clients and Realtors, and each day has its own theme.

“Mondays are my top 40, Tuesdays are my Tuesday update calls, Wednesday I’m following up with anybody who’s pre-qualified to make sure they’re taken care of, and Thursdays and Fridays I’m following up with miscellaneous—builders, leads that haven’t applied yet, and whatnot. Every single day, there’s work to be done.”

What are mortgage rates like right now? Chris says that they’re, in a word, awesome. In fact, the 30-year fixed rate is as low as 4.125%. This means if you’re a buyer and you’ve been on the fence the past few months, now’s a great time to take advantage of these conditions. We don’t know what’s going to happen in the future, but we do know that you can lock in a low rate right now. Since so many buyers will be getting into the market, now is also a great time to sell. 

If you’d like to get pre-qualified and start your home buying journey or you have any mortgage questions for Chris, you can message him at his website ThePadleyTeam.com. 

If you have any other real estate questions for me, feel free to give me a call. I’d love to speak with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Mortgage+Experts+Take+on+Our+Spring+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Mortgage+Experts+Take+on+Our+Spring+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The spring market is very busy right now, but because mortgage rates are so low, both buyers and sellers can take advantage of current conditions.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The spring market is very busy right now, but because mortgage rates are so low, both buyers and sellers can take advantage of current conditions.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Youth Services of Tulsa Provides Help for Young Adults and Teens</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-youth-services-of-tulsa-provides-help-for-young-adults-and-teens.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-25 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/MAY/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+See+How+This+Organization+Saves+Young+Lives+Every+Day+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m here today with Brian Young, who works with Youth Services of Tulsa. We’d like to share all the wonderful things this organization is doing for our community.

Youth Services of Tulsa is a nonprofit partner agency of the Tulsa Area United Way. They’re celebrating their 50-year anniversary this year.

The agency works with teenagers and young adults, and they’re the only organization in the area that focuses on these age groups. They offer a full continuum of care to end youth homelessness.

Brian sees a lot of runaway and homeless youth end up in their facilities. They offer safe places to stay and hold outreach programs during the day where youth can have their basic needs met.They have 20 beds in their facility and have helped 300 different individuals in their shelter within the last year.

“They helped 300 different individuals in their shelter within the last year.”

Many come to Youth Services of Tulsa through their safe place program, which is advertised throughout the area. If an adolescent is going through a crisis and needs immediate help, a volunteer can pick them up and bring them to the shelter.

A common misconception is that youth become homeless through some fault of their own. The vast majority are simply going through hard times. A third of the homeless youth population, for example, is made up of 18-year-olds who aged out of foster care and don’t know how to make it on their own.

You can help support Youth Services of Tulsa through donations or volunteer work. They rely on both in order to operate, and they also need items such as underwear and socks. To see how to donate and learn more about the organization, visit www.YST.org.

I’d like to thank Brian for giving us an insightful look at this wonderful organization. If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/MAY/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+See+How+This+Organization+Saves+Young+Lives+Every+Day+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/MAY/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+See+How+This+Organization+Saves+Young+Lives+Every+Day+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s why Youth Services of Tulsa is such a wonderful resource for area teens and young adults.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s why Youth Services of Tulsa is such a wonderful resource for area teens and young adults.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tulsa Foodie, Episode 5: SMOKE. Woodfire Grill</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-5-smoke-woodfire-grill.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-07 13:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Episode+5-+Tulsa+Foodies+Latest+Feature-+SMOKE.+Woodfire+Grill+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

We love Tulsa. We love food. And we really love featuring local restaurants. 

For today’s “Tulsa Foodie” feature, we’re shining the spotlight on “SMOKE. Woodfire Grill” here on Cherry Street. With the help of Chef Tim, the restaurant’s culinary craftsman, we’ll get to know more about SMOKE. and go on a little tour as well. I’m so excited to acquaint you with this wonderful restaurant! 

Tim joined the SMOKE. team a year and a half ago, and the restaurant itself has existed on Cherry Street for close to eight years, where it has built up its reputation as a preeminent restaurant in Tulsa. They boast a full-service experience with a bar and cigar lounge to complement their outstanding food. 

And no matter what time or day of the week you’d like to stop in, SMOKE. can oblige: They serve lunch and dinner seven days a week and are open a little earlier on weekends to serve brunch options. In Tim’s own words, they “have a little bit of everything to offer everybody.”

“SMOKE. has existed on Cherry Street for close to eight years, where it has built up its reputation as a preeminent restaurant in Tulsa.”

Some of Tim’s personal menu favorites come from their steak selections, but he was excited to share some other novel choices that give SMOKE. its signature feel. Many people don’t realize that, as Tim points out, beyond the meat and potatoes cookery, they offer some great vegan dishes including their vegan cauliflower steak. 

From the moment you walk into SMOKE., you’ll notice a delightfully smoky smell. This permeates from their Aztec grill from which their chefs cook over an open fire. This really draws out an unmatchable amount of flavor in the food they serve, Tim says. 

Now, we’re going to take a look around and get to know SMOKE. inside and out as well as check out their recent remodel. You can begin viewing our brief tour at 3:53 in the video.  

For more information about SMOKE., you can visit their website at SmokeTulsa.com or go ahead and stop in today to find out all that it has to offer! 

And for any real estate-related questions you have, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me by phone at 918-706-9845. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Episode+5-+Tulsa+Foodies+Latest+Feature-+SMOKE.+Woodfire+Grill+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Episode+5-+Tulsa+Foodies+Latest+Feature-+SMOKE.+Woodfire+Grill+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Welcome back to my series “Tulsa Foodie”! For today’s feature, we’re getting to know SMOKE. Woodfire Grill, along with one of its top chefs, Tim.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Welcome back to my series “Tulsa Foodie”! For today’s feature, we’re getting to know SMOKE. Woodfire Grill, along with one of its top chefs, Tim.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting to Know Scott Stulen and the Philbrook Museum of Art</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/getting-to-know-scott-stulen-and-the-philbrook-museum-of-art.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-04 11:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/MAY/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Have+You+Visited+the+Philbrook+Museum_.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Today I am joined by Scott Stulen, the president and director of Philbrook Museum of Art. Originally from Minnesota, Scott, his wife, and two kids moved to Tulsa from Indiana two-and-a-half years ago. He studied studio art as well as art history before finding work in the museum field as an educator, curator, and, now, a director. He came to Tulsa because of a job opportunity and has loved the weather ever since.

“You can find out more about upcoming exhibits at the Philbrook Museum as well as sign up for the member opening party for Mel Bochner by visiting www.philbrook.org”

Having grown up in the Tulsa area, I love the Philbrook Museum of Art. For those of you unfamiliar with this great Tulsa attraction, Scott and I had a chat that I would like to share with you today. I have provided timestamps below so you can find out all about this local treasure.

3:05 – Some background history about the Philbrook Museum of Art4:25 – Scott’s favorite place in the museum5:30 – What Scott is most proud of at the Philbrook Museum6:55 – Upcoming shows and events8:00 – What it costs to visit the museum

You can find out more about upcoming exhibits at the Philbrook Museum as well as sign up for the member opening party for Mel Bochner by visiting www.philbrook.org. And, to learn about upcoming events for all the members of your family, you can check out their events page, here. 

As always, if you have any questions for me about buying or selling, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/MAY/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Have+You+Visited+the+Philbrook+Museum_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/2019/MAY/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Have+You+Visited+the+Philbrook+Museum_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Scott Stulen joins me today to talk about all the new and exciting changes at one of  Tulsa’s gems: the Philbrook Museum of Art.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Scott Stulen joins me today to talk about all the new and exciting changes at one of  Tulsa’s gems: the Philbrook Museum of Art.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Need Ideas for a Kitchen Remodel? Check Out Elite Cabinets</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/need-ideas-for-a-kitchen-remodel-check-out-elite-cabinets.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-19 11:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Spotlight+on+Elite+Cabinets.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m excited to cast the spotlight on a premier local business, Elite Cabinets, and to get to know the story of its owner, Brandon Massey. I also had the opportunity to pick his brain for his advice to those thinking about doing a kitchen remodel.

Right out of high school, Brandon began his trade as a carpenter. From there, he transitioned into finished carpentry, and then to building cabinets in the modern, European-style that Elite Cabinets specializes in today.

Since he began his business four years ago, Brandon has been very busy due to the popularity of his cabinets. In that time, he’s noticed that the market in Tulsa has trended toward modern, clean, simple lines. What’s really cool about Elite Cabinets is that Brandon’s products can also blend into more rustic, traditional, or craftsman-style homes, depending on the finishes and wood grain colors.

“Think about the layout of the cabinets and how that will interact with the way you use your kitchen in terms of storage and access.”

If you’re planning to remodel your kitchen, Brandon has some advice to offer: Keep the finishes of the products in mind so that they tie into the aesthetic of your home, and also think about the layout of the cabinets and how that will interact with the way you use your kitchen in terms of storage and access (e.g., if you’re right-handed or left-handed).

To make an appointment with Brandon and to learn more about his excellent products, he can be reached at (918) 794-0757 or you can visit his website at www.EliteCabinetsTulsa.com.

For any other questions regarding real estate, you are, as always, encouraged to reach out to me. I’d be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Spotlight+on+Elite+Cabinets.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Spotlight+on+Elite+Cabinets.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m here today at Elite Cabinets with Brandon Masse not as an agent, but as a customer, to show you their awesome products.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m here today at Elite Cabinets with Brandon Masse not as an agent, but as a customer, to show you their awesome products.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Most Recent MLS Stats Are In! How Did We Do in December?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-most-recent-mls-stats-are-in-how-did-we-do-in-december.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-04 10:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Most+Recent+Mls+Stats+Are+In!+How+Did+We+Do+in+December_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Based on the market statistics that just came in for December 2018, we’re seeing that compared to December 2017, home sales were down 13%. Speaking truthfully, our team definitely felt that drop; it was slower than what we’ve experienced in recent years.  

It’s also useful to note that the number of new homes that came on the market was down 8% to 1,380 homes. Though fewer homes were coming on the market and fewer were selling, homes that were in great condition did sell pretty quickly. Some of you may have noticed that as well.

“We fully expect more sellers to place their homes on the market this year, especially as we draw closer to the prime time of the spring market.”

In Tulsa, the average sales price was $189,325. Within that price point, our average days on market was 47 days. Now, if your home was listed at a price higher than that, it would have taken a little longer to sell. That’s why it’s so important to work with a professional—they can look at your area market to come up with a detailed pricing strategy appropriate for your home. 

We monitor whether a market is a buyer’s, seller’s, or balanced market by looking at the absorption rate, otherwise known as our months’ supply of inventory. The market is always in a state of flux between those market types, so we look at where it’s been to help us understand where it’s going. In December 2017, there were 5.49 months of inventory available. As of last month, there were 4.35 month’s worth of homes on the market. We fully expect more sellers to place their homes on the market this year, especially as we draw closer to the prime time of the spring market.

These stats are important to have on hand when you’re thinking about real estate, no matter if you’re buying, selling, or both. Whatever the case is, we can help and guide you through the process so that you can make smart decisions regarding when it’s a good time to buy or sell. If you have any questions or need any guidance, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Most+Recent+Mls+Stats+Are+In!+How+Did+We+Do+in+December_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Most+Recent+Mls+Stats+Are+In!+How+Did+We+Do+in+December_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>It’s a new year, and we’re so excited for what’s to come! Finally, the 2018 market report statistics are out. Here is a summary of how we did in the Tulsa-area market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>It’s a new year, and we’re so excited for what’s to come! Finally, the 2018 market report statistics are out. Here is a summary of how we did in the Tulsa-area market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Shedding Some Light on Home Inspections in Tulsa</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/shedding-some-light-on-home-inspections-in-tulsa.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-03 12:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+An+Experts+Take+on+Home+Inspections+(2).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m joined by professional structural engineer Jahan Abdoveis of Foundation Engineering Inspections (FEI) to talk a little about home inspections.

For Jahan, structural engineering is a family affair. His father was a structural engineer too, and he’s the one who started FEI. Their company handles all kinds of inspections, but their primary focus is structural inspections. According to Jahan, the biggest home inspection issue he deals with in Tulsa is the foundation and floor slab problems. 

“Unfortunately, we have uniquely bad soil and uniquely relaxed building standards in Tulsa,” he says.

“A great way for sellers to lay a foundation for a successful home sale is to get a pre-inspection done on their house before they list it.”

Becoming a certified engineer requires a lot of schooling and a long apprenticeship, so inspectors like Jahan are the main authority on whether a home is safe and secure. Jahan and his father don’t see eye to eye on every single home, but between the two of them, they’ve done about 50,000 inspections. 

A great way for sellers to lay a foundation for a successful home sale is to get a pre-inspection done on their house before they list it. That way, you won’t have to deal with any unwelcome surprises when the buyer does their own inspection and you give them peace of mind that they’re getting a quality house. 

If you have any more home inspection questions for Jahan, you can visit www.FEIinspections.com or give their office a call at (918) 865-2593. 

As always, if you have any questions for me about our Tulsa market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+An+Experts+Take+on+Home+Inspections+(2).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+An+Experts+Take+on+Home+Inspections+(2).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The home inspection is an important part of the home sale process, and today I’ve brought in an expert to shed some light on this topic.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The home inspection is an important part of the home sale process, and today I’ve brought in an expert to shed some light on this topic.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tulsa Foodie, Episode 4: Hodges Bend</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-4-hodges-bend.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-13 14:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Foodie+Ep.+4-+Where+you+can+find+high-quality+coffee%252C+wine%252C+and+cocktails.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today on “Tulsa Foodie,” I’m spotlighting Hodges Bend, a coffee and cocktail bar in Downtown Tulsa. Joining me for a quick chat is co-owner Noah Bush. 

Noah got into the restaurant business at a young age and has worked a lot of different jobs in the industry over the years. He always had a love of food, but after he started working at a wine bar here in town, he fell in love with wine too. After making a name for himself at Doc’s Wine &amp; Food, he met up with his business partner and they developed the concept of a bar that specializes in coffee, wine, and cocktails. 

Aside from serving high-quality drinks, what you might not know about Hodge’s Bend is that they also serve food. They open at 7 a.m. every weekday and serve breakfast all throughout the day. Once nighttime hits, they switch over to their dinner menu, and on weekends they also serve brunch. Moving forward, they plan to make a few exciting menu changes while retaining their core products.

“Moving forward, they plan to make a few exciting menu changes while retaining their core products.”

“We always wanted to be a bar with really good food,” Noah says. With his wine background and the background of their two chefs, they plan on putting on more wine dinners in the future.

What they’re really known for, though, is their drinks, and I had the pleasure of sampling their best-selling item while we sat at the bar: Irish coffee. Their version of this popular cocktail is made with espresso, sugar syrup, Irish whiskey, and a nice, thick layer of cream on top. 

If you want to try one yourself, you can find Hodges Bend at 823 3rd Street. If you’d like to know more about their establishment, you can visit their website at www.hodges-bend.com/welcome-tulsa/ or email them at info@hodges-bend.com. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Foodie+Ep.+4-+Where+you+can+find+high-quality+coffee%252C+wine%252C+and+cocktails.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Foodie+Ep.+4-+Where+you+can+find+high-quality+coffee%252C+wine%252C+and+cocktails.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>For the latest episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” I’m showcasing Hodges Bend, a bar in downtown Tulsa that specializes in coffee, wine, and cocktails.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>For the latest episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” I’m showcasing Hodges Bend, a bar in downtown Tulsa that specializes in coffee, wine, and cocktails.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Highlighting a Great Local Business: Kitchen Concepts</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/highlighting-a-great-local-business-kitchen-concepts.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-04 11:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Kitchen+Concepts+Can+Meet+Your+Remodeling+Needs+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently I had the opportunity to speak with Jim Means of Kitchen Concepts about his business here in Tulsa. 

Jim has been in working in design since 1994, but it wasn’t until eight years ago that he transformed his business into what it is today. Now, Kitchen Concepts has its own design team and in-house construction staff, which work together on kitchen and bathroom remodel, additions, parties, and more. 

According to Jim, Kitchen Concepts is “all about you.” 

And as far as price goes, Jim and his team prefer to work within their clients’ budgets. From super high-end products to more modest options, there’s something for every price range.

“Jim and his team at Kitchen Concepts are more than happy to work around your schedule, budget, wants, and needs.”

In general, though, Jim says a full kitchen remodel will tend to cost between $50,000 and $70,000. That said, Jim is more than willing to find solutions for clients who can’t afford quite that much. 

Their showroom is conveniently located in the London South Shopping Center at 5936 S Lewis Avenue. Walk-ins are welcome during the week, or you can visit by appointment on Saturdays. 

Of course, if you aren’t quite sure what you’re looking for, they would be happy to guide you. Not only does the team at Kitchen Concepts stay on top of current trends, but they also like to focus on functionality. Often, this means opening things up to create more space. 

The bottom line is that Jim and his team at Kitchen Concepts are more than happy to work around your schedule, budget, wants, and needs. As their motto says, the goal of Kitchen Concepts is “Creating a kitchen for the way you live.” 

If you want to get in touch with Jim and his team, you can reach them by visiting www.kitchenconceptstulsa.com or by calling (918) 779-4480. 

And, as always, if you have any other questions or would like more information from me, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Kitchen+Concepts+Can+Meet+Your+Remodeling+Needs+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Kitchen+Concepts+Can+Meet+Your+Remodeling+Needs+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we’re highlighting a great local business: Kitchen Concepts.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we’re highlighting a great local business: Kitchen Concepts.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Team Is Thankful for You This Thanksgiving</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-team-is-thankful-for-you-this-thanksgiving.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-20 08:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Happy+Thanksgiving+from+Our+Team+to+Your+Family.mp4</guid>
        <description>
The leaves are changing, the holidays are approaching, and Thanksgiving is just around the corner. Right now is the perfect time to reflect on what you’re thankful for. And we at the Wolek Group are thankful for all of you. We can’t say how much we appreciate your continued support. It’s easy to get caught up in the business of life, but we hope you’re able to take time this holiday season to slow down and appreciate the small things. From our team to your family: Happy Thanksgiving! To hear our full message of thanks, watch this short video.

“What are you thankful for?”
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Happy+Thanksgiving+from+Our+Team+to+Your+Family.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Happy+Thanksgiving+from+Our+Team+to+Your+Family.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This Thanksgiving, we’d like to extend our sincere thanks to all of you who have made our business possible.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This Thanksgiving, we’d like to extend our sincere thanks to all of you who have made our business possible.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tulsa Foodie Episode 3: Ediblend Superfood Cafe</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-3-ediblend-superfood-cafe.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-25 10:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Foodie+Ep.+3+%2528Ediblend+Superfood+Cafe%2529.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today on “Tulsa Foodie,” we’ve decided to feature Ediblend Superfood Cafe in Utica Square. To give us a better idea about what this great restaurant is all about, we decided to meet up with its founders: Piper Kacere and Amy Murray. 

The idea for Ediblend Superfood Cafe began years ago when Piper and Amy, who are sisters, decided to do a juice cleanse. They got off to a rocky start, but shortly after beginning their second attempt, Piper and Amy began to attract the interest of people around them. 

Eventually, they started making cleanses for these people and, before they knew it, they started receiving text messages and calls from total strangers who were interested in their product. So they bought up all the mason jars and shower caddies they could find, then started making and packaging cleanses from a playroom in Piper’s home that they had converted into a kitchen.

“Though these juice blends are where they got their start, the Ediblend Superfood Cafe has a lot more to offer.”That coming summer, they moved their operation into a test kitchen they had rented out, and, lo and behold, they completely sold out for the season. Their satisfied customers couldn’t stop raving about their experience, so Piper and Amy knew it was time to open a permanent location. Now, since opening in 2014, the Ediblend Superfood Cafe has two locations and a massive fan base here in Tulsa.

Looking at their wide range of healthy and delicious blends, like the Sweet Green, 1717, and Sexy Yowza, it’s no wonder why. And though these juice blends are where they got their start, the Ediblend Superfood Cafe has a lot more to offer. When you visit their restaurant, you can also enjoy great salads or one of their customizable açaí bowls. Best of all, everything in the cafe is made fresh every single day. 

In the future, Amy and Piper are looking forward to expanding their business, and its menu, even wider. If you’re as interested as we are in seeing what’s on the horizon for Ediblend Superfood Cafe, or you’re curious about their hours, locations, or menu, be sure to follow them on Facebook or visit their website: https://ediblend.com/

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Foodie+Ep.+3+%2528Ediblend+Superfood+Cafe%2529.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Foodie+Ep.+3+%2528Ediblend+Superfood+Cafe%2529.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>'Today on “Tulsa Foodie,” we’re giving you a behind-the-scenes look at a great and healthy local restaurant: Ediblend Superfood Cafe'</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>'Today on “Tulsa Foodie,” we’re giving you a behind-the-scenes look at a great and healthy local restaurant: Ediblend Superfood Cafe'</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Need a Home Warranty</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-need-a-home-warranty.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-11 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Benefits+of+a+Home+Warranty.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Should you get a home warranty? I think so. There are many benefits of having a warranty, no matter if you just bought your home, currently own, or are looking to sell. To help me explain why home warranties are so important, I recently met with Shelley Carson of First American Home Warranty to discuss home warranties and all their benefits.

I have timestamped the conversation below so you can jump to the section(s) that you find the most interesting.

“There are many benefits of having a warranty no matter if you just bought your home, currently own, or are looking to sell.”

0:25 – How Shelley got into the industry.1:20 – What she has learned about that value of home warranties.2:15 – The cost of adding a home warranty.3:00 – The benefit of adding a home warranty at the time of buying.4:40 – Why sellers should get a home warranty.5:50 – How a home warranty works for sellers.

If you have any additional questions about home warranties, you can reach out to Shelley by phone at (918) 480-0924.

As always, if you have any questions about buying or selling, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Benefits+of+a+Home+Warranty.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Benefits+of+a+Home+Warranty.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Home warranties can help save you money for the fun things in a new home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Home warranties can help save you money for the fun things in a new home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Deal-Breakers That Can Wreck Your Home Sale</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-deal-breakers-that-can-wreck-your-home-sale.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-05 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+These+5+Deal-Breakers+Can+Ruin+Your+Home+Sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are five deal-breakers sellers must prepare for and avoid if they want to sell their home quickly and for top dollar:

1. Structural problems. Here in Oklahoma, our houses move over time. Depending on how old your home is, you might be able to notice a few settlement cracks here and there. Sometimes these are the normal effects of settling, while other times they can be more serious and may require the installation of a few piers. A single pier costs around $500, so if you see some cracks around your house that look a little more extreme than normal settling, you’ll want to get that checked out. 

2. The roof. Is your roof insurable and do you have proper coverage on it? If the buyer’s insurance company isn’t able to insure your roof, many times the only other solution is to replace it. 

3. The HVAC system. It’s a good idea to schedule regular maintenance checks for your HVAC system with a local heating and air company. When the appointment is finished, make sure to ask for a receipt or to have a sticker placed on your system. This way, you can prove to buyers that the system has been checked.

“Termites aren’t prejudiced—they love all types of wood and all types of houses.”

4. Termites. Termites aren’t prejudiced—they love all types of wood and all types of houses. If there’s termite activity in your house, treatment costs anywhere from $1,000 to $2,000. If your home had termite problems in the past, it may have been damaged, so get a visual inspection to see if that’s the case. If past termite damage is apparent and it isn’t fixed, termite inspectors will have to declare that your home needs termite treatment. Wood rot is another item that gets checked during a termite inspection, and if your home has this problem too, you need to get it cleaned up. 

5. Low appraisals. This is a prevalent deal-breaker we’re seeing in our market right now. Appraisals are based on the current market, and appraisers have to look back in time at recent sales to make sure your home is priced correctly. There are always ups and downs in the market, though, so even though your appraisal might not be up to date with current trends, you have to go with what the appraiser says. A low appraisal hurts both sellers and buyers because when a buyer’s obtaining a mortgage, they can’t pay more than the price the appraiser sets. 

We love helping sellers plan their move in advance, so if you’re thinking of selling your home any time soon, give us a call so we can help you get it ready for the market and have buyers wanting to pay full price for it. 

If you have any other real estate questions or you’re thinking of buying a home in our Tulsa market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us as well. We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+These+5+Deal-Breakers+Can+Ruin+Your+Home+Sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+These+5+Deal-Breakers+Can+Ruin+Your+Home+Sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are five transactional deal-breakers that sellers need to plan for before putting their home on the market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are five transactional deal-breakers that sellers need to plan for before putting their home on the market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are You Frustrated by Recent Market Inactivity? Don't Give up Yet</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-frustrated-by-recent-market-inactivity-dont-give-up-yet.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-11 11:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+This+Dip+in+Market+Activity+Means+for+You.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re more than halfway through 2018, and it’s been an amazing year for The Wolek Group. 

We’ve been able to help more than 104 families buy and sell real estate so far, and we look forward to helping many more through the end of 2018 and beyond. Of course, another way we love to help all of you is by providing key insight into what’s happening in our market. 

At this point in the year, real estate tends to slow down a little bit. With school starting up, buyers with families are mostly done shopping for homes by this point. This lull in our market is nothing out of the ordinary, but those looking to sell should be aware that it might take a little longer now than in recent months to find a buyer. Not to worry, though.

“It’s not the time to throw in the towel, but it is time to be realistic about how you’re presenting your listing to the market.”

After school is back in full swing and labor day is over, market activity will likely pick back up. Seasonal market changes are normal, and there is still plenty of time and opportunity to sell your home before 2019. 

If your home is already on the market and you’re feeling discouraged by current conditions, though, a price adjustment may be just the thing to jumpstart buyer interest. Buyer activity may be down, but it is not stagnant. 

There are still people out there looking for homes, and, with the right strategy, your property could be the one they choose. It’s not the time to throw in the towel, but it is time to be realistic about how you’re presenting your listing to the market. 

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or are curious how we can help you achieve your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+This+Dip+in+Market+Activity+Means+for+You.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+This+Dip+in+Market+Activity+Means+for+You.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buyer activity has slowed down lately, but does this mean sellers should throw in the towel? Let’s take a look at the truth about recent market conditions.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buyer activity has slowed down lately, but does this mean sellers should throw in the towel? Let’s take a look at the truth about recent market conditions.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Tulsa Foodie” Episode 1: Wild Brew 2018</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-1-wild-brew-2018.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-30 10:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Local+Food+and+Beer+for+a+Good+Cause.mp4</guid>
        <description>

On today’s episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” I’m at Wild Brew 2018 to sample some great artisan beers and food selections from both the local area and abroad. 

There are more than 50 breweries and 50 restaurants at this fun event, and if you follow along in the video above, you can hang out with me as I make the rounds and chat with several restaurateurs and brewers. 

Here are the timestamped portions of the video along with the specific vendors I was able to visit and get some face time with:

1:09 - Crushed Red2:22 - Laffa 3:42 - Burnco BBQ5:14 - That Vault/Roppongi/Elote Cafe6:38 - R Bar &amp; Grill/Prairie Brew Pub/Roosevelt’s7:27 - Old School Bagel Cafe8:14 - Nola’s Creole &amp; Cocktails10:05 - Marshall Brewing Co.

“There are more than 50 breweries and 50 restaurants at this fun event.”

I had such a great time at this event, and I want to thank everyone I had the pleasure of meeting and speaking to. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Local+Food+and+Beer+for+a+Good+Cause.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Local+Food+and+Beer+for+a+Good+Cause.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>For this episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” you’ll need to bring your appetite and your beer mug.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>For this episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” you’ll need to bring your appetite and your beer mug.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Tulsa Foodie” Episode 2: Satisfy Your Cravings With Fresh Local Flavors at Juniper</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-foodie-episode-2-satisfy-your-cravings-with-fresh-local-flavors-at-juniper.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-27 10:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Tulsa+Foodie%252C+Episode+2-+Juniper%252C+Tulsa%252C+OK.mp4</guid>
        <description>

On today’s episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” we’re taking a look at one of my favorite downtown restaurants: Juniper. 

To give you all a better idea of what makes Juniper great, and how it got its start, I met up with general manager Derek Hillman. 

Opened six years ago by first-time restaurateur Justin Thompson, Juniper has been a local favorite ever since. Juniper offers standout entrees such as seared duck, fried chicken curry, and a refreshing seared ahi salad. 

Of course, Juniper’s menu is always changing. New dishes are released each week to fit the restaurant’s ever-shifting themes, as well as the seasons. It’s no wonder why Juniper’s growth comes from its kitchen, where head chef Neil Trumpy works his culinary magic. 

“Whether you’re in the mood for a savory meal or a sweet, tasty drink, you can find what you’re craving at Juniper.”

Chef Trumpy received his education from the Oregon Culinary Institute, where he developed a skill set based around sustainability and the use of local ingredients. As you’ll see in today’s episode, watching him work is an amazing sight to behold. 

But delectable dishes aren’t the only thing there is to enjoy at Juniper. Diners can also enjoy any of the many refreshing signature cocktails they offer. So whether you’re in the mood for a savory meal or a sweet, tasty drink, you can find what you’re craving at Juniper. 

Dining at Juniper is an amazing experience, so be sure to come check it out yourself. 

Juniper (located at 324 East 3rd Street in downtown Tulsa)  is open for lunch Monday through Friday from 11 a.m. to 2 p.m., and for dinner from 4 p.m. to 10 p.m. on Monday through Saturday. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Tulsa+Foodie%252C+Episode+2-+Juniper%252C+Tulsa%252C+OK.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Tulsa+Foodie%252C+Episode+2-+Juniper%252C+Tulsa%252C+OK.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>On today’s episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” we’re taking a look behind the scenes at one of my personal favorites: Juniper.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>On today’s episode of “Tulsa Foodie,” we’re taking a look behind the scenes at one of my personal favorites: Juniper.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Hope to See You at WildBrew on August 25</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/we-hope-to-see-you-at-wildbrew-on-august-25.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-15 15:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Wildbrew+Will+Be+a+Fantastic+Time+for+All.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m back to talk about a fantastic event that’s coming up here in a few weeks. Angela Evans, who works in the marketing department for WildBrew, joined me recently to talk about the event and what you need to know about it.

They don’t call it the greatest party ever hatched for nothing. WildBrew is a fundraiser for the Sutton Avian Research Center located in Bartlesville. This is the 20th year for this festival, making it the oldest craft beer festival in Oklahoma!

The event is on Saturday, August 25th at the Cox Business Center downtown. 

Over 50 local and non-local breweries and 50 amazing restaurants will be in attendance for this wonderful indoor festival. Here’s what a ticket to this festival will get you:


  All the beer tastings that you can responsibly handle
  All the food from all the restaurants.


“Over 50 breweries and 50 restaurants will be in attendance.”

General admission tickets are $65.00 and get you in for three hours from 5:00 p.m. to 8:00 p.m. The patron-level tickets get you in an hour early and get you into a special area for an additional hour.

In addition to having a heck of a time, your ticket purchase will fund some amazing research. The Sutton Avian Research Center played a crucial role in bringing the bald eagle off of the endangered animal list. More recently, they’ve been working with the Greater Prairie Chicken and the Masked Bobwhite Quail. For the Masked Bobwhite Quail, they incubate eggs, hatch them, then take the chicks to Mexico to mate and become released into the wild.

To get tickets to this wonderful event, head on over to wildbrew.org. Experience the restaurants, the beers, and the ciders. It’s going to be a great time and we would love to see you there. We’re very excited to sponsor this event.

If you have any other questions about the event or about real estate in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Wildbrew+Will+Be+a+Fantastic+Time+for+All.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Wildbrew+Will+Be+a+Fantastic+Time+for+All.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The 20th annual WildBrew is happening on August 25. We sat down with Angela Evans to discuss the event and why it’s always a great time for attendees.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The 20th annual WildBrew is happening on August 25. We sat down with Angela Evans to discuss the event and why it’s always a great time for attendees.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Wouldn’t Be Able to Do What We Love Without You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/we-wouldnt-be-able-to-do-what-we-love-without-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-02 11:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Today+We+Want+to+Say+Thanks+(3).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Without you, we wouldn’t be able to do what we love every single day and have fun doing it. For this, we want to say thank you. 

We’ve been able to help over 100 families buy or sell a home this year so far. What’s most exciting about this is it allows us to give back to our Tulsa community. Every time we help someone buy or sell a home, we make a commitment to donate to their favorite local nonprofit. On top of that, we donate to Keys to the City, which is a foundation that we set up that allows for strategic donation. 

“Without you, we wouldn’t be able to do what we love every single day and have fun doing it.”

For example, we’ve donated $500 to Global Gardens, Emergency Infant Services, and the Community Food Bank of Eastern Oklahoma. 

We also put together an event where we collected donations for Dress for Success. Every time we host one of these events to raise money for a local nonprofit, we have so much fun, so if you have a favorite local nonprofit, don’t hesitate to mention them to us. We’d be happy to include them in this initiative. 

We appreciate you very much, so if there’s anything you need from us or we can assist you in any way, give us a call or send us an email anytime. We’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Today+We+Want+to+Say+Thanks+(3).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Today+We+Want+to+Say+Thanks+(3).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buying and selling homes gives us the opportunity to give back to our community, and we want to thank you for helping us do this.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buying and selling homes gives us the opportunity to give back to our community, and we want to thank you for helping us do this.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons to Hire a Real Estate Professional When Buying</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-to-hire-a-real-estate-professional-when-buying.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-28 16:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Should+You+Hire+a+Buyers+Agent%253F+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

We all know that it’s important for a homebuyer to use a licensed real estate agent when buying a home. But do you know why? Today I will share three of the top reasons. 

1. We have the inventory. As real estate professionals, we have access to the multiple listing service (MLS), which is a database for Realtors. Of course, there are other websites out there that list houses for sale, but we all know that the MLS is the most up-to-date database for listings. Buyers who look for homes on other websites will only to be disappointed to find out they’re not available.

And, if we do not have the inventory, we have the tools and technologies and databases to help find you a home that fits all of your needs.

“When a seller lists their home on the market, they have already agreed to pay the buyer agent’s compensation.”

2. We have the negotiation skills. As a homebuyer, you may be hesitant to speak your mind on certain points, for fear of offending the seller.

With an agent on your side, you will get the best deal and terms, you will know what is normal, and you will know what to expect. We will keep you up to date on timelines to make sure that you do not miss out on an opportunity for inspections or appraisals.

3. A buyer agent is free. When a seller lists their home on the market, they have already agreed to pay the buyer agent’s compensation. There is no reason for you to do all of the work when you can use us. We can help you negotiate your best terms, hold the deal together to get you to closing on time, and provide you with all of our years of experience for free!

If you have any additional questions or are interested in buying, please feel free to call me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Should+You+Hire+a+Buyers+Agent%253F+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Should+You+Hire+a+Buyers+Agent%253F+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You know you should have a licensed real estate agent on your side when buying, but do you know why?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You know you should have a licensed real estate agent on your side when buying, but do you know why?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What 1 Organization Is Doing to Address Childhood Hunger</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-1-organization-is-doing-to-address-childhood-hunger.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-22 11:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+An+Opportunity+to+Help+Hungry+Children+(2).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I am excited to bring you some important information about a great local organization: the Community Food Bank of Eastern Oklahoma. 

Eileen Bradshaw, the executive director of the Community Food Bank, joined me to explain a little bit about what they do. 

With approximately 450 partner programs, this organization helps to distribute food throughout the state. According to Eileen, about one in every four children goes to bed hungry at night. And, as we can all agree, this is unacceptable. 

“It’s part of our job just to make sure [these children] get what they need,” says Eileen.

It was truly amazing to get a behind-the-scenes look at operations here at the Community Food Bank. Especially because at the time of my visit, they were preparing for “Summer Feeding.” The Summer Feeding program is one way that they are able to continue providing for kids who rely on school meals at other times of the year. On day one of this program, they fed an estimated 1,100 children.

“Approximately one in every four children goes to bed hungry at night, so the work the Community Food Bank is doing is critical.”

The workers at the Food Bank are also delegating more resources to their partner programs, as they know that their lines grow longer in the summer months, as well. 

So, with as much as this organization does for our community, how can we give back and help them make a difference? Well, for every dollar donated, the Food Bank is able to produce four meals. Obviously, financial gifts are always welcomed. 

Of course, volunteering your time and donating food are also great ways to help.

So, if you want to get in touch with Eileen, you can give her a call at (918) 585-2800, or visit www.okfoodbank.org. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+An+Opportunity+to+Help+Hungry+Children+(2).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+An+Opportunity+to+Help+Hungry+Children+(2).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I am taking you behind the scenes at an amazing local organization: the Community Food Bank of Eastern Oklahoma.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I am taking you behind the scenes at an amazing local organization: the Community Food Bank of Eastern Oklahoma.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Get a Raised Garden Bed This Season?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/should-you-get-a-raised-garden-bed-this-season.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-22 11:31:14 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Pros+and+Cons+of+Raised+Garden+Beds.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It’s spring and that means it’s time to get our hands dirty in the garden. 

With that being said, today I’d like to discuss some pros and cons of a common gardening option: raised beds. 

One benefit of raised garden beds is simply that they’re nice to look at. Beyond that, raised beds also keep animals from getting to your garden. 

They also allow you to plant earlier, since the loose soil you fill the bed with will be warmer than the ground itself.

“The decision as to whether a raised bed is right for you depends on your preferences and circumstances.”

Now, let’s take a look at some of the downsides. 

First, they’re pricey. You’re going to have to invest in the bed, the materials, soil, and fertilizer to get started. Raised beds also aren’t as sustainable as simply planting your garden in the ground.

Ultimately, the decision as to whether a raised bed is right for you depends on your preferences and circumstances. And if you’re unsure, my friends over at Grogg’s Green Barn can help you decide what gardening solutions may work best for you.

As always, if you have any other questions for me or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Pros+and+Cons+of+Raised+Garden+Beds.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Pros+and+Cons+of+Raised+Garden+Beds.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is a raised bed the right solution for your garden? There are a few pros and cons you should consider before making that decision.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is a raised bed the right solution for your garden? There are a few pros and cons you should consider before making that decision.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Emergency Infant Services: Where Struggling Tulsa Families Can Find Help</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/emergency-infant-services-where-struggling-tulsa-families-can-find-help.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-22 11:25:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+EIS+Helps+Families+in+Our+Community.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m coming to you live from the downtown office of Emergency Infant Services (EIS) here in Tulsa to tell you a little bit about this great organization and what they do for our community. Joining me is EIS Executive Director Bill Andoe. 

For the last 40 years, the mission of EIS has been to serve families who are experiencing financial hardship and have children under the age of five. They provide clothing, diapers, groceries, formula, and other essential needs these families have. All these families have to do is meet with an EIS interviewer to assess their needs so they can determine which services they can provide and which community services might be available to them—even if their children are over five. 

Aside from their downtown location, they also have a location on the east side of Tulsa and two satellite locations on the north and south sides of town. Right now they’re in the middle of a capital campaign, so a year from this summer, they’ll be moving to 11th and Denver. This move will help them provide more resources for families, centralize their warehouse, and stockpile more supplies.

“Anyone is welcome at EIS.”

One thing in particular I love to share about EIS is anyone is welcome there. They provide their services with love and without judgement—it’s one of their founding principles. According to Bill, they average about 18,000 visits per year, and they expect that number to reach 20,000 in the near future. To help carry the loan, they have church groups, school groups, and a number of other regular volunteers who help them on a weekly basis. 

“We’re in this because we want to help,” Bill says. “That’s what attracts employees and volunteers to EIS. We often talk about the people who come in—we talk about professionally mentioning them statistically as clients, but they’re really more than just clients. They’re members of our community. They go to our churches. We see them at public events. They’re Tulsans just like us. We’re here to help them.”

EIS relies on the generosity of donors and the Tulsa community at large, so if you’d like to help them in their mission, they always welcome financial donations. They also accept diapers, wipes, car seats, strollers, and anything else a family with a young child might need. 

If you’d like to get in touch with EIS or you’d like more information on how to donate, you can visit their website at www.EISTulsa.org. 

As always, if you have any questions for me or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+EIS+Helps+Families+in+Our+Community.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+EIS+Helps+Families+in+Our+Community.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Emergency Infant Services provides relief and support to families in Tulsa who are struggling financially. They do so with love and without judgment.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Emergency Infant Services provides relief and support to families in Tulsa who are struggling financially. They do so with love and without judgment.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7 Tips for Decluttering Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/7-tips-for-decluttering-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-22 11:20:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Declutter+Your+Home+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Decluttering is so important in getting your home ready to sell as well as just cleaning up for spring. Whatever your motivation, thinning out your home is a great way to feel good. Today let’s go through the seven steps it takes to declutter your home.

1. Make sure the front of your home is welcoming and encourages buyers to come inside. First impressions are everything. Buyers are probably going to find your home online first, and then they might even drive around the neighborhood to check it out. You’ll want to clear out any dead leaves and put some fresh mulch down. Be sure that there are no mud daubers or bird’s nests in your eaves. Pretend you’re a buyer and walk up to your front porch. What would you think? 

2. Take it one room at a time. Decluttering can be really overwhelming, so just start small. Thin out the things in your room and closet; think about what your room would look like in a photograph. What isn’t needed? Pictures will amplify those extra things on countertops and other areas. 

3. Decide what furniture you really need in the home. To make your property look like a model home, get rid of extra furniture and end tables.

4. Clean off countertops. These are common places for us to pile things up, but kitchens are very important rooms to make a good impression with. Put your toaster, blender, and other similar appliances away in a cabinet, and clear away other extraneous papers and tidbits.

“Think about what your room would look like in a photograph. What isn’t needed?”

5. Clean your shower. When we come to preview your home, we’re going to pull back the shower curtain. Be sure the grout is clean and that tiles or paint aren’t peeling. Your shower will tell buyers a lot about how you take care of your home.

6. Take away your collectibles. It’s great that you care about and collect things that are dear to your heart, but that can become a distraction to buyers. Go ahead and box it up and put it away.

7. Declutter the garage and storage sheds. If there are things in there that you need to keep on hand, put them in boxes or storage bins that are neat and organized.

All these things sound crazy, however, they make a lot of difference. A decluttered home will help you get the most money for your home in the shortest amount of time.

If you need any help with decluttering your home or have other questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you however I can.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Declutter+Your+Home+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Declutter+Your+Home+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Decluttering your home can feel overwhelming, but these seven steps will hopefully help you simplify the process before you sell your home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Decluttering your home can feel overwhelming, but these seven steps will hopefully help you simplify the process before you sell your home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Are Looking for Homes to Sell</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/we-are-looking-for-homes-to-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-22 11:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Are+Low+on+Inventory.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Spring has sprung for us here in the Tulsa market. We’re very busy this time of year, so I wanted to take a short minute to talk about our listing shortage.

We need good, ready-to-move-in homes in the $150,000 to $250,000 price range. If you have a home that would match this criteria, please let us know so that we can help all of our buyers. We have more buyers than we have homes for sale that match their criteria.

“We need good, ready-to-move-in homes in the $150,000 to $250,000 price range.”

Another tool that we use is called “My Buyer Listings,” a website just for buyer listings. That means we’ve met with our buyers, we’ve qualified them, and they’re ready to go buy a home. They’re just not finding homes that match what they’re looking for. Be sure to check out our listings that we already have with buyers and let us know if this is the perfect time to put your home on the market in this price range. That way, you get to take advantage of the market by moving up—and that’s always a win.

If you have a home in this price range that you’d consider selling or if you have any other questions, please reach out to us and let us know how we can help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Are+Low+on+Inventory.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Are+Low+on+Inventory.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our market is short on listings. Do you have a home to sell for between $150,000 and $250,000?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our market is short on listings. Do you have a home to sell for between $150,000 and $250,000?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Kids About Science and Teamwork Through Global Gardens </title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-community-spotlight-global-gardens.html</link>
        
          <category>The Wolek Group</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-22 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Maryann Donahue from Global Gardens is here today to share how this wonderful organization helps empower children in high-poverty areas of Tulsa.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Something that’s really important to us as a real estate team is giving back to our community, which is why we like to spotlight our local nonprofits that are doing great things in the Tulsa area. Today, I’m talking to Maryann Donahue from Global Gardens.

Global Gardens was created by a teacher from Tulsa named Heather Oakley [spelling?] in 2007. Heather had a background in urban science education and peace education. She also had a bachelors degree in botany. She combined all of those things to create Global Gardens.

The purpose of Global Gardens is to help fight the cycle of poverty and empower kids from high-poverty communities to be agents of change in their own lives and in their communities.

When Heather came back to Tulsa in 2007, she started the first program at Eugene Field. She offered during and after-school programs. At that time, there was an empty lot next to Eugene Field that was bare, empty, and forgotten. She and that first group of students turned it into a beautiful, bountiful garden, and that’s what Global Gardens has done ever since.

Since then, Global Gardens has added three more sites in addition to Eugene Field, including the one Maryann and I are filming from today. This field services Union Middle School and Union High School. There are two other elementary schools in the program as well: Rosa Parks Elementary and McAuliffe Elementary in East Tulsa.

“THE PURPOSE OF GLOBAL GARDENS IS TO HELP FIGHT THE CYCLE OF POVERTY AND EMPOWER KIDS.”

“We serve over 1,800 kids every week in this program,” says Maryann. “We’re helping about 2,500 people a year.”

Global Gardens uses gardening as a vehicle for empowerment. They also use gardening to teach science and how to be peaceful. “In the during-school program, they have a class garden. They get to decide what to plant, and they have a harvest party at the end of the year,” says Maryann. “They do all of that together. It’s very intentional.”

These programs teach science that addresses state science standards while also teaching teamwork. The students don’t have many opportunities outside of Global Gardens to do hands-on, real-world things and have to do them as a team.

We really believe that Global Gardens is doing a great thing. How can you help? Go to Global-Gardens.org to make an online donation. All of their funding is raised from community donations; they don’t have state contracts or charge fees.

Maryann says that Global Gardens hopes to add a fifth site at Jackson Elementary School in North Tulsa by 2019. This has been in the works for a while, so please consider helping them reach their goal.

I would like to thank Maryann for taking the time to talk to me today. You can learn more details about Global Gardens at Global-Gardens.org.

If you have any real estate questions or know another local nonprofit you think we should spotlight, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Maryann Donahue from Global Gardens is here today to share how this wonderful organization helps empower children in high-poverty areas of Tulsa.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Maryann Donahue from Global Gardens is here today to share how this wonderful organization helps empower children in high-poverty areas of Tulsa.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Cleansing Rain Help You Clean and Organize Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-clean-your-home-with-cleansing-rain.html</link>
        
          <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-22 13:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Clean+Your+Home+with+Cleansing+Rain.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I want to talk about Cleansing Rain, which is an incredible home cleaning business here in our town.To learn more about the business and how it began, I spoke with the owner, Lacie Partney.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Today, I want to talk about an incredible home cleaning business here in our town: Cleansing Rain.

When I asked how she got the idea to begin her business, owner Lacie Partney told me she wasn’t always such a neat and organized person.

According to Lacie, it all began when she returned to Tulsa after two years on the mission field. At that point in time, she was searching for something to do.

Since then, she’s found cleaning homes to be very fulfilling. She says it really helps her build relationships. On top of that, Lacie herself makes all of the natural cleaning products she uses.

“FROM YOUR ATTIC TO YOUR JUNK DRAWER, LACIE IS HAPPY TO HELP ANYONE DECLUTTER.”

This is just one of the things that help her stand out from other cleaning companies in town. She also loves to help people get more organized. From your attic to your junk drawer, Lacie is happy to help anyone declutter.

But, it doesn’t stop there. Once she helps her clients declutter their spaces, Lacie also helps them develop an organizational system that can be implemented into their specific lifestyle.

One thing Lacie highly recommends is to make use of vertical space. Instead of buying new furniture that takes up floor space, she suggests that people try to utilize their walls for storage, instead.

To learn more about Lacie and her business, you can visit her website at www.CleansingRain918.com.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Clean+Your+Home+with+Cleansing+Rain.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Clean+Your+Home+with+Cleansing+Rain.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, I want to talk about Cleansing Rain, which is an incredible home cleaning business here in our town.To learn more about the business and how it began, I spoke with the owner, Lacie Partney.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, I want to talk about Cleansing Rain, which is an incredible home cleaning business here in our town.To learn more about the business and how it began, I spoke with the owner, Lacie Partney.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How John Carter Bathrooms Can Help You </title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-favorite-bathroom-remodel-specialist.html</link>
        
          <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-22 13:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/FEB+18'/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+Favorite+Bathroom+Remodel+Specialist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

John Carter from John Carter Bathrooms is here today to answer a few questions about his business and some of the latest trends in bathroom remodels.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Today, I’m here with John Carter from John Carter Bathrooms. John has graciously agreed to answer some questions about his business.

How did you get into this business?

It started way back. I’m from Namibia and my father did remodeling. He taught me everything I know. I learned everything from scratch and got to love remodeling, which made me decide to make it a business.

I moved to the United States a couple of years ago and got a job like everybody else. Then I realized that I wouldn’t be able to work on my dreams, so I decided to start a remodeling business. I can do kitchens, bathrooms, and even build homes, but I wanted to focus on something special, so I learned how to specialize in bathrooms.

I love your story and that you are doing something you are passionate about, which is important to me as well. What makes you stand out from the competition?

There are a couple of things that make us different. First, we complete all projects on time and on budget. It is a top priority for us to work around your schedule and your finances. Second, all of our projects are designed to fit your size and your style. We don’t ask you to cut corners on the perfect remodel. Finally, we are the most available and we provide daily progress reports on what’s done, so you’re never left wondering what we did all day.

“YOU WILL GET DAILY PROGRESS REPORTS SO YOU KNOW EXACTLY HOW MUCH WORK HAS BEEN DONE.”

What’s a new style or trend that you have noticed lately?

In kitchens, soapstone has been popular lately. We’ve been using it in bathrooms for a little bit. People do want to use quartz for their surfaces these days. There are a lot of new materials out there. People like wooden countertops as well.

For bathrooms, people stick to light, neutral colors. Those will last a long time. Back in the 80s, people made pink, green, and purple bathrooms. That doesn’t work. My job is to come into somebody’s home and put something in there with tile that will last. Technology has improved with tile and cement, so we can build up bathrooms that are mold-free and 100% waterproof, which is great.

How can someone get in touch with you about a remodel or to ask any questions?

My phone number is 918-574-4610 or look at my website, JohnCarterBathrooms.com. You can enter your information and get a free 3-D model of what your bathroom could look like at no cost to you.

Thank you to John for answering my questions. As always, if you have any real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/FEB+18'/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+Favorite+Bathroom+Remodel+Specialist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/FEB+18'/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+Favorite+Bathroom+Remodel+Specialist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

John Carter from John Carter Bathrooms is here today to answer a few questions about his business and some of the latest trends in bathroom remodels.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

John Carter from John Carter Bathrooms is here today to answer a few questions about his business and some of the latest trends in bathroom remodels.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Does Luxe Furniture and Design Have to Offer?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-luxe-is-great-for-products-and-design.html</link>
        
          <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-24 11:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/January+2018/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Luxe+Is+Great+for+Products+and+Design.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m here with Tamara Noel, owner of Luxe Furniture and Design, to discuss the products and services her company provides.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Today I’m here with Tamara Noel, owner of Luxe Furniture and Design, and I’m so excited for her to share with you all the great things they have here at Luxe.

Along with beautiful furniture and decor, Luxe also offers a great design service that’s complimentary with purchase. When you shop there, you get to work with a qualified, educated, and talented interior designer to help you every step of the way.

They’re not just salespeople who are knowledgeable about all the products Luxe offers; they are honestly legitimate design experts. The designers went to school to learn the skill and have spent their entire career honing the craft. They love what they do, and they’re very good at it.

When somebody walks through the door with a need, what does the process of helping them look like?

It could be anything from one of the designers helping the client navigate the store to identify their wants and needs to schedule a house call where someone isn’t quite sure what they’re looking for or they have a larger project they don’t know how to start.

“THE HELP OF A DESIGNER CAN MAKE ALL THE DIFFERENCE.”

Our designers make complimentary house calls out to your home. They’ll do all the measuring, look at your paint colors, work with what pieces you already have, give guidance on space planning, give direction for new pieces, and more. It could be something as simple as window treatments, but whatever it is, the help of a designer can make all the difference.

We do a lot in stages. It may just be planning for the big picture—doing a few changes now and a little bit more down the road to ultimately get the look that you want.

What are you seeing in terms of design trends?

Clean lines are still key here in Tulsa. It’s becoming a transitional market, but neutrals are still very popular, and a lot of the taupes of years past are coming back. Adding in a little bit of fun with texture or a pop of color is a good way to brighten up your space.

How can people get in touch with you?

You can find us in our showroom at 9922 Riverside Parkway in Tulsa, Oklahoma, in the King’s Landing Shopping Center. You can also visit our website www.luxetulsa.com, give us a call at (918) 459-8950, or like us on Facebook.

As always, if you need anything in terms of real estate from the Wolek Group, please feel free to reach out to us. Have a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/January+2018/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Luxe+Is+Great+for+Products+and+Design.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/January+2018/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Luxe+Is+Great+for+Products+and+Design.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m here with Tamara Noel, owner of Luxe Furniture and Design, to discuss the products and services her company provides.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m here with Tamara Noel, owner of Luxe Furniture and Design, to discuss the products and services her company provides.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Will I See You at the Toyland Ball in January?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/will-i-see-you-at-toyland-ball-in.html</link>
        
          <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-19 12:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/December/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Don%2527t+Miss+This+Chance+to+Make+a+Difference.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The mission of The Parent Child Center of Tulsa is to prevent child abuse and neglect through education, treatment, and advocacy.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Today I’m excited to be joined by special guest Carey Baker. I had the opportunity to ask Carey some questions about her involvement with The Parent Child Center of Tulsa. Her and her husband, Brett Baker, are Co-chairs for Toyland Ball 2018.

The Toyland Ball, held every January, is The Parent Child Center of Tulsa’s annual signature fundraising event. This black tie gala featuring a whimsical theme offers an elegant evening of dinner and dancing, with a live auction.

I caught up with Carey at the Toyland Ball Stock the Bar Party where attendees bring a bottle of wine valued at $50 or more to be auctioned off at the Toyland Ball 2018 in January. In past years, the wine auctioned off at the event in January has raised between $8,000 and $10,000 for The Parent Child Center of Tulsa. That is just the money raised from auctioning the wine. There are other items that are auctioned off that raise even more money for the cause.

For those of you who may not know, the mission of The Parent Child Center of Tulsa is to prevent child abuse and neglect through education, treatment, and advocacy. People who have been victims of abuse or neglect are given education and counseling so that they are able to end the cycle. Many people only know what they’ve been taught, so The Parent Child Center of Tulsa aims to reverse this.

If you’re interested in attending, the Toyland Ball auction will take place on January 20th, 2018 at the Cox Business Center. For tickets, visit www.ParentChildCenter.org. You can also become a patron sponsor by donating $1,000 for two people.

At the event, there will be raffles, an auction, and a live band. Also, all of the proceeds go directly to the counseling funds for The Parent Child Center of Tulsa.

We hope you have a very Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year!

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/December/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Don%2527t+Miss+This+Chance+to+Make+a+Difference.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/December/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Don%2527t+Miss+This+Chance+to+Make+a+Difference.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The mission of The Parent Child Center of Tulsa is to prevent child abuse and neglect through education, treatment, and advocacy.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The mission of The Parent Child Center of Tulsa is to prevent child abuse and neglect through education, treatment, and advocacy.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>This Time, I'm the One Who's Buying</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/this-time-im-the-one-whos-buying.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-05 09:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/January+2018/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+I%2527m+Looking+for+an+Investment+Property.mp4</guid>
        <description>
I’m on the hunt for an investment property in the TU/Midtown area. These kinds of properties are hard to find, so I’d love your help.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Usually, I’m the one helping buyers. Today though, I’m the one who’s buying.

I’m looking to buy an investment property around the TU/Midtown area for anywhere up to $125,000. I would love one that has three bedrooms, but I’d be fine with two bedrooms as well. One or 1.5 bathrooms would be ideal.

Midtown is a great place to live, so these kinds of properties are hard to find. If you’re thinking about selling your home and don’t have it on the market yet, I would love to talk to you and see if I could be your buyer.

“I WOULD LOVE TO TALK TO YOU AND SEE IF I COULD BE YOUR BUYER.”

If you know of anyone else making a move from or selling an investment property that’s already being leased in that area, don’t hesitate to send them my way.

If you have any questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call at (918) 712-2252 or send me an email at info@TheWolekGroup.com. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/January+2018/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+I%2527m+Looking+for+an+Investment+Property.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/January+2018/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+I%2527m+Looking+for+an+Investment+Property.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
I’m on the hunt for an investment property in the TU/Midtown area. These kinds of properties are hard to find, so I’d love your help.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
I’m on the hunt for an investment property in the TU/Midtown area. These kinds of properties are hard to find, so I’d love your help.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Holiday Gift Ideas and More with Candra at Saks</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-a-few-more-holiday-gift-ideas.html</link>
        
          <category>Tulsa Real Estate Agents</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-21 09:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Holiday+Gift+Ideas+and+More+with+Candra+at+Saks.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Looking for some great holiday gift ideas? Look no further than Saks Fifth Avenue Tulsa.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

I’m back again to highlight another great business here in town. We’re getting into the holiday spirit today at Saks Fifth Avenue. Candra Monck joined me to discuss holiday gift ideas, style advisors, and some fun events they have coming up at the store.

First, let’s take a look at some great holiday gift ideas, all of which are available in the store:

• Artist makeup brushes. Not only is this set of brushes gorgeous, they are light and easy to use as well.
• Dyson hairdryer. This is a brand new product from Dyson. They have taken their air circulation and noise-canceling technology to the hairdryer market.
• Chanel skin regeneration set.

If you have somebody on your list that’s a little bit harder to buy for, Candra recommends giving one of their style advisors a call. They know the ins and outs of everything that the store carries. Candra even uses these advisors herself.

“KEEP AN EYE OUT FOR ALL OF THEIR UPCOMING EVENTS ON THEIR FACEBOOK PAGE.”

There are a ton of great events coming up at Saks Fifth Avenue Tulsa. They include visits from national makeup artists, spa days, complimentary makeovers, makeup lessons, and more.

The best way to contact them is through their Facebook page, which they are constantly updating with events, deals, and more.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call at (918) 706-9845 or send me an email at Info@TheWolekGroup.com. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Holiday+Gift+Ideas+and+More+with+Candra+at+Saks.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Holiday+Gift+Ideas+and+More+with+Candra+at+Saks.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Looking for some great holiday gift ideas? Look no further than Saks Fifth Avenue Tulsa.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Looking for some great holiday gift ideas? Look no further than Saks Fifth Avenue Tulsa.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Let Us Help You Find Your Dream Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-our-tool-to-help-you-find-that-dream-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Tulsa Real Estate Buyers Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-14 11:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/FEB+18'/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+Tool+to+Help+You+Find+That+Dream+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’ve struggled to find your dream home by searching on your own, we have a proactive solution that may be the answer you need: buyer listings.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Today I wanted to tell you about our buyer listings.

We’ve had many buying clients who have either exhausted the market because they just can’t find what they’re looking for, or they aren’t ready to move right this minute.

We have come up with a plan to proactively search for listings for our buying clients. We call this our buyer listings.

Just like we do for sellers, when we gather all the information on the property and market it on the MLS, our websites, and social media, we do the same thing for our buyer clients.

We have a website set up specifically to host all of these properties for our buyers, and we definitely push those listings out to our social media avenues and networks as well.

“IT’S KIND OF LIKE A DATING GAME BUT FOR A HOME.”

It’s kind of like a dating game but for a home. We are so excited to help match you up with a great home you’d be interested to move to.

Even if you’re just starting to think about the buyer search or you’ve been searching online with no luck, go ahead and get with us. We’ll have a consultation where we talk about all your wants and dreams and get you set up on our website so we can help you find your perfect home.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call at (918) 712-2252 or send me an email at info@TheWolekGroup.com. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/FEB+18'/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+Tool+to+Help+You+Find+That+Dream+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/FEB+18'/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+Tool+to+Help+You+Find+That+Dream+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’ve struggled to find your dream home by searching on your own, we have a proactive solution that may be the answer you need: buyer listings.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’ve struggled to find your dream home by searching on your own, we have a proactive solution that may be the answer you need: buyer listings.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Groggs Green Barn Is Unique to Tulsa</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-groggs-green-barn.html</link>
        
          <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-25 11:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Grogg%2527s+Green+Barn.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re out at Grogg’s Green Barn today with owner Carla Grogg. She’s going to talk to us a bit about what they do.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Today I’m happy to be joined by Carla Grogg of Grogg’s Green Barn. This place is so cool, so I wanted to talk a little bit with Carla about all the things that are going on here.

Carla and her husband started Grogg’s Green Barn seven years ago. As far as I know, this business is the only one of its kind in Tulsa. Carla and her husband started Grogg’s Green Barn, an all-sustainable organic nursery, after a few of their family members were affected by cancer, causing them to take their own health more seriously.

Grogg’s Green Barn carries all kinds of perennials, trees, shrubs, and more. Additionally, they have quite a selection of edibles, like berry bushes, fruit trees, vegetables, and herbs. They also have a ton of great pollination plants, which are becoming more and more important as bee and butterfly populations continue to dwindle.

“YOU NEED TO COME DOWN AND CHECK THIS PLACE OUT.”

Just this year, Grogg’s has added another component to their business. They are transitioning part of their facility to be a new dining facility: The Reserve at Grogg’s Green Barn. They will use their own produce as well as meat and dairy from other local farmers to prepare delicious meals from Chef Matt Owen. You can RSVP to the next dinner right here on their site.

I highly recommend that you come down here and check out Grogg’s Green Barn. To learn more about what they do, head on over to their website. If you have any questions, you can give Carla a call at (918) 994-4222.

If you have any real estate questions or needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re always here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Grogg%2527s+Green+Barn.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Grogg%2527s+Green+Barn.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We’re out at Grogg’s Green Barn today with owner Carla Grogg. She’s going to talk to us a bit about what they do.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re out at Grogg’s Green Barn today with owner Carla Grogg. She’s going to talk to us a bit about what they do.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Should You Handle a Low Offer?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-dont-reject-low-offers-out-of-hand.html</link>
        
          <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-20 13:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Handle+Lower+Offers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you encounter an offer that is lower than asking price, it’s common to negotiate.
Do not take the low offer personally.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Today, I’m going to give my two cents on a topic that keeps coming up in our business. I know if you’ve watched my videos in the past, I say the same things over and over again. That just because we sell lots and lots of houses and we get to help lots and lots of people. We have a lot of experience with this.

I am still primarily the listing agent for our team, so I mostly work with sellers. I receive offers from agents that are working with buyers, and so many times these offers come in lower than the listing price, and sometimes with other concessions built in, such as closing costs and warranties.

I will admit that sometimes, I’m a little shocked at some of the offers we get.

Then I remember that in a buyer’s mind, they are doing the best that they can for their family. Of course they want to make a lower offer, because they feel like it’s their job to negotiate.

Well, as an agent, that’s also part of our job: to best prepare our clients and to explain the market to them.

When we receive these lower offers or offers that have different contingencies built in, it’s our job to settle the client (the seller) and explain to them that these are expected—low offers like these are the norm.

“I WILL ADMIT THAT SOMETIMES, I’M A LITTLE SHOCKED AT SOME OF THE OFFERS WE GET.”

I’ll admit it: I forget that you guys don’t do this every day like I do. I do need to slow down and understand where you’re coming from, because as a seller, you are working to get your best deal and to put the most money in your pocket. That is my goal for you, too.

However, I do know that I’m studying the market all the time and monitoring the average list-to-sales price of the MLS, how we can put the most money in your pocket and at the same time, get your home sold.

An offer early on may be a little lower than you were planning on, and yet, if it doesn’t sell, how much longer will you have it?

Remember that the process of selling is a negotiation. Please do not ever reject an offer; you have to do a little bit of negotiating to show that you want to sell your house. The buyer is working to get their best number, and you’re working to get your best number, so sometimes you have to get together in the middle somewhere.

That’s our goal: to get you the most money, and for the buyers to get the best deal. At the same time, we have to work together to achieve your real estate dreams.

Let me know if this was helpful to you, and if you have any questions, give me call! I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Handle+Lower+Offers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Handle+Lower+Offers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When you encounter an offer that is lower than asking price, it’s common to negotiate.
Do not take the low offer personally.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When you encounter an offer that is lower than asking price, it’s common to negotiate.
Do not take the low offer personally.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Take Advantage of Our Shifting Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-what-do-shifting-markets-mean-for-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Tulsa Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-25 16:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Do+Shifting+Markets+Mean+for+You%253F+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our market is shifting, but if you’re a home seller, it’s still an ideal time to put your home on the market as long as you price it correctly.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Our market is starting to shift, so what does that mean for you?

We’re at the end of the summer rush and the kids are back in school. Typically during this time of year, our market experiences a slight downturn before encountering another uptick in early fall. This is a seasonal trend that happens every year—the real estate market always works in cycles, after all.

We don’t know what’s going to happen beyond this cycle, but I do know there are buyers and sellers in the market all the time looking to make a move. I also know from years of experience that it’s always about price.

This means if you’re a seller, it’s still an ideal time to sell—you just have to price your home correctly. This will give you your best chance at attracting a buyer early on, getting the most money in your pocket, and moving onto where you want to go. Pricing right from the start is everything, and we call this “pricing ahead of the market.” When we get together and examine the numbers, we analyze what’s happened with sales in the recent past and what’s happening currently with your competition.

“REAL ESTATE IS A CONTEST—ARE YOU GOING TO WIN?”

Real estate is a contest—are you going to win? Are you going to be the No. 1 or No. 2 house buyers have to choose from in your area? Buyers buy homes that offer the most value. Do you have all the nice amenities, updates, and features that the other homes you’re competing with have? If not, you need to offset that by offering a better price.

You have only one opportunity, and that’s early on in the listing period. That’s where you’ll see the most amount of activity, and that’s when you need to capture a buyer.

Whether you’re thinking about selling or buying a house in our market, we’d love to help you out. Just give me a call or send me an email and I’d be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Do+Shifting+Markets+Mean+for+You%253F+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Do+Shifting+Markets+Mean+for+You%253F+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our market is shifting, but if you’re a home seller, it’s still an ideal time to put your home on the market as long as you price it correctly.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our market is shifting, but if you’re a home seller, it’s still an ideal time to put your home on the market as long as you price it correctly.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Shouldn't Fear the Shift in Our Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-are-we-finally-seeing-a-shift-in-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-31 15:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Are+We+Finally+Seeing+a+Shift+in+Our+Market%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As we start to see our local market trend away from the seller’s market we’ve been enjoying, it’s more important than ever to stay educated about what’s going on locally.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

We are seeing a shift in our market. I know that some people might have a little fear about that word, but we are always seeing shifts in this market throughout the year. As real estate agents, we are always prepared for these types of shifts.

Based on the last few months, we’re seeing a bit of a change in the market. You’ve heard me talk about home sales above $200,000 slowing down. Homes in the $100,000 to $200,000 price range which have been selling within days over the last few months have also seen a slowdown in sales as well.

We have put great homes on the market in the last month in the $150,000 to $185,000 price range that I thought for sure would be easy sellers, and they haven’t sold as quickly as we thought.

If you’re a consumer, just know that the market is always changing. You should always pay attention to what’s happening locally, and pay less attention to what’s happening on a national scale. There are other markets in different parts of the country that aren’t seeing the same type of shift that we’re seeing locally.

“BASED ON THE LAST FEW MONTHS, WE’RE SEEING A BIT OF A CHANGE IN THE MARKET.”

Here at the Wolek Group, we make sure to pay attention to those local trends and statistics. All the Keller Williams agents in town do their best to ensure that we’re sharing the same message to the consumers. We want to be open and honest about what’s going on, especially now that we’re starting to move away from the seller’s market we’ve been enjoying for quite awhile.

Make sure that you’re choosing an agent that is really researching the market and understands what’s going on in your neighborhood. As a final note, I wanted to assure you that homes still are selling, so don’t be afraid of the market if you’re looking to dive in. Just make sure to be educated on what’s going on.

If you have any questions or need anything at all, give me a call. I’m happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Are+We+Finally+Seeing+a+Shift+in+Our+Market%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Are+We+Finally+Seeing+a+Shift+in+Our+Market%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As we start to see our local market trend away from the seller’s market we’ve been enjoying, it’s more important than ever to stay educated about what’s going on locally.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As we start to see our local market trend away from the seller’s market we’ve been enjoying, it’s more important than ever to stay educated about what’s going on locally.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Great Day Moving Makes Moving Stress Free</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tulsa-real-estate-agent-are-you-tired-of-moving-related-stress.html</link>
        
          <category>Featured Service Providers</category>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-18 15:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Are+You+Tired+of+Moving+Related+Stress%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The moving and real estate industries have a lot in common. I recently spoke with Julie Woolslayer about some tips and tricks of the moving process.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

I was recently joined by Julie Woolslayer of Great Day Moving, who you may remember from past conversations we’ve had.

She and her husband have a great business that I’ve used personally and also that I’ve referred to multiple clients.

The moving industry is very much related to the business of real estate, so I wanted to give Julie the chance to present some tips and tricks for moving.

First of all, Julie recommends that you should always start early in the process. If you think you’re moving, decluttering will help you for a number of reasons. Not only does it prepare a home for showing but it also makes it easier on you when it comes time to move your belongings.

Get as much help as you can from friends and family members when you undertake the task of organizing and decluttering your home. One tip that Julie recommended on the matter was to read the book “It’s All Too Much” by Peter Walsh. It’s full of great tips on how to organize and get rid of items in your home.

You may even want to enlist the help of professional organizers. The bottom line is that there is a lot of help available—you just need to get motivated and get started.

“THERE IS A LOT OF HELP AVAILABLE—YOU JUST NEED TO GET MOTIVATED AND GET STARTED.”

This process is especially helpful for sellers who are downsizing. Julie and her team are more than happy to talk to people undergoing the downsizing process in order to assess what kind of help will be most useful to them. She also mentioned Settled In—a company she’s worked with in the past that helps clients decide what to take and what to leave in a move.

Julie also has a plan for people who are unable to move into their new home right away but need to move their items out of their old home.

In situations like these, Great Day Moving partners with another Tulsa business: Premier Logistics. Premier Logistics has trucks and trailers available for rent, which Great Day Moving then loads and stores at their 24-hour secured lot for as long as the seller might need.

Then, once it is time to move, Great Day Moving brings the truck on site to the new home and unloads it as they would during any other moving process.

Overall, Julie works hard to offer moving solutions. In fact, if you call and tell our scheduler Kelsey that you saw this video, you can save $75 off on any move over two hours.

If you’d like to reach out to Julie you can contact her by calling (918) 877-1971 or by visiting GreatDayMoving.com.

If I can answer any other questions or you’d like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you, soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Are+You+Tired+of+Moving+Related+Stress%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Are+You+Tired+of+Moving+Related+Stress%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The moving and real estate industries have a lot in common. I recently spoke with Julie Woolslayer about some tips and tricks of the moving process.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The moving and real estate industries have a lot in common. I recently spoke with Julie Woolslayer about some tips and tricks of the moving process.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Interested in a Career in Real Estate?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/interested-in-a-career-in-real-estate.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-15 10:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Help+Wanted+for+the+Most+Fun+Job+in+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Our workload is growing and we need our team to grow too. Are you or someone you know interested in working for a team like ours?


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

Team building is today’s hot topic because our buyer division is exploding and we need help.

I wanted to reach out to see if you know anyone who has been in the real estate business for a couple years but not finding the success they’re looking for, or they’re looking to hook up with a great team. Our buyer specialist needs help showing our houses to buyers, so we’re looking for a showing agent.

“WE’RE LOOKING TO ADD A TEAM MEMBER WHO CAN TAKE CARE OF THE FUN PART OF REAL ESTATE TRANSACTIONS.”

As a showing agent, you’ll get to do the fun part of real estate: opening doors for clients and helping them check out homes.

We’re looking to build our team with a member who has been looking to get into real estate or has their license already. If you or someone you know fits the bill, reach out to us so we can connect! We’d love your help.

Just give us a call or send us an email soon. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Help+Wanted+for+the+Most+Fun+Job+in+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/November+/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+Help+Wanted+for+the+Most+Fun+Job+in+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Our workload is growing and we need our team to grow too. Are you or someone you know interested in working for a team like ours?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Our workload is growing and we need our team to grow too. Are you or someone you know interested in working for a team like ours?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Downloaded Our Homekeepr App?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/have-you-downloaded-our-homekeepr-app.html</link>
        
        <author>The Wolek Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-23 15:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/May+17/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Word+About+Our+Homekeepr+App.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Our Homekeepr app is a must-have for homeowners. These are just a few of the features it has.


Looking to sell your Tulsa area home? Get a free home value report
Looking to buy a Tulsa area home? Click here to browse Tulsa homes for sale

If you’re a homeowner and you haven’t already, you need to download our Homekeepr app. It’s got so many different uses, but I wanted to highlight some of its best features today.

One is maintenance reminders for your home. Whether you need to have your furnace filter changed or it’s time to clean out your gutters, this app will remind you at regular intervals to do those things. There are so many things that we can forget to do around the house, but this app stays on top of things for you.

Another awesome feature is our directory. Within it, you’ll find all of our preferred service providers. These are people we have vetted, people we have worked with, and people we trust to give you fair prices and great customer service. All of their contact information is located right here within the app.

“OUR DIRECTORY IS FULL OF REPUTABLE, VETTED SERVICE PROVIDERS.”

Finally, it can be stressful trying to keep or remember where you put certain receipts, manuals, and home improvement plans. If your phone has a camera, you can just take a picture of these documents and save them right in the app. You can then access the documents from any device or desktop.

If you’re a small business owner or service provider who’s interested in being one of our partners, give us a call or send us an email today.

If you have any other questions for us or you’re looking to buy or sell in Tulsa anytime soon, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/May+17/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Word+About+Our+Homekeepr+App.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jennie+Wolek/Videos/May+17/Tulsa+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Word+About+Our+Homekeepr+App.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Our Homekeepr app is a must-have for homeowners. These are just a few of the features it has.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Wolek Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Our Homekeepr app is a must-have for homeowners. These are just a few of the features it has.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tulsa, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>The Wolek Group</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">The Wolek Group</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Keller Williams Realty Advantage - your professional Tulsa Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
