<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Orange County Real Estate Podcast with Alex Yu</title>
    <link>http://insideocrealestate.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://insideocrealestate.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional Orange County Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Alex Yu</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-10-11 10:41:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Alex Yu</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>alexyu@firstteamestates.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Alex Yu</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://insideocrealestate.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Orange County Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional Orange County Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Questions to Consider Before Moving Up</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/3-questions-to-consider-before-moving-up-copy.html</link>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-08 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/3+Questions+to+Consider+Before+Moving+Up.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Moving up is an exciting topic, but it’s also one that generates a lot of questions from homebuyers. There are three questions, in particular, we get asked most commonly, and asking yourself these questions will help you get a better idea if now’s the time for you and your family to move up. 

1. What is my current home worth? There are a lot of factors that go into this, but the majority of offers you’ll receive for your home will be using financing, which means your home will undergo an appraisal. 

Aside from knowing what your home is worth, you also need to know what makes it unique and what features make it stand out. It’s not just about how nice your home is and what other homes are selling for in the area—it’s about what other homes people can buy in your community, your city, or the surrounding cities. 

2. How do I time the move? Once you know your home’s value, you’ll know what kind of proceeds you’ll get that you can carry into your next home purchase. In this scenario, we create a net sheet for our clients to use. If you can buy without needing to sell your current home first, that makes you more attractive as a buyer because you’re not a contingent buyer. However, the downside is you may have to pay two mortgages at once for a short time. There are strategies around this scenario, such as renting out your home, that we’d be happy to discuss with you further. 

“Aside from knowing what your home is worth, you also need to know what makes it unique and what features make it stand out.”

3. What happens if I sell but I don’t find the right home to move into? On our team, we always put our buyers in a strong position, so to prevent this from happening, we only accept offers that are subject to you being able to find a suitable replacement property. If you can’t find one, you don’t have to sell. This reduces your risk all around. 

Buyers will want assurances that you’re looking for other properties, and once you’ve found the next home you’d like to purchase, that seller will want to know that your current home is on the market and is desirable. 

This can be a stressful situation, but certain life events (e.g., a new addition to your family or a job promotion) either necessitate more space or allow you to buy a bigger home. In any case, we’ve created an in-depth guide for moving up that we’d be happy to share with you if you’d like to know more about this topic. Just send me a comment with the words “move up” and I’ll send you a copy. 

If you have any other real estate questions I can answer for you, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.  
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/3+Questions+to+Consider+Before+Moving+Up.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/3+Questions+to+Consider+Before+Moving+Up.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re thinking of moving up, there are three important questions to consider.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re thinking of moving up, there are three important questions to consider.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Is Our Orange County Market Right Now?</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/how-is-our-orange-county-market-right-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-21 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/How+Is+Our+Orange+County+Market+Right+Now_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Summer is in full swing here in Orange County, and our real estate market has definitely seen some interesting changes throughout this season. Today, let’s take a look at some of the most notable developments.

For one thing, inventory is way down. This July, there were 11% fewer listings available on our market than there were during that same month last year. The number of new listings hitting our market has also slowed, with a growth of just 2% year over year this July.

“Buyers, sellers, and investors alike can enjoy the unique opportunities presented by today’s dynamic market.”

However, given that homes are still taking approximately 91 days to sell, our market remains fairly balanced. Neither buyers nor sellers have a distinct advantage. This might surprise sellers who have fallen for the myth that summer is the hottest time of year to sell, but the truth is that spring, not summer, is actually the most active season for real estate. 

Once spring passes, the rate of home sales (and the rate of new inventory coming to the market) tends to slow down. And activity drops even more significantly by the time fall arrives.  

This year, though, low interest rates have prevented our market from slowing down quite so severely as we progress further into summer. This is because demand is rising more quickly than supply, which allows our market to keep moving forward even as fall draws near. 

In short: Buyers, sellers, and investors alike can enjoy the unique opportunities presented by today’s dynamic market. Whatever your goals, we would be happy to help you meet them. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/How+Is+Our+Orange+County+Market+Right+Now_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/How+Is+Our+Orange+County+Market+Right+Now_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our Orange County market has undergone some interesting developments this summer, and we’ll review all of the most important changes in today’s market update.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our Orange County market has undergone some interesting developments this summer, and we’ll review all of the most important changes in today’s market update.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Are We Giving Back?</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/how-are-we-giving-back.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-14 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/How+Are+We+Giving+Back_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

For the past three years, our real estate team has partnered with [Organization] to source backpacks for local children, so that families without the resources to provide them on their own can still send their kids to school with all the necessary tools. 

In addition to The Purist Group, we also work closely with local law enforcement to create these opportunities year after year for our area’s youth. 

I like to think of our impact on the community as being similar to the old folk tale of the young boy throwing starfish back into the sea after a storm. In the story, thousands of starfish have been stranded on a beach. The boy throws back as many as he can, but is obviously unable to save them all. As he’s working to help the starfish, an old man approaches him and says, “You aren’t making a difference. You can’t save them all.”

“Every good deed matters.”

Throwing back another starfish into the sea, the little boy looks at the old man and says, “I made a difference to that one.”

In this same way, even knowing that we can’t help every child in America, our team is proud to know that we are making an impact at all. Every good deed matters. One local woman, a special education teacher named Karina, exemplifies this point. 

Three years ago, it was Karina who came to us with the idea of beginning our now-annual backpack drive. Fast forward to this year, and we’re about to donate 2,000 supply-filled backpacks to children in our community. Katrina’s idea has grown into something amazing, and each of us has the capacity to make a difference, just like she did. 

In our real estate business, for example, we strive to do this every day. More than just selling properties, it’s our mission to connect families with their next home. The bottom line is that there are many ways to make a difference. Even something as simple as smiling at a stranger or holding open a door for someone has a positive impact. 

If you have any other questions about today’s message, would like more information about how we can serve your real estate goals, or would like to talk about other ways to give back, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/How+Are+We+Giving+Back_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/How+Are+We+Giving+Back_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re passionate about giving back to our community, and our annual backpack drive is just one more way we do so. Let’s discuss this today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re passionate about giving back to our community, and our annual backpack drive is just one more way we do so. Let’s discuss this today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What the Looming Recession Means for Our Housing Market</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/what-the-looming-recession-means-for-our-housing-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-19 15:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/What+the+Looming+Recession+Means+for+Our+Housing+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A recession is looming, but there’s no reason to believe it will look anything like the crash of 2008.  

The stock market is close to all-time highs, unemployment is extremely low, and inflation is still seemingly in check.

And yet, this might be the last party before the crash. 

A recent Wall Street Journal poll of 73 economists found that the majority believe a recession is coming in 2020. Current homebuyers in the market echo these predictions, with 70% believing a recession will come in the next few years.

What does this mean in terms of our housing market? Nationwide, home prices continue to slow in growth. On top of that, the number of homes sales has slowed down too. This reminds me of the time between 2006 and 2008, but do we automatically think history will repeat itself? I don’t think so, and there are a couple of reasons why.

First of all, unlike in 2008, there aren’t a ton of bad mortgages out there. Back then, practically anyone could qualify for a mortgage. These days, a lot of rule changes have been implemented to protect the future of the housing market. 

“A lot of rule changes have been implemented to protect the future of the housing market.”

Second, the looming recession will not be an exception. In recessions past, the housing market as a whole wasn’t affected the way it was in 2008. In my opinion, homes that are still desirable will continue to sell—even in a recession. Homes that are overpriced, don’t have the same features as the rest of the homes, or are somewhat affected by this recession will take longer to sell. That’s just the reality of the situation. 

If you’re a home seller, this means you need to focus on your needs, goals, and circumstances. After that, examine the market environment and look toward the future to see what makes sense for you. If you’re curious what your Orange County home is worth, you can use our home value calculator right here on our website. 

If you’re thinking of buying a home and are wondering if now’s the time to do it, you need to figure out what your short-, medium-, and long-term goals are. It might be in your best interest to rent, but it’s a good idea to get a feel for the available inventory before you make a final decision.

Whether you’re looking to buy, sell, or invest, everyone’s needs are different, so if you have any more questions about our current market and how it affects you, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to speak with you and help you reach your future goals.  
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/What+the+Looming+Recession+Means+for+Our+Housing+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/What+the+Looming+Recession+Means+for+Our+Housing+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A recession is looming, but there’s no reason to believe it will look anything like the crash of 2008.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A recession is looming, but there’s no reason to believe it will look anything like the crash of 2008.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Start Your Real Estate Investment Career Off Right With These 5 Tips</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/start-your-real-estate-investment-career-off-right-with-these-5-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-15 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/Start+Your+Real+Estate+Investment+Career+Off+Right+With+These+5+Tips.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Real estate investing is hotter than ever, and it’s no wonder why. 

Mortgage rates are low, home prices continue to grow, and demand for rentals is strong.

But if you’re interested in investing in real estate, where do you start? And what do you need to know? Here are five crucial tips I’ve gathered from successful real estate investors to help you out:

1. Don’t stick to your own backyard. Many fledgling real estate investors limit their search to neighborhoods they know well. This might cut into your potential for profit. The best deals might be a bit further away, and emerging neighborhoods might offer better growth potential and tax incentives.

2. Use the 1% rule. A good rule of thumb for real estate investing is to look for properties that will offer a monthly return that is greater than 1% of the sales price. In other words, if a home costs $100,000, you should only invest in it if you expect to get at least $1,000 a month in rent.

“It pays to know the many possible tax benefits associated with real estate investing.”

3. Don’t over-rehab. An investment property doesn’t have to look like a Pinterest photo shoot. Instead of trying to convert an investment into your dream home, go with middle-of-the-road fixtures—and save yourself both time and money.

4. Look to single-family rentals. Single-family homes tend to consistently appreciate. They are also most likely to attract good tenants, and they are something you have direct experience with—and can evaluate personally. 

5. Understand the tax benefits. It pays to know the many possible tax benefits associated with real estate investing. These include deductions for depreciation, mortgage interest deductions, and maintenance, as well as the benefits that come from investing through qualified plans like self-directed IRA accounts.

Now, these five tips are valuable—but they are only a start.

If you’re seriously considering real estate investing, I’d advise you to first take a look at some of the great homes available around the Orange County area. And if this gets your investment appetite going, give me a call. There are two reasons why. 

First, I can give you my impressions about which types of homes (and in which neighborhoods) might make for a sensible first investment. 

Second, I can also point you to other professionals I personally trust—mortgage brokers, tax advisors, contractors—who can help you make that first investment profitable with the minimal amount of fuss.

If you have any other real estate questions, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/Start+Your+Real+Estate+Investment+Career+Off+Right+With+These+5+Tips.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/Start+Your+Real+Estate+Investment+Career+Off+Right+With+These+5+Tips.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re thinking of investing in real estate, I have five tips to share with you that will help you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re thinking of investing in real estate, I have five tips to share with you that will help you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Should Think About as a Buyer</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/what-you-should-think-about-as-a-buyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-20 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+What+You+Should+Think+About+as+a+Buyer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re in the market to buy a new home, I’ve got some advice for you today. Here are the top things you should take into consideration before making the plunge:

1. Location, location, location. You’ve probably heard this phrase before. When you’re looking at a new home, it’s important to know where you’re at and what school district you’re in. Even if you don’t have kids, the future resale value of your home is going to be affected by the district it’s in. Also, how close is the home to local shopping, dining, and entertainment options? These are all things to consider.

2. Financial commitment. Real estate is a long-term investment. If you want to move in a few years, you might want to consider renting instead. Having your money tied up in a home is not a great short-term investment. 

3. Running the well dry. Most buyers spend every penny that they have to get into their new home, especially first-time buyers. Even though we’ll make sure you have a home warranty for your first year, it’s important to have a home savings fund for any repairs or maintenance that happens outside of that.

“These are just five of the things that you need to consider.”

4. Loving your space. The reason that you want to love your space is that it’s not just the indoor area that you’re going to enjoy. You’re going to want to set up an entertainment area or spend a nice night in the backyard. However, if you’re busy, you might want something a little lower maintenance like a townhouse or a condo. 

5. Untapped potential. The truth is that there are a lot of different neighborhoods, but finding one that’s undergoing a renaissance is ideal. You might be able to find a home at a great price in a neighborhood that’s a little rough at the moment, but you’ll have the opportunity to be part of something great going forward as the neighborhood grows, improves, and changes.

These are just five of the things that you need to consider as a buyer. If you need help in your home search or just have any questions at all about the process, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+What+You+Should+Think+About+as+a+Buyer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+What+You+Should+Think+About+as+a+Buyer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are things that all homebuyers need to take into consideration before starting the process. Here are five of them.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are things that all homebuyers need to take into consideration before starting the process. Here are five of them.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Home Upgrades That Are Actually Worth Making</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/3-home-upgrades-that-are-actually-worth-making.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-03 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+3+Home+Upgrades+That+Are+Actually+Worth+Making.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As home buying season really kicks off, sellers are in a prime position to earn top dollar—that is, assuming they take the time to properly prepare their properties for the market. 

If you want to sell quickly and for a great price, you need to make sure your home is in the best possible shape before you list it. But not all home upgrades are worth making. 

Today I’d like to share a list of three projects that will bring a high return on your investment so that you can avoid wasting money on projects that won’t. 

1. Improve your curb appeal. A fresh coat of paint and some landscaping can go a long way. The way your home looks from the outside serves as a buyer’s first impression, after all. Updating your curb appeal tends to cost between $3,000 to $5,000—an amount you’ll more than likely earn back (and then some) because of the positive impact this upgrade has on buyers. If you need design ideas, check out local new construction properties in your area. This will help you understand current popular styles, color palettes, and more.

“If you want to sell quickly and for a great price, you need to make sure your home is in the best possible shape before you list it.”

2. Upgrade your bathrooms—but not too much. Mid-range bathroom upgrades bring about $1.71 for every $1, while high-end bathroom upgrades could actually hurt your bottom line. In other words, you need to choose your projects carefully. Adding in dual sinks, swapping out flooring, and changing out cabinets are all good upgrades to make, but make sure you don’t choose the most expensive options for each of these projects. Otherwise, your bathroom will look out of place compared to the rest of your home. 

3. Install new windows. Mid-range, energy-efficient windows can bring you $1.15 return for every $1 spent. Not only do these new windows look nice, but they will also help your home’s new owner save money on their energy bills. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me or my team a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+3+Home+Upgrades+That+Are+Actually+Worth+Making.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+3+Home+Upgrades+That+Are+Actually+Worth+Making.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Not all upgrades are good upgrades, and today I’d like to explain what I mean by this.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Not all upgrades are good upgrades, and today I’d like to explain what I mean by this.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Homeownership the Key to Your Financial Future?</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/is-homeownership-the-key-to-your-financial-future.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-20 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Is+Homeownership+the+Key+to+Your+Financial+Future_+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

First-time homebuyers often focus on two things: the price of a home and the monthly payment they’ll be bound to after purchasing it. This is quite understandable. However, there’s one more thing you need to consider when buying a house: the future value of the property.

In a nutshell, appreciation, or the increase in prices over time, is how a majority of wealth is built in real estate. That’s why homeownership is a great, stable, long-term investment.

There are ultimately two ways to take advantage of your home’s equity: actively and passively.

“Homeownership has traditionally been one of the most stable opportunities to build wealth.”

By paying off a mortgage during your working years, you actively eliminate a big expense from your plate during your retirement years. 

What’s more is that if you’re not great about having a savings plan, owning a home is a great opportunity to passively create a financial cushion that renting can’t. If you start when you’re young, it gives you a longer opportunity to create wealth.

Now, owning a home doesn’t necessarily guarantee that you can have a greater net worth, but homeownership has traditionally been one of the most stable opportunities to build wealth. Obviously, real estate values do fluctuate over time, but it’s still a great vehicle for stable growth for many people. It gives you an opportunity (and a structure) to build wealth.  After all, a home isn’t just four walls that provide you shelter—it’s a place for you to grow.

If you’re interested in buying, selling, or investing in real estate, feel free to reach out to me. We’re here to help you make the right moves every step of the way. I hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Is+Homeownership+the+Key+to+Your+Financial+Future_+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Is+Homeownership+the+Key+to+Your+Financial+Future_+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is homeownership the best way to secure your financial future? Today I’ll discuss my thoughts on the topic.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is homeownership the best way to secure your financial future? Today I’ll discuss my thoughts on the topic.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s There to Love (and Hate) About Buying in Spring?</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/whats-there-to-love-and-hate-about-buying-in-spring.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-28 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Whats+There+to+Love+(and+Hate)+About+Buying+in+Spring_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Spring is here, and if you’re a buyer, there are plenty of things to love about buying a home right now. However, there are also a few things to hate about the spring buying season.

I recently came across an article from Realtor.com that outlines all the major positives and negatives you need to be aware of before taking the plunge. To read the full article, click here. 

In the meantime, here are some of the main points to take away from it.

Things you’ll love:


  Increased inventory. There are more homes to choose from, so you need to focus your time effectively and distinguish between areas you love and areas that are less desirable. 
  More open houses. As more and more homes hit the market, there are more and more open houses taking place that give you a great opportunity to match what you see online with what you see in person and size up the competition from other buyers. As always, use your time effectively when sightseeing open houses.


“You need to focus your time effectively and distinguish between areas you love and areas that are less desirable.”

Things you’ll hate: 


  More competition. This means you need to fine-tune what you’re looking for and make your choices quicker. In an active market, new listings don’t even make it to their first open house before they’re snatched up. 


 


  Time-related pressure. Like I said above, you’ll have to make decisions quicker in this market. If you have to sleep on it, odds are, you won’t get to sleep in it. Doing as much prep work up front as possible while working with an agent who has their finger on the pulse of the market will help tremendously in this regard. 


 


  Increased prices. It all boils down to supply and demand. If there’s a lot of demand and many different buyers vying for the same homes, prices will go up. 


If you have any questions about buying in the spring or you have any other real estate needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Whats+There+to+Love+(and+Hate)+About+Buying+in+Spring_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Whats+There+to+Love+(and+Hate)+About+Buying+in+Spring_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As a buyer, there are plenty of things to love about the spring market, but there are also a few things to hate.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As a buyer, there are plenty of things to love about the spring market, but there are also a few things to hate.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Developments in the Orange County Market</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/the-latest-developments-in-the-orange-county-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-19 11:40:06 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+The+Latest+Developments+in+the+Orange+County+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

With the onset of Daylight Saving Time, the times have changed, and so has the spring market.

There are currently 44% more homes on the market than there were last year at this same time, increasing from 4,420 to over 6,000 homes. Overall, demand for housing has picked up, rising 91%.

A big portion of that increase can be attributed to our interest rates, which are directly entangled with housing demand in the market. Interest rates peaked during the worst time in 2018—right around the holidays, rates hit 5.05%. As of this video recording, rates are only at 4.45%.

What does this mean for you?

For buyers, it means you have 10% more buying power than you did just four months ago.

“Our current market is different from previous years, but that also means there are different opportunities to take advantage of.”

For sellers, it means that your home is a little more marketable and, more importantly, more affordable to potential buyers at the same time.

We can’t say for sure what will happen this year, but we do expect that market times will continue to decrease as spring approaches and that inventory will continue to grow. The current average days on market is 140 days, which means we’re in a different market entirely compared to last year.

In past years, there was a quick run-up of multiple offers on every home, but these days, you’ll need to be a little bit more selective: Market aggressively, but also be sure to price your home in a way that will get the most attention from buyers in the shortest amount of time.

No matter if you’re looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate this year, feel free to reach out to us. We’d be happy to provide you with all the information you need to make the right moves.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+The+Latest+Developments+in+the+Orange+County+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+The+Latest+Developments+in+the+Orange+County+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s going on in our current market? Find out in today’s update.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s going on in our current market? Find out in today’s update.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Hot (and What’s Not) In Home Design This Year?</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/whats-hot-and-whats-not-in-home-design-this-year.html</link>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-21 15:54:38 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Whats+Hot+(and+Whats+Not)+In+Home+Design+This+Year_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

One thing we’re noticing in the world of real estate design trends is that there’s a shift occurring. Modern styles are becoming more popular where rustic was once en vogue. For colors, blacks, mattes, and grays are wending their way into the forefront of the market.

Even though modern styles are resurging in popularity, that doesn’t mean that rustic designs will disappear altogether. Instead, the two styles will meld together. Rustic chic will incorporate more modern colors, as well as asymmetry.

We’re also noting a focus on effortlessness in regards to technology these days. Products like Google Home, Amazon’s Alexa, and Apple’s HomePod will undoubtedly impact home design. The way that we’re experiencing our homes is different in today’s world, and it’s helping us modernize and automate our lives just with the sound of our voice.

It’s expected that we’ll see a continuation of the industrial focus in home design, with matte black and bronze really complementing the industrial look. Colors like grays and moody blues will continue to demand top dollar in the market when you’re selling your home or setting it up as a vacation rental.

HGTV’s popular show “Fixer Upper” really ushered in the farmhouse chic look. However, one thing we’ve seen is that the farmhouse door made with reclaimed wood (popularized by the show) is giving way to the same farmhouse barn door, though refined with a modern appeal—you can expect wood that’s been more squared out, as well as more glass and metal accents.

“Colors like grays and moody blues will continue to demand top dollar in the market when you’re selling your home or setting it up as a vacation rental.”

Bold, trendy colors like ‘millennial pink’ that were all the rage a couple years ago are slowly moving out, making room for more earthy tones and other colors that can appeal to a wider audience, from light gray to matte black. Whether or not they inspire you personally, these are the colors that will help people stand out in multiple markets. When you’re thinking of selling your home, you need to show it at the very top of your game, which means appealing to a broad audience.

If you have any questions about this or are thinking of selling your home, reach out to us. We’ll do a first-time walkthrough of your home and give you some ideas of things you can do to really make your home pop so that buyers will be drawn to it. I hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Whats+Hot+(and+Whats+Not)+In+Home+Design+This+Year_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Whats+Hot+(and+Whats+Not)+In+Home+Design+This+Year_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What real estate design trends are on their way in, and which ones are on their way out? Find out today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What real estate design trends are on their way in, and which ones are on their way out? Find out today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Buying a Remodeled Home</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/5-tips-for-buying-a-remodeled-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-04 09:11:45 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+5+Tips+for+Buying+a+Remodeled+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When it comes to buying a remodeled home, there’s usually more to it than meets the eye. Here are five tips to help you avoid buying a remodeled home that might be more than what you bargained for:

1. Make sure all of the major systems work. Having new floors and counters is great, but if you have to replace the home’s heating system or electrical system, that might cost you more than the remodel itself.

2. Make sure the kitchen doesn’t disappoint. A good way to make sure the builder didn’t cut corners in this area is to double check that the backsplash is even.

3. Make sure there was attention to detail in the bathrooms. If they remodeled the bathrooms, you need to make sure they invested heavily in them—not only with high-end tile, but also with new supply valves, shut-off valves, trim rings, etc. This will tell you whether they finished the job or not.

4. Make sure the home is on even footing. Poorly installed laminate or hardwood can buckle and pop over time. A good way to know if your floors are even is to kick off your shoes, slide across them, and see if you catch any corners (think of Tom Cruise in “Risky Business”).

5. Make sure they took pride in the work they did. A good way to do this is to check the molding in the corners and frames of each room.

“Having new floors and counters is great, but if you have to replace the home’s heating system or electrical system, that might cost you more than the remodel itself.”

As a Realtor, I’ve seen just as many terrible remodels as I’ve seen great ones, so if you have any more questions about how to tell if a remodeled home you’re thinking of buying is a good investment, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+5+Tips+for+Buying+a+Remodeled+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+5+Tips+for+Buying+a+Remodeled+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How do you know if the remodeled home you’re thinking of buying is a winner? By following these five tips.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How do you know if the remodeled home you’re thinking of buying is a winner? By following these five tips.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Much Should Home Repairs Really Cost You?</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/how-much-should-home-repairs-really-cost-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Repairs</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-17 12:13:56 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+How+Much+Should+Home+Repairs+Really+Cost+You_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I recently read an article in The New York Times titled, “Why Do All Home Repairs Cost $1,000?” The author was complaining that it didn’t matter much what went wrong at home—be it a leaky faucet, broken garage door, or failed water heater. In each case, the bill came out to at least $1,000. 

Most homeowners underestimate the costs of various home repairs, often by as much as four times the actual cost. Can anything be done about this? Here are three recommendations to help you deal with home repair costs:

1. Save for a rainy day and create a special account for repairs. The average homeowner spends $2,000 a year on maintenance. As a homeowner myself, I have a tax fund, a “happy fun day” fund, and a rainy day fund. When you use the rainy day fund to pay for your repairs, you’ll be in a much better financial position. 

“Sometimes it can make sense to look for a new home that won’t require frequent repairs.”

2. Enjoy being a homeowner. $50 in parts and a YouTube tutorial or a Google search will be enough to repair most home maintenance issues, so try focusing on the smaller, simpler fixes yourself and delegate the more complicated ones to the professionals. 

3. Negotiate smart. This means getting multiple quotes from different professionals so that you get the best price. Also, don’t pre-frame the cost of a repair. A lot of contractors will agree to do something for $1,000 if you assume it costs that much, but not everything does, so don’t automatically pay them $1,000 for a job that doesn’t cost nearly that much. 

Of course, if you reach a certain point where you’re constantly needing things fixed, it might just make more sense to look for a new home that won’t require frequent repairs.  

If you’re considering buying or selling a home or if you need recommendations for contractors to fix those things you don’t want to deal with yourself, give me a call or send me an email today. I can recommend several reliable businesses and I’m always here to help. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+How+Much+Should+Home+Repairs+Really+Cost+You_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+How+Much+Should+Home+Repairs+Really+Cost+You_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Nobody likes dealing with expensive home repairs. Here are a few tips to help you make that process easier.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Nobody likes dealing with expensive home repairs. Here are a few tips to help you make that process easier.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Year-End Market Update</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/year-end-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-26 13:20:06 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Year-End+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’ll be going over our latest market numbers, as well as recap what we’ve seen throughout the year.

2018 had an incredible start with a limited amount of inventory, record-breaking prices, and multiple-offer situations for nearly every property sold.

This is a stark contrast to today.

Currently, homes spend an average of 127 days on market—the longest since the recession we saw in December 2010. Though our market has definitely shifted, it’s a normal shift for it to go through.

Interest rates peaked on November 7 at 5.05%, but have since lowered to 4.74% as of December 15. This means buyers have more buying power and the demand for homes should increase.

“Though our market has definitely shifted, it’s a normal shift.”

Inventory is up 59% from this time last year. Sellers need to ensure their homes are in top shape for showings and are priced competitively.

Buyers, you have a lot of options right now, and you also have the room to negotiate a good price on a home.

Whether you’re looking to buy or sell a home, have any questions, or need more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Year-End+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Year-End+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our year-end market is completely different from what we saw in the beginning of 2018.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our year-end market is completely different from what we saw in the beginning of 2018.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Foreclosed Properties</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-foreclosed-properties.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-29 13:57:35 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Foreclosed+Properties.mp4</guid>
        <description>

One thing that some people don’t know about me is that I actually worked for the REO Division at JPMorgan Chase. ‘REO’ means ‘real estate owned’; we dealt with the bank-owned foreclosed properties. Since then, I’ve been able to help a number of clients successfully purchase foreclosed homes. 

Sometimes, however, foreclosed homes are more than people bargain for.

Every foreclosed home is sold in as-is condition, meaning that no repairs will be done. This is why it’s very important to have a thorough and effective property inspector go through all the major systems, including the plumbing, electric, water, and HVAC systems. These are all things that could end up costing a lot of money to repair if they’re not in good shape. Additionally, don’t forget that California is termite country, so be sure to have pest control come through to look for signs of potential infestations.

When a home is foreclosed upon, sometimes there are unpaid contractor liens, homeowner association dues, and tax liens on the property. These are all things that will come up on the title report, so it’s a good idea to review that to be sure there aren’t any nasty surprises.

It should come as no surprise that when a home is foreclosed, the seller may not have left on the best of terms. Sometimes, fixtures have been removed or there are other damages on the property. I once purchased a foreclosed property myself; all the toilets removed, door handles were missing, windows were broken, and there were holes in the walls. It’s wise to go into a foreclosure home purchase understanding that these types of things are typical.

“It should come as no surprise that when a home is foreclosed, the seller may not have left on the best of terms.”

Because these homes have often been vacant for a long time, it’s also smart to get a home warranty. That will protect you for all the major systems in the home, and it offsets some of the costs you might be incurring when you buy one of these properties.

In the previous downturn of the market, foreclosed homes were plentiful and often ignored. However, in our current market, there are investors that are specifically looking for these types of properties. This can lead to frenzied bidding wars that raise the price up to market value. Be sure to review all other relevant sales in the area that are comparable in neighborhood and in the content of the property.

The bottom line is that there’s definitely an opportunity to get a value when purchasing foreclosed homes if you’re educated and have someone on your side who knows the ins and outs of what to expect. I purchased a home at $45,000 below market value, after which, I invested about $30,000 in upgrades. Recently, we closed on a home that was worth $800,000 for the neighborhood, but we got it for $750,000.

If you do your homework and then create and execute a smart plan for pursuing a foreclosed home, you can definitely be successful.

If you have any questions about foreclosed properties, you are encouraged to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Foreclosed+Properties.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Foreclosed+Properties.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>For today’s topic, I’ll be discussing a few things you need to know about purchasing foreclosed homes.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>For today’s topic, I’ll be discussing a few things you need to know about purchasing foreclosed homes.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Not to Do: A Lesson From Bad Real Estate Photos</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/what-not-to-do-a-lesson-from-bad-real-estate-photos.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-06 16:51:51 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Bad+MLS+Photos.mp4</guid>
        <description>

To fully understand what I mean for today’s topic of bad real estate photos, follow along in the video above, or use the timestamps I’ve provided below to navigate the video at your leisure:


  0:20—Distracting colors on the walls. Lurid wallpaper or paint can make a room look even smaller. To counter that effect, use lighter, more neutral colors.
  0:50—Mirrors above the bed. This look reminds me of the first time that I went to the Tropicana Hotel; I’d recommend something more neutral and less reminiscent of Las Vegas.
  1:20—Upside down photos. I was initially very confused about this photo; how and why did the homeowner manage to install an elevated washing machine? Then I realize they had uploaded the photo to the MLS upside down. You only get one chance to make a first impression, so double-check your photos before making this mistake.
  1:45—This photo looks like every horror movie I’ve ever seen was filmed here. To make it less creepy, I’d move the sparing items on the right and showcase the floor to brighten it up.
  2:20—Carpet in the bathroom. Alone, carpet in the bathroom is a turn-off for buyers, but this photo really takes it over the top: They not only have a toilet, but also a bidet and a sitting chair all in the same bathroom. This photo should have focused on the countertops and less on the urinal in the middle of the room.
  2:50—A woodsy, surf-and-turf disaster. Instead of focusing on the mounted deer head, marlin, and monkey, the photographer should have focused on the room, instead of the just the corner in which this odd arrangement of mounts. If taken from a different angle, the photo could have shown off the room’s size or flow and helped a potential buyer appreciate the space more.


“Alone, carpet in the bathroom is a turn-off for buyers, but this photo really takes it over the top: They not only have a toilet, but also a bidet and a sitting chair all in the same bathroom.”

I always tell my sellers that you should always want to make sure the home speaks to as many buyers as possible. The sound of one tree falling is always going to be louder than a thousand trees growing, so eliminate those things that may turn people off and focus on things that will appeal to more people.

If you have any questions on home staging or about how to make your home appeal to a wider audience, please feel free to reach out to me.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Bad+MLS+Photos.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Bad+MLS+Photos.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to show you and talk about some simply bad real estate photos we’ve come across in our time, as well as give you some advice about how to take awesome home photos for your listing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to show you and talk about some simply bad real estate photos we’ve come across in our time, as well as give you some advice about how to take awesome home photos for your listing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Are Now a Team Kids Community Partner</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/we-are-now-a-team-kids-community-partner.html</link>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-23 11:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Team+Kids.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Julie Hudash started Team Kids 18 years ago in part because of her own children. She wanted them to have the opportunity to know that they were powerful, to understand that the community was counting on them, and to be exposed to critical issues in the community. She started the organization to let all children learn that they’re strong enough to make a difference in the world.

Since its founding right before September 11, 2001, Team Kids has accomplished a lot. Julie’s proudest achievement in that time has been orchestrating the Team Kids Challenge Program, a month-long early-intervention program run in public elementary schools by both staff and trained police and firefighters. They spend the duration of the program learning about homelessness, hunger, kids with terminal diseases, and how to support our troops. The program is run in Orange County, Los Angeles, and Arlington, VA; just this spring, they launched the program in New York City.

Julie is proud to mobilize our youngest citizens to become change-makers, to connect with social issues, and to create a country that truly invests in our kids and puts our resources where our words are.

“Julie started the organization to let all children learn that they’re strong enough to make a difference in the world.”

We have recently partnered with Team Kids to develop a new program here in Orange County: The Superhero Program. Modeled after the Team Kids Challenge Program, the Superhero Program serves to involve children with their communities to create a positive impact by learning how to support their heroes, the hungry, the homeless, and those who have undergone tragedy. With each project, they earn stickers and are eventually launched as superheroes to address key issues.

If you’d like to learn more about the Team Kids organization and see what they’re doing to create change in their communities, visit www.TeamKids.org and follow them on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter.

If you think your children would be interested in participating and becoming superheroes themselves, or if you have general questions for me about real estate, please feel free to reach out to me. I hope to hear from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Team+Kids.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Team+Kids.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’m here with the founder and CEO of Team Kids, Julie Hudash, to talk about the organization and all of the amazing things they do.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’m here with the founder and CEO of Team Kids, Julie Hudash, to talk about the organization and all of the amazing things they do.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stay in the Loop With Your Mortgage Lender by Asking These Questions</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/stay-in-the-loop-with-your-mortgage-lender-by-asking-these-questions.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-03 11:30:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Stay+in+the+Loop+With+Your+Mortgage+Lender+by+Asking+These+Questions.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What questions should you be asking your mortgage lender? Today I’ll discuss eight of them.

1. “What type of loan is best?” This depends on your scenario—how long you plan to own the property, if it’s a primary residence you plan to live in for a long time or if you plan to rent it out at some point.

2. “What is the interest rate and annual percentage rate (APR)?” The interest rate is the rate the loan is at, but once you include the cost of obtaining, that is how you get the APR. It’s a better indicator of the overall costs.

3. “What are discount fees and origination points?” This is a percentage of the loan amount, and its often between a quarter of a percent and 1%, depending on the loan amount you obtain. In a way, it’s prepaid interest to buy down your interest rate. It’s also another expense related to your loan, so review it accordingly.

4. “What are all the costs?” There are discount points of origination fees, application fees, appraisal fees, and others besides the costs of general homeownership. Be sure to ask for a detailed list of fees so you can review them and plan accordingly.

“It’s a better experience when they can approve the loan in-house because it’s much faster; they can walk over to an underwriter to review the loan directly at that time.”

5. “What is a loan estimate?” This is a breakdown of all the expenses related to obtaining the loan.

6. “Do you offer rate locks?” Sometimes you can obtain a rate and your lender can lock it for a period of 30 days, which is the average escrow timeline to close. However, they’ll also sometimes float the rate, meaning they can’t lock it until it’s been approaved. This means that if the interest rates go up during that time, you’re at risk.

7. “Do you offer in-house loan approval?” It’s a better experience when they can approve the loan in-house because it’s much faster; they can walk over to an underwriter to review the loan directly at that time.

8. “How long is it going to take to fund the loan?” This is important especially in the case in which you’re purchasing a house and you only have 30 days to accomplish the transaction. If you’re just refinancing and looking to reduce your payments, 60 days is the average time. You will want to review this with your lender to make sure.

If you have any further questions about loans, please feel free to reach out to us. We have access to some of the best loan specialists to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Stay+in+the+Loop+With+Your+Mortgage+Lender+by+Asking+These+Questions.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Stay+in+the+Loop+With+Your+Mortgage+Lender+by+Asking+These+Questions.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Many people don’t really know what to ask their mortgage lender when they’re applying for a loan. Today I’ll cover eight questions you should be asking in order to be sure you’re on top of the process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Many people don’t really know what to ask their mortgage lender when they’re applying for a loan. Today I’ll cover eight questions you should be asking in order to be sure you’re on top of the process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know Before Buying a Home Security System</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/what-you-need-to-know-before-buying-a-home-security-system.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-17 15:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Security+Systems.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Having a home security system comes with both benefits and drawbacks, and if you’re thinking of getting one for yourself and your family, there are a few facts you should know before making a decision. 

A study by HomeFacts found that just having a theft deterrent was beneficial, but one of the main reasons homeowners decide against getting a home security system is the cost involved—there’s usually an upfront setup fee and ongoing maintenance costs. Between these two expenses, the overall cost of a home security system can vary widely. 

“The average home break-in costs $1,725”

Having a home security system should go beyond providing peace of mind and also make sense in terms of dollars and cents. An FBI study found that the average home break-in costs $1,725 in terms of stolen valuables and damage. Another study also found that one in four homes is likely to be broken into. 

These days, there are plenty of programs that are less expensive relative to the amount of monitoring you get in return. You can also purchase an ongoing monitoring system so that when a door or window is open, the police are automatically notified. It’s all a matter of deciding which option is best for you.

If you’re curious about the best kinds of home security systems out there or you have any other questions about this topic, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Security+Systems.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Security+Systems.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are many different home security options you can choose from. It’s all a matter of deciding which one is best for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are many different home security options you can choose from. It’s all a matter of deciding which one is best for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Market Crash May Not Be on the Horizon After All</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/a-market-crash-may-not-be-on-the-horizon-after-all.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-04 11:19:55 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Is+There+An+Impending+Crash%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Is there a housing crash on the horizon? We don’t think so, and there are eight key reasons behind our perspective: 

“Right now, loans are of higher quality than they have been since before the last crash.”


  The state of subprime loans. Before the crash in 2008, subprime loans constituted $620 billion and made up 20% of the total mortgage market. Today subprime loans account for just $56 billion (5%) of the total mortgage market. Right now, loans are of higher quality than they have been since before the last crash. 
  Credit scores have increased. Over the last 15 years, FICO scores have been steadily rising. In 2009, the average credit score for borrowers seeking a loan was 686. In 2001, it dropped down to between 490 and 510. Since then, though, we’ve seen significant improvements. 
  Lending is far more strict. CoreLogic’s Housing Credit Index reports that loans originated in 2016 were of higher quality than any filed in the last 15 years. Tightened lending standards have reduced the impact of fix-and-flip investors. Currently, lenders only finance 55% of home value in the “flip” market. This is a major shift from the 80% or more banks lent out during the subprime crisis. 
  The number of homes sold right now is 20% below the pre-crash peak. Right now, there’s less than two months’ worth of available inventory in Orange County. 
  Young people are having to save more money due to the past recession. As a result of this, homebuyers are submitting larger down payments in recent times, which provides an additional level of security in their real estate investment. 
  Total home equity is still significantly lower than in 2006. Instead of an explosion of home values, recent growth has been steady. There was $85 billion in equity in 2006, and today there is about $14 billion. 
  Home prices today make sense if you factor in inflation. Between 2012 and 2017, home prices have risen 6.5% per year on average, and surpassed their 2006 peak as a result. However, these increased prices actually indicate an adjustment for the 11 years of inflation we’ve seen.
  Home builders are focusing on high-end properties. This is likely due to changes in demand, but the question of whether demand is stronger today than in the past is one no one can definitively answer. 


The bottom line is this: No one has a crystal ball, but looking to recent market data and forming an educated perspective based on that information can help you gain a general sense of where things may be headed. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Is+There+An+Impending+Crash%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Is+There+An+Impending+Crash%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Though some predict that we’re headed for a crash, there are eight key points that may indicate otherwise.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Though some predict that we’re headed for a crash, there are eight key points that may indicate otherwise.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Everything Buyers Should Know About Earnest Money</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/everything-buyers-should-know-about-earnest-money.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-16 15:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Earnest+Money.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Earnest money deposits are a crucial component of any real estate deal. This sum shows sellers how serious you are about purchasing their home, so today let’s discuss a few of the most common, and most crucial, questions people have on this subject:

What is an appropriate amount to offer when submitting an earnest money deposit?

On average, a good earnest money deposit should be between 1% and 3% of the total purchase price. This will, however, depend on your area. 

“If a real estate deal proceeds without issue, the earnest deposit will be applied toward your down payment or closing costs.”

When is the earnest money deposit due? 

As a general rule, earnest money must be submitted within three days from the time you sign the purchase agreement. 

Where does the earnest money deposit go after it’s been submitted?

Earnest money deposits will be held by the bank in a third-party escrow account until closing.

How do you get the earnest money deposit back?

When you sign a purchase agreement, certain contingencies will protect you against losing out on this deposit. So long as you don’t violate the terms of the contract, the earnest money deposit can be refunded to you if you withdraw from the deal within the due diligence period. If the deal proceeds without issue, the deposit will be applied toward your down payment or closing costs. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Earnest+Money.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Earnest+Money.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is an earnest money deposit, and why is it such an integral part of any real estate deal? Today, we’ll examine the answers to these and other questions.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is an earnest money deposit, and why is it such an integral part of any real estate deal? Today, we’ll examine the answers to these and other questions.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Avoid These 7 Deadly Sins When Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/avoid-these-7-deadly-sins-when-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-26 13:17:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+7+Things+Holding+Up+Your+Home+Sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do you know about the seven deadly sins of selling a home? Today I am going to share them with you, so that you can avoid them and sell your property for top dollar, instead. 

1. An unkempt yard. Many people think that it’s what’s on the inside that matters. But if your home looks like a tornado blew through the yard, potential buyers may never actually get inside.

2. Keys that do not work. If the potential buyer and their agent cannot get in, they may become frustrated by the experience.

“If a room has excessive or poorly arranged furniture, it may appear less spacious than it actually is.”

3. Dingy or faded front door. The front door will serve as a buyer’s first impression, so make sure it’s in great shape before they arrive. 

4. Animals. I love animals, and I think that most people do, too. However, it’s important to clean up after them by eliminating messes, hair, and odor before buyers enter your home.

5. Furniture arrangement. If a room has excessive or poorly arranged furniture, it may appear less spacious than it actually is. Buyers will have a very difficult time looking past ineffective staging. 

6. Junk drawers and packed cabinets. Overly full storage areas will reflect poorly on your home. 

7. Cluttered countertops. Showcasing your counter space is critical, so make sure to remove all unnecessary items before buyers tour your property. 

If you have any additional questions or are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+7+Things+Holding+Up+Your+Home+Sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+7+Things+Holding+Up+Your+Home+Sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are seven deadly sins to avoid when selling your home. I will list each of them for you, today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are seven deadly sins to avoid when selling your home. I will list each of them for you, today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8 Maintenance Tips to Keep Your Home Running Smoothly This Summer</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/8-maintenance-tips-to-keep-your-home-running-smoothly-this-summer.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-02 15:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Summer+Maintenance.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are eight tips that will help you keep your home well-maintained over the course of the summer: 

1. Double-check that all your carbon monoxide and smoke detectors work. You can never be too safe, so instead of assuming your carbon monoxide and smoke detectors are working, double-check just to make sure. The summer is a great time to do this. 

2. Change the filter in your air conditioner every 30 days. Changing them every 30 days will increase your air conditioner’s efficiency and lengthen its lifespan. 

3. Keep your ceiling fans dust-free. Otherwise, they’re just swirling dust around inside your house. 

“These tips will keep your home in tiptop shape over the summer.”

4. Use a clothesline instead of your dryer. This will not only help you save energy, but it will also keep your clothes smelling summer-fresh all week long. 

5. Get your grill on. Clean your grill at the beginning of summer so you can grill all summer long. 

6. Let the sunlight in. Longer summer days mean longer sunlight, so clean your windows and enjoy the warm, ambient light for as long as you can. 

7. Check for leaky faucets. We’re not in a drought anymore, but it’s still a good idea to check that you’re not wasting any water. Leaks can also cause damage to your home that you won’t even notice until later on when it’s much more costly. 

8. Stop dirt at the door. Keep dirt out of your house by using a coarse doormat on the outside of your entryway and a soft doormat on the inside.

If you have any other questions about how to keep your home well-maintained over the summer or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Summer+Maintenance.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Summer+Maintenance.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to keep your home clean and running smoothly this summer, I have eight maintenance tips to share with you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to keep your home clean and running smoothly this summer, I have eight maintenance tips to share with you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Trust Zestimates?</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/should-you-trust-zestimates.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-08 14:27:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Zestimates.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Should you trust Zillow’s Zestimate tool? The short answer is no, but today I will explain why. A lot of people go to Zillow for real estate information. The website has home evaluations called Zestimates and, while this feature is a good barometer for general information, the truth is that Zestimates cannot account for certain key differences between homes. Zestimates do not take home upgrades, for example, into consideration. They also don’t factor in what kind of views you have from your home. 

“All homes are different and Zillow’s Zestimate feature does not account for the differences.” It really takes a professional to go through all of a home’s features and compare it to what is going on in the market, what has sold, and more importantly, what is going to be on the market - because the market is constantly changing. At the end of the day, what you need is an “exactimate” which you can only get from a licensed real estate professional such as myself. If you want more information about this or are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to reach out to me by phone, email, or through my website. I look forward to getting you the right value for your home soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Zestimates.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+Zestimates.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Zillow’s Zestimates may be an easy tool to use, but it may not provide the information you need to find a proper value for your home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Zillow’s Zestimates may be an easy tool to use, but it may not provide the information you need to find a proper value for your home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Orange County Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <link>http://insideocrealestate.com/a-quick-orange-county-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>MarketUpdate</category>
        
        <author>Alex Yu</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-25 14:43:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+5-23+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re going to talk a little bit about the current real estate market in Orange County. 

The active listing inventory has increased by 296 homes and is up by 5%. Even though inventory is growing, there is still a lot of pent-up demand. That’s keeping us in a seller’s market. 

Over the past month, the interest rates have been going up by about 0.75% to 1%. Overall, the amount that homeowners can afford is less than it was before. The prices may be affected slightly because of this. 

If you’re a home seller, this means that the amount that buyers can qualify for is a little less. Your ability to price your home higher than last year may be capped slightly.

“Interest rates have gone up nearly 1% over the past month.”

If you’re a homebuyer purchasing with cash, these interest rate changes mean nothing to you. However, if you’re financing a home purchase, it’s a good idea to get your pre-qualification updated to make sure you know exactly what you can afford in the current market.

If you have any questions about buying or selling a home in Orange County or about the real estate market in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+5-23+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://insideocrealestate.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Alex+Yu/2018/Orange+County+Real+Estate-+5-23+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The latest news and information is in for the Orange County real estate market. Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Alex Yu</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The latest news and information is in for the Orange County real estate market. Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orange County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Alex Yu</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Alex Yu</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional Orange County Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
