<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Memphis Real Estate Podcast with Melissa Thompson</title>
    <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.weknowmemphis.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Your Key To Memphis - your professional Memphis Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Melissa Thompson</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-07-23 12:31:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Melissa Thompson</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Melissa@YourKeyToMemphis.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Melissa Thompson</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://www.weknowmemphis.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Memphis Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Your Key To Memphis - your professional Memphis Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Real Estate Terms You Should Know</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/3-real-estate-terms-you-should-know.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-19 11:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/July/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Real+Estate+Terms+You+Should+Know.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to explain a few different real estate terms in detail. Oftentimes, we use a lot of shorthand or abbreviated words without realizing it, and I wanted to make sure you’re clear on what some of these terms mean when you hear them come up in conversation.

1. Comps. This is short for “comparables.” It’s just a word that we use to refer to homes that are comparable to yours when we’re getting ready to buy or sell a home. They help us know whether or not a home’s value is in the right range.

“PMI is required for homebuyers that are putting down less than 20% on their home purchase.”

2. PMI. This stands for private mortgage insurance. It’s required for homebuyers that are putting down less than 20% on their home purchase. This insurance insures the lender, but it doesn’t have to last forever. Once you have 20% equity in your home, you can get a re-appraisal and get it removed.

3. Closing costs. They refer to all the additional fees it takes to finalize a home closing. They include things like escrow fees, lender fees, and attorney fees. It doesn’t include inspection costs.

Those are just a few terms that I wanted to make sure you were aware of. If you have any questions about the Memphis real estate market or anything else, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/July/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Real+Estate+Terms+You+Should+Know.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/July/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Real+Estate+Terms+You+Should+Know.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you know what “comps” or “closing costs” are? If you don’t, you will after reading this.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you know what “comps” or “closing costs” are? If you don’t, you will after reading this.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Things You Should Not Compromise on as a Buyer</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/5-things-you-should-not-compromise-on-as-a-buyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-05 11:23:13 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/July/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Things+You+Should+Not+Compromise+on+as+a+Buyer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to talk about five things that you should never compromise on as a buyer:

1. The floor plan. Make sure that it fits your needs now and in the future.

2. The school district. Even if your kids are out of the house, this matters for resale value.  You can find out about the different municipalities online to see what school system the home you are looking at is in.

“It is important not to overextend yourself financially.”

3. The neighbors. If you are interested in a house in a neighborhood you are unfamiliar with, drive around during different times during the day to make sure you will be happy and comfortable there.

4. Your budget. It is important not to overextend yourself financially. You want to be comfortable with what you are buying.

5. The commute. Maybe take a test drive of the commute before you decide to pull the trigger. This is another important factor.

If you have any questions for me or you are interested in buying or selling a home here in Memphis, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/July/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Things+You+Should+Not+Compromise+on+as+a+Buyer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/July/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Things+You+Should+Not+Compromise+on+as+a+Buyer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Homebuyers will always have to make certain compromises because no home is perfect. However, here are five things that you should not budge on if you are purchasing a home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Homebuyers will always have to make certain compromises because no home is perfect. However, here are five things that you should not budge on if you are purchasing a home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6 Ways to Compete Against Cash Buyers and Win Your Dream Home</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/6-ways-to-compete-against-cash-buyers-and-win-your-dream-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-08 09:38:56 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/June/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+6+Ways+to+Compete+Against+Cash+Buyers+and+Win+Your+Dream+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do you make a competitive offer when you are going against cash buyers? While a lot of the market is not paying cash, there are some people who are. You’re not out of luck, though. I have a few options for you that will help you be competitive and win your dream home.

1. Provide a level of comfort to the seller. If you are comfortable with it, show them your bank statements and credit scores to prove that you have your finances in order. They will know you have quite a bit of cash if you are putting 20% down on a loan.

2. Consider not doing an inspection. You always have the right to an inspection. But, if you are comfortable with not doing an inspection because you are buying as-is anyway, it could be huge for the seller to not have to deal with that. Inspections are a source of contention which could be avoided.

“If you are comfortable not having an inspection, you may be more appealing to a seller since they can avoid that possible contention.”

3. Have all the documentation ready for your lender. This way, all they need is a contract from you and an appraisal. This will cut down the process tremendously.

4. Expedite the appraisal process. When you are supplying the documentation, ask the lender if they can order an appraisal the day they have the address. Let the seller know this so they can have a quicker closing.

5. Cash buyers think they should get a discount since they are spending cash. This is not necessarily true. You could finance a little more to pay the seller more and the difference could only be $15 to $20 per month. The seller will choose you because you are providing more.

6. Provide a letter about yourself. If you write a personal letter about your family, it touches the seller’s heart. They know they are selling the home to someone who will love it as opposed to an investor, which means a lot to a seller.

If you have any questions about any of this or about buying or selling, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/June/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+6+Ways+to+Compete+Against+Cash+Buyers+and+Win+Your+Dream+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/June/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+6+Ways+to+Compete+Against+Cash+Buyers+and+Win+Your+Dream+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>With the real estate market as competitive as it is, it is no surprise that buyers pay with cash to win over sellers. But how do you win when you are someone who is paying with loan money?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>With the real estate market as competitive as it is, it is no surprise that buyers pay with cash to win over sellers. But how do you win when you are someone who is paying with loan money?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Numbers Are in for Memphis Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-latest-numbers-are-in-for-memphis-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-24 15:07:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/May/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+Numbers+Are+in+for+Memphis+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I just wanted to give you a quick update on the Memphis real estate market. We took a look at the numbers for April and wanted to share them with you.

We saw 1,664 home sales recorded in the month of April. That figure is up 13% from this time last year. At the same time, the average sale price was up by 7%. We usually see around 5% appreciation on average, but the jump to 7% is great news for homeowners.

“36% of all purchases during this time were from investors.”

36% of all purchases during this time were from investors, for what it’s worth.

The average list price is up 26% from this time last year, and the average sale price for new construction homes is up to $394,000.

That’s just a quick overview of some of the general numbers in the Memphis market. If you want some more specific numbers for the area you’re in, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email and I’d be happy to discuss them with you. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/May/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+Numbers+Are+in+for+Memphis+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/May/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+Numbers+Are+in+for+Memphis+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The latest numbers are in for the Memphis real estate market. Here’s why homeowners should be excited about them.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The latest numbers are in for the Memphis real estate market. Here’s why homeowners should be excited about them.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7 Interview Questions to Ask Your Realtor</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/7-interview-questions-to-ask-your-realtor.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-10 15:34:57 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/May/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+7+Interview+Questions+to+Ask+Your+Realtor.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to give you some tips on how to interview agents before you hire them to help you sell your home. Here are seven questions you need to ask:

1. How long have you been in the business? A good way to gauge an agent’s experience and productivity is to ask them about their designation. A good designation for an agent to have is the CRS, or certified residential specialist, which requires you to have a certain level of production and work a certain number of hours.

2. What is your list-to-sale price ratio? Your Realtor should know their average list price to sales price. If they listed a home for $100,000 and sold it for $95,000, then their list price to sales price would be 95%. Seeing the averages can show you how much more they can get you. And, how much more money in your pocket.

3. What’s our best marketing plan or strategy? Are they online? How do they take their pictures? Are they on Zillow? Whatever you would like to know about that, feel free to ask. They should even have some samples for you to see, or different sites to go to.

“Whatever you would like to know about that, feel free to ask.”

4. Do they have references that you can talk to? You should look for someone that can point you to references. You should be able to call them if you wanted. Zillow is huge right now for reviews, so we try to get a lot of reviews on Zillow. You can see if a Realtor that you are looking at has their reviews on Zillow and what they say.

5. Can you review the documents ahead of time? Some people may send pre-listing documents that you may want to look at before they come back. There is nothing wrong with looking at that and asking questions.

7. How much do you charge and what kind of guarantee do you offer? Since commissions are not a set amount, this can range. Nobody can set these fees for you as they do depend on different companies and agents. Is there a satisfaction guarantee included as well, or some other kind of guarantee?

7. What have I not asked that I need to know about? See if there are any common questions that slipped your mind or you didn’t even think to ask about.

If you have any questions about this list or anything else related to selling your home, please contact me by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/May/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+7+Interview+Questions+to+Ask+Your+Realtor.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/May/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+7+Interview+Questions+to+Ask+Your+Realtor.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I have seven questions you should be asking your potential Relator during the interview process to ensure you are getting the best fit.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I have seven questions you should be asking your potential Relator during the interview process to ensure you are getting the best fit.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest From Our Memphis Area Real Estate Market</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-latest-from-our-memphis-area-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-26 13:44:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/April/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+From+Our+Memphis+Area+Real+Estate+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The latest numbers from our real estate market have just come in, so I’d like to share a quick update with you today. Let’s take a look at how our market fared this February and March compared to what we saw during the same time in 2017.

First of all, sales and average home prices have both risen year over year. Year-to-date, prices have actually risen 8% so far. This is a decent improvement upon the 5% average increase we typically see over this period.

“This lack of inventory is great for sellers but can make it difficult for buyers to find the right property.”

While sales volume is up, we are still experiencing a shortage of inventory. As of the end of March, we recorded just 3,883 units on the market. In March of 2017, there were 4,464 units on the market. This lack of inventory is great for sellers but can make it difficult for buyers to find the right property.

If they are able to find a home, buyers currently have the opportunity to take advantage of today’s low interest rates.

No matter what your real estate goals may be, I would be happy to help you discover the best way to navigate these current market conditions.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/April/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+From+Our+Memphis+Area+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/April/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+From+Our+Memphis+Area+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A lot has changed since this time last year, so let’s take a look at the latest year-over-year market update.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A lot has changed since this time last year, so let’s take a look at the latest year-over-year market update.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>10 Repairs to Make Before a Home Inspection</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/10-repairs-to-make-before-a-home-inspection.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-12 10:09:19 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/April/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+10+Repairs+to+Make+Before+a+Home+Inspection.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’d like to share with you 10 observations I received from an inspector that he sees during every home inspection.

1. Windows often need to be replaced or resealed. In terms of cost, it’s not as big of a deal as you would think to fix those issues.

2. Check to make sure the chimney is cleaned and well-maintained. It’s a good idea to have the chimney checked every two years. Almost nobody does that, but we have people we can refer you to if you need.

3. Make sure doors seal and shut properly.

4. Take care of the heating and air conditioning system. If you haven’t changed the filter recently, it’s a good thing to do. It’s cheap and a great thing to do ahead of time so that you can provide the letter of service when it’s time for the inspection.

5. Provide and change the lightbulbs. I know it sounds silly, but you would not believe how many times we see in inspection reports that a certain number of lights don’t work.

“Move or pack away any items that will prevent an inspector from accessing areas they’ll need to in order to do their jobs.”

6. Check for rotten wood around the home. That includes walking around the exterior, looking behind the gutters, and under the eaves and soffits. Home inspectors will be looking for that.

7. Buyers want a roof that is in great shape. We have a roofer who can come out and inspect yours to see if there are any issues or leaks. For $75, he can give us a roofing letter.

8. Tighten your plumbing fixtures. Make sure there aren’t any drips or cracks that could cause water- or mold-related damages.

9. Make sure there is no furniture in the inspector’s way. Move or pack away any items that will prevent an inspector from accessing areas they’ll need to in order to do their jobs. Panel boxes, water heaters, furnaces, and other such key areas are especially important to keep clear.

10. Know your home. We always put things off until we get ready to list, but if you take the time to familiarize yourself with the workings and condition of your home, the easy it will be for you to address any problems before it comes to inspect it.

If you need any resources or have any questions, please feel free to reach out to us. We’re always happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/April/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+10+Repairs+to+Make+Before+a+Home+Inspection.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/April/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+10+Repairs+to+Make+Before+a+Home+Inspection.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When inspectors come into a home to examine them, there are 10 things that they almost always find that could easily be fixed or avoided. Here is that list.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When inspectors come into a home to examine them, there are 10 things that they almost always find that could easily be fixed or avoided. Here is that list.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Additional Home Buying Costs You Need to Look Out for</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/4-additional-home-buying-costs-you-need-to-look-out-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-29 13:13:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/March/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Additional+Home+Buying+Costs+You+Need+to+Look+Out+for.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When buying a home, there are a few costs you need to look for besides PITI (principal, interest, taxes, insurance) to get an idea of what you can really afford.

1. Utility bills. You can get an estimate of this cost from www.mlgw.com, and you also have to take into consideration who will be living in the home to get a better idea.

2. Commuting costs. What’s the difference, location-wise, between where you want to live and where you work?

“HOA fees can really affect your monthly mortgage payment.”

3. Homeowners association fees. We have many HOA neighborhoods here in Memphis, and HOA fees aren’t considered part of the payment your lender provides you. These fees can vary quite a bit and can really affect your monthly mortgage payment.

4. Different credit cards. When you move in, you’ll receive a lot of different credit cards in the mail from Home Depot, Lowe’s, Sears, and other places, so be careful about signing up for them.

If you’re saving for a home, here’s a list of ways you can conserve your money.

If you have any more questions about additional costs to look out for when buying a home or you have any other real estate needs I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/March/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Additional+Home+Buying+Costs+You+Need+to+Look+Out+for.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/March/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Additional+Home+Buying+Costs+You+Need+to+Look+Out+for.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Your PITI isn’t the only thing you need to think about when buying a home. There are four other costs you should budget for too.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Your PITI isn’t the only thing you need to think about when buying a home. There are four other costs you should budget for too.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do Rising Interest Rates Mean for Buyers and Sellers Right Now?</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/what-do-rising-interest-rates-mean-for-buyers-and-sellers-right-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-09 13:38:10 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/March/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Do+Rising+Interest+Rates+Mean+for+Buyers+and+Sellers+Right+Now%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How are interest rates impacting our current market?

They’ve been increasing slowly lately, and we’re above the 4% mark now. It’s hard to complain, though, since they were so low for such a long time, and it’s predicted that they won’t be that low again for a while.

“Inventory is low and it’s a strong seller’s market.”

For the rest of 2018, rates are expected to rise even further into the high 4% range. This means a lot of sellers have been looking at their current interest rate and thinking about refinancing. Any seller who’s considering refinancing is probably staying where they’re at, and this trend has created a shortage of inventory in our market, both locally and nationwide. As you can see in the graph in the video, our year-to-date inventory is the lowest it’s been in the last decade.

If you’re a buyer, the current situation might be a bit of a struggle. There aren’t very many homes to choose from, and in some price points, multiple offer situations are common. If you’re a seller, you might be able to get more money that you thought you could for your home sale right now.  

As spring progresses,  the inventory situation will hopefully get better. In the meantime, if you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email.

I’d love to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/March/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Do+Rising+Interest+Rates+Mean+for+Buyers+and+Sellers+Right+Now%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/March/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Do+Rising+Interest+Rates+Mean+for+Buyers+and+Sellers+Right+Now%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Interest rates are increasing in our market, and this has created a shortage of inventory that means different things for buyers and sellers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Interest rates are increasing in our market, and this has created a shortage of inventory that means different things for buyers and sellers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Get a Pre-Home Inspection</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/why-you-should-get-a-pre-home-inspection.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-09 08:20:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/February/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+You+Should+Get+a+Pre-Home+Inspection.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’d like to talk to you about what you need to know, as a future home seller, about pre-home inspections.

When you’re getting ready to list your property, we can give you a list of home inspectors who we know and like. The cost will be in the $300 to $400 range. They’ll come out to look at everything to make sure there aren’t any surprises that buyers may come across. That way, the buyer won’t come back asking for a discounted price for some malfunction they discovered.

“If you take care of the inspection ahead of time, you won’t have to rush through to get things done.”

Another reason to get a pre-home inspection is that when you go under contract, there are only so many days to negotiate the home inspections and the resolution period. As a seller, you may only have three to five days to get estimates. If you take care of it ahead of time, you won’t have to rush through to get things done. Additionally, it helps you get a good price for your home to make any repairs that come up during the inspection.

The buyer may still do their own inspection, but with a pre-home inspection, you can say that you’ve already disclosed everything. It will make the buyer feel better about your home.

If you need a list of trusted inspectors or have any further questions, feel free to reach out anytime.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/February/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+You+Should+Get+a+Pre-Home+Inspection.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/February/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+You+Should+Get+a+Pre-Home+Inspection.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Why should you do a pre-home inspection? I’ll clue you in to a couple benefits you stand to gain.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why should you do a pre-home inspection? I’ll clue you in to a couple benefits you stand to gain.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Look Back at the 2017 Market</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/a-look-back-at-the-2017-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-02 08:32:30 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/February/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Look+Back+at+the+2017+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’d like to give a quick review of the numbers for the 2017 market.

For the second year in a row, the average home sales prices in all of Memphis and Shelby County were up. Landing at $165,644 in 2017, this is a 5% increase from 2016.

Additionally, the total home sales volume was up 20%. In fact, every zip code increased in volume. We haven’t seen numbers like this since 2006, and we’re seeing an increase in activity lately across the board.

“We haven’t seen numbers like this since 2006.”

Over 40% of the homes were paid for with cash, which I thought was interesting.

Home sales over the $500,000 price point went up by 20%, yet homes over $1 million were down 6%.

As a whole, my team actually closed 192 homes last year. This is because we have great team in place, so the credit doesn’t go to just one person. All the different parts work together to make sure that nothing falls through the cracks.

If you have any questions or need any help with your real estate goals, feel free to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/February/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Look+Back+at+the+2017+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/February/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Look+Back+at+the+2017+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What happened in our market in 2017? Today I’ll give you a quick review of the numbers last year.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What happened in our market in 2017? Today I’ll give you a quick review of the numbers last year.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Does the New Tax Reform Bill Impact Real Estate?</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/how-does-the-new-tax-reform-bill-impact-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-19 07:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/January/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Does+the+New+Tax+Reform+Bill+Impact+Real+Estate%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The tax reform bill has been signed into law. How does the final bill impact real estate?

The good news is that the capital gains exclusion remains. Basically, you do not have to pay taxes on a certain amount of profit from your home sale. If you are single, the limit is $250,000. If you are married, the limit is $500,000.

The mortgage interest deduction stayed in tact, which is also good. The cap did go down from $1 million to $750,000.

“The capital gains exclusion remains.”

They were trying to eliminate state and local tax deductions altogether, but instead, there is a $10,000 limit. That is pretty good for Memphis. A buyer came in from New York, and their property taxes were $50,000, so $10,000 is a pretty good deal. It may not be what we wanted, and people within the city limits have probably seen more than that, but it’s better than eliminating state and local deductions entirely.

That is what we know so far. Everybody will see some benefits from the tax reform in different aspects, and there was some good news in the final bill for real estate.

If you have any other questions about our real estate market, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/January/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Does+the+New+Tax+Reform+Bill+Impact+Real+Estate%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/January/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Does+the+New+Tax+Reform+Bill+Impact+Real+Estate%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How does The Tax Cuts and Jobs Act impact the Memphis real estate market?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How does The Tax Cuts and Jobs Act impact the Memphis real estate market?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Look Back at Our November 2017 Market</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/a-look-back-at-our-november-2017-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-05 05:11:43 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/January/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Look+Back+at+Our+November+2017+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’d like to take a look back into our recent Memphis market. What happened in November?

The month of November was the third time that home prices did not increase in 2017. This isn’t necessarily a bad thing, it just indicates a lack of change.

“Homes are still moving off the market despite our low inventory.”

However, we did see the percentage of homes sold increase by 4%. This means homes are still moving off the market despite our low inventory.

Of course, prices and inventory levels do vary between municipalities. I’d be happy to send information about your specific information to you. All you need to do is reach out.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/January/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Look+Back+at+Our+November+2017+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2018/January/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Look+Back+at+Our+November+2017+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How was our Memphis market in the month of November?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How was our Memphis market in the month of November?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Choose the Right Home Inspector</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/how-to-choose-the-right-home-inspector.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-14 07:14:01 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/December/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Choose+the+Right+Home+Inspector.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What makes a good home inspector?

As a buyer, one of the best things you can do is to work with a quality home inspector. First and foremost, you should make sure the inspector is licensed and is a member of the American Home Inspector Institute.

There’s also nothing wrong with calling a home inspector for an interview, to make sure you’re comfortable working with them as you move forward.

“Home inspectors look at everything in the home we wouldn’t think to look at ourselves.”

Of course, sometimes home inspectors will tell us things we aren’t so happy to hear. But ultimately, that’s a good thing. Home inspectors look at everything in the home we wouldn’t think to look at ourselves.

When you have a home inspection performed, the inspector may flag some things for you to have looked at more thoroughly by another specialized professional.

Even if there’s nothing glaringly wrong, it’s a good idea to have specialists come and look at specific areas of the home.

If you would like any recommendations, my team and I would be happy to assist you. Also, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/December/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Choose+the+Right+Home+Inspector.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/December/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Choose+the+Right+Home+Inspector.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Choosing the right home inspector is as important as the inspection process, itself. Here are some ways you can make sure the person you work with is qualified.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Choosing the right home inspector is as important as the inspection process, itself. Here are some ways you can make sure the person you work with is qualified.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Numbers Are In: Memphis Market Update</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-numbers-are-in-memphis-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-01 05:39:10 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/December/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Numbers+Are+In-+Memphis+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The numbers from October are in, so it’s time give you a market update.

We continued to see home prices rise this year. October specifically was a slower month with 1,474 home sales, as compared to October 2016’s 1,507 sales.

Home values keep going up, and we’re still seeing low inventory as well, which I think is part of the reason for those values. Through the first 10 months of the year, the number of home sales went up 9%, which is awesome.

“It’s still a great time of year to start listing.”

Homes sold in the $500,000 range increased 40% in October. For those homes over $1 million, there were three sold, which makes that percentage quite high.

Attached in the video is a chart of home sales by municipality where you can see the number of units sold, average sale price, and average price per square foot for each municipality. If you want to know something more specific about that, just shoot me an email.

The average days on market for the whole Memphis area was 60 days, though our team’s average was 42.

We’re still seeing multiple offers, and it’s still a great time of year to start listing.

If you have any questions for us, reach out and let us know. We’d be happy to talk with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/December/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Numbers+Are+In-+Memphis+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/December/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Numbers+Are+In-+Memphis+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The October numbers are in, which means it’s time for another update on market trends.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The October numbers are in, which means it’s time for another update on market trends.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Surprising Benefits of Selling in the Fall</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/5-surprising-benefits-of-selling-in-the-fall.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-17 05:52:57 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/November/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Surprising+Benefits+of+Selling+in+the+Fall.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’ve been thinking of waiting until next spring or summer to get your home on the market, you might be surprised to hear that there are a number of advantages that home sellers only see in the fall real estate market here in Memphis. Here are five good reasons to consider selling your home in this market:

1. Tax breaks. If the transaction is completed before the end of the year, you will receive a tax break and a number of different write-offs as well.

2. A home for the holidays. We recently sold a home to a young couple. They are so excited to move into their new home just in time for the holidays. Right now, we can get you into a new home in just about 22 days, so you’ve still got some time to make your decision if you’re debating it. Keep in mind that homes show well when decorated for the holidays.

“Interest rates have continued to stay low.”

3. The price is right. We aren’t seeing as many multiple offer situations as we have in the past, but the limited inventory is still putting the pressure on buyers to make winning offers.

4. Less competition. Although this means that you’ll have to wait a bit longer if you’re in the market to buy a home, it’s great news for you if you’re a seller.

Interest rates have continued to stay low, making this a great market to buy and sell in. These are perfect conditions if you’re looking to move up into a bigger or better home. If you have any questions for me about the market or about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/November/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Surprising+Benefits+of+Selling+in+the+Fall.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/November/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Surprising+Benefits+of+Selling+in+the+Fall.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are plenty of reasons to choose to sell this fall. Here are a few of the most tempting.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are plenty of reasons to choose to sell this fall. Here are a few of the most tempting.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>You’re Invited to Our Annual Pie Giveaway</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/youre-invited-to-our-annual-pie-giveaway.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-08 07:36:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/November/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Youre+Invited+to+Our+Annual+Pie+Giveaway.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It would be my pleasure to invite you to our Annual Thanksgiving Pie Giveaway.

On Tuesday, November 21st, from 10 a.m. to 5 p.m., we invite you to our office  to pick up your choice of free apple or pumpkin pie. This is the fourth year we’ve hosted this event, and it’s sure to be a great time yet again.

“We invite you to our office  to pick up your choice of free apple or pumpkin pie.”

We do ask that you reserve your pie in advance by Friday, November 17th, by emailing your reservation to team@yourkeytomemphis.com, or else by calling or texting (901) 729-9526.

We’ll have some food and spend some time catching up with each other. We’d love to see you there!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/November/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Youre+Invited+to+Our+Annual+Pie+Giveaway.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/November/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Youre+Invited+to+Our+Annual+Pie+Giveaway.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You’re invited to our fourth annual free pie giveaway!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You’re invited to our fourth annual free pie giveaway!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Protect Yourself Against the Equifax Breach?</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/how-can-you-protect-yourself-against-the-equifax-breach.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-19 06:28:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/October/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Protect+Yourself+Against+the+Equifax+Breach%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you curious how you can protect yourself against the recent Equifax data breach? Here are five tips you can use:

1. Know the facts. Reach out to a professional and see if you’ve been affected.

2. Find out if you’ve been impacted. You can visit www.equifaxsecurity2017.com to do so.

“If you’ve been impacted, don’t hesitate to take action.”

3. Take action. There is a resolution service you can use that will help you see what needs to be done. Place a 90-day fraud alert on all of your credit bureaus to let them know you’ve been affected by the breach. You can also take advantage of the free credit monitoring. I use Credit Karma, which is a free service and sends you an email once a month to keep you updated on the latest developments and lets you know what you can do to improve your credit.

4. Raise your awareness. Be positive about the experience. We even have to send out notices to our clients about different things that can happen with our emails in real estate work.

5. If identity theft strikes, contact a resolution expert so they can help you take care of it as fast as possible. Credit Karma actually has a service that lets you know if something has been done so you can know about it immediately. Some people don’t check their credit often, so they can be tremendously affected by this kind of thing.

If you have any questions about these tips, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/October/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Protect+Yourself+Against+the+Equifax+Breach%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/October/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Protect+Yourself+Against+the+Equifax+Breach%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re worried about the recent Equifax data breach, I have five tips to help you protect yourself against it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re worried about the recent Equifax data breach, I have five tips to help you protect yourself against it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Look at Our Market: 2016 vs. Now</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/a-look-at-our-market-2016-vs-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-05 07:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/October/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Look+at+Our+Market-+2016+vs.+Now.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to bring you a quick look at how our market is faring right now. So, what’s been going on recently?

Over the summer, home sales continued to soar. Sales are up 14% compared to this time last year, and home prices have gone up as well.

“Home sales continued to soar.”

According to chandlerreports.com, home prices have actually risen by 6%, though specific prices will vary slightly depending on your specific subdivision. You can look at how things differ depending on municipality here.

Another notable statistic is the rise of overall home sales, which have increased by 21%. Additionally, home sales over $500,000 are up 28%. Home sales over $1 million, though, are the same as they were in 2016.

Two other things that haven’t changed much are interest rates and inventory.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/October/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Look+at+Our+Market-+2016+vs.+Now.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/October/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Look+at+Our+Market-+2016+vs.+Now.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As we move into the end of the year, it’s time for us to take a look at the latest market numbers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As we move into the end of the year, it’s time for us to take a look at the latest market numbers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Few Easy Ways to Increase Your Curb Appeal</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/a-few-easy-ways-to-increase-your-curb-appeal.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-11 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/September/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Few+Easy+Ways+to+Increase+Your+Curb+Appeal.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When I show a home to a buyer, the first thing they notice is its curb appeal. That’s a term for how a home looks from the curb. The better the curb appeal, the more interested a buyer is in seeing the inside of your home. Here are a few areas you should focus your efforts on in order to improve your curb appeal.

1. Paint. Buyers are going to notice cracked or chipping paint. Even if it’s not cracked or chipped, a fresh coat of paint can really increase your curb appeal.

2. Landscaping. It doesn’t have to be elaborate, it just has to be clean. If your yard isn’t in the best shape, we’d be happy to refer you to someone who can help get it back on track.

“The better the curb appeal, the more interested the buyer is.”

4. Make sure doorknobs and knockers are polished

5. Test your doorbell to make sure it is working properly.

6. Make sure your address is clearly visible on the house and the mailbox.

7. Get a new doormat

These are just a few of the things you can do to help buyers have a fantastic first impression when they come to see your home. If you have any questions for us about getting your home ready for sale, don’t hesitate to reach out. We would love to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/September/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Few+Easy+Ways+to+Increase+Your+Curb+Appeal.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/September/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Few+Easy+Ways+to+Increase+Your+Curb+Appeal.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Curb appeal is an essential part of home selling. Here’s what you should be focusing on.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Curb appeal is an essential part of home selling. Here’s what you should be focusing on.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest News From Our 100th Home Sale Giveaway and the Memphis Market</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-latest-news-from-our-100th-home-sale-giveaway-and-the-memphis-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-28 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/August/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+News+From+Our+100th+Home+Sale+GIveaway+and+the+Memphis+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the latest word from our Memphis market?

We’ll get to that, but first, we have an exciting announcement to make. We’ve helped 118 families buy and sell homes this year, but as you know, we’ve been asking people to vote for one of two local charities—Hope Works and Youth Villages—to win our 100th home sale giveaway and receive the majority of the proceeds from that sale.

The voters have spoken, and the 1st place winner of our 100th home sale giveaway is…

Hope Works!

We were glad to be able to drop off our check to this wonderful organization and learn more about their ministry in the process. We were also happy to deliver Youth Villages their 2nd place check and learn more about them as well.

“Overall, the market is still good.”

Now, let’s look at the latest numbers from our market and how they compare with where we were this time last year.

The number of units for sale is up 14% compared to July 2016. For the first seven months of the year, they were up 9% compared to last year. The average home sale price is up 3%. Interest rates are rumored to be going up again in the future, but we haven’t seen anything yet. Overall, the market is still good.

If you have any questions about our Memphis market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, feel free to get in touch with us. We’d love to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/August/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+News+From+Our+100th+Home+Sale+GIveaway+and+the+Memphis+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/August/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+News+From+Our+100th+Home+Sale+GIveaway+and+the+Memphis+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our market is still in good shape, and a few important numbers are up compared to July 2016.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our market is still in good shape, and a few important numbers are up compared to July 2016.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Smooth Out Your New Construction Home Purchase With These Tips</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/smooth-out-your-new-construction-home-purchase-with-these-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-15 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/August/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Smooth+Out+Your+New+Construction+Home+Purchase+With+These+Tips.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I recently read an article in Realtor Magazine that claimed 2017 was the best year in a decade for new construction homes—not just in the Memphis area, but everywhere.

According to this article, “A shortage of homes for sale combined with growing buyer demand will likely spark home builders to construct the most homes this year than in the last decade.”

If you’re interested in buying a newly built home, there are a few tips you should know to make the process go smoother.

First, choose a reputable builder. Make sure they’re a member of the Home Builders Association (in our case, the West Tennessee Home Builders), which allows them to provide a one-year warranty. Beware of all of the add-ons, too, because there are many things that could be considered upgrades that might pull you out of your budget. Stay involved in the building process and don’t be afraid to ask questions. Also, learn about the surrounding neighborhood before you buy.

“Stay involved in the building process and don’t be afraid to ask questions.”

Next, be flexible. With the weather being how it is, builders can’t always determine when your house will be totally completed. They should be able to keep you updated and informed, but you’ll need some flexible dates in mind so everything can be controlled.

Lastly, it’s not a bad idea to have a home inspection. The builder will do a walkthrough with you, but it’s still worth the money to have a home inspection and let someone else take a look at the home to make sure nothing gets overlooked.

If you have any questions about buying new construction or any other real estate topic, feel free to give me a call. I’d be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/August/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Smooth+Out+Your+New+Construction+Home+Purchase+With+These+Tips.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/August/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Smooth+Out+Your+New+Construction+Home+Purchase+With+These+Tips.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re interested in buying a new construction home, here are a few tips to make the process go smoother.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re interested in buying a new construction home, here are a few tips to make the process go smoother.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Numbers for Our Market</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/the-latest-numbers-for-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-01 08:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/August/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+Numbers+for+Our+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to give you an update on the latest numbers and trends that we’ve seen in our real estate market. According to chandlerreports.com, June was a great month and we saw a lot of promising trends, such as:


  Overall home sales are up by 8%.
  Average sale prices are up by 5%.
  Bank-owned property sales are down by 20%.
  Home sales over $500,000 are up over 30%.


As far as that steep drop in bank-owned property sales is concerned, it’s actually a good sign for our market. A drop in the number of foreclosed properties is good for your resale value. There are still foreclosures available out there, but they are a little harder to find now.

“Bank-owned properties are down a whopping 20%.”

There is a chart below that shows the numbers for all the different municipalities in the area. As you can see, the average sale price has increased in Arlington, Bartlett, Collierville, and Germantown.

The market is still very strong for sellers, but we aren’t seeing as many multiple offer situations. If you have any questions about the market or about your home specifically, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email today. I would love to hear from you.


</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/August/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+Numbers+for+Our+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/August/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Latest+Numbers+for+Our+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’ve got a quick update for you today on our real estate market. Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’ve got a quick update for you today on our real estate market. Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Protect First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/3-tips-to-protect-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Buying a House</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-12 12:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Tips+to+Protect+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you or someone you know is considering buying a home for the first time, there are a few things you need to be aware of. Here are our top three tips to protect first-time homebuyers:


  Know what you can afford. This doesn’t just include your mortgage payment. You need to make sure you can afford that in addition to property taxes, utilities, and various other maintenance fees.


“HOME VALUES HAVE BEEN INCREASING YEAR BY YEAR IN MEMPHIS.”


  
    Choose your lender wisely. Online lenders aren’t always the best option, even if they advertise the lowest rate. You should really get a recommendation from a Realtor or some other person you trust. Local lenders tend to work best in terms of being able to close on time.
  
  
    Don’t overlook the details. Purchase contracts have a lot of them. Take your time to read through it carefully and don’t hesitate to ask your Realtor any questions you have.
  


These are just three tips for successfully buying a home for the first time. If you would like some more tips or just have a question, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Tips+to+Protect+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/+Videos/2017/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Tips+to+Protect+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you or someone you know is considering buying a home for the first time, there are a few things you need to be aware of. Here are our top three tips to protect first-time homebuyers:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you or someone you know is considering buying a home for the first time, there are a few things you need to be aware of. Here are our top three tips to protect first-time homebuyers:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Promising Numbers From Our Memphis Market</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/promising-numbers-from-our-memphis.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-23 08:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Your+latest+Memphis+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do the numbers from our current market compare to where we were at this time last year?

The number of units sold has risen 9% from 1,625 to 1,771, which is good. Home values have been increasing year by year in the Memphis area as a whole, and the median sale price is up to $165,000. The number of home sales above $500,000 has increased 32%.

“HOME VALUES HAVE BEEN INCREASING YEAR BY YEAR IN MEMPHIS.”

On a related note, I’d like to remind you that we’re donating the commission of our 100th home sale to a local charity, and you have the opportunity to vote on this website for who wins. The candidates are HopeWorks, Youth Villages, and the Bartlett Animal Shelter.

If you have any questions about our market, you’d like to know what your home is worth, or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to assist you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Your+latest+Memphis+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Your+latest+Memphis+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How do the numbers from our current market compare to where we were at this time last year?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How do the numbers from our current market compare to where we were at this time last year?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Make Your Offer on a Memphis Home Stand Out</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/how-to-make-your-offer-on-memphis-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-13 13:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re looking to buy a home here in Memphis, you might have to compete against other offers for a home you like.

For starters, remember that no other buyers know what the offers are, so you don’t have to worry about your offer being revealed. However, you can do a few things to make your offer better.

First, put down as much earnest money as possible. This speaks volumes to the seller about your interest level in the home and that you can follow through with the loan process. Putting down a small amount means you don’t have any skin in the game, and the seller might not see your offer as worth it at that point.

Secondly, show the seller that you are qualified for a home loan. Get fully pre-approved for a loan instead of just getting pre-qualified, which carries less weight. An offer with a pre-approval is akin to a cash offer for a seller.

“SHOW THE SELLER THAT YOU ARE QUALIFIED FOR A HOME LOAN.”

You can also give the seller extra time to move. Call the listing agent and ask them what’s important to their seller, because it’s not always all about money. For example, I recently worked with a seller who needed to rent the house back for a couple months after closing because they have a handicapped child. There are many situations going on in people’s lives, and accommodating them can help you win the home.

Finally, add a personal touch by writing a letter telling the seller why you love the home. Also be aware of what you’re willing to pay for the home.

If you have any questions about multiple offer situations when buying a home, give us a call or send us an email soon. We’d be more than happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re looking to buy a home here in Memphis, you might have to compete against other offers for a home you like.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re looking to buy a home here in Memphis, you might have to compete against other offers for a home you like.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Get the Best Possible Credit When Applying for a Home Loan</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/how-to-get-best-possible-credit-when.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-24 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+get+your+credit+mortgage+loan+ready.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about buying a home, you need to start preparing to have the best possible credit when applying for a mortgage loan.

First, pay attention to your accounts. Don’t close any accounts or open any new ones when preparing to buy a home. Also, make sure your credit to debt ratio looks good on all your open accounts. If you have a $500 limit, don’t let the balance sit at $495.

Next, don’t switch jobs. If you do need to switch, try to stay in the same field so lenders have information about the switch. They want to see some job security, so if you’ve hopped around a lot that can be a problem.

“DON’T CLOSE ANY ACCOUNTS OR OPEN ANY NEW ONES WHEN PREPARING TO BUY A HOME.”

Pay attention to your balances. If you have a high limit and you’ve maxed that out, it won’t look good to lenders. On the other hand, if you had a credit card that you use and pay off regularly, lenders will love that.

Finally, don’t make any big purchases until after closing on a home. After you’ve got the keys to your new home, feel free to get that new furniture, just hold off until then.

If you have any questions or are looking to buy or sell a home, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m always happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+get+your+credit+mortgage+loan+ready.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+get+your+credit+mortgage+loan+ready.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re thinking about buying a home, you need to start preparing to have the best possible credit when applying for a mortgage loan.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re thinking about buying a home, you need to start preparing to have the best possible credit when applying for a mortgage loan.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Homeowners & Homebuyers Need to Know About Taxes</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/what-homeowners-homebuyers-need-to-know.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-20 12:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+your+tax+appraisal+too+high%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m here with Wendy Thompson of the Wendy Thompson Lending Team to talk about your tax appraisal. Unless you live in the downtown area, you should have received your appraisal by now.

If you disagree with your appraisal, you can go to the Shelby County tax assessor site and fill out an informal request for a reassessment. You don’t have to provide a lot of documentation for an informal request, so it is a fairly easy process. That said, there is a short time frame for informal requests. Beginning on May 1st, you can make a formal request. That is a much more involved process.

“MAKE SURE YOUR LENDER IS USING THE CORRECT TAX ASSESSMENT.”

If you are selling your house and your taxes have gone up, this could impact you. Since taxes are divided between you and your potential buyer at closing, the buyer could come to you and ask for additional taxes since your appraisal went up.

If you are a buyer and you are currently under contract to purchase a home, make sure that your lender is using the correct tax assessment. Unfortunately, in some instances even a slight increase in monthly taxes can make a huge difference between getting approved for a loan or not.

As always, if you have any questions about this topic, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+your+tax+appraisal+too+high%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+your+tax+appraisal+too+high%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m here with Wendy Thompson of the Wendy Thompson Lending Team to talk about your tax appraisal. Unless you live in the downtown area, you should have received your appraisal by now.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m here with Wendy Thompson of the Wendy Thompson Lending Team to talk about your tax appraisal. Unless you live in the downtown area, you should have received your appraisal by now.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Will Recent Interest Rate Changes Affect You?</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/how-will-recent-interest-rate-changes.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-06 13:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+recent+interest+rate+changes+affect+you.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Interest rates have been a hot topic recently, so today, I’ve brought in Wendy Thompson with the Wendy Thompson Lending Team of Bank of England Mortgage to help me explain.

The Federal Reserve raised interest rates by 0.25% last week, and the market actually responded very positively. Rates had been rising before, but we’ve actually settled with rates at about 4.25% with FHA, VA, and USDA interest rates at 4%. The Federal Reserve anticipates two more rate increases of 0.25% this year as well.

The good thing is that despite the recent rise, rates are still very low. If you’re thinking about buying a new home, it’s better to act sooner than later.

Rates have been so low for so long that it’s actually better for the economy for them to go up now. After all, we all want our retirement funds and investments to do well also. The impact of rising rates on your costs isn’t substantial either. For a $200,000 home, a 0.25% increase in rates only equates to about $25 more per month. Historically speaking, having rates this low is great compared to the 18% I saw when I started in real estate.

“RATES HAVE BEEN SO LOW FOR SO LONG THAT IT’S ACTUALLY BETTER FOR THE ECONOMY FOR THEM TO GO UP NOW.”

Many people don’t know that mortgage-backed securities control mortgage rates. That’s why it’s important to work with a mortgage lender who follows rate changes daily. As Wendy says, it’s a bit volatile right now because things outside of the country can even have an effect on rates, so they can change on a dime. Having a knowledgeable lender is more important in these conditions.

If you have any questions for Wendy about rates or getting approved for a home loan, you can reach her at Wendy@TheWendyThompsonTeam.com or give her a call at 901-461-8858.

As always, if you have any questions about our market or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+recent+interest+rate+changes+affect+you.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+recent+interest+rate+changes+affect+you.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Interest rates have been a hot topic recently, so today, I’ve brought in Wendy Thompson with the Wendy Thompson Lending Team of Bank of England Mortgage to help me explain.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Interest rates have been a hot topic recently, so today, I’ve brought in Wendy Thompson with the Wendy Thompson Lending Team of Bank of England Mortgage to help me explain.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dont Let Your Pets Mess up Your Home Sale</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/dont-let-your-pets-mess-up-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-04 12:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+Fido+can+ruin+your+home+showings.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I have a pet and I love animals but, unfortunately, pets can mess up your home sale. After all, the way we live in our home every day is different from the way we live in it after it has been on the market. Here are five things you need to pay attention to when selling a home with pets:


  
    Tufts of fur: If you have a cat or dog that sheds, you need to clean up the extra fur that gathers around the house so that your home doesn’t look messy.
  
  
    Floor stains: Redo your hardwood floors if need be and make sure that any pet stains are cleaned out of the carpet.
  


“CLEAN UP ANY PET STAINS TO THE BEST OF YOUR ABILITY.”


  
    Pet odors: You can get used to the smell when you live there, but you don’t want buyers to walk in and think your house smells like wet dog. Pet stores sell products, like candles, that will cover up pet odors without being too overwhelming.
  
  
    Scratches and dings: Puppies love to chew and scratch at things. If you have marks on your furniture, there are special pens out there that can cover those up. Pay attention to your windowsills and doors, as dogs tend to scratch on those as well.
  
  
    Bowls, pet beds, and litter boxes: Put away all of the pet paraphernalia that you can and make sure that the litter box is clean; buyers don’t want to see or smell that.
  


Take care of these five things so that your home shows well. If you have any other questions about selling with pets or about the home-selling process in general, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+Fido+can+ruin+your+home+showings.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+ways+Fido+can+ruin+your+home+showings.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I have a pet and I love animals but, unfortunately, pets can mess up your home sale. After all, the way we live in our home every day is different from the way we live in it after it has been on the market. Here are five things you need to pay attention to when selling a home with pets:

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I have a pet and I love animals but, unfortunately, pets can mess up your home sale. After all, the way we live in our home every day is different from the way we live in it after it has been on the market. Here are five things you need to pay attention to when selling a home with pets:

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selling in 2017? Start Your Renovations Now</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/selling-in-2017-start-your-renovations.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-20 10:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Make+Those+Pre-List+Renovations+Now%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a few good reasons to do some renovations in your home, especially if you plan to sell this year.

For one, if you renovate now, you get to enjoy the new stuff! There are plenty of things you may have put off, like new appliances or granite countertops, so why not enjoy them a bit before selling your house? Give yourself a chance to cook with those new appliances first.

The second reason to start renovations early is that they always take longer than you expect. If you get an estimated timeline of six weeks, plan on 12 weeks. It’s just the nature of the beast. If you plan for this, you won’t have to be stressed about getting your house finished and on the market in a certain amount of time.

Thirdly, you might run into issues that you’re not aware of. A big part of my job is going to potential listings early to get a look at things that might need to be done. We often uncover issues that you never notice because you live in the home every day.

“YOUR RENOVATIONS DON’T HAVE TO BE MASSIVE.”

Your renovations don’t have to be huge. I’m not talking about taking things down to the studs for a renovation. In fact, that’s not beneficial in many cases. **My goal is to get you $3 in return for every $1 you spend. **

The fifth reason is that in this competitive market, you simply might need renovations. With the popularity of HGTV in the last few years, we see that buyers simply want what they want. As an agent, I know these things that buyers want to see in a home and will get you more money for your home in the long run.

Finally, if you make the right renovations, you’ll see a good return on your investment. Again, we want to get $3 in return for every $1 you spend on these renovations. My main job is to identify the best ways to do this ahead of time.

If you’re thinking about selling your house this year and you’d like to know more about the smart renovations that will increase your net sales price, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Make+Those+Pre-List+Renovations+Now%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Make+Those+Pre-List+Renovations+Now%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are a few good reasons to do some renovations in your home, especially if you plan to sell this year.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are a few good reasons to do some renovations in your home, especially if you plan to sell this year.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect When Hiring a Home Inspector?</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/what-can-you-expect-when-hiring-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-16 10:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+can+you+expect+from+home+inspectors%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Once you’re under contract for a home and you’ve hired a home inspector to do an inspection, what can you expect from them? What does a home inspector do, exactly?

During their inspection, inspectors aren’t looking for cosmetic concerns like whether or not to repaint the bathroom or whether the wallpaper should come off. Instead, they’re looking for things of importance like heating, electrical, cooking, and other systems vital to the integrity of the house.

“INSPECTORS ARE LOOKING FOR WHAT’S IMPORTANT—NOT ANY COSMETIC FLAWS.”

After they’re done inspecting those items, they’ll give you a report on the house. As the buyer, this report goes to you only. It doesn’t go to the seller unless their agent requests it. After you receive this report, it’s up to you to look through it, see what’s important to you, and negotiate with the seller going forward.

If you have any questions about this topic or are looking to buy or sell a home in our market, please feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to speak with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+can+you+expect+from+home+inspectors%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+can+you+expect+from+home+inspectors%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Once you’re under contract for a home and you’ve hired a home inspector to do an inspection, what can you expect from them? What does a home inspector do, exactly?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Once you’re under contract for a home and you’ve hired a home inspector to do an inspection, what can you expect from them? What does a home inspector do, exactly?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do You Need to Know About TRID?</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/what-do-you-need-to-know-about-trid.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-19 14:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+does+TRID+do%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You may have heard the acronym TRID before, but you also may not be totally clear about what it is and how it can affect you.

If you’re a buyer or under contract, you’ve already heard, but here are the basics. TRID was put into effect in October 2015 to protect buyers. TRID allows buyers to have three days prior to closing to look at all your documents as a buyer.

“TRID IS IN PLACE TO HELP BUYERS.”

As a seller, you have a closing date and a possession date which is however many days after the closing date. The three-day TRID window takes place in that time period. We do the best we can, but we are at the mercy of the lenders most of the time. TRID is a good thing and it helps protect consumers, but things can get awfully hairy if you’re in a rush.

Make sure your lender gets it out in time because although we will do everything we can to have this not affect your closing, it still can. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+does+TRID+do%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+does+TRID+do%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

You may have heard the acronym TRID before, but you also may not be totally clear about what it is and how it can affect you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

You may have heard the acronym TRID before, but you also may not be totally clear about what it is and how it can affect you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Is Winter a Good Time to Sell Your House?</title>
        <link>http://www.weknowmemphis.com/why-is-winter-good-time-to-sell-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Melissa Thompson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-06 10:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+winter+is+a+great+time+to+sell+your+house.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Is winter a good time to put your home on the market? It’s actually the second best time to sell a home, just behind springtime. Why?

There is less inventory on the market for buyers to choose from, and those buyers out looking in the winter are great buyers. These buyers are moving for a reason; they’re not the semi-serious tire kickers that you see looking at houses in the spring and summer.

“WINTER IS STILL A GREAT TIME TO SELL YOUR HOUSE.”

Interest rates went up a little bit after the election, but they are still very low. These low rates have been the tipping point for some buyers who have been on the fence.

If you have any questions about selling during the winter or you’re thinking about buying or selling a house, give me a call or send me an email soon. I’d be happy to help in any way I can!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+winter+is+a+great+time+to+sell+your+house.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.weknowmemphis.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Melissa+Thompson/Memphis+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+winter+is+a+great+time+to+sell+your+house.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Is winter a good time to put your home on the market? It’s actually the second best time to sell a home, just behind springtime. Why?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Melissa Thompson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Is winter a good time to put your home on the market? It’s actually the second best time to sell a home, just behind springtime. Why?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Memphis, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Melissa Thompson</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Melissa Thompson</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Your Key To Memphis - your professional Memphis Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
