<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Phoenix Real Estate Podcast with Oggie Penev</title>
    <link>http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Penev Realty Advisors - your professional Phoenix Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Oggie Penev</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-06-20 16:04:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Oggie Penev</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>oggiepenev@penevrealtyadvisors.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Oggie Penev</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Oggie Penev</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Phoenix Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Penev Realty Advisors - your professional Phoenix Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways We Can Sell Your Home for Free</title>
        <link>http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com/5-ways-we-can-sell-your-home-for-free.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Oggie Penev</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-12 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+No+Commish.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m going to talk about five different ways that we can sell your home for free. That’s right, we can sell your home in a number of different ways that result in you not having to pay any listing commission. Here’s how we do it:

1. Buy &amp; Sell for Free Program. If you are planning to upsize into a bigger home from a smaller one, we can waive our listing commission if you complete both transactions with us. We are only paid when you buy a home.

2. Smart Seller Program. When you list a property with us, you always have the option to sell the property yourself and pay no commission. If you find a buyer on your own while we are selling your home, we won’t charge you any commission.

“If you aren’t happy with your new home within the first two years of owning it, we’ll sell it for free.”

3. Auction Marketing Program. With this program, we will sell your property auction-style. It’s a five-day online auction that will get your home multiple offers. With this program, the buyer ends up paying all of these commissions for you. To find out more about this specific program, go to www.ArizonaRealtyAuction.com.

4. Sell to a cash investor. If your home needs some repairs or a lot of work in general, this is a great option. We can connect you directly with an investor who will pay cash for your home and they will cover our fees, leaving you to pay no commission fees.

5. VIP Buyer Program. Anytime you buy a property with us and you aren’t happy with it in the first two years for some reason, we will sell it for you for free. 

These are five ways we can sell your property for free. If you have any questions or want to learn more about any of these programs we offer, don’t hesitate to give me call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+No+Commish.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+No+Commish.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is it possible to sell your home without having to pay your agent’s commission? If you work with our team, there are actually five different ways that we can help you sell your home without charging a commission. For example, our Auction Marketing Program will list your home auction-style in a five-day online auction where the buyer ends up paying all of the commissions. To learn about the other four ways we can help save you money on your home sale, watch this short video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Oggie Penev</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is it possible to sell your home without having to pay your agent’s commission? If you work with our team, there are actually five different ways that we can help you sell your home without charging a commission. For example, our Auction Marketing Program will list your home auction-style in a five-day online auction where the buyer ends up paying all of the commissions. To learn about the other four ways we can help save you money on your home sale, watch this short video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What 3 Fees Should Sellers Keep in Mind?</title>
        <link>http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com/what-3-fees-should-sellers-keep-in-mind.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Oggie Penev</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-17 07:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Fees.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today let’s talk about closing costs. What should the seller expect to pay when selling their property?

There are three major costs that apply to sellers:

1. Broker fees. Usually the seller pays anywhere from 0% to 10% commission, depending on the case. Yes, it is possible to pay 0% commission. Here in our market, the average commission fee comes to about 6%, which is split between the selling agent and the buyer’s agent. The seller does not pay the buyer representative directly; the seller pays the whole commission to the listing agent and that agent pays the buyer agent at closing.

2. Title fees. Usually title fees include title policy, escrow fees, and some fees related to notaries and records of the deal. It’s customary in the Phoenix market that the seller will buy title policy insurance for the property. The title policy fee is usually a percentage of the price of the home; the higher the price, the higher the cost of the title policy.Escrow fees are the fees that the title company charges for the labor for handling the paperwork, accounting, signings, and so one. Sometimes, if you want to have a notary come to your home, there will be additional fees. A lot of times title companies have a relationship with brokers such that they can give some discounts to the sellers. For example, an investor who does multiple deals with a title company, you can sometimes get a 50% discount on the escrow fees.

“The title policy fee is usually a percentage of the price of the home; the higher the price, the higher the cost of the title policy.”

3. HOA fees. These could be HOA disclosure fees, transfer fees, or capital improvement fees. The disclosure fee is the fee that the seller pays the property management company to prepare the documents. The transfer fee is what the HOA charges to create a new profile for the new buyer and transfer from the old account to the new one. As far as who pays it, this fee is negotiable. The final, rare HOA fees are capital improvement fees which can be a flat fee or a percentage of the sale.

If you have any questions or you would like a niche sheet specific to your property, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Fees.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Fees.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When it comes time to sell your home, you’re probably more focused on what you’re going to make than what you’ll have to pay. However, there are fees that sellers specifically need to pay for their part in the transaction. Today I’ll discuss three of the main types of fees a seller should expect to pay. The first type is the broker fee, which is what they’ll pay the agent(s) for their commission. To learn more about this and the other types of fees, watch my latest video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Oggie Penev</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When it comes time to sell your home, you’re probably more focused on what you’re going to make than what you’ll have to pay. However, there are fees that sellers specifically need to pay for their part in the transaction. Today I’ll discuss three of the main types of fees a seller should expect to pay. The first type is the broker fee, which is what they’ll pay the agent(s) for their commission. To learn more about this and the other types of fees, watch my latest video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t List Your Home as For Sale By Owner</title>
        <link>http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com/dont-list-your-home-as-for-sale-by-owner.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Oggie Penev</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-01 06:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Dont+List+Your+Home+as+For+Sale+By+Owner.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m going to discuss why a person might list their house as For Sale By Owner (FSBO) and three reasons why you shouldn’t be listing your home without the help of an agent.

1. Buyers shopping for FSBO homes are looking for a deal. Why would a buyer ignore 95% of all other listings to look at a property that isn’t represented by an agent? The reason is that they’re going to ask for a discount. They’ll probably ask pretty quickly in the transaction if you’ll take off the 6% that would normally go toward commission.

“Negotiating on your own property is like a doctor operating on a family member; there’s a reason why they don’t do that.”

2. It’s difficult to distinguish the lookers from the buyers. A lot of the people who come in to buy homes have frozen equity and have to sell a home before they can qualify for another property. A FSBO owner probably wouldn’t know to ask about that, meaning that they wouldn’t be sure whether a buyer’s offer is legitimate or not.

3. You’re emotionally involved with the property. This interferes with properly negotiating terms, price, and conditions on the contract. Negotiating on your own property is like a doctor operating on a family member; there’s a reason why they don’t do that.

Before you sell your home, you should consider working with a real estate broker. If you’re thinking about selling in the near future, feel free to reach out to me. We can have a discussion about which is the better option for you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Dont+List+Your+Home+as+For+Sale+By+Owner.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Dont+List+Your+Home+as+For+Sale+By+Owner.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Some people believe it's better to list by themselves, as opposed to listing with an agent's help. This way, they won’t have to pay the agent’s commission or have to deal with constantly interacting with an agent. However, there are more reasons to sell with an agent than not. Why would a buyer ignore 95% of all other listings to look at a property that isn’t represented by an agent? To find out, watch my latest video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Oggie Penev</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Some people believe it's better to list by themselves, as opposed to listing with an agent's help. This way, they won’t have to pay the agent’s commission or have to deal with constantly interacting with an agent. However, there are more reasons to sell with an agent than not. Why would a buyer ignore 95% of all other listings to look at a property that isn’t represented by an agent? To find out, watch my latest video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Do if You’re the Victim of Tax Fraud</title>
        <link>http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com/what-to-do-if-youre-the-victim-of-tax-fraud.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Oggie Penev</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-17 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Taxes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Last week, I found out that I was a victim of a tax fraud—someone else filed my taxes instead of me. To make matters worse, I was in the middle of purchasing and refinancing a home, which could have created big problems for me. I was, fortunately, able to fix everything, but it took me a few hours’ worth of online research and phone calls.

If you’re ever faced with this kind of situation, here are the three steps you need to take.

First, remember that IRS officers only communicate by mail, not by phone. In my case, the scam worked like this: Someone filed my taxes, and I received and deposited a refund check. The scammer called me sometime afterward, posing as an IRS agent, and said there had been a mistake. They told me I would need to send the money back to them.

So, if you get a check from the IRS that you didn’t expect or looks suspicious, don’t cash that check. Also, don’t send money to anyone based on a phone call. Everything must be in writing and communicated by mail.

Second, call someone to confirm that there’s fraud being attempted. You can start with your accountant—they can confirm whether the check is real or fake and provide instructions on what to do next. If you’re in the middle of a home purchase or refinance, call your mortgage broker right away and let them know what’s going and that everything’s getting fixed. After that, call the IRS. The direct phone number for their fraud line is 1-800-908-4490. They will process your claim over the phone so you don’t have to file anything.

Since federal taxes and state taxes are separate, you’ll have to call your state tax office separately to notify them that there has been fraud and to file a claim. The number for Arizona’s state tax office is (602) 716-6300.

“Tax fraud is a common thing, so there’s no need to worry about it.”

You’ll also have to call a couple more places to let them know about the fraud. First is the Federal Trade Commission at 1-877-438-4338. Next is the Social Security Administration at 1-800-772-1213.

Lastly, take steps to prevent similar problems from happening down the road. You can do this by placing a 90-day fraud alert with the credit bureaus. The good thing here is that when you place a fraud alert with one credit bureau, the other two place it automatically. The number to contact Equifax is 1-800-525-6285.

Tax fraud is a common thing, so there’s no need to worry about it. Just follow these steps and you’ll be fine. In fact, according to IRS, a false tax return will not be disclosed if a mortgage company requests tax transcripts for the purpose of approving you for a loan, so this type of fraud attempt shouldn’t have any effect on a home purchase or refinance.

If you’d like more information on different kinds of tax fraud and how you can avoid these scams, I’ve included this link that leads you directly to the IRS website.

If you have any other questions about tax fraud or you’re thinking of buying, selling, or investing in real estate in the Phoenix area, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Taxes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Taxes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Last week, I got a $2,500 tax return check from the state of Arizona. My initial excitement was short-lived, however, because I remembered that I hadn’t actually filed my taxes yet. Today, I’ll go over the steps you need to take if you find out that someone stole your identity and filed your taxes. This will save you a lot of time and help you prevent the same thing from happening in the future. To find out how to protect yourself from tax fraud, watch my latest video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Oggie Penev</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Last week, I got a $2,500 tax return check from the state of Arizona. My initial excitement was short-lived, however, because I remembered that I hadn’t actually filed my taxes yet. Today, I’ll go over the steps you need to take if you find out that someone stole your identity and filed your taxes. This will save you a lot of time and help you prevent the same thing from happening in the future. To find out how to protect yourself from tax fraud, watch my latest video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Select an Investment Property</title>
        <link>http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com/how-to-select-an-investment-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Oggie Penev</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-30 08:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+How+to+Select+an+Investment+Property.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a few simple tips to follow if you’re planning on investing in real estate. These tips will ensure that you get the highest return on your investment.

There are three tips I’d like to cover, today.

1. Find the right location. In any area, the best locations are near the center of the city. This is where the good schools and the most jobs are. However, be careful not to pay for premium lots. Views don’t appreciate. Paying extra for things like this won’t bring you high returns.

“Investors should seek out properties that will bring you the most appreciation.”

2. Find the right type of home. It’s important to seek out properties that will bring you the most appreciation. Single-family homes with a minimum of three bedrooms and two bathrooms will be ideal for this. Avoid homes across from schools or on busy streets. Also, make sure there’s no pool. Pools bring extra expenses and extra liability.

3. Find the right price. Look at entry-level price points. In Phoenix, this means looking at properties that are less than $300,000. Entry-level properties are easier to rent and easier to sell.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+How+to+Select+an+Investment+Property.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+How+to+Select+an+Investment+Property.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Have you been thinking lately about getting started in the world of real estate investing? If you have, I’ve got three tips to share with you. These tips will be your key to getting the highest return on your investment.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Oggie Penev</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Have you been thinking lately about getting started in the world of real estate investing? If you have, I’ve got three tips to share with you. These tips will be your key to getting the highest return on your investment.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Find Your Dream Home With These 3 Creative Methods</title>
        <link>http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com/find-your-dream-home-with-these-3-creative-methods.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Oggie Penev</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-13 16:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Find+Your+Dream+Home+With+These+3+Creative+Methods+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’ll be giving you three creative suggestions of how to find distressed and off-market homes.

“A foreclosure auction is open for everybody, and they can buy the property at a pretty decent discount.”

1. Foreclosure auctions. In Arizona, when a homeowner stops making payments, the bank will try to work out a deal with them, but if they’re not successful, they’ll file for foreclosure. They’ll give the homeowner 90 days to pay whatever they owe, and if they haven’t paid that, then the home will be put up on a foreclosure auction. This auction is open for everybody, and they can buy the property at a pretty decent discount. You do need to be careful because you’re buying the property in as-is condition and you have to buy it with cash. You have to bring the cash within 24 hours of winning the bid.

2. Tax and court records. Through searching the tax and court records, you can find motivated sellers such as those going through a divorce, those who have tax defaults, probate estates, or anyone who might need to sell. However, a lot of these people might not want to sell, or don’t want to be bothered. Additionally, searching these records could be time-consuming.

3. Use direct marketing.This could mean using direct mail or phone calls. You can write to the homeowners and offer to buy the property, or if you like a specific subdivision, ZIP code, or city, you can pull phone numbers and call them directly. This approach can be successful for specific situations. However, it could also be very expensive, so be careful not to go over budget.

If you have any questions or need any help, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Find+Your+Dream+Home+With+These+3+Creative+Methods+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://oggiepenevrealtyblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Oggie+Penev/Videos/Penev+Realty+%257C+Find+Your+Dream+Home+With+These+3+Creative+Methods+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When it comes to seeking out a home, you have a lot of different options. Many choose the traditional MLS home search. However, there are some creative routes you can try if your situation calls for them. Today, I have three unconventional ways you can find the home of your dreams. One such method is to scope for foreclosure auctions. To learn more about this and the other two approaches, watch my latest video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Oggie Penev</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When it comes to seeking out a home, you have a lot of different options. Many choose the traditional MLS home search. However, there are some creative routes you can try if your situation calls for them. Today, I have three unconventional ways you can find the home of your dreams. One such method is to scope for foreclosure auctions. To learn more about this and the other two approaches, watch my latest video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Oggie Penev</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Oggie Penev</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Penev Realty Advisors - your professional Phoenix Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
