<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Northern Virginia Real Estate Podcast with Allen Johnson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from AJ Team - your professional Northern Virginia Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Allen Johnson</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-08-14 16:43:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Allen Johnson</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>careers@AJTeamRealty.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Allen Johnson</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Northern Virginia Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from AJ Team - your professional Northern Virginia Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Ultimate Guide to Attending a Real Estate Conference</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-ultimate-guide-to-attending-a-real-estate-conference.html</link>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-15 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

As an agent, attending a real estate conference can be extremely overwhelming. With all of the different options and information, how do you know what to implement into your business? Today, I have three key takeaways to make your next real estate conference successful.


  Go to the conference with one thing in mind. You can go in there with many ideas, but focusing on one thing will allow you to get more out of the conference.


“Go to the conference with one thing in mind.”


  
    Network smart. You’ll meet many people, and receive many business cards. Year after year, I’ve had to hand off a stack of business cards to my staff, as I didn’t have the capacity to follow up. I’ve learned to add people to social media immediately after meeting them, so that we can stay in touch.
  
  
    Ask yourself these three questions. Before you leave the real estate conference, there are three major questions you need to ask yourself. What is one thing you plan to implement in the next 48 hours? What is one thing you plan to implement in the next two weeks? What is one thing you plan to implement in the next month?
  


Thinking about these three things at your next real estate conference will allow you to get the most you can from the money you’re investing in your real estate career. If you have any other questions or are interested in furthering your real estate career, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I have three key takeaways to make your next real estate conference successful.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I have three key takeaways to make your next real estate conference successful.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>My Journey from Car Sales to Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-journey-from-car-sales-to-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Motivational Videos</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-04 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, we’re going to discuss my journey from car sales to real estate.

When I graduated from George Mason University, I needed a job. At the time, I had a friend in car sales that encouraged me to get into the business. I was definitely hesitant at first, but after I found out how much money I could make, I happily took the interview. The very next day I interviewed, and by the end of the week, I was selling cars!

There are many things I learned during my experience as a car salesman, one if which is a dedicated work ethic. If you’re in sales, you already know that you need to dedicate yourself to the customer. This means long days and long nights, no matter what the weather outside may look like. I also learned to swallow my pride. After earning a four-year degree, there’s a bit of a stigma selling used cars. I used the opportunity to work out my self-confidence.

“There are many things I learned during my experience as a car salesman, one if which is a dedicated work ethic.”

I was in car sales for two years and did really well. After speaking with my accountant and my father, I decided to buy a house. The next time my dad came up to visit, we went to a couple of open houses, where I connected with a Realtor. Long story short, she stood me up. As you can imagine, I wasn’t very happy. In fact, I took it as a sign to not buy property at all. The very next customer I had at the car dealership was another real estate agent, and that’s when I knew it was time to buy my first home.

Two months later, I was buying a house and taking real estate classes. I knew that if I had issues buying a home, that there were other people in my situation too. That’s when I made the decision to get into real estate.

It’s been 17 years since I’ve entered real estate, but there are a few things from my time as a car salesman that I will never forget:

Your friends will travel with you. There are so many people that I’ve sold both cars and houses to, and there are many people I still have wonderful relationships with.

Your database is extremely important. There are so many people in your life who will follow you into the next steps of your career.

Work ethic is important. When you’re selling someone a car, you really need to understand what they need. That lesson also goes for real estate. You can’t sell someone what you think is best for them, but what is actually best for them in the long run. Sometimes those conversations are easy, and sometimes they are difficult.

That’s my journey from car sales to real estate. If you have any other questions or are interested in furthering your real estate career, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, we’re going to discuss my journey from car sales to real estate.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, we’re going to discuss my journey from car sales to real estate.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Choose the Correct Path in Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-choose-the-correct-path-in-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Career Advice</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-16 08:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I hear this question at least a few different times per week: “I want to get into real estate. What should I do?” My initial response is to think about the question a little more and then get back to me. However, I want to answer the question once and for all today.

There are two ways to “get into” the real estate business. The first is real estate sales. That’s what we do here every day on the AJ Team. We take clients out, help them find properties, and ultimately, our job is to sell.

&lt;a href=”https://twitter.com/home/?status=”Most of the time, people aren’t talking about getting into the sales business.”%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-choose-the-correct-path-in-real-estate.html%20via%40” target=’_blank’ class=”pullquote”&gt;““Most of the time, people aren’t talking about getting into the sales business.””&lt;/a&gt;

Think of the highest pressure sales job you could ever think of, then add a layer of emotions on top, and multiply it by the fact that Northern Virginia is one of the craziest markets here in the U.S. I’d say that 99% of time when people say they want to get into real estate, this is not what they are talking about.

What most people are talking about when they say they want to get into real estate is actually real estate investing. That’s the other side of the ledger. Investors take their money, put it into properties, and watch it grow over time. Traditionally, this is the way that most people are looking to “get into” the real estate business.

If you want to get into real estate, start to think about which side you want to be on. When you’ve decided, we can help you get closer to achieving your goals by offering you advice and/or assistance. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I hear this question at least a few different times per week: “I want to get into real estate. What should I do?” My initial response is to think about the question a little more and then get back to me. However, I want to answer the question once and for all today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I hear this question at least a few different times per week: “I want to get into real estate. What should I do?” My initial response is to think about the question a little more and then get back to me. However, I want to answer the question once and for all today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>As the Market Turns</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/as-the-market-turns.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-11 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

“I often have this very same conversation with our sellers.”


					
						We&rsquo;re here today to discuss real estate &ldquo;as the market turns&rdquo;. I didn&rsquo;t intentionally plan on naming this video after the soap opera, but the market is shifting and I need all of you to be prepared for it. We&rsquo;ve been discussing the market shift for the last two years now, but I&rsquo;m starting to have more difficult conversations with sellers about what to do with their property. In some situations, they have to reduce the price, selling at less than what their neighbors sold for a year ago. There a lot of tough decisions that sellers have to make right now. 
						
						&nbsp;
					
					 
				

 


					
						
							
								"There a lot of tough decisions that sellers have to make right now."
							
						
					
				


					
					
						
							
							I&rsquo;m going to take you through a situation that happened to me personally. Remember, there 
								
							
							is a big difference between being able to sympathize and empathize. This is one situation in which 
								
							
							I can truly empathize with sellers that are perhaps a bit worried about selling their property.
								
							
							In 2005, I bought a property at the top of the market for $323,000. I held onto that property as an
								
							
							 investment property for 11 years. At the end of 2016, I ended up having to sell the property for only 
								
							
							$230,000. Having to write a check for $95,000 wasn&rsquo;t the easiest thing to do, but it was what I chose to do with the remaining money that made a huge difference.
								
							
						
						
						
						
							
							For my property to get back to its original purchase price, it would take two full market cycles. 
								
							
							That&rsquo;s well over 11 years. I starting thinking about where to put the money instead. 
								
							
							After a conversation with my financial advisor, I decided to pull my chips off the table and relocate 
								
							
							them into something that would give me a higher return.
								
							
						
						
						
						
							
							I often have this very same conversation with our sellers. Sometimes you need to take the loss and move on, because there is a better investment that can 
								
							
							get you where you want to be. When I sit down and speak with you, I&rsquo;m speaking from experience. 
								
							
							I&rsquo;ve had to write that check, too. I know exactly how you feel. 
								
							
						
						
						
						
							
							If you&rsquo;re currently in this situation about selling your home, let&rsquo;s sit down and have a conversation. 
								
							
							We&rsquo;ll come up with a decision based off facts instead of emotion. 
								
							
						
						
							
							If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon
								
							
						
					
				
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re here today to discuss real estate “as the market turns”.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re here today to discuss real estate “as the market turns”.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Three Ways to Get Your Offer Accepted in Today's Competitive Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/three-ways-to-get-your-offer-accepted-in-todays-competitive-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-23 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

“How is it possible to get your offer accepted in a competitive market? I’ve got three tips today to help you achieve this.”




					How is it possible to get your offer accepted in a competitive market?
					Imagine you&rsquo;ve been searching for months and have finally found your dream home. Now you want to write an offer, but you can&rsquo;t get the home. 
					This is a common problem. People think they can simply look at a home, write an offer, and prepare to move in. But this isn&rsquo;t how it works. You need a game plan from the start if you want to win in this market.
				
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How is it possible to get your offer accepted in a competitive market? I’ve got three tips today to help you achieve this.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How is it possible to get your offer accepted in a competitive market? I’ve got three tips today to help you achieve this.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do I Need a Realtor If I Buy New Construction?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-do-i-need-a-realtor-if-i-buy-new-construction.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-18 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

“hey don’t want you to hire an agent. So, you should hire an agent.”


					
						They don&rsquo;t want you to hire an agent. So, you should hire an agent. 
					
				




					Some people think that if they&rsquo;re going to buy a new home, they should do it on their own in order to get the best deal possible. They think that maybe they will save on commission costs or get a better deal. The truth is, none of that is true. 
				




					In fact, builders prefer working with teams like ours as opposed to a lone-wolf buyer. The reason why is because we have the potential to bring them multiple deals. Because of that, they give us better deals than you could typically get on your own.
				




					We work with several home builders, such as Ryan Homes, who are willing to give our clients better deals because they know that if they do, we will bring the next client back to get a good deal as well.
				


					
						
							
								"We work with several builders who have given great deals to our clients."
							
						
					
				




					If you are thinking of buying a new home, give us a call. It doesn&rsquo;t cost you a thing to work with us because our commission is covered by the builder, and we&rsquo;d love to help you get into the new home you&rsquo;ve been dreaming of.
				




					If you have any other questions in the meantime, don&rsquo;t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
				
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>hey don’t want you to hire an agent. So, you should hire an agent.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>hey don’t want you to hire an agent. So, you should hire an agent.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Good Agents Keep Negotiating Until the Very End</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/good-agents-keep-negotiating-until-the-very-end.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-10 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

When you sell your home, it’s very important that you hire an agent who will negotiate all the way through the deal.

We recently sold a property that was on the market for about 20 days before an offer came in. We went back and forth and got to the point where we were about to accept the offer when another one came on the table.

This second offer wasn’t necessarily as high as the one we already accepted, but we wanted to make sure that we continued to pay attention to it.

So, we almost got to the end of negotiations with the original buyer when they suddenly got flaky. This buyer ultimately bailed on the transaction for whatever reason.

An experienced listing agent is taught to negotiate through the deal. My communication with the new offer was consistent and crystal clear. I continued to call them and treat them like they were the bee’s knees so they felt like their offer was the only offer.

Had I not done that, our seller would have had to go back on the market and we would have had to find someone else to buy the house.

“My communication with the second buyer got the seller more money in the end.”

Not only that, the second offer ended up netting the seller more than the original offer because I continued to negotiate with them.

When you hire someone to sell your property, these are the small things that an experienced listing agent should be doing. Selling is more than pricing, staging, and painting, although those things are important. Ultimately, you need someone who understands how to negotiate and will put you in a position where you can win.

If you are thinking of selling your home or if you have any other questions, just give us a call or send us an email. After all, you have the dream; we have the address. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When you sell your home, it’s very important that you hire an agent who will negotiate all the way through the deal.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When you sell your home, it’s very important that you hire an agent who will negotiate all the way through the deal.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Crazy Story of 2 Home Inspections on the Same House</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-crazy-story-of-2-home-inspections-on-the-same-house.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-26 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

It’s time for me to tell you the tale of two home inspections.

We had a property on the market in Fairfax where the original buyer backed out. The buyer claimed they backed out due to the home inspection, but I know this wasn’t the case. The simple truth is that they got cold feet.

Only a matter of days later, another buyer came to the property and went under contract. This buyer ordered a home inspection, which gave us the opportunity to see two different inspections on the exact same property within about a five-day period.

This is where things got interesting. The two home inspections were both done by professionals, but ended up being completely different. Because they found completely different things to fix within the home, the buyers asked for completely different things following their respective inspections.

It’s because of scenarios like these that we encourage our sellers to negotiate a credit instead of fixing specific items. This just makes more sense, since the likelihood of two home inspections being exactly the same is slim to none.

I’ve seen this kind of situation many times in our business. If you aren’t careful, you may end up making fixes on home inspection items for a buyer who will ultimately back out, only to be asked about making completely different repairs from the next buyer.

Understand that there will always be things within your home that you never noticed or cared about but that will be important to a buyer.

Don’t make any hasty repairs before you list. There are certain things you should definitely fix, but sometimes those things aren’t what you might think. We can help you determine the right repairs, and help you move forward with your listing. The right repairs will make all the difference.

Even if you aren’t considering selling for another year, my team and I would still love to get in touch. The earlier you call, the more we can do to put you in the position to win.

If you have any other questions or would like more information. Feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’d like to tell you the tale of two home inspections. If a buyer backs out after a home inspection, what happens when the next buyer’s inspection results are completely different?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’d like to tell you the tale of two home inspections. If a buyer backs out after a home inspection, what happens when the next buyer’s inspection results are completely different?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Can’t Quite Trust Zillow’s Zestimates</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-cant-quite-trust-zillows-zestimates.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-22 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Online home valuations can give you an idea of what your home’s worth, but you shouldn’t price your home based on their calculations.

When selling their home, most people nowadays do their own online research on websites like Zillow so they can get an estimated value of what their home is worth. That’s a dangerous thing to do, however, and I have some numbers to show you why. Below is a list of homes we’ve sold in different areas this year and how wide the difference was between their Zillow Zestimates and their actual sold price:

A Clifton property was sold for $610,000, while its Zestimate was $611,000—a $1,000 difference.

A Lake Ridge property sold for $330,000, while its Zestimate was $386,000—a $56,000 difference.

A Manassas home sold for $485,000, while its Zestimate was $564,000—an $80,000 difference.

An Alexandria home sold for $735,000, while its Zestimate was $780,000—a $45,000 difference.

A Woodbridge home sold for $360,000, while its Zestimate was $435,000—a $75,000 difference. Why is Zillow a dangerous place to calculate your home’s value? Let me put it this way—has Zillow ever actually been into your house? Have you ever gone to Zillow and informed them about any of your home’s updates? Of course not. Zillow’s Zestimate is based on an algorithm that gives sellers unrealistic expectations of what their home is worth.If you’re thinking about selling a home, give us a call so we can give it a thorough, accurate valuation and you don’t leave money on the table once it’s sold. If you have any other questions about our market or determining your home’s value, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Online home valuations can give you an idea of what your home’s worth, but you shouldn't price your home based on their calculations.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Online home valuations can give you an idea of what your home’s worth, but you shouldn't price your home based on their calculations.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Help Us Help Our Community's Children</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/help-us-help-our-communitys-children.html</link>
        
          <category>Motivational Videos</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-04 17:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>


						It&rsquo;s time for this summer&rsquo;s annual backpack challenge.&nbsp;
					




						This year, we&rsquo;ll be donating pre-filled backpacks to children in need at a local homeless shelter as well as in local schools.&nbsp;
					




						But we can&rsquo;t do this alone. We&rsquo;d love to have your help.
					




						All you need to do is fill a backpack with school supplies such as erasers, pencils, crayons, and notebooks, and drop it off with us&mdash;we&rsquo;ll take care of the rest.
					


						
					


					
						
							
								"We&rsquo;d love to have your help."
							
						
					
				




						For your convenience, we have two drop-off sites you can bring your donations to.&nbsp;
					


						
					




						You can either drop off your pre-filled backpack at our office, which is located at 4310 Prince William Parkway, Suite 200, or with our cosponsors at the Frostie Moose&mdash;located at 12581 Milstead Way.
					




						But that&rsquo;s not all. As a way to thank you for your generosity, the Frostie Moose will be giving out coupons for free ice cream to anyone dropping off donations at their location.&nbsp;
					




						Of course we all love ice cream, but we also love taking care of our community.&nbsp;
					




						We&rsquo;re excited for the opportunity to help kids in need, and we hope you&rsquo;ll help us do so.&nbsp;
					




						If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
					
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>It’s time for this summer’s annual backpack challenge.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>It’s time for this summer’s annual backpack challenge.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do We Live Our Core Value "Be a Blessing"?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-we-live-our-core-value-be-a-blessing.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-13 17:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

&lt;a href=”https://twitter.com/home/?status=How Do We Live Our Core Value “Be a Blessing”?%20http://localhost:4000/how-do-we-live-our-core-value-be-a-blessing.html%20via%40” target=’_blank’ class=”pullquote”&gt;“How Do We Live Our Core Value “Be a Blessing”?”&lt;/a&gt;


						Today I want to talk about what &ldquo;be a blessing&rdquo; means to me, and how I recently had an opportunity to really serve my community.
					




						&ldquo;Be a blessing&rdquo; is our core value and is one of the things we take extremely seriously. It goes beyond just being a blessing to our clients, but also to our community, our family, and the other agents in the office. We want to make sure that wherever we are and whatever we do, we come from a standpoint of contribution to those around us.
					




						Awhile back, we held a toy drive in the community and had such an amazing response that we ended up with more toys, school supplies, and other needed school items than we anticipated. I called Lori Williams, who is on our county school board, and asked her what school would benefit most from these items. I got the number of a local school, Featherstone Elementary, and called the principal to ask her if I could come drop off those items.
					




						Later while I was there doing so, I asked her if there was anything else that we could do to help. She told me that they needed mentors, and from there we were able to build a fantastic mentoring program. We had a group of 5th graders that we met with regularly and taught them things they weren&rsquo;t learning in the classroom&mdash;including life skills like conflict resolution, how to tie a tie, how to shake someone&rsquo;s hand, and how to look a person in the eye.
					


					
						
							
								"We taught them things they weren&rsquo;t learning in the classroom."
							
						
					
				


						We really wanted to show these boys how to be cool young men, and give them a space where they could learn from college-educated business owners and other professionals about these life skills.&nbsp;
					




						The biggest challenge with this mentorship program was the time. We went there every Tuesday for the hour right after school, which cut right through the middle of the work day. We had a few instances where parents were unhappy that we were keeping them after school and confrontations would happen. It helped me remember that what we were doing there was showing the boys that there was a better way to handle situations just like that, which was a huge motivator in bringing us back every week.
					




						I&rsquo;m grateful that I had the chance to serve my community in this way. If you have any questions about this mentorship program or you&rsquo;re looking to buy or sell a home in our area, give me a call. I&rsquo;d be happy to help.
					
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How Do We Live Our Core Value "Be a Blessing"?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How Do We Live Our Core Value "Be a Blessing"?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mid Year Real Estate Review</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/mid-year-real-estate-review.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-20 17:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

“In the big picture, this is a healthy slow down. Homes are still appreciating, but not at a breakneck rate.”


						Today I wanted to bring you some statistics from today&rsquo;s local market.&nbsp;
					




						Here in Lake Ridge, the average sale price is up by 4%. In the past, we predicted we&rsquo;d be seeing a slow down year over year in this area, which is the case when you look at this number compared to last year&rsquo;s five or 6%.&nbsp;
					




						In the big picture, this is a healthy slow down. Homes are still appreciating, but not at a breakneck rate.&nbsp;
					




						Sellers should be happy to hear that the average days on market is down 28%. This will drive up demand because homes in good shape will sell quickly.&nbsp;
					


					
						
							
								"Buyers and sellers alike should be aware of how fast things can move on today&rsquo;s market."
							
						
					
				




						Because of this, buyers and sellers alike should be aware of how fast things can move on today&rsquo;s market.&nbsp;
					




						Finally, townhomes and condos are still selling at a much higher rate than this time last year, having experienced an increase of 7%.&nbsp;
					




						More and more, we&rsquo;re seeing people move out of condos for a number of reasons. Many people want larger living accommodations, and many others are simply tired of renting. This trend can definitely be expected to continue in the future, as well.
					




						If you have any other questions feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you, soon.
					
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In the big picture, this is a healthy slow down. Homes are still appreciating, but not at a breakneck rate.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In the big picture, this is a healthy slow down. Homes are still appreciating, but not at a breakneck rate.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Win $5000 for the Charity of Your Choice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/win-5000-for-the-charity-of-your-choice.html</link>
        
          <category>Motivational Videos</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-11 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

“We’re giving back to those in need in our community, and we need your help. Here’s how you can give back, too.”


						Today we&rsquo;re taking a break from real estate to talk about how we&rsquo;re fulfilling one of our core values, which is to be a blessing to others in our community.&nbsp;
					




						First, we have an initiative this month with the ACTS Homeless Shelter here in northern Virginia where we&rsquo;re acting as a drop-off site to help them collect donation items for those in need. ACTS is a transitional shelter intended for those who are going from one phase of their lives to the next, and they&rsquo;re in need of simple things that you and I take for granted. We want to help them collect these things so they can be a blessing to the less fortunate.&nbsp;
					


					
						
							
								"A generous person will prosper; whoever refreshes others will be refreshed."
							
						
					
				




						If you would like to help and make a donation, you can either call us or drop off any items you want to donate at our office. We want to be a resource for you to be able to give back.&nbsp;
					


						Click here for more information on how you can support ACTS 
					




						Secondly, we plan on donating the proceeds from our 100th transaction to your charity of choice. We&rsquo;ll be holding a poll on our Facebook page where you&rsquo;ll be able to vote which charity gets the proceeds. The grand total will be up to $5,000.&nbsp;
					




						We want to know what you care about and which charities move your heart and soul. If you could take some time and think about this, we&rsquo;d love to hear about it and we&rsquo;d love to see you vote.&nbsp;
					

				[



							
								
									
										
											Submit your nominee by Wednesday, Ma
												
													y
												 31th
												
													 for a chance to win up to
														
															$5,000 for the loc
																
																	al charity of your
																		
																			choice!
																		
																	
																
															
														
													
												
											
										
									
								
							
						
](https://www.ajteamrealty.com/100thhome/)




						Remember, you have the dream and we have the address. If you have any other questions, please feel free to give us a call. We&rsquo;d be happy to assist you.
					
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re giving back to those in need in our community, and we need your help. Here’s how you can give back, too.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re giving back to those in need in our community, and we need your help. Here’s how you can give back, too.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Trump Will Affect the Real Estate Market: Part 3</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-trump-will-affect-the-real-estate-market-part-3.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-19 15:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
					Whether you&rsquo;re buying or selling a home in our market, you need to pay attention to how interest rates are moving since the election.&nbsp;
				


					
					
						
							
						
					
					
						I expect President Trump&rsquo;s policies to produce a pause in our market. Here&rsquo;s what you can do to take advantage of that pause.&nbsp;
						
							
								Now that the new president is in office, what other changes can you expect him to make to our real estate market? As you may recall, we&rsquo;ve already touched on this topic in two previous videos, which you can see here&nbsp;and here. Today, we&rsquo;re focusing on policy and tax changes. What types of policies will the new president implement?
							
						
						
							
								One of the policies he&rsquo;s talked about is reducing regulation in our market. Less regulation tends to be more favorable to real estate development. With this in mind, an overhaul of the Dodd-Frank Act has been a hot topic in the news, lately. It also remains to be seen whether the administration will alter FHA and private mortgage insurance or get rid of those things altogether.
							
						
						
							
								The next thing to keep an eye on is lower capital gains. If President Trump lowers capital gains, how is that going to affect the investor market? Overall, I think you&rsquo;ll see a pause in our local market due to a lot of people waiting on the sidelines. How does this affect you? If you&rsquo;re a buyer, you want to buy during that pause because there will be more inventory and more opportunity for you to get a better deal.
							
						
						
							
								If you&rsquo;re a buyer, take advantage of the pause we&rsquo;re about to see.
							
						
						
							
								Personally, I&rsquo;m not in wait-and-see mode&mdash;I&rsquo;m in buy mode. Interest rates drive my economy, and I need to know if my money is cheap. If my money is cheap, I can do more with it.
							
						
						
							
								If you have any questions about this topic or would like to know more about what&rsquo;s happening in your local real estate market, please don&rsquo;t hesitate to reach out to us so we can sit and talk with you. You have the dream&mdash;I have the address.
							
						
					
				


					&nbsp;
				
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Whether you’re buying or selling a home in our market, you need to pay attention to how interest rates are moving since the election.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Whether you’re buying or selling a home in our market, you need to pay attention to how interest rates are moving since the election.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2 More Things to Consider in a Trump Presidency</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2-more-things-to-consider-in-a-trump-presidency.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-19 15:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
					Whether you&rsquo;re buying or selling a home in our market, you need to pay attention to how interest rates are moving since the election.&nbsp;
				


					
					
						
							
						
					
					
						President-elect Donald Trump has expressed a desire to increase defense spending. What will happen with our local real estate market if he does?
					
					
						
							There are a lot of things we&rsquo;ll need to keep an eye on during Donald Trump&rsquo;s presidency in terms of real estate. Here are two more factors we&rsquo;ll need to pay close attention to over the next four years:
						
					
					
						
							1. Real estate is local. It has always been about local real estate. What happens here is very different than what happens in the Midwest. Our economy is greatly influenced by big government and government spending. Donald Trump has talked about spending more money on the department of defense. If he does that, it means the economy is going to benefit in our area. If those things come to fruition, expect local real estate to see a jump.
						
					
					 
						
							2. Foreign money. On the flip side, President-elect Trump talked about being tougher on immigration. There are a lot of immigrants here in the area and a lot of international money, too. If foreign investors start to get skittish, they won&rsquo;t be spending as much in the local economy and they may decide to make other investments instead.
						
					
					
						
							Those are two important local real estate factors you should pay attention to. Think back to the market crash in 2008 and what happened in Prince William County. Immigration policy changed, the market crashed, and look what happened there.
						
					
					
						
							If you have any questions for us, don&rsquo;t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you.
						
					
				


					
						
							
						
					
				


					&nbsp;
				
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Whether you’re buying or selling a home in our market, you need to pay attention to how interest rates are moving since the election.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Whether you’re buying or selling a home in our market, you need to pay attention to how interest rates are moving since the election.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Will Trump’s Election Affect Our Real Estate Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-will-trumps-election-affect-our-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-22 15:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
					Whether you&rsquo;re buying or selling a home in our market, you need to pay attention to how interest rates are moving since the election.&nbsp;
				


					
					
						
							Now that the 2016 presidential election has come and gone, what kind of impact can we expect President-elect Donald Trump to have on our Northern Virginia market?
						
					
				


					
						
							As we all know, Trump&rsquo;s former business was real estate development, so that in itself should be beneficial. There&rsquo;s still a lot of uncertainty hanging in the air, though. The thing we&rsquo;re watching most closely are interest rates.&nbsp;
						
					
				


					The day after the election, rates went from 3.5% to almost 4%.
						
							 That was triggered by a big sell-off in the bond market. This really affected buyers&rsquo; affordability. We ourselves had a client who was quoted a rate of 3.5% before the election, and afterward, the rate jump increased her monthly payment by $200.&nbsp;
						
					
				

&nbsp;


					
						
							So, if you think there&rsquo;s a lot of uncertainty now, imagine what&rsquo;s going to happen after the inauguration. 
						We&rsquo;re paying close attention to when the Federal Reserve meets this month, and you&rsquo;d better believe that rates are going up after that happens.
						
							 I expect them to rise to the mid-4% range.
						
					
				

&nbsp;


					
						
							Whether you&rsquo;re buying or selling a home, pay attention to the interest rates.
						
					
					
						&nbsp;
					
				


					
						
							Now, there are a few other things in the real estate market that will be affected by a Trump Presidency as well: What's happening in local real estate, and&nbsp;Policy and Tax Changes.
						
					
					
						
							Not all of this could be broken down into one video, so I encourage you to check out the other videos in this series by clicking here.
						
					
					
						
							Finally, if you have any questions about how the election will affect our real estate market, please don&rsquo;t hesitate to reach out to me by phone or email. I&rsquo;d be happy to help!&nbsp;
						
					
				


					&nbsp;
				
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Whether you’re buying or selling a home in our market, you need to pay attention to how interest rates are moving since the election.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Whether you’re buying or selling a home in our market, you need to pay attention to how interest rates are moving since the election.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do Home Sellers Need to Look at Interest Rates?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-do-home-sellers-need-to-look-at-interest-rates.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-09 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>


						Realtors always talk about how interest rates affect home buyers. Today, however, we&rsquo;re going to focus on how interest rates affect your ability to sell a property.&nbsp;
					


						First of all, you need to know the 1%, 10% rule. If interest rates go up by 1%, home values go down by 10%. On the other hand, if interest rates go down 1%, home values will rise 10%.&nbsp;
					


					
						If interest rates go up by 1%, your home value will go down 10%
					
				


						Right now, interest rates are at 3.5%. If your home is currently worth $500,000 and rates go up to 4.5%, you will lose 10% off of your home value. In other words, your home value will go down by $50,000. Most people don&rsquo;t talk about the 1%, 10% rule for home sellers, but it&rsquo;s something you need to keep in mind if you are considering selling your home.&nbsp;
					

 


						Here is a quick history lesson for you: in 2013, interest rates were at 4.5%. During 2008, the bottom of the market, interest rates were at 6%. Now, I don&rsquo;t think that rates will skyrocket and drastically impact the economy in the next 12 months. However, I do think that 3.5% interest rate will look very different at this time next year.&nbsp;
					

 


						If you are selling your home, you also need to consider how interest rates will affect your buyer. If interest rates go up, your potential buyer&rsquo;s mortgage payment will go up. Not only that, they may not be able to afford your house if the 3.5% interest rate goes up. If you are looking to sell your property, I recommend selling when rates are low so that more people can afford your home and your home value will go up.&nbsp;
					

 


						Finally, here in Northern Virginia, there are not many cash buyers in our market. Roughly 95% of people buying homes in our market use some kind of financing, so you need to consider interest rates and the value of your home when deciding whether or not to sell.&nbsp;
					

 


						If you have any other questions about interest rates or selling your home in the current market, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
					
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Why Do Home Sellers Need to Look at Interest Rates?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why Do Home Sellers Need to Look at Interest Rates?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Know When to Sell Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-know-when-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-21 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>


						
							
								
									When is the best time to sell your home? Most people think that the best time of year to sell is in the spring or summer, but that is not necessarily true for all markets. 
								 &nbsp;&nbsp;
						
					


						
							
								
									If you are trying to figure out when to sell your home, there are a few things you should consider: 
								 &nbsp; 
						
					


  
    
							
								 What are your neighbors doing?
									
										 If all of your neighbors are waiting until spring to put your home on the market, that means your competition will go up in the spring. Generally, when competition goes up, home prices tend to go down. 
									
								
							
						
  
  
    
							
								 Pay attention to pricing and positioning. 
									
										Make sure you price and position your home properly in the market. As far as positioning, it can be beneficial to be on the market when most of your neighbors are not. You should also make sure that your home is priced competitively for the market. 
									
								
							
						
  
  
    
							
								 What kind of home are you selling? 
									
										Are you selling a condo, a single-family home, or a townhome? Depending on what kind of property you are selling, you will be working to attract a different kind of buyer. 
									
								
							
						
  



						
							
								
									For example, if you are selling a single-family home, the buyer you are looking for will probably have kids. The buyer&rsquo;s schedule may be governed by when school is open and when school is closed, so you need to make sure that your home is available when that buyer is able to make a move. 
								 &nbsp;&nbsp;
						
					


						
							
								
									If you are selling a condo or townhome, your buyer may be young and single, or married with kids that are too young to be in school. These buyers move when their leases are up, when they save enough money, or when interest rates are low enough that they can afford the property. 
								 &nbsp;
								
									As you can see, part of putting your home on the market is considering the buyer&rsquo;s profile. You need to understand your ideal buyer and when they will be able to move. 
								 &nbsp; &nbsp;
						
					


						
							
								
									So, when you&rsquo;re thinking about the best time to sell your home, don&rsquo;t just focus on the season. There are plenty of other factors to pay attention to. 
								 &nbsp;
								
									In other news, We recently moved our office right in the middle of Lake Ridge, and we are excited to be here. We have even heard some rumblings that HGTV is filming in the area! We&rsquo;ll go into more detail on that later. 
								
								
									If you have any questions about preparing your home for the market or about real estate in general, give us a call or send us an email. 
								
							
						
					
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How Do You Know When to Sell Your Home?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How Do You Know When to Sell Your Home?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is Happening in the Northern Virginia Real Estate Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-happening-in-the-northern-virginia-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-18 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

“Low interest rates have spurred the market on and made homes more affordable.”


					
						
							
								
									&ldquo;Is it a buyer&rsquo;s or seller&rsquo;s market?&rdquo; I get that question all the time, and it&rsquo;s a loaded question. In Northern Virginia, we kind of live in a bubble; our real estate reality is not the same as the rest of the nation&rsquo;s. 
								
								
									Let&rsquo;s dive into some numbers so 
								you can be proactive about your real estate decisions
								
									 instead of reactive.
								
								
									The average days on market right now is 40 days. If you&rsquo;re out in tertiary markets, the suburbs, or Loudoun, that number is a bit higher. If you&rsquo;re in Alexandria, Arlington, or Annandale, that number is a bit lower. 
								
								
									The X factor that determines whether we&rsquo;re in a buyer&rsquo;s or seller&rsquo;s market is actually 
								the price of your money. 
								
									Interest rates were expected to go a bit higher this year but rates have actually gone down. Right now, rates are hovering around 3.5%. To put that in perspective, the lowest rates ever recorded were low to mid three&rsquo;s in 2012.
								
							
						
					
				
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What Is Happening in the Northern Virginia Real Estate Market?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What Is Happening in the Northern Virginia Real Estate Market?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Would You Help Us Be a Blessing to Families in Need?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/would-you-help-us-be-a-blessing-to-families-in-need.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2016-10-13 16:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

 

“Help us be a blessing to 15 families in need.”


					Last year, we were fortunate enough to bless five different families who needed gifts for their kids. You guys went out of your way to help them in an extraordinary way. Each year, we try to level it up, so this year, we&rsquo;re trying to help 15 families here in the Northern Virginia community. When you&rsquo;re blessed, you&rsquo;re able to bless even more!
					
				


					We&rsquo;re reaching out to you in hopes that you can help us be a blessing to these families this holiday season.
				




					Click here to help us give gifts to these families and their children, and help them with a few things that we take for granted. 
				




					I can personally tell you that giving gifts sure makes my two favorites assistants here happy!
				




					There are plenty of things you can give&mdash;anything helps. We like to give the parents time to give these gifts to their kids, so we love for you to hustle up with us and help us give a happy holiday to some families in need.
				




					If you have any questions about how to help, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
				
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Help us be a blessing to 15 families in need.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Help us be a blessing to 15 families in need.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Join Us in the 2016 Backpack Challenge!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/join-us-in-the-2016-backpack-challenge.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Allen Johnson</author>
        <pubDate>2016-08-02 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>


						
							
								We've always been big advocates of supporting the local community, and this time, we wanted to give you the chance to help us out with the Community Backpack Challenge 2016.
							 We're excited to invite you to help us set our local youth up for success in the future.
							
								We're collecting pre-filled backpacks for elementary and middle school aged kids, starting now! 
							We'll collect backpacks all the way up to the end of August
							
								. You can drop off contributions at our Keller Williams Alexandria office, 6408 Grovedale Dr. #101, Alexandria, VA 22192. You can also drop off at Tropical Smoothie Woodbridge, or set up a personal pick-up if you give us a call or send us an email.
							 Ideas for included supplies include: 
					


  
    
							
								Wide-rule notebooks
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Crayons (24 box)
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Glue sticks
							
						
  
  
    
							
								#2 pencils
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Colored Pencils
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Pencil box
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Plastic folders
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Glue bottle
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Pencil sharpener
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Washable markers
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Yellow highlighter
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Large erasers
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Wide-ruled paper
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Three-ring binder
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Blue, black, and red pens
							
						
  
  
    
							
								Ruler
							
						
  



						
							Thank you so much for joining us as we help support the local school community! If you have any further questions, please feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We hope to see you soon!
						
					
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Join Us in the 2016 Backpack Challenge!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Allen Johnson</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Join Us in the 2016 Backpack Challenge!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Virginia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Allen Johnson</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Allen Johnson</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from AJ Team - your professional Northern Virginia Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
