<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Real Estate Podcast with Kati Spaniak</title>
    <link>http://realestategrit.net</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://realestategrit.net"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Real Estate Grit - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Kati Spaniak</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-08-22 10:47:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Kati Spaniak</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Kati@SpaniakTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Kati Spaniak</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://realestategrit.net/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Chicago Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Real Estate Grit - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Set Boundaries With Clients</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-to-set-boundaries-with-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-24 10:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/June/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+to+Set+Boundaries+With+Clients.mp4</guid>
        <description>

One of the biggest complaints among those working in real estate is that it’s a 24/7 job. In truth, though, it doesn’t have to be. In fact, it shouldn’t be. 

Have you ever found yourself up in the middle of the night texting or emailing a buyer or seller? If so, then it’s time to establish some boundaries. 

But how do you do so? What’s the best way to establish boundaries with your clients?

There are three main steps you need to take: 

1. Think about what you want your life to be like. For some, this means being off-the-clock by a certain time of night. If you don’t want clients to text you at 11 p.m., then make it clear from the beginning that you’re only available until 6 p.m. Making a clear distinction between which points in your day (and your week) are dedicated to clients and which points are dedicated to your personal life will be essential to maintaining a good work/life balance. 

“Sticking to your boundaries will improve your well-being both on and off the clock.”

2. Figure out how much you want to work on weekends. Many showings occur on the weekends, but this doesn’t mean you have to be available at every waking minute of every day. If a client calls you and wants to see a house, simply tell them when you’re available. Keep that window of time consistent so that you still have time for yourself and your loved ones. Everyone needs time off, after all. 

3. Don’t break your own boundaries. If you give an inch, people will take a mile. For your own sake (and for your family’s sake), make sure that you stick to the boundaries you set for yourself. Doing so will improve your well-being both on and off the clock. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/June/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+to+Set+Boundaries+With+Clients.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/June/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+to+Set+Boundaries+With+Clients.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Setting boundaries with your clients is essential, and there are three steps you must take to achieve this.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Setting boundaries with your clients is essential, and there are three steps you must take to achieve this.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is It Like to Be an Agent?</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/what-is-it-like-to-be-an-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-10 14:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/June/Real+Estate+GRIT-+What+Is+it+Like+to+Be+an+Agent_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Often at the end of a particularly difficult deal, clients will ask me, “How do you do it?” Well, the more I think about it, this is an interesting question. 

And now that I’ve taken some time to consider my answer, it’s really quite simple: I do this because I love helping people. Buying or selling a home is much more than just a simple, run-of-the-mill business transaction. There’s a lot of emotion that goes along with it. And, as an agent, I know that I need to play a much greater role than just that of a salesperson. I have to be someone who they can trust to guide them through a massive step in their life. 

“The job of an agent is often much more than just a job.”

When you are a real estate agent, being communicative, patient, and open-minded is a must. Buyers and sellers give their agents a window into some very personal aspects of their lives, so having these qualities is essential. Buyers and sellers deserve to know that their agent will keep private matters private. Honesty, confidentiality, and respect are very important. 

With that said, though, I also find it important to be honest even when it’s uncomfortable. 

At the end of the day, the job of an agent is often much more than just a job. And, personally, I wouldn’t have it any other way. 

If you have any other questions or would like to speak in greater detail on this topic, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/June/Real+Estate+GRIT-+What+Is+it+Like+to+Be+an+Agent_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/June/Real+Estate+GRIT-+What+Is+it+Like+to+Be+an+Agent_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>People sometimes ask me what it’s like to be an agent, and today I’ve decided to finally share my answer to this common question.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>People sometimes ask me what it’s like to be an agent, and today I’ve decided to finally share my answer to this common question.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Should Agents Select Homes to Show Clients?</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-should-agents-select-homes-to-show-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-14 16:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/May/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+Should+Agents+Select+Homes+to+Show+Clients_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you are working with a buyer, you should really only show them a maximum of eight to 10 homes. If you are providing services like a buyer consultation up front, you should not have to show them more properties than this. Buyers these days are very busy, so it is important not to waste their time.

Personally, I like to streamline the process by having a conversation with my clients about what non-negotiable features their future home must have. It is essential that you find out what a client needs and wants in a home. Knowing what is important to them will guide you in selecting viable properties. 

That said, it is also important to be honest with your clients. If their list of wants and needs isn’t feasible, you have to tell them that. Your buyers should have a realistic expectation of the kinds of homes that are available. 

As agents, we know what is available. Our clients shouldn’t have to tour 50 different homes to learn something we already know. 

“Knowing what is important to your clients will guide you to selecting viable properties.”

For example, if a client says they have a non-negotiable budget of $500,000 or less, but they also demand to see homes of a specific size and in a specific location, you must be honest with them about their prospects. And as you explain their options, make sure you continually check in with whether they are comfortable with the choices you are laying out for them. Clients should understand that you are not going to show them homes that do not fit their criteria. 

Yet this does not mean clients will not ask you to show them homes that do not make sense. This is why you, as their agent, should do your research before taking them to any property they suggest. If the property they are pushing you toward truly is not a good fit, I would advise you to steer them away from it. 

Sometimes, you may have to reevaluate their preferences and needs later on in the process. If you have toured dozens of homes with no results, something is wrong. At this point, it is time to go back to basics and get to the bottom of what your clients are looking for in a home.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/May/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+Should+Agents+Select+Homes+to+Show+Clients_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/May/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+Should+Agents+Select+Homes+to+Show+Clients_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is the secret to selecting homes to show your clients? Let’s take a look at what process you should follow.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is the secret to selecting homes to show your clients? Let’s take a look at what process you should follow.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Build Relationships With Potential Clients</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-to-build-relationships-with-potential-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-29 14:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/April/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+to+Build+Relationships+With+Potential+Clients.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I find it interesting to watch how people work with their clients. So, I decided that today I am going to talk about how to build relationships with potential clients. I have found that coming across as a consultant results in people trusting and valuing you. Years ago, I took a sales training class where they talked about how you cannot go into a situation feeling like you need the money. If you go in thinking that you are financially secure, you are going to build a relationship with that potential client. I come from a place of giving back to my clients. When you meet someone, you really want to listen to what they are looking for and decide if you are really able to help them. If you are not able, tell them. You will get much further in life with your client by being honest. Sometimes this means that you must be a little confrontational. I am personally not great at being confrontational, so I try to tone it down. For agents who have a really hard time with needing to be liked by everyone, this can be a little challenging.“The client needs to understand that they will not necessarily get everything that they want.”An example of this is when you have a client who has specific wants. They want a 3-bedroom, 3-bathroom home within walking distance to downtown and is completely updated for $500,000. This is not possible, but some agents will neglect to tell their clients this and instead tell them they will find it. The client needs to understand that they will not necessarily get everything that they want. When they start their home search and discover that nothing is matching well, that is a problem. It is your job to guide them using your communication skills. You must have those uncomfortable conversations so you don’t end up showing them 20 homes and none of them match. If this happens, they will eventually go to another agent. You really have to understand what a client is looking for and be honest with them. You need to guide them and communicate with them that they may not get exactly what they want. Being honest may lead to you not getting the sale, but the client will view you as trustworthy. So, when I am working with people, I really try and connect with them as a consultant. I provide them information about the real estate industry and am sure to be myself. I enjoy hearing their story and deciding if I can help them or not. To find out more about how to build relationships with your clients, please feel free to contact me. I would be happy to speak with you further about this.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/April/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+to+Build+Relationships+With+Potential+Clients.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/April/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+to+Build+Relationships+With+Potential+Clients.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Although it may seem like you could lose a potential client, you have to be honest with them so nobody ends up unhappy.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Although it may seem like you could lose a potential client, you have to be honest with them so nobody ends up unhappy.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We’re Looking for New People to Sell Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/were-looking-for-new-people-to-sell-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-12 11:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/April/Real+Estate+GRIT-+Were+Looking+for+New+People+to+Sell+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Does anyone in your circle of family, friends, co-workers, or acquaintances want to sell real estate?

We are always looking for great additions to the team, and we’re not just searching for people with experience in real estate—we’re looking for anyone who is personable, authentic, great with sales, hard-working, and self-accountable.

Here at the Spaniak Team, we offer the opportunity to learn, grow, get leads, and start out your career using a base of people you know. 

“On our team, we think that you should be making at least $50,000 in your first year.”

A lot of times, agents get into the business and it takes a few years in order for them to start making money. However, on our team, we think that you should be making at least $50,000 in your first year. In your second year, we hope that you can even make as much as $150,000 or more.

So think about it: Do you know anyone who would be a great fit on our team? If so, please forward this email to them. You can access the information about how to apply here.

It’s okay if you don’t know of anyone right now—but keep this in mind for the future. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/April/Real+Estate+GRIT-+Were+Looking+for+New+People+to+Sell+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/April/Real+Estate+GRIT-+Were+Looking+for+New+People+to+Sell+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Instead of answering a question, today I want to ask YOU one: Do you know anyone who wants to sell real estate?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Instead of answering a question, today I want to ask YOU one: Do you know anyone who wants to sell real estate?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How I Slowly but Surely Built a Successful Real Estate Business</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-i-slowly-but-surely-built-a-successful-real-estate-business.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-27 12:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

People ask me all the time, “How did you get started in real estate?”

Today I would like to tell you the answer to this question. So, let’s take a look back at how I got my start.

I entered this industry back in 2003 when I got my license and began working as part of a real estate team. This chapter in my career lasted until about 2008, when I left the team and took a few years off from this path. 

Ultimately, though, I did come back. I got a new license in 2012 and started up the team that I am still leading today. Since then, I have built my business to be among the top real estate professionals on the North Shore of Chicago and the Number One Team in Northbrook. 

And, actually, being in the business prior to founding my current team proved to be a great benefit as I re-entered the industry. It gave me time to really focus on my business plan, as well as my plan for daily activities. Immediately after re-entering real estate, I was very committed to dedicating certain days and times to being in the office working on my business plan. From the very beginning, my goal was to be the No. 1 agent in Northbrook. I wanted people in this community to think of me as their go-to real estate professional.

So, once I had developed a plan, I began reaching out to people. I started sending out emails, I took out a little bit of advertising space, and I began providing market evaluations for community members. And I did this because whether people are moving or not, everyone loves real estate.

“I wanted people in this community to think of me as their go-to real estate professional.”

Diving deeper into real estate was a slow-going process, but I kept going. I continued to put my name out there and provide services for the community, knowing that it would eventually pay off. After about six months of doing this, people began to notice. They would say things like, “You’re everywhere!” 

In actuality, I wasn’t everywhere. I was just making sure to stay visible in the places that mattered. I kept my focus small and found my niche. Doing this, in my opinion, is one of the keys to building a business. Being persistent without making people feel as though they are being constantly sold to is what put me on the path to success. If you hope to build a business, you have to show people what kind of value you can provide for them. 

Even if someone has no immediate real estate need, it is good to establish yourself as a resource. That way when the time does come for them to make a move, they know who to reach out to. 

Another way I got my start and established myself within the community was by hosting roundtable discussions about Northbrook. Doing this allowed me to meet a lot of people without spending a lot of money in the process. 

Everything you do as an agent should be done with a certain question in mind: “What do people need and want from you as a real estate agent?”

Being an agent is not about being a salesperson—it is about being someone who the community can turn to for their real estate needs. If you work toward this and do so consistently, you are sure to find success in your business.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I would like to share the story of how I got started in real estate. I hope that this look into my past will help you grow a better future.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I would like to share the story of how I got started in real estate. I hope that this look into my past will help you grow a better future.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Generate Leads</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-to-generate-leads.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-12 13:54:40 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Generating leads is a huge part of growing your business. You can get started by simply picking up the phone and making some calls—and it works great! But the reasoning behind why this works goes much deeper. What you’re really doing is nurturing a relationship with your database of contacts, so today I’ll be sharing with you how to find those leads and turn them into future clients.

For your convenience, I’ve included timestamps of the video topic. Feel free to navigate to the section(s) you’re most interested in viewing:

“What you’re really doing is nurturing a relationship with your database of contacts.”

00:12— Introduction to today’s topic: How to get leads00:57— The best way to get leads01:54— Cultivating relationships is more important than finding leads02:55— How to position yourself as a valuable source03:50— If they choose someone else, it’s nothing personal04:36— The ultimate goal: Connecting on a personal level05:50— Anyone can be a lead06:10— Summary of today’s topic

If you have any questions or need further information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Finding a lead is just the first step in gaining a future client. Here’s how to go about the process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Finding a lead is just the first step in gaining a future client. Here’s how to go about the process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Should Sellers Approach Our Spring Market?</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-should-sellers-approach-our-spring-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-08 11:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What should we expect from our spring market in 2019? Specifically, what should sellers do to prepare for it?

We started 2019 with a great spike in activity, and my team and I sold a handful of properties that had been on the market for months. With that in mind, my advice for sellers as we move toward spring is to list your house as soon as possible.

While it’s true that the weather is better come springtime, buyers are out shopping for homes all year long. You may need to work around bouts of extreme cold, but it’s important for your home to be on the market even if the market isn’t great.Buyers can be difficult, and they like to look at houses online before seeing them in person, so your first order of business should be to make your home’s online listing photos look perfect. Also, don’t go overboard with how many photos you use. When I take photos of a home, I usually don’t use more than 15 or 20 shots unless it’s a luxury home or a new construction home. Why? You don’t need to document every inch of your house, and if a buyer sees a bathroom that needs to be redone, they’ll count that as a reason not to look at the house in person.

“My advice for sellers as we move toward spring is to list your house as soon as possible.”

Another thing you can consider doing is virtual staging. I don’t always do this with my sellers because I find it to be a little deceptive, but it does help attract buyers. For example, one of my sellers has a house with carpeted floors, but underneath the carpet is hardwood, so that’s what we showed in the home’s pictures. 

As with every other time of year, you also need to make sure you price your home correctly. If your home is still unsold when June or July rolls around because it’s priced too high, you might end up in a race to the bottom with other panicked home sellers who have to slash their prices and ride the market down. The trick is to get under the market—not ride it down. 

Overall, I predict that we’ll see the same type of spring market this year that we saw last year. In the meantime, we’re off to a pretty good start and we’ll see how the rest of February goes. 

If you have any more questions about our upcoming spring market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The spring market will be here before you know it, so here’s what you need to do to sell your home quickly and for top dollar.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The spring market will be here before you know it, so here’s what you need to do to sell your home quickly and for top dollar.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Most Important of the 20 C’s: Coachable</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/the-most-important-of-the-20-cs-coachable.html</link>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-31 09:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Real+Estate+GRIT-+The+Most+Important+Quality+of+a+Successful+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to separate yourself from all the other agents out there and take your career to the next level, you need to remember the 20 C’s. In time, I’ll share all of these with you and explain why each one is important, but for today I’ll start with the most important C: coachable. 

As an agent, you have to be coachable. This isn’t about needing to hire a coach; it’s about opening your eyes to the opportunities that are out there to learn from. 

I can sit down with anyone, even those who don’t have as much experience as me, and learn something from them. Why? Because my eyes are open. I’m willing to listen to them, and I believe that everybody has something to provide me.

“This isn’t about you getting a coach; it’s about you opening your eyes to the opportunities that are out there to learn from.”

Along with being coachable, you have to continue your education. In real estate, education means learning about the real estate industry and learning how to sell. You have to do these things if you want to be successful, and that’s why being coachable is so valuable. 

So open your mind and keep education at the forefront of your life. Every day I educate myself, and ever since I started doing this, my business has taken off. And don’t forget to learn from other people—even if you think they don’t know anything, they probably do, and you can identify bits and pieces of information that can help you. 

To register for my next agent seminar where I’ll talk more in depth about the 20 C’s, click here.

In the meantime, if you want to talk more about the relationship between coachability and success or you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Real+Estate+GRIT-+The+Most+Important+Quality+of+a+Successful+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Real+Estate+GRIT-+The+Most+Important+Quality+of+a+Successful+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Being coachable is the most important quality you need to be successful in real estate, and here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Being coachable is the most important quality you need to be successful in real estate, and here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Benefits of Joining a Real Estate Team?</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/what-are-the-benefits-of-joining-a-real-estate-team.html</link>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-15 12:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Real+Estate+GRIT-+The+Advantages+of+Being+on+a+Team.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Why should you join a real estate team? I hear this question a lot. Our team has five licensed agents in addition to myself, and here’s what I think about real estate teams.

A team environment is not for everyone. It’s for agents who want to make good money, who want to sell, and who don’t necessarily need to have their name out there in lights. 

Here’s how my team is set up. I have five buyer’s agents and I take care of all the listings. In addition, I have a director of operations, a listing manager, and am currently hiring a transaction coordinator. I also have three unlicensed assistants, as well as a full-time runner. 

We are a full-service team with our own office and we work pretty independently. Our goal is to make life awesome for our agents by providing leads, transaction coordination, and other support. If you like working with a team and like the camaraderie, we provide a ton of value.“100% of nothing is still nothing.”

The agents on my team have minimal expenses. They pay for their MLS fees and dues, but we pay for all the leads, marketing expenses, and office expenses that they might have.

A lot of agents get hung up on the splits. What I’d say to that is that 100% of nothing is still nothing. On a team, you can make more money than you can as a regular agent, and it’s much more consistent too. 

Being on a team isn’t easy, especially if you’re an agent on my team. I want people who are dedicated and focused on their careers and who want to work hard. I listen to what agents want and take it very seriously. If you tell me you want to make $150,000 per year and you aren’t taking the necessary steps to get there, I will let you know that and push you to reach your goals. 

My team members don’t have to pay for coaching because I am their coach. I provide resources, support, and a full CRM for our agents. I also hold them accountable to their goals.

In a nutshell, that’s what it’s like to be on a team like mine. I’m always looking for great team members so if you think you have what it takes based on what you’ve heard, feel free to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Real+Estate+GRIT-+The+Advantages+of+Being+on+a+Team.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Real+Estate+GRIT-+The+Advantages+of+Being+on+a+Team.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Joining a real estate team isn’t a move that every real estate agent should make. However, there are quite a few advantages that agents who are part of a team can enjoy.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Joining a real estate team isn’t a move that every real estate agent should make. However, there are quite a few advantages that agents who are part of a team can enjoy.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Set Yourself Up for Success in Our Shifting Market</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/set-yourself-up-for-success-in-our-shifting-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-18 16:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+can+you+prepare+for+our+shifting+market%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does a shifting market mean for you as a real estate agent?

I’m not nervous about it, because I know that if I’m consistent, I keep up with the market, and I keep doing the activities I’m supposed to be doing, my team and I will continue to do well. In a shifting market, a lot of agents tend to get out of the business because they can no longer fund their lifestyle. Going into fall and winter, the market is always slower, so what can you do to set yourself up for success and keep earning the income you need?

First, you need to work harder. You have to work more hours than your competition and time block so that you’re lead generating two to three hours a day. This is not the time to be working on your business plan; this is the time to reach out and connect. In a shifting market, you need to be touching around 25 people a day. This doesn’t mean just sending out 25 texts; this means getting responses from 25 different people. This is hard to do, but if you’re connecting with that many people a day, five days a week, you won’t feel the shifting market. If anything, your market share will increase. 

During your time blocking sessions, you can also go door-knocking. If you don’t have any listings, find someone in your office who does, ask if you can sit in during one of their open houses, and go door-knocking through that home’s neighborhood.

“This is not the time to be working on your business plan; this is the time to reach out and connect.”

Another thing you can do is set up some coffee appointments with your 20 influencers. Sit down with the people who love you and would refer you and have an honest conversation with them about the shifting market and how they can help you take your business to the next level. Set those appointments, mark them down on your calendar, and don’t stop until you’ve asked for those referrals. 

Additionally, you can call FSBOs and expired listings. A lot of agents make all of their business just handling these two types of listings. You may not be an expert over the phone or familiar with the scripts, but you can still pick a couple of these listings to pursue and connect with them consistently. Pick the ones you really want to have a relationship with. 

If you’re really stuck, open up your database, pick 30 people you know, do a CMA for each one, and send them listings the very moment they come on the market in their area. Everybody wants to know when houses come on the market, and this way you can see when they log in to your site and whether they look at any listings. 

Again, though, I can’t stress enough the importance of time blocking for lead generation first. If you don’t set aside time, you won’t succeed. You need to take our shifting market seriously, so don’t just sit back and wait for the phone to ring. As someone who does a lot of business, I can tell you that it’s not the way to set yourself up for success. 

If you have any other questions about preparing yourself for our shifting market or you want to talk about your business plan, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+can+you+prepare+for+our+shifting+market%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Real+Estate+GRIT-+How+can+you+prepare+for+our+shifting+market%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our market is shifting, but there are several things you can do to set yourself up for success and increase your business during this time.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our market is shifting, but there are several things you can do to set yourself up for success and increase your business during this time.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Overpricing Is the Worst Mistake an Agent Can Make</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/why-overpricing-is-the-worst-mistake-an-agent-can-make.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-04 14:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Have you ever heard of being the “third agent in?” This idea came about because sometimes sellers will go through a couple of inexperienced agents before making a more informed choice. 

Quality agents know that, in real estate, the client isn’t always right. While of course we take our clients’ wants and needs into account, we must also know how to be honest with them if their goals are unrealistic. Not all agents do this, though, which is where the idea of being the “third agent in” comes into play. 

Sometimes, a client will hire one agent who lets them price their home however they want, then, after that fails, hire a second agent who can only convince them to lower it slightly. When this second Realtor inevitably leaves the picture, it’s time for a third agent to come in and present the client with something they might not want to hear. 

With this in mind, not all sellers will jump from agent to agent. Ideally, they should select a professional who can put their goals within reach from the start. 

But sellers aren’t the only ones in this scenario who must avoid certain mistakes. Agents have a responsibility to get the job done right—and whether you’re a client’s first choice of agent or their third, the biggest mistake you can make is to overprice their home.

“If you know a seller’s pricing goals are unrealistic, don’t agree to them.”

For your sake and your client’s, you should always set your sights ahead of the market when pricing. It’s always a good idea to be aware of current conditions, but it’s also important to price properties correctly to begin with, regardless of what’s going on in the market. Overpricing, even in favorable markets, is never a smart move. 

So when you approach sellers to develop a pricing strategy, honesty is essential. Also, make sure that you discuss both the appraised value and the market value as you make this decision. Sellers must know that if a home doesn’t appraise at the price they’d like to set their home at, this could cause major issues. 

Actually, the lower the price you set from the start, the more offers you’ll get coming out of the gate. As I always say: You can’t underprice a house. Even if you put a home on the market for $1, someone would still come in and offer what the home is worth—assuming you’ve opened up the property to the market. 

The bottom line is this: If you know a seller’s pricing goals are unrealistic, don’t agree with them. It’s easier to have an honest conversation about price at the beginning of the process than to have a conversation about price reductions later on. It isn’t always easy to have this discussion, but it’s crucial. 

To learn how to sell more homes than you ever believed, attend our agent’s seminar by clicking here.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you know the biggest mistake an agent can make? Today, we’ll be discussing the crucial answer to this question.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you know the biggest mistake an agent can make? Today, we’ll be discussing the crucial answer to this question.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 20 C's of Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/the-20-cs-of-real-estate.html</link>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-20 15:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+makes+a+real+estate+agent+great%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The “20 C’s of Real Estate” is a real estate course I created to explain what makes a real estate agent great.

The idea for this course came to me one day while I was reflecting on what distinguishes great agents from good agents, and both from people that don’t make it in the industry. I created a list of 20 qualities of great agents, and all begin with the letter “C.”

For example, the first C is “coachable.” You have to be coachable and willing to listen to other people, and you also have to be willing to do your research. Whether it be practicing scripts, roleplaying, or hiring a coach, you need to listen to the people who are providing you with constructive criticism.

“If you’re not taking that in an accepting responsibility for yourself, you’re not really learning what it takes to be a great agent.”

If you fail, or if you lose a listing or listing appointment, you need to find out why so that you can learn how to improve; if you’re not taking that in an accepting responsibility for yourself, you’re not really learning what it takes to be a great agent.

I started this class because I love coaching and teaching and I want to build a better real estate industry. It’s free and open to anyone from any brokerage, and it’s also a nice way to network in a casual setting. We typically hold them every month, so if you’re interested in attending, you cansign up here.If you have any questions, please feel free to contact me. I would be happy to discuss this event with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+makes+a+real+estate+agent+great%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+makes+a+real+estate+agent+great%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The 20 C’s of Real Estate are twenty qualities that great agents possess, all of which start with the letter C. Attend my monthly class to learn what it takes.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The 20 C’s of Real Estate are twenty qualities that great agents possess, all of which start with the letter C. Attend my monthly class to learn what it takes.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Should Agents Select Homes to Show Clients?</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-should-agents-select-homes-to-show-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Listing Presentation</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-28 13:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

When you are working with a buyer, you should really only show them a maximum of eight to 10 homes. If you are providing services like a buyer consultation up front, you should not have to show them more properties than this. Buyers these days are very busy, so it is important not to waste their time.

Personally, I like to streamline the process by having a conversation with my clients about what non-negotiable features their future home must have. It is essential that you find out what a client needs and wants in a home. Knowing what is important to them will guide you to selecting viable properties. 

That said, it is also important to be honest with your clients. If their list of wants and needs isn’t feasible, you have to tell them that. Your buyers should have a realistic expectation of the kinds of homes that are available. 

As agents, we know what is available. Our clients shouldn’t have to tour 50 different homes to learn something we already know.

“Knowing what is important to your clients will guide you to selecting viable properties.”

For example, if a client says they have a non-negotiable budget of $500,000 or less, but they also demand to see homes of a specific size and in a specific location, you must be honest with them about their prospects. And as you explain their options, make sure you continually check whether they are comfortable with the choices you are laying out for them. Clients should understand that you are not going to show them homes that do not fit their criteria. 

Yet this does not mean clients will not ask you to show them homes that do not make sense. This is why you, as their agent, should do your research before taking them to any property they suggest. If the property they are pushing you toward truly is not a good fit, I would advise you to steer them away from it. 

Sometimes, you may have to reevaluate their preferences and needs later on in the process. If you have toured dozens of homes with no results, something is wrong. At this point, it is time to go back to basics and get to the bottom of what your clients are looking for in a home.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is the secret to selecting homes to show your clients? Let’s take a look at what process you should follow.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is the secret to selecting homes to show your clients? Let’s take a look at what process you should follow.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Build Relationships With Potential Clients</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-to-build-relationships-with-potential-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-14 12:45:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
I find it interesting to watch how people work with their clients. So today I am going to talk about how to build relationships with potential clients. I have found that coming across as a consultant results in people trusting and valuing you. Years ago, I took a sales training class where they talked about how you cannot go into a situation feeling like you need the money. If you go in thinking that you are financially secure, you are going to build a relationship with that potential client. I come from a place of giving back to my clients. When you meet someone, you really want to listen to what they are looking for and decide if you are really able to help them. If you are not able, tell them. You will get much further in life with your client by being honest. Sometimes this means that you must be a little confrontational. I am personally not great at being confrontational, so I try to tone it down. For agents who have a really hard time with needing to be liked by everyone, this can be a little challenging.

“The client needs to understand that they will not necessarily get everything that they want.”An example of this is when you have a client who has specific wants. They want a 3-bedroom, 3-bathroom home within walking distance to downtown and is completely updated for $500,000. This is not possible, but some agents will neglect to tell their clients this and instead tell them they will find it. The client needs to understand that they will not necessarily get everything that they want. When they start their home search and discover that nothing is matching well, that is a problem. It is your job to guide them using your communication skills. You must have those uncomfortable conversations so you don’t end up showing them 20 homes and none of them match. If this happens, they will eventually go to another agent. You really have to understand what a client is looking for and be honest with them. You need to guide them and communicate with them that they may not get exactly what they want. Being honest may lead to you not getting the sale, but the client will view you as trustworthy. So, when I am working with people, I really try and connect with them as a consultant. I provide them information about the real estate industry and be myself. I enjoy hearing their story and deciding if I can help them or not. To find out more about how to build relationships with your clients, please feel free to contact me. I would be happy to speak with you further about this.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Although it may seem like you could lose a potential client, you have to be honest with them so nobody ends up unhappy.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Although it may seem like you could lose a potential client, you have to be honest with them so nobody ends up unhappy.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Gaining Leads From an Open House</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/the-key-to-gaining-leads-from-an-open-house.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-29 12:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Key+to+Gaining+Leads+from+an+Open+House+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Open houses can go really well or really badly. In any case, there will be a lot of people walking through the house to check things out. 

So, how do you sit an open house to get leads? 

The first thing you need to focus on is having the right mindset. You’ve got to believe that the connections you make at the open house will either translate to a sale or to a new lead. After all, when you sit an open house you’re there for two reasons: To sell the house and to gain leads. 

Beyond simply having the correct mindset, it’s also important to have adequate signage. The more signage you have, the more traffic you’re going to see through the open house. Putting out a lot of signs can be time-consuming, but it will be well worth it in the end. 

Door knocking is another great way to generate interest in the open house. Even though the people you meet this way may not be looking for a home, it’s still good to make connections. They could make a great addition to your database. 

Now that we’ve discussed a few ways to prepare for the open house, let’s move on to what you should be doing the day of. First, make sure you arrive about 15 minutes early. There’s nothing worse than walking up to an open house to find people already waiting in the driveway. 

“The goal of an open house is to make connections and then follow up with them.”

It’s also important to have a sign-in sheet prepared and readily available to everyone who passes through. You can use anything from an iPad to pen and paper. All that matters is that you’re capturing the contact information of the people who attend. This includes their names, phone numbers, and email addresses. They should also provide the name of their agent. However, people who aren’t willing to fill out the sign in sheet shouldn’t be allowed to view the home.

The goal of the open house is to connect with people on a personal level. Do not be overbearing as people tour the home. You want people to feel at ease. You are not there to sell them on you. If a neighbor comes over, make sure to welcome them as you would anyone else, this is a great way to make a connection.  

Once the open house is over, it’s good to take notes about the connections you made. And don’t forget to enter these people into your database. Of course, you should always keep in mind that you’re also there with the goal of helping to sell the home. If anyone visiting the home comes along with their agent, be sure to let the listing agent know. This creates a great opportunity to get some feedback about the house. 

So, in short, the goal of an open house is to make connections and then follow up with them. Open houses are a great way to get clients. Remember to keep your energy up and be yourself.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Key+to+Gaining+Leads+from+an+Open+House+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Key+to+Gaining+Leads+from+an+Open+House+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are two goals you should keep in mind when you sit an open house: selling the property and gaining leads.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are two goals you should keep in mind when you sit an open house: selling the property and gaining leads.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Kati Spaniak</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Kati Spaniak</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Real Estate Grit - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
