<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Baystate Financial Podcast with Stephen Cunha</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>Stephen Cunha can help you take charge of your financial future by developing a customized strategy to reach your financial goals and further your success.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Stephen Cunha</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-07-03 12:00:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Stephen Cunha</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Stephen Cunha, Financial Planning, Retirement Plans, Retirement Planning, Wealth Management, Financial Advisor, Certified Financial Planner, Benefit Planning, Retirement Plan Management</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>scunha@baystatefinancial.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Stephen Cunha</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Stephen Cunha</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Stephen Cunha, Financial Planning, Retirement Plans, Retirement Planning, Wealth Management, Financial Advisor, Certified Financial Planner, Benefit Planning, Retirement Plan Management</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Whether you are interested in retirement planning, wealth management, or benefit strategies, Certified Financial Planner™ Stephen Cunha is here with the latest tips.</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>Stephen Cunha can help you take charge of your financial future by developing a customized strategy to reach your financial goals and further your success.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Most Important Auto to the 5th Power Tool: 10-1 Now</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-most-important-auto-to-the-5th-power-tool-10-1-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Financial Advice</category>
        
        <author>Stephen Cunha</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-02 10:09:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/The+10-1+Now+Rule.mp4</guid>
        <description>


  


If you’ve been following my content, you’re probably already aware of what “Auto to the 5th Power” is. As a quick reminder, Auto to the 5th Power is a set of five automatic retirement planning tools.

Today we’ll be discussing the third feature in this collection of fiduciary tools: 10-1 Now. This concept is actually the one I believe to be most important among all of features in Auto to the 5th. So what does 10-1 Now mean?

On average, most people would agree that you should save 10% of your annual income to build up adequate retirement savings. But when I stand in front of your employees, how many of them will realistically be willing and able to put away that amount? Probably not as many as you’d like.

Yet a lot of people, your employees included, likely don’t realize that there’s more than one way to reach this 10% savings goal. To illustrate this, I’d like to share the examples of three hypothetical employees: Susan, George, and Morgan.

In this scenario, Susan is able to begin saving 10% of her annual income right away. She continues to do this for each of the 35 years before her retirement. Based on some very reasonable projects of asset growth, Susan is likely to end up with about $445,000 in retirement assets.

Susan’s friend George realizes he should be saving 10% each year as well, but just isn’t in the position to do so. So George decides to put aside 5% in the first year he begins his retirement savings, and then increase that amount by 1% each year for the next five years. This is the 10-1 Now method, and eventually this strategy will allow George to start saving 10% on an annual basis. And by 65, the same age at which Susan retired, he will have about $405,000.

Lastly, there’s Morgan. Morgan is in a similar position as George was when he began saving. She starts saving 5% annually with the intention of increasing her savings 1% each year for five years, like George did, but fails to follow through on that goal. She continues saving just 5% each year until age 65, and is left with $225,000. I call this last savings path, the one Morgan followed, the “$200,000 mistake.”

“Using automatic escalation to enroll your employees into the 10-1 Now method can help more of them succeed in reaching that 10% savings goal.”

By not increasing her contributions, even by just 1% each year, she missed out on about $200,000 in savings.

Unfortunately, most of your employees will follow this same path. They will never increase their contribution on their own, because it’s a habit that people are generally poor at forming. But using automatic escalation to enroll your employees into the 10-1 Now method can help more of them succeed in reaching that 10% savings goal.

Every year on January 1, you can send a notice out to your employees letting them know that you will be increasing their deferral percentage by 1%. That said, they are welcome to opt out if they prefer not to let this occur. You would be shocked by the number of people who will choose to engage in this saving strategy, though, when they are automatically enrolled. Ultimately, the 10-1 Now rule can be massively beneficial to your employees.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/The+10-1+Now+Rule.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/The+10-1+Now+Rule.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is the 10-1 Now rule and how can it position your employees closer to their retirement savings goal? Allow me to explain.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Stephen Cunha</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is the 10-1 Now rule and how can it position your employees closer to their retirement savings goal? Allow me to explain.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Stephen Cunha, Financial Planning, Retirement Plans, Retirement Planning, Wealth Management, Financial Advisor, Certified Financial Planner, Benefit Planning, Retirement Plan Management</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Increase Participation and Decrease Stress With Auto to the 5th Power</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/increase-participation-and-decrease-stress-with-auto-to-the-5th-power.html</link>
        
          <category>Financial Advice</category>
        
        <author>Stephen Cunha</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-18 14:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/Auto+To+The+5th+Power.mp4</guid>
        <description>


  


How can you use technology to automate retirement saving for your employees? Allow me to introduce you to “Auto to the 5th Power.” This fiduciary tool is bound to make your life, and your employees’ lives, easier.

Auto to the 5th Power refers to five automatic plan features that can be used to improve retirement plan health. A healthy plan is one that has high employee participation rates, high savings rates, and has good investment allocations—all while providing protection to you as a plan sponsor.

Today I would like to introduce you to two of these plan features, explain why they are so beneficial, and discuss how you can put them to use.

The first feature is automatic enrollment. If you are not using automatic enrollment, you are missing out on one of the easiest ways to improve your plan help. Rather than chasing after your employees, handing out enrollment booklets or forms, and crossing your fingers in the hope that they will sign up, this feature allows you another option.

With automatic enrollment, all you need to do is send out a 30-day notice to your employees letting them know that they will be automatically enrolled in the plan at a chosen rate. If your employer match right now is 50% on-the-dollar up to 6% of pay, you might want to set your contribution rate at 6%. However, the government will allow you to set the rate as low as 3% if you are concerned about your employees’ reaction. But, truthfully, my team always encourages plan sponsors to set the rate at whatever their match is, since the goal is to eventually get your employees saving around 10% of their income each year.

The key to automatic enrollment is the 30-day notice period. This period will ensure that you are covered under the Pension Protection Act (the PPA), because employees do have the ability to opt out during these 30 days.

There have been many different studies done that prove the effectiveness of automatic enrollment. In fact, a recent study conducted by Vanguard shows that companies are averaging over 91% employee participation rates when they utilize automatic enrollment.

“These tools could allow your employees to at last do what it takes to create a retirement income for life.”

The second automatic feature I want to discuss today is automatic QDIA. QDIA stands for qualified default investment alternative, and this feature helps employees avoid getting overwhelmed from trying to make investment decisions on their own. Under the PPA, you can automatically enroll people into this option. A QDIA will typically be a risk-based or target-date fund that’s based on the employees’ age. It provides them with professional management and also gives them greater diversification on their investments.

Like the first feature we discussed, the key to the QDIA is giving employees notice. You must let your participants know that if they do not make an investment election, you are going to make it for them. Providing you’ve done your due diligence in monitoring and selecting the investment option, you will be protected under the PPA.

But why bother using these automatic features?

The bottom line is: They work! They are a convenient way to use technology to improve your plan health. Additionally, these automatic features help to combat the procrastination that so often tends to be an issue for people trying to save money. In the end, this could be a game-changer for your employees. These tools could allow your employees to at last do what it takes to create a retirement income for life.

If you want to learn more about implementing automatic features into your retirement plan, check out www.selectretirementplans.com to see how easily this can be done. Also, if you are interested in meeting with me to go over an analysis if your plan, please reach out.

And, as always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/Auto+To+The+5th+Power.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/Auto+To+The+5th+Power.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is Auto to the 5th Power, and how can it benefit your employees? Today we will go over this, and discuss two key components to this set of fiduciary tools.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Stephen Cunha</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is Auto to the 5th Power, and how can it benefit your employees? Today we will go over this, and discuss two key components to this set of fiduciary tools.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Stephen Cunha, Financial Planning, Retirement Plans, Retirement Planning, Wealth Management, Financial Advisor, Certified Financial Planner, Benefit Planning, Retirement Plan Management</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Advice for Retirement: When to Start Taking Social Security Benefits</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/advice-for-retirement-when-to-start-taking-social-security-benefits.html</link>
        
          <category>Financial Advice</category>
        
        <author>Stephen Cunha</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-04 09:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/Social+Security+Optimization+Strategies.mp4</guid>
        <description>


  


Today I want to provide some key insight into optimizing your Social Security benefits. This information may help you plan for your future as you approach or enter your retirement years.

In 2015, the Obama administration carried out a major overhaul of the Social Security system. This overhaul eliminated some things but did make it easier to calculate benefits.

As you probably know, you can start taking your earliest benefit at the age of 62. However, if you continue working after this you will have a reduction of your benefits depending on your income threshold. You can find more details about this by visiting www.ssa.gov.

Normal retirement age is 66, at which point you can get your full benefit without any reduction if you continue to work. At age 70, you can fully maximize your benefits.

For each year up to age 70 that you delay your benefits, you will get an 8% increase. This will be locked in for the rest of your retirement, meaning it is something to seriously consider.

When deciding when to start taking your Social Security income, there are a few questions to ask yourself. For example: When you start taking your benefits, do you plan on continuing to work? You should also consider your family’s history of longevity.

“For each year up to age 70 that you delay your benefits, you will get an 8% increase.”

Your investment philosophy is another key point to think about. What my team ultimately recommends is that you work with a qualified financial advisor to help make the best decision possible. This is especially important since the decision will be irrevocable.

If you’re interested in learning more on the subject, please note that my team and I do conduct Social Security webinars and seminars. To learn more about these learning opportunities, please contact Sandra Brinez at (781) 876-4138.

And, as always, you can also find more information by visiting my website: www.retirementcfo.com.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/Social+Security+Optimization+Strategies.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/Social+Security+Optimization+Strategies.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are a few Social Security optimization strategies to keep in mind as you approach retirement.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Stephen Cunha</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are a few Social Security optimization strategies to keep in mind as you approach retirement.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Stephen Cunha, Financial Planning, Retirement Plans, Retirement Planning, Wealth Management, Financial Advisor, Certified Financial Planner, Benefit Planning, Retirement Plan Management</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is The Rule of 72?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-is-the-rule-of-72.html</link>
        
        <author>Stephen Cunha</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-20 10:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/The+Rule+Of+72.mp4</guid>
        <description>


  


Today we are going to answer the following questions: How much do your employees need to save for retirement and how can we use The Rule of 72 to explain some important financial concepts to them?

This is one of the most common questions we are asked at various employee education meetings. The magic number is to save 10% of your income. If they start saving a little late, they’ll need to save more. How do you determine how much income you’ll need during your retirement years?

In the business, we call this “Calculating your income replacement ratio.” You’ll generally need between 60% to 100% of your pre-retired income to maintain your standard of living.

Let’s explain this a little more with an example. A 40-year-old earning $50,000 per year may be able to save less if they plan to have their house paid off and their children no longer on the payroll. With the two large expenses gone, you only need 60% to 80% of that income. However, inflation is something you’ll need to take into account. As consumer goods and services rise over time, your income will have less purchasing power to buy those goods.

Now, what’s the rule of 72? Basically, it’s a simple math formula that we can use to estimate the growth rate of money over time. Here’s the formula. Take the number 72 and divide it by an interest rate. That will give you the number of years that it will take for a dollar to double. For example, if you’re earning 8% on your money, it would take nine years for it to double. We can do this with inflation, too. Take 72 and divide it by a potential inflation rate of 3%, and we get 24. This tells us that the purchasing power of our dollar will be cut in half over a 24-year period.

“The magic number to save for retirement is 10% of your income.”

Now, back to our 40-year-old earning $50,000 a year with 3% inflation. If he wants to retire on time in 25 years, he’ll need $100,000 to be able to replace his income in the future. Most of the 401(k) record keepers we work with have the ability to put an income replacement ratio on a quarterly statement.

Understanding and communicating these rules and calculations is critical so that your employees understand the concept of inflation, the income replacement ratio, and the importance of financial planning. We’d be happy to provide you with our “gap analysis statement,” a tool we use to help employees understand how much they need to retire and what they need to do.

If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/The+Rule+Of+72.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Steve+Cunha/2018/The+Rule+Of+72.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we’re going to go over “The Rule of 72”. Here’s how it can help you get to retirement on time.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Stephen Cunha</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we’re going to go over “The Rule of 72”. Here’s how it can help you get to retirement on time.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Stephen Cunha, Financial Planning, Retirement Plans, Retirement Planning, Wealth Management, Financial Advisor, Certified Financial Planner, Benefit Planning, Retirement Plan Management</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Fix America’s Savings Crisis</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-fix-americas-savings-crisis.html</link>
        
          <category>Financial Advice</category>
        
        <author>Stephen Cunha</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-19 10:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>


  


How do we fix America’s savings crisis?

First, we need to understand the problem. The average savings rate in America is around 5%, and the average 401(k) balance in 2016 was a little over $96,000, according to Vanguard’s recent “America Saves” report. Of course, that’s hardly enough for the average employee to generate enough income at retirement, especially when you consider taxes and inflation.

Even though these 401(k) plans have been around since 1980 and the total assets in all private retirement plans is greater than $7 trillion, there’s still not enough money in these plans to replace the average American’s income at retirement.

The U.S. government under the Obama administration took over our healthcare system. Could the government do the same for our private retirement system?

Already, individual states are establishing retirement plans for employers with fewer than 50 employees. Is that what you want? Do you want the government managing our private retirement system?

I really hope not. You don’t have to look very far to see what the government has done with social security to get your answer. It’s a pay-as-you-go system with fewer people putting in then those who are taking out.We know that the definition of insanity is doing the same thing over and over again and expecting different results.

In addition, the Department of Labor’s new enforceable fiduciary standard of care will put an even greater spotlight on your responsibilities as a plan sponsor fiduciary and the responsibilities of all of your service providers.

Now is not the time to sit back with a “business as usual” attitude. There are significant cost-effective strategies you can implement now to protect your company and positively impact your employees. If you focus on things like savings rates, income replacement ratios, fees and expenses, and investment performance, you can make measurable improvements to your plan’s health.

Stay tuned for my next video, where I’ll cover how much an employee needs to save, how to use the Rule of 72, and how to keep the government’s hands off your 401(k) plan.

“Now is not the time to sit back with a “business as usual” attitude.”

If you’re ready to take action to improve your retirement plan health and its ability to help your employees create retirement income for life, you can visit me at www.retirementcfo.com or pick up the phone and give me a call.

If you want to learn about a next-generation retirement plan solution that can help you outsource over 90% of the liability and administrative hassles of running a retirement plan, check out www.selectretirementplans.com.

If you have any other questions or there is anything else I can help you with, fee free to reach out to me by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Focusing on savings rates, income replacement ratios, fees and expenses, and investment performance can protect your company and positively impact your employees.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Stephen Cunha</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Focusing on savings rates, income replacement ratios, fees and expenses, and investment performance can protect your company and positively impact your employees.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Stephen Cunha, Financial Planning, Retirement Plans, Retirement Planning, Wealth Management, Financial Advisor, Certified Financial Planner, Benefit Planning, Retirement Plan Management</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Know the Secrets of a Successful Retirement Plan</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/know-the-secrets-of-a-successful-retirement-plan.html</link>
        
        <author>Stephen Cunha</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-14 13:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>


  


Imagine that you’re getting ready to go on a great vacation, you’re standing at the gate at Logan Airport, and you’re ready to board. Then, all of a sudden, the gate agent announces over the PA, “Ladies and gentlemen, the captain would like me to make the following announcement: He’d like me to share with you that there’s an 85% chance that this flight will not make it to your destination safely and on time. Have a nice flight.”

Would you be getting on that plane? Of course not. Why? Because there’s an 85% chance the plane won’t get to its destination on time safely.

I ask this same question to employers sponsoring a 401(k) or 403(b) plan. Why are they boarding their employees on their company-sponsored retirement plan when there’s a possibility they won’t arrive safely at their destination?

I call it the probability question: Are you giving your employees the opportunity to make it to retirement with a high probability of success? Will they have enough money saved to replace their current paycheck and create retirement income for life?

That’s what my video series is about. Over the course of the next year, I’ll send you a series of videos talking about everything you need to know as a plan sponsor and how you can help your employees create retirement income for life.

“I will share with you everything I know.”

Basically, I’ll share with you the secrets of a successful retirement plan. Every other week, I’ll cover topics like courageous plan design, fee and expense control, retirement readiness, litigation, fiduciary responsibility, cutting-edge 401(k) solutions, financial wellness, and so much more.

I’ll share with you everything I know from my 25 years of experience as an adviser focusing on the personal and corporate retirement plan markets, helping you create retirement income for life.

For more information, check out my website www.retirementcfo.com. If you’d like to learn about a next-generation retirement plan solution that can help you outsource over 90% of the liability and administrative headaches of running a retirement plan, check out www.selectretirementplans.com

If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My new video series will teach you everything you need to know as a plan sponsor and how you can help your employees create retirement income for life.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Stephen Cunha</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My new video series will teach you everything you need to know as a plan sponsor and how you can help your employees create retirement income for life.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Stephen Cunha, Financial Planning, Retirement Plans, Retirement Planning, Wealth Management, Financial Advisor, Certified Financial Planner, Benefit Planning, Retirement Plan Management</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Stephen Cunha</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Stephen Cunha</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">Stephen Cunha can help you take charge of your financial future by developing a customized strategy to reach your financial goals and further your success.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
