<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Northern Nevada Real Estate Podcast with Rick Canale</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional Northern Nevada Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Rick Canale</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-09-30 12:02:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Rick Canale</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Rick@NorthernNevadaHouseHunters.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Rick Canale</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Northern Nevada Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional Northern Nevada Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your Latest Reno Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-latest-reno-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Rick Canale</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-03 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Your+Latest+Reno+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our year-to-year numbers show some big changes in our market. What does this mean for buyers and sellers?

 

Today we’ll be going over the latest numbers for the Reno, Carson City, and Carson Valley areas. We’ll be focusing primarily on the Reno numbers, but the changes are similar for each of the three markets. You can see a chart with the numbers of all three beginning at 0:27 in the video.

What changed in the Reno-Sparks market from January 2018 to January 2019?


  Average sales price increased from $381,272 to $387,449—a 1.59% increase
  Quantity sold decreased from 534 to 276—a 93.48% decrease
  Dollar volume sold decreased from $203,599,158 to $106,935,802—a 90.39% decrease
  Average days on market increased from 66 to 99—a 33.33% increase
  The number of new homes decreased from 87 to 21


Home inventory is going to remain low, but because of the high demand for homes, prices will likely increase. Homes will still stay on the market for a longer time, however, as there are fewer qualified buyers. This is primarily due to the perception buyers have of rising interest rates on the horizon.

“Home inventory is going to remain low, but because of the demand for homes, prices will likely increase.”

If you’re a buyer, know that home values will increase throughout the year. You want to buy sooner rather than later.

Sellers, you want to make your home more marketable. You want to create value in the eyes of your buyers since you’ll have competition among other sellers. You also want to price your home properly from the outset. Lastly, you want to use the services of a professional Realtor—they know the best ways to ensure your home sells quickly and for top dollar.

If you’d like my guidance throughout the home buying or selling process, have any other questions, or need more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Your+Latest+Reno+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Your+Latest+Reno+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our year-to-year numbers show some big changes in our market. What does this mean for buyers and sellers?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our year-to-year numbers show some big changes in our market. What does this mean for buyers and sellers?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Expert Explains Why Home Staging Is So Important</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-expert-explains-why-home-staging-is-so-important.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rick Canale</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-27 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+An+Expert+Explains+Why+Home+Staging+Is+So+Important.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I&rsquo;m joined by professional home stager Michael Siva to talk about why staging your home is paramount if you want to sell it quickly and for top dollar.

 

One of the keys to selling your home quickly and for top dollar is getting it professionally staged. With that in mind, I’ve invited professional home stager Michael Siva to sit down with me today and explain why this is.

For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps of our conversation so that you can jump ahead to the section(s) that interest(s) you the most: 

1:22 - The statistics that prove the value of home staging2:34 - How staging appeals to homebuyers4:21 - The importance of staging a home correctly 5:27 - Why staging is essentially a marketing tool8:44 - What a staging consultation looks like9:55 - Why a staged home needs to appeal to as many people as possible

“When a buyer walks through a property, you want the home to invoke an emotion in them.”

If you have any more home staging questions for Michael, you can reach him by phone at (775) 412-1515, email him at staging@kdonavan.com, or visit his website. 

If you have any other real estate questions or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or message me on my website. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+An+Expert+Explains+Why+Home+Staging+Is+So+Important.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+An+Expert+Explains+Why+Home+Staging+Is+So+Important.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m joined by professional home stager Michael Siva to talk about why staging your home is paramount if you want to sell it quickly.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m joined by professional home stager Michael Siva to talk about why staging your home is paramount if you want to sell it quickly.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why We’re Thankful to You This Holiday Season</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-were-thankful-to-you-this-holiday-season.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Rick Canale</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-17 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Why+Were+Thankful+to+You+This+Holiday+Season.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our team is so thankful for you this holiday season. We hope your season is as merry and bright as ours.

 

Happy holidays! In the spirit of the season, our team would like to extend our warmest thanks to all of you for the amazing year we’ve had. Your continued support means so much to us. The success we achieved in 2018 wouldn’t have been possible without you. We look forward to continuing to serve our community and are excited to work with you all in the new year to come. Merry Christmas, happy holidays, and a happy New Year!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Why+Were+Thankful+to+You+This+Holiday+Season.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Why+Were+Thankful+to+You+This+Holiday+Season.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our team is so thankful for you this holiday season. We hope your season is as merry and bright as ours.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our team is so thankful for you this holiday season. We hope your season is as merry and bright as ours.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Tax Benefits That Come With Owning a Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-tax-benefits-that-come-with-owning-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rick Canale</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-14 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+The+Tax+Benefits+That+Come+With+Owning+a+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I have a special guest with me to give us advice about the tax benefits of homeownership: Kelly Bullis is a CPA and the president of his own company.

 

I’m often asked if there are really tax benefits to homeownership, and today, CPA Kelly Bullis is here to help lay out what those benefits are.

For one, if you rent a home, you don’t get any tax deductions for that property. If you buy a home, you can deduct the mortgage insurance and interest, as well as property taxes if you buy the house for less than 80% of the loan-to-value, as itemized deductions. With the new Trump tax law, the standard deduction for married couples has been raised to $24,000, which you can deduct with no questions asked.

If you’re a charitable person—perhaps you belong to a church or you just like to give to causes—your donations, mortgage interest, property taxes, and even medical expenses would push you over that $24,000 standard deduction, giving your a bigger window.

Another benefit applies to those who are self-employed. Those who work from home pay two taxes: First, there’s the federal income tax, in which you’re probably in the 25% bracket; and then there are also the self-employment taxes, which is another 15.2%. That means for every $1 a self-employed individual earns, they’re paying 40% or more in taxes.

Self-employed individuals get to deduct a portion of their mortgage interest, mortgage insurance, homeowners insurance, property taxes, utilities, repairs, maintenance, and even a part of the original purchase price. Added up, deducting 40 cents out of every dollar of taxable income could amount to major savings.

“When you own a home, remember that you’re living in an investment.”

Further still, homeownership benefits the elderly. As we get older, our bodies don’t work as well as they used to. If you own a home, you can make improvements to that home for medical purposes if you get a recommendation from your doctor—this can be anything from installing a wheelchair-accessible ramp to a walk-in bathtub. These expenses can also be deducted. Most landlords won’t let you do that to a rental property, so these benefits allow you to stay in your home for longer.

Homeowners also get to benefit from appreciating home values. Kelly has a friend who purchased his house in the 1970s for $40,000; today, that house is worth $600,000 with the improvements he’s made over his lifetime there. If he sold the house, he and his wife would get up to $500,000 of the gain on the sale of that house tax-free. For single individuals, that figure would be $250,000, which is still big.

When you own a home, remember that you’re living in an investment. A lot of people are fearful of buying a home because of the rising interest rates, which are now close to 5%. However, you need to live in the home for two of the past five years; buying now means that you’ll be able to benefit two years down the road, whereas if you waited to buy, the higher rates mean that you’ll pay that much more for the same home.

As a last tip, Kelly mentioned something that sometimes gets people overwhelmed: imputed rent. This usually works best for high-end tax clients who own multiple real estate properties and view their home as one of their rental investments. It’s a bit complicated, so if you’re in this situation or if you have any other tax-related questions about homeownership, feel free to reach out to Kelly Bullis at (775) 882-4459, kbullis@bullisandco.com, or visit BullisAndCo.com.

I appreciate Kelly taking the time to share his advice with us; it’s extremely beneficial to understand what benefits you stand to gain by owning a home. If you have any questions about real estate, feel free to reach out to us. We’ll be happy to answer your questions in a video so that others can learn the answers as well. Hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+The+Tax+Benefits+That+Come+With+Owning+a+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+The+Tax+Benefits+That+Come+With+Owning+a+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I have a special guest with me to give us advice about the tax benefits of homeownership: Kelly Bullis is a CPA and the president of his own company.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I have a special guest with me to give us advice about the tax benefits of homeownership: Kelly Bullis is a CPA and the president of his own company.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>This New Loan Program was Designed for First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/this-new-loan-program-was-designed-for-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rick Canale</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-10 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+This+New+Loan+Program+was+Designed+for+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Special guest and expert lender Kyle Rush joins us today to discuss a great new loan program that was designed with first-time homebuyers in mind: the 3-2-1 Program.

 

In today’s local market, inventory is low and interest rates are on the rise. These changes have left some area homebuyers feeling discouraged. Many people who have been looking for the right home now believe they’ve lost their chance to do so, but this isn’t the case.

According to my special guest, Kyle Rush of Guild Mortgage, there are many local loan programs that can help first-time buyers find and secure a home.

In fact, Kyle and his team at Guild Mortgage recently launched a great loan option called the “3-2-1 Program.” This loan program is specifically designed to assist first-time homebuyers, and today we’ll be shedding some light on what it is, how it works, and who can qualify for it.

Using the 3-2-1 Program, first-time buyers can submit a down payment as low as 3%, will receive a $2,000 gift card (to be spent however they’d like) after closing, and will also be given a $1,500 credit toward closing costs. This loan option is truly a great opportunity.

“If you’re considering purchasing a home but previously assumed it was an out-of-reach goal, now may be the time to consider pursuing that milestone.”

Better still, this is a conventional loan—and, as you may or may not know, offers with conventional financing tend to have greater traction within the market than those with government backing.

The eligibility requirements for this loan program are also fairly straightforward. To qualify, you will need a credit score of 620 or higher, you must fall within your area’s median income, and at least one of the people on the application must be a first-time homebuyer.

If you’re considering purchasing a home but previously assumed it was an out-of-reach goal, now may be the time to consider pursuing that milestone. If you’d like more information or are interested in whether you might qualify for the 3-2-1 Program, feel free to call Kyle at (775) 885-6892 or send him an email at krush@guildmortgage.net.

And, as always, if you have any other questions for me, please give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Guild’s 3-2-1 Home program offers affordable lending for first-time homebuyers. With as little as 3% down, buyers can receive a $2,000 gift card to The Home Depot® and $1,500 towards closing. The advantages you need with the perks you want.  See if you qualify and contact your loan officer today. Learn more here.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+This+New+Loan+Program+was+Designed+for+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+This+New+Loan+Program+was+Designed+for+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Special guest and expert lender Kyle Rush joins us today to discuss a great new loan program that was designed with first-time homebuyers in mind: the 3-2-1 Program.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Special guest and expert lender Kyle Rush joins us today to discuss a great new loan program that was designed with first-time homebuyers in mind: the 3-2-1 Program.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Advantages of Buying a Home Over Renting One</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-advantages-of-buying-a-home-over-renting-one.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rick Canale</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+The+Advantages+of+Buying+a+Home+Over+Renting+One.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Is it a better idea to rent a home or buy one? Kyle Rush joined me recently to discuss.

 

Today Kyle Rush of Guild Mortgage is here to answer a common question we both hear from our clients: Is it better to rent a home or to buy one?

That’s a question on a lot of people’s minds today. The answer is pretty obvious from where I’m standing. It’s a much better option to buy a home because you can grow credit, build equity, and create passive income all in one.

Kyle agrees. A mortgage is one of the most impactful reported items that can show up on your credit. Making your mortgage payment each month will grow your score substantially with all three bureaus.

When you are renting a home, you are essentially paying someone else’s mortgage payment without any benefits. When you make your own mortgage payment each month, you are paying down the balance of your own loan as the value of your home increases. As that gap spreads, it creates equity (and wealth) in your pocket.

“There are still plenty of $0 down loan programs out there.”

Finally, creating passive income can start with your first home purchase. You are required to live in the home for 12 months, but after that you can convert it into a rental. Rental income from your property can also help create wealth for you and your family and create that passive income.

Even if you don’t think you can afford a home, you might be wrong. There are still plenty of programs out there that have $0 down payment loan programs.

If you’d like to learn more about this program or if you have any other mortgage-related questions, give Kyle a call at (775) 885-6892 or send him an email to krush@guildmortgage.net.

If you have any other real estate-related questions that we can answer in a future blog, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+The+Advantages+of+Buying+a+Home+Over+Renting+One.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+The+Advantages+of+Buying+a+Home+Over+Renting+One.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is it a better idea to rent a home or buy one? Kyle Rush joined me recently to discuss.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is it a better idea to rent a home or buy one? Kyle Rush joined me recently to discuss.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Explanation of How Pre-Qualifications and Pre-Approvals Differ</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-quick-explanation-of-how-pre-qualifications-and-pre-approvals-differ.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rick Canale</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-05 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Pre-Qual+vs.+Pre-Approval.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is the difference between a pre-qualification and a pre-approval? A mortgage expert joins us today to explain.

&nbsp;

One of my clients recently asked about the difference between a pre-qualification and pre-approval, and today, Brian Cushing of Guild Mortgage has joined us to explain. 

According to Brian, a pre-qualification is much less in-depth than a pre-approval. Pre-qualifications are generally done over the phone at the beginning of the lending process and are essentially designed to give the lender and the buyer a preliminary idea of what they may qualify for. After getting some basic information, the lender can issue a pre-qualification letter indicating the buyer’s potential position. However, unlike in the case of a pre-approval, this initial opinion is unverified. 

Pre-approvals are similar to pre-qualifications, but differ in that they require the buyer to provide proof of their financial standing. Pre-approvals are verified with documentation. By looking at a buyer’s credit, finances, employment status, and more, the lender will be able to address and tackle any potential issues from the start. This alleviates the potential for unpleasant surprises later on in the transaction.

“These days, putting your best foot forward is key.”

Pre-approvals enable buyers to make a strong, verified offer as you proceed with the home buying process. These days, putting your best foot forward is key. Sellers may have other offers on the table, and being pre-approved will give you a leg up against these competing buyers. 

If you have any other questions for Brian, feel free to give him a call at (775) 453-0345 or email him at bcushing@guildmortgage.com.

And, as always, if you’d like any additional information from me, please reach out. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Pre-Qual+vs.+Pre-Approval.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Pre-Qual+vs.+Pre-Approval.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is the difference between a pre-qualification and a pre-approval? A mortgage expert joins us today to explain.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is the difference between a pre-qualification and a pre-approval? A mortgage expert joins us today to explain.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beware of Zillow Zestimates</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/beware-of-zillow-zestimates.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rick Canale</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-06 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Beware+of+Zillow+Zestimates.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to get an accurate valuation of your home, don&rsquo;t rely on Zillow. Instead, you should call a professional Realtor.

 

If you’re thinking about selling your home, whether it’s to downsize, upsize, or relocate, it’s important to know how to get top dollar for it.

If you’re like most home sellers, you’ll educate yourself by going online to estimate what your home’s worth. Why? Because you know that if you price it too low, you’ll lose money. If you price it too high, on the other hand, you’ll get fewer showings and perhaps no offers, which will delay the sale of your home and cost you both time and money.

When getting an online home value estimate, most people visit Zillow and use their Zestimate thinking that they’re getting accurate information. However, you should beware of the Zestimate, because it’s not accurate.

You don’t have to take my word for it. Back in 2016, the CEO of Zillow himself sold a Seattle home for $1.05 million—about 40% less than what that home’s Zestimate claimed it was worth. Not only are Zestimates inaccurate, but the website itself readily admits that fact. Unfortunately, though, there are still people out there who take it at face value.

“Not only is the Zestimate inaccurate, but Zillow themselves readily admit it’s inaccurate.”

I understand wanting to start your home sale research online. If I have a health question, I might go on WebMD and research it. If I really need help with that issue, though, I’ll see a doctor. The same holds true for real estate—you don’t want to risk one of the largest investments of your life to an inaccurate valuation from Zillow. You should instead seek the services of a professional Realtor like myself.

If you’re serious about wanting to know your home’s true value, don’t hesitate to give me a call or visit my website. I’d be happy to provide you with a free valuation so you can make an informed decision.

If you have any other real estate needs, feel free to reach out to me as well. I look forward to speaking with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Beware+of+Zillow+Zestimates.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Videos/Rick+Canale+-+Beware+of+Zillow+Zestimates.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to get an accurate valuation of your home, don’t rely on Zillow. Instead, you should call a professional Realtor.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to get an accurate valuation of your home, don’t rely on Zillow. Instead, you should call a professional Realtor.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Will Waiting to Buy Cost You More?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/will-waiting-to-buy-cost-you-more.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Rick Canale</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-26 12:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Keller+Williams+The+Costs+of+Waiting+to+Buy+Until+Later.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you plan on buying a home this year, you should do so sooner rather than later. Here&rsquo;s why.



If you’re thinking of buying a home in 2018, are you better off doing so now or waiting until later in the year?

Let’s review a few facts about our market. Currently, our level of inventory will likely remain low throughout 2018. Over the past 12 months, home prices have appreciated by about 12% and interest rates have remained at historic lows, which has allowed many buyers to enter the market.

Because of this, sellers will most likely be concerned about short-term prices—in other words, where home values are heading in the next six to 12 months. As a buyer, however, you should pay more attention to the long-term cost of a home than its price.

The Mortgage Bankers Association, Freddie Mac, and Fannie Mae all predict that interest rates will increase by this time next year. According to CoreLogic’s most recent home index report, prices are expected to appreciate by 4.7% over the next 12 months.

“By buying now, you could save thousands of dollars.”

If home prices do appreciate by 4.7% during that time span, a $250,000 home with a 3.9% mortgage and a monthly payment of $1,179 will increase by the fourth quarter to costing $261,750 with a 4.6% mortgage and a monthly payment of $1,342. That’s a difference of $163 per month, $1,956 per year, and $58,564 over the course of 30 years.

The bottom line is if buying a home is a part of your plan for 2018, doing so sooner rather than later could save you thousands of dollars over the term of your loan.

If you have any questions about today’s topic or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, call or email me for a free real estate consultation that will give you the competitive edge you need. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Keller+Williams+The+Costs+of+Waiting+to+Buy+Until+Later.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Keller+Williams+The+Costs+of+Waiting+to+Buy+Until+Later.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you plan on buying a home this year, you should do so sooner rather than later. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you plan on buying a home this year, you should do so sooner rather than later. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Work With an Agent?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-should-you-work-with-an-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Rick Canale</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-09 05:59:31 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Keller+Williams+5+Reasons+to+Use+a+Real+Estate+Professional.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Why should you resolve to work with a real estate professional in your transactions? Today, I’ll be discussing five of the benefits you’ll gain from partnering with an agent when you go to buy or sell a home.

1. Experience. A well-educated real estate agent understands the entire sales process and will help you navigate through it, all while brokering a deal and working with other professionals to streamline the transaction.

2. Negotiations. Real estate professionals represent you and act as a buffer, negotiating with all the parties throughout the entire transaction to a successful close.

3. Pricing. We can help you understand today’s real estate values when setting the price of the home you want to list or making an offer on a home you want to purchase. Don’t rely on third-party applications, which we know are way off the mark when it comes to pricing.

4. Understanding the market conditions. We can simply and effectively explain today’s real estate headlines and decipher what they mean to you.

5. Paperwork. We’ll help explain and navigate all the disclosures and paperwork necessary in today’s heavily regulated environment.

“A well-educated real estate agent understands and will help you navigate the entire sales process.”

If you have any questions about this topic or if you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, feel free to give me a call or send an email. We can provide you a free consultation so that you can have a competitive advantage.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Keller+Williams+5+Reasons+to+Use+a+Real+Estate+Professional.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Rick+Canale/Keller+Williams+5+Reasons+to+Use+a+Real+Estate+Professional.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are a number of reasons you should work with a real estate professional in your transactions. Here are five of them.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Rick Canale</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are a number of reasons you should work with a real estate professional in your transactions. Here are five of them.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northern Nevada, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Rick Canale</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Rick Canale</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional Northern Nevada Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
