<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Savvy Agent Real Estate Video Blog with Marcus Green</title>
    <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://blog.savvyagent.biz"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Savvy Agent - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Marcus Green</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-03-12 16:41:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Marcus Green</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Marcus@KWUtah.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Marcus Green</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Savvy Agent - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Work Hard and Work Smart to Hit Your 2019 Goals</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/work-hard-and-work-smart-to-hit-your-2019-goals.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-08 14:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2019/February/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Work+Hard+and+Work+Smart+in+Hitting+Your+2019+Goals.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It’s crazy to think about, but we’re already about 8% done with 2019. Are you making significant progress with your 2019 goals?

I’ve had the opportunity to speak with many agents over the past few days, and I’m impressed with the energy and commitment they’ve demonstrated in accomplishing their goals. This experience also made me think of a personal story I want to share with you that relates to today’s topic: How we apply our energy toward our goals.

Back when I was 16 years old, I worked for my dad’s construction company. One day he asked me to deliver a dump truck to a job site in Nevada. I’d only recently learned how to drive a stick shift, but I agreed to it. During the drive, though, as I worked the truck into fifth gear, it would only go as fast as 45 miles per hour. At the same time, I noticed the RPM gauge redlining. We were putting a huge amount of stress on the engine, but we were barely making 45 miles per hour.

After a while, I pulled over at a gas station and called my dad (remember—this was before everyone had cell phones). When I explained the situation, I heard him laugh on the other end of the line. As it turned out, that particular truck was a split transmission. Basically, there was a switch on the stick shift that allowed you to switch over to another transmission with higher gears, but I completely missed it. All those other gears were available to me the whole time I was overheating the engine just to get to 45 miles per hour, and I had no idea.

“Realistically, all some agents need is a small tweak in their energy and focus to really hit all of their goals for 2019.”

I see a lot of agents putting a ton of time and energy into accomplishing their goals, which is great, but I’m also worried that some of them will burn out because they’re not putting their energy into the right activities that will produce optimum results.

For me to get into sixth, seventh, eight, and ninth gear in that truck, all it took was noticing a minor detail on the stick shift. Realistically, all some agents need is a small tweak in their energy and focus to really hit all of their goals for 2019. You don’t need to apply twice the amount of energy to duplicate your goals—you only need to change how you apply your energy.

If you think you need to change how you apply your energy in accomplishing your goals, there are a couple of questions you need to ask yourself.

First, is your time blocking designed to match your goals in 2019? You need to commit to protecting your time—both your business time and your personal time.

Second, are you spending enough time on dollar-producing activities? You don’t want to be maxing out your RPMs while only going 45 miles per hour.

If you have any questions about the best way to apply your energy toward your 2019 goals, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you achieve your greatest success this year!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2019/February/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Work+Hard+and+Work+Smart+in+Hitting+Your+2019+Goals.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2019/February/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Work+Hard+and+Work+Smart+in+Hitting+Your+2019+Goals.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you on your way to accomplishing all your goals in 2019? If not, maybe it’s time to change how you apply your energy toward those goals.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you on your way to accomplishing all your goals in 2019? If not, maybe it’s time to change how you apply your energy toward those goals.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Coaching Strategies and Closing Techniques</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/coaching-strategies-and-closing-techniques.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-22 11:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2019/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Coaching+Strategies+and+Closing+Techniques.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In part 13 of our real estate fundamentals series, we’ll be taking a look at communication strategies and, more specifically, closing techniques. These are areas we should always be focusing on as real estate agents, as a strong understanding of these tactics can mean the difference between making a deal and losing it. This section will be building off what we learned about communication and problem solving in the previous webinar.

Here’s an outline of the discussion we had, with timestamps, so you can skip around to the part(s) that interest you the most:

00:46 — An introduction to today’s topic

02:54 — Mirror and match strategy

05:05 — Building rapport and using it

05:28 — Using connectivity points

06:16 — Identifying and using emotion

07:08 — Using tie-down questions and presuppositions

07:53 — Examples of tie-down questions

13:12 — Examples of presuppositions

14:21 — How presuppositions work

17:03 — Why these strategies help you close

17:30 — How to deal with objections

21:47 — Handling the close

23:48 — The Columbo tactic for closing the deal

24:40 — The assumptive close

25:54 — The take away close

27:08 — The hard close

28:30 — The leading close

29:40 — Why no doesn’t mean no forever

30:43 — What to take away from the webinar

If you have any questions or need more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2019/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Coaching+Strategies+and+Closing+Techniques.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2019/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Coaching+Strategies+and+Closing+Techniques.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Join us today to learn innovative communication strategies and powerful closing techniques.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Join us today to learn innovative communication strategies and powerful closing techniques.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Communication and Problem Solving Are Critical</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/why-communication-and-problem-solving-are-critical.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-02 16:20:40 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2019/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Why+Communication+and+Problem+Solving+Are+Critical.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As we’ve said before, the agents who are listing-focused and have a strategy for taking listings are dominating the market right now. Today we’re going to talk about a few things that are very critical in preparation for your listing presentation: communication and problem-solving.

To me, these are the two most critical skills you can learn whether you’re a real estate agent or not. If you can be a great communicator and problem solver, you have the ability to make a huge impact on the world and the people around you. Here’s an outline of the discussion we had, with timestamps, so you can skip around to the part(s) that interest you the most:

2:30- An intro to communication and problem solving.

4:00- The business of relationships.

5:15- Tips for building rapport and being aware.

6:30- The 5-step process of communication and how it relates to receiving a present.

11:50- How to use communication strategies to solve problems in your business and in your life in general.

21:20- The “Three P” approach to negotiation.

23:00- How my daughter used the “Three P” approach to come up with an agreement when she wanted to make an Instagram account.

25:50- Additional negotiation tips to help you have success.

26:30- How rapport comes in handy when dealing with “Chicken Littles.”

29:00- Final thoughts.

Thanks for joining us yet again. Next time, we’ll talk about some closing strategies. If you have any questions for me in the meantime about this topic or about your business in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2019/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Why+Communication+and+Problem+Solving+Are+Critical.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2019/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Why+Communication+and+Problem+Solving+Are+Critical.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In our latest webinar, we discussed two of the most important skills any agent can have. Here’s what they are and why they’re essential to success.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In our latest webinar, we discussed two of the most important skills any agent can have. Here’s what they are and why they’re essential to success.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Does a Great Listing Presentation Entail?</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/what-does-a-great-listing-presentation-entail.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-07 11:54:08 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/December/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+What+Does+a+Great+Listing+Presentation+Entail%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Welcome back to our series on the real estate fundamentals.

As we’ve covered before, running a great real estate business isn’t just about being creative. It’s also about knowing, and closely following, the basics of the industry. You need to know the fundamentals before you can put your own spin on things. This time, we’ll be discussing buyer and listing consultations.

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the interview. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:

1:26 - An introduction to today’s topic.

2:26 - The importance of knowing a buyer or seller’s motivation.

4:00 - How to prepare for buyer and listing consultations.

12:57 - Why listing presentations matter.

15:27 - Important aspects of a listing presentation.

19:40 - How to use eEdge to create and edit a listing presentation.

28:10 - Selling yourself during the listing presentation.

30:34 - How to incite immediate action after a listing presentation.

After reviewing today’s video, I encourage you to check out this listing presentation example. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/December/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+What+Does+a+Great+Listing+Presentation+Entail%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/December/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+What+Does+a+Great+Listing+Presentation+Entail%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In continuing our real estate fundamentals series, today we’ll discuss how to create listing and buyer presentations.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In continuing our real estate fundamentals series, today we’ll discuss how to create listing and buyer presentations.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Utilize List Reports to Set Yourselves Apart</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-utilize-list-reports-to-set-yourselves-apart.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-21 16:06:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Utilize+List+Reports+to+Set+Yourselves+Apart.mp4</guid>
        <description>

My conversations the past several weeks have focused on listing: In this market, an agent that can control the listings and have more listing conversations is going to win more easily. Given that, it’s critical for us to be utilizing any tools we have available to us to set us apart.

That’s why I asked James and Mark Western from CityWide Home Loans to join us for today’s conversation. I’m very particular about my partnerships, and the reason I decided to bring them on as our mortgage partners is that they’re incredible businessmen—their ethics, culture, and quality of service are very much in line with our standards, and they constantly bring value to the table.

In addition to introducing James and Mark to you, I wanted to also discuss a particular tool that will set our agents apart when they’re speaking to their clients about their listings: ListReports. Though it’s been available to our agents for a while, they’re not plugging into it the way I’d like to see.

“Utilizing this tool will set you apart from what other agents are doing, and it can help you secure more listings.”

Using the timestamps below, feel free to navigate the conversation we had at your leisure:


  2:30—Introducing James and Mark and their journey in the real estate industry.
  4:00—Diving into ListReports: James and Mark show us what it is and how it. works, as well as highlight the power of the tool and give recommendations for using it.
  10:40—Intuitive marketing elements: The marketing materials ListReports provides for an agent’s listings.
  14:40—ListReports is formatted for both desktop and phone browsers, giving it on the go convenience.
  16:45—Open houses are made easier with ListReports.
  18:25—Need promotional flyers? ListReports can do that, too.
  19:35—Showing your clients how you’ll be marketing their listings
  20:05—The School Report.
  22:15—Who has access to the listings on ListReports?
  23:10—ListReports can help buyers’ agents and their clients, as well.
  25:00—Making the most of ListReports’s sign-writing service.
  27:55—Summarizing the benefits of using ListReports.


This is my actionable recommendation to anyone who is looking for tools and resources to enhance your control of your listings: Partner with a CityWide Representative and ask them to help you implement the ListReports tool; they’ll help you set up your account. Then, pull up and look at every report and make a system out of them. Decide what reports you’ll use on which listings, but don’t use all of them.

I want to thank James and Mark for joining me today, and especially for being such a phenomenal resource and partner for our team. They’re truly an asset for us.

If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to us. Until then, make it a great week! Get out there and crush it.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Utilize+List+Reports+to+Set+Yourselves+Apart.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Utilize+List+Reports+to+Set+Yourselves+Apart.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m joined by James and Mark Western from CityWide Home Loans to talk about an excellent tool for listing agents: ListReports.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m joined by James and Mark Western from CityWide Home Loans to talk about an excellent tool for listing agents: ListReports.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Use Your Website to Leverage Your Business</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-use-your-website-to-leverage-your-business.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-02 14:57:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Use+Your+Website+to+Leverage+Your+Business.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Welcome back to our webinar series on real estate fundamentals. For part nine of our series, I wanted to touch on one of the pieces of technology that is underutilized in many of our agents’ businesses: websites.

In no way do I think it’s critical that our agents become web developers, but at the very least, they should know what the tools that are available to them can do to increase their business. Keller Williams invests $1 million per week in technology and that technology is available for us to use to leverage our businesses.

For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps so that you can jump around to whatever part of the discussion interests you most:

2:20- A few helpful tips for getting started with setting up your own website through KW.

7:30- What setting up your own site outside of KW will cost you and why it’s silly to do so.

8:20- How to customize your domain.

10:45- How to add branding to your site and the benefits of doing so.

12:20- Launching your site and what a live website looks like from the front end.

13:30- How to update your “Featured Listings” page on your site.

17:30- The two options for capturing leads through your site and the benefits and drawbacks of each.

19:30- How changing the overall look of your site through theme selection can help set you apart.

20:35- Tips for customizing the slideshow pictures that appear on your site.

22:30- How to integrate blogs and testimonials into your website.

25:00- A few additional tips and tricks to help you maximize the value of your site, including social media and KW app integration.

If you have any questions about your website or about anything else we touched on in this webinar, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Use+Your+Website+to+Leverage+Your+Business.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Use+Your+Website+to+Leverage+Your+Business.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>All real estate agents should use technology to their advantage. One of the best pieces of technology at our disposal is our agent websites.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>All real estate agents should use technology to their advantage. One of the best pieces of technology at our disposal is our agent websites.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Use the KW Mobile Search App</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-to-use-the-kw-mobile-search-app.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-19 14:46:07 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Use+the+KW+Mobile+Search+App.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Keller Williams invests $1,000,000 per week into technology for us to use. This shows not only the significance of the technology, but also the company’s awareness of its agent’s needs. One form of technology that they have invested money into is the KW Mobile Search App. This app can be personalized to have your information linked to it automatically for each user. I recently held a webinar on setting up and using the KW Mobile Search App to help you with lead generation that I want to share with you today.

I have included timestamps below so that you can jump to the sections that most interest you.

2:30 – A tool to help walk you through how to use the KW app.

2:55 – Where to download and brand the app to you.

4:55 – The importance of sharing your app information.

6:40 – How the app can help your client.

“The KW Search App can be personalized, when set up, to have your information linked to it automatically for each user.”

7:40 – How the app can help you nationally.

8:35 – Adding a link to your email signature.

11:05 – Scripts to share your app.

13:00 – Who you can give your app to first.

14:05 – Run a contest to get more engagement.

16:30 – A crash course to the KW app.

20:25 – Who else should have your app and give it away.

21:40 – How KW video can help you with distribution.

25:00 – The trick to letting the tools work for you.

27:00 – Next week’s topic.

If you have any questions about this, please let me know. I would be happy to help you in any way that I can.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Use+the+KW+Mobile+Search+App.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Use+the+KW+Mobile+Search+App.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to share my recent webinar with you about setting up and using your KW Mobile Search App to create your leads.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to share my recent webinar with you about setting up and using your KW Mobile Search App to create your leads.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using the Final 2 Tools</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/using-the-final-2-tools.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-05 15:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Using+the+Final+Two+Tools.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I recently held a webinar for part seven of Real Estate: The Fundamentals that I would like to share with you. These recent weeks have been a lot of fun for me, personally, because it has given me the opportunity to reanalyze how the fundamentals are being run on my own team.

I have timestamped the conversation to make it easier for you to jump to the sections most interesting to you.

1:20 – A quick recap of the career growth initiative tools.

2:50 – An overview of the last two tools: The Agent Language of Real Estate (LORE) and the Local Expert.

4:55 – What should you compare your business against?

6:20 – How the LORE and Local Expert tools work together.

7:50 – Where you find the LORE report on kwconnect.com.

8:50 – What the LORE spreadsheet looks like and how we use it.

10:20 – Where the numbers are coming from and how they get compared.

11:40 – Where the story starts showing up.

12:45 – Why does the data tell this particular story?

13:15 – Comparing your business to your board, market center, region, and KWRI.

13:50 – Developing your value statements and choosing the right ones.

17:00 – What you do with your value statements after you have them.

17:30 – How we compare each category and why.

18:55 – Tell the story with the Local Expert tool.

20:05 – Why this tool is cool and where you can use it.

21:20 – The benefits of adding a video to your flier.

23:20 – Why you need to do this for yourself.

25:35 – What is coming up.

If you have any additional questions about this, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Using+the+Final+Two+Tools.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Using+the+Final+Two+Tools.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I am looking at how the Agent Language Real Estate and Local Expert tools help you create a great story.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I am looking at how the Agent Language Real Estate and Local Expert tools help you create a great story.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Fundamentals, Part 6</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/real-estate-fundamentals-part-6.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 12:10:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/September/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Real+Estate+Fundamentals%252C+Part+6.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do you be purposeful and strategic in how you make changes to your business? You look at the numbers and adjust accordingly.

Today in the sixth installment of my webinar series about the fundamentals of real estate, I’ll show you how to utilize your multi-year trend report and look at it in relation to the business plan you’ve put together so you examine the right numbers and make the right adjustments.

Here are timestamped sections of the video above so you can jump ahead to certain points at your leisure:

0:40 - A quick review of what we’ve learned from previous videos.

2:11 - Explaining the CGI tools of the Career Growth Initiative.

3:51 - The agent trend report—where you can find it and how it can help you stay on track with your listing goals.

“If your business plan isn’t working, you alter it based on the numbers.”

15:10 - Why you need to ask “Why?”

19:10 - The numbers that can and can’t be tracked in the multi-year trend report and where you can go to find the numbers that aren’t tracked:  Daily104.com.

20:04 - The activities that are tracked on Daily104.com.

23:34 - The final piece of analyzing your multi-year trend report and how it breaks down where you’re at with your four conversations: appointments, listings taken, closed units, and GCI.

27:20 - How focusing on two conversations, your number of appointments, and the number of listings taken can tell you what activities need to change in your business.

This is the same playbook that the best agents in the country are running; it’s just a matter of modifying the effort and activity within that model. If you haven’t already done this with your first quarter numbers of 2018, I encourage you to download your multi-year trend report today and use the second quarter to get back on track. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/September/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Real+Estate+Fundamentals%252C+Part+6.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/September/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Real+Estate+Fundamentals%252C+Part+6.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re into week six of my series on the fundamentals of real estate, and this time we’ll focus on how to utilize your multi-year trend report and adjust your business according to the numbers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re into week six of my series on the fundamentals of real estate, and this time we’ll focus on how to utilize your multi-year trend report and adjust your business according to the numbers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Fundamentals, Week 5: Capitalizing on Your Pipeline</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/real-estate-fundamentals-week-5-capitalizing-on-your-pipeline.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-24 16:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/August/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Real+Estate+Fundamentals%2C+Week+5%3A+Capitalizing+on+Your+Pipeline.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Thus far in my webinar series, I’ve discussed how mastering just one of the fundamentals in a given area isn’t enough—you need to master many of them so that your basic skills can fuel and support each other. Fundamentals are all just pieces of one big puzzle without which you cannot see the full picture. To see in detail all of what we’ve discussed so far, visit www.savvyagent.biz/fundamentals.

Today’s installment begins our journey into week five of my seminar. To those who have been following along, have you taken specific action in relation to every one of these fundamentals that we’ve covered to turn them into habits? For example, have you take action to better time block your calendar? Are you better utilizing your lead generation time? Are you now making an effort to utilize your CRM and systematically follow up with your people? I hope that you are.Today I want to focus on capitalizing on your pipeline, which is a representation of how much business you can expect to close in a given timeframe. We have a pipeline tool that is sure to help you visually organize your appointments and transactions, as well as a means of setting and tracking the goals you set for yourself in terms of appointments set and met.

For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps so that you can jump around to whatever topic interests you most:

0:00-4:10—An overview of our previous topics

4:10—Our weekly WIG meetings (Wildly Important Goal) and the four conversations we have:


  Listing Appointments
  Listings Taken
  Closings
  Profit


6:10—Your CGI (career growth initiative) tools are all interconnected—their power is maximized when each one is used to build upon, support, and strengthen the others.

8:12—My modified KWRI pipeline sheet: who is most likely to give me business within the next several months?

12:15—The different ways people get into your pipeline

21:50—What if your pipeline doesn’t match your goals?

22:55—My challenges for you.

26:15—Q&amp;A

I’ll return next time to continue this discussion on mastering the fundamentals. Until then, be sure that you’re implementing all these ideas and working to build yourself a better process. If you have any further questions, feel free to reach out to me.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/August/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Real+Estate+Fundamentals%2C+Week+5%3A+Capitalizing+on+Your+Pipeline.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/August/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Real+Estate+Fundamentals%2C+Week+5%3A+Capitalizing+on+Your+Pipeline.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to focus on improving your grasp on important tools you’ll need to use in order to be as efficient as possible.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to focus on improving your grasp on important tools you’ll need to use in order to be as efficient as possible.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Keeping Your Conversation Values High Systematically</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/keeping-your-conversation-values-high-systematically.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-14 11:47:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/August/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Keeping+Your+Conversation+Values+High+Systematically.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today is part four of the real estate fundamentals series. This really is a sequential process where you need to stack these pieces up to build up to the more advanced topics later.  Previously I spoke about the significance of clarity of goals, the importance of time blocking, and finally I debunked the myths about lead generation. For this segment, I am talking about how to systematically keep the value of the conversations we have with clients high.

I have timestamped the different sections of the video so that you can jump to the sections that are most interesting to you.

1:50 - A quick recap of last week’s content.

4:20 - Explaining a graph that shows you how to capture a lead.

6:45 - An overview of today’s content.

8:00 - Using MyKW to create marketing material.

9:30 - Where you can find pre-made templates.

11:00 - The 8x8 template that I use for buyers.

“This really is a sequential process where you need to stack these pieces up to build up to the more advanced topics later.”

14:10 - The 8x8 seller’s template I use.

16:25 - The special campaigns that I use and where to find them.

17:30 - How to choose your 33-touch campaign.

18:05 - The other three touches.

19:55 - How to add people to the campaign.

21:10 - What you can do through the system.

22:30 - Use reminders to follow up with your commitments.

23:15 - How to create a new client in the system.

26:15 - Adding a new client to a campaign.

27:30 - The depreciation of your leads and why this system helps.

29:10 - Your assignment for the week.

If you have any additional questions about this week’s topic, please feel free to reach out to me by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/August/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Keeping+Your+Conversation+Values+High+Systematically.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/August/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Keeping+Your+Conversation+Values+High+Systematically.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Continuing the series on real estate fundamentals, today I am talking about how to systematically keep conversation values high with clients.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Continuing the series on real estate fundamentals, today I am talking about how to systematically keep conversation values high with clients.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>It's Time to Change the Way You Think of Lead Generation</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/its-time-to-change-the-way-you-think-of-lead-generation.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-30 10:58:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/July/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+It%2527s+Time+to+Change+the+Way+You+Think+of+Lead+Generation.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Being in the real estate industry requires a constant dedication to continuing your education. That said, we hope our webinar series can serve as an asset to you as you grow as a real estate professional. You can check out our most recent webinar above, where we’ll be covering more fundamentals of real estate.

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:

1:06 - How to address fears about our market.

1:49 - A recap of our last webinar.

3:35 - An explanation of “The Machine.”

8:10 - Why you should think of lead generation as relationship nourishment.

10:32 - A look at whether quality or quantity is more important to lead generation.

13:23 - What we can learn from Keller Williams’ 2017 lead gen survey.

15:25 - A look at a common lead generation mistake.

17:47 - Why making more contact attempts will increase your probability of connecting.

18:32 - How to follow the “eight days of pain” strategy.

22:40 - The importance of identifying your top four lead sources.

25:15 - When to implement paid lead sources.

25:47- What to do after identifying top lead sources.

27:15 - Outlining a few recommendations to implement moving forward.

28:24 - An explanation of the “Alphabet System.”

31:25 - A conclusion on today’s discussion.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/July/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+It%2527s+Time+to+Change+the+Way+You+Think+of+Lead+Generation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/July/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+It%2527s+Time+to+Change+the+Way+You+Think+of+Lead+Generation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>During this week’s webinar, the main focus of our discussion was lead generation.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>During this week’s webinar, the main focus of our discussion was lead generation.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Creating Structure Result in More Freedom?</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-can-creating-structure-result-in-more-freedom.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-13 12:42:43 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/July/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Can+Creating+Structure+Result+in+More+Freedom%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently, I gave a webinar about the importance of time blocking. Although it may not be the most stimulating topic, this fundamental task can lead to systematic success for you and your real estate career. I have time blocked the different topics that I discussed below so that you can jump to the parts that most interest you:

2:40 – How structure feels and why we want to resist it.

4:25 – Creating our own structure creates more freedom.

6:00 – Does your calendar reflect your four conversation goals we learned about in my last video?

7:20 – Building a calendar that matches your goals to give you freedom and results.

8:05 – Deconstruct and structure your calendar to make your goals show up.

9:05 – Add what is most important and non-negotiable to your calendar.

11:30 – How to schedule in planning time.

“My challenge for you now is to create your own ideal time block for yourself.”

12:40 – How to schedule your lead generation time.

15:20 – Why actual appointments need to be scheduled so you can hit your goals.

17:25 – Don’t miss an appointment or you will get behind.

19:20 – What is time blocking?

20:30 – Why is time blocking important and where do I find it?

22:25 – How do I set up a calendar and systematically use it?

23:00 – Tips to protect your time block.

25:35 – Our office’s one-touch commitment and what it means.

27:55 – Prioritize your tasks and how long they should take each day.

My challenge for you now is to create your own ideal time block for yourself. Then ask yourself how you will protect your time and create more freedom.

If you have any additional questions about time blocking and how this type of structure can create you more freedom, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/July/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Can+Creating+Structure+Result+in+More+Freedom%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/July/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Can+Creating+Structure+Result+in+More+Freedom%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I am providing you with a webinar I recently held that tells you about how structuring your life can actually provide you with more freedom.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I am providing you with a webinar I recently held that tells you about how structuring your life can actually provide you with more freedom.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Fundamentals: #1 Know Your Numbers</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/real-estate-fundamentals-1-know-your-numbers.html</link>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-28 14:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/June/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Real+Estate+Fundamentals-+CGI+Calculator.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I recently hosted a coaching webinar series titled “Real Estate Fundamentals.” I thought some of this information was really useful, and I wanted to make sure that you received it. Here’s an outline of what was discussed, with timestamps so that you can skip ahead to the points that interest you the most:

4:15- A quick walk-through of the series as a whole.

8:00- Why adding value to relationships via your database is key to growing your business.

11:00- An in-depth look at the Career Growth Initiative calculator and how you should be using it.

“One of the fundamental tools you should be working with in your real estate business is the CGI calculator. Here’s how it works.”

23:50- The four conversations you should have on your mind and in your life every single day.

26:00- How my team tracks these four conversations and uses them to our advantage.

27:30- My challenge for you today that should take no longer than 30 minutes.

29:20- The main takeaways you should have after watching this video.

If you have any questions for me in the meantime about anything we discussed in the webinar above, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/June/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Real+Estate+Fundamentals-+CGI+Calculator.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/June/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Real+Estate+Fundamentals-+CGI+Calculator.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Have you heard of the CGI calculator? If not, it’s something you need to add to your business today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Have you heard of the CGI calculator? If not, it’s something you need to add to your business today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Truth About Joining Keller Williams</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/the-truth-about-joining-keller-williams.html</link>
        
          <category>Keller Williams Success Stories</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-19 09:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/April/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+The+Truth+About+Joining+Keller+Williams.mp4</guid>
        <description>

One of Keller Williams’ newer agents, Justin Yoder, sat down recently to share his experience.

Justin was previously a top-producing agent at a small company and was looking for a chance to expand his horizons. That’s when he came to Keller Williams. “I wanted to reach a new ceiling,” said Justin. “I came to Keller Williams because they have a system of highly successful agents.”

According to Justin, the professionals on our team have done a great job helping him put his goals into action.

Justin isn’t new to real estate. In fact, he’s been in the business full-time for 14 years. “I care deeply about making sure that my clients don’t get just any home, but the right one,” says Justin. One of the main things that sets Justin apart as a Realtor is his ability to problem-solve and negotiate for his clients.

“There are a lot of buyers out there who are making offers and aren’t getting homes. My clients are getting contracts. It’s not always about the highest price. Sometimes it’s asking what’s important to the seller and making sure that my client can do that,” says Justin.

“Since joining Keller Williams, Justin stretches himself to meet goals he once believed impossible.”

Justin may be highly skilled at what he does, but he also recognizes that there are some common fears held by real estate agents. Inconsistency, in particular, is something he says many agents worry about. On top of that, many professionals in the real estate industry have fears about lacking support.

But thanks to the guidance provided by Keller Williams’ training programs, KW agents don’t have to worry about either of these fears.

Justin feels that at his brokerage, specifically, he can call the owners directly at any time. He knows his team’s leaders are there to help him. “One of the best things about KW is having people willing to help you,” said Justin

These days, Justin says that he stretches himself to meet goals he once wouldn’t have believed were possible.

As always, if you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/April/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+The+Truth+About+Joining+Keller+Williams.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/April/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+The+Truth+About+Joining+Keller+Williams.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How has joining Keller Williams changed Justin Yoder’s real estate career? Let’s find out.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How has joining Keller Williams changed Justin Yoder’s real estate career? Let’s find out.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reconnect Yourself to the Fundamentals of Your Business</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/reconnect-yourself-to-the-fundamentals-of-your-business.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-03 10:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/April/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Reconnect+Yourself+to+the+Fundamentals+of+Your+Business.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Several years ago, I walked into a CrossFit gym for the first time.

I had a background in competitive bodybuilding, and I had heard all about CrossFit, so I wanted to go check it out. My first day, I saw a guy who was about 40 pounds lighter than me snatching a significant amount of weight more than what I could possibly do at the time. Snatching, in the Olympics, is when you pull the weight from the ground all the way overhead and catch it in a full overhead squat. It really bothered me that this kid was so much smaller than me and made it look so effortless.

After watching several times, I finally put my finger on what it was that made him able to do this—it was his shoes. The pair he wore were the exact same pair as they wore in the Olympics. I later went on to Amazon and found and bought the same pair of shoes. I returned to the gym with a new level of confidence; I was going to show this kid up, since I was so much bigger than he was.

Do you think I was able to crush him, now that I had on the exact same shoes?

Absolutely not.

Yes, the shoes do have value, but here’s the trick: I didn’t have the skillset that I needed to be able to do the lift in the first place. This can serve as a message for today’s real estate market.

In today’s market, there are more shiny tools and distractions than ever before. Every single day, there’s someone walking into your office offering you a new tool or strategy. So many people are jumping from one strategy to the next, thinking that this one will be one. Someone else succeed with it, so why shouldn’t they?

It was the same thing with the Olympic snatches; I learned that the shoes were just a piece of the tool. My mobility was nowhere near what it should’ve been. I didn’t understand the techniques of the movement or how to break down the mechanics of every single piece of the lift.

It really came down to the question, “What are the fundamentals for success?” What are the fundamentals of the lift that I need to learn in order for me to be able to increase my ability to snatch?

“Commit yourself to the monotony of success.”

There are a couple things that are important to think about:

1. Reconnect with the basics. Break things down into their simplest form—too many of us are looking for the new, shiny way to do things when, realistically, success comes down to mastering the fundamentals. There is a place for adding creativity to our world, but only on top of the proven models and basics of our business.

2. Consistently commit to your tasks. It’s not that we can decide to go lead generate for a day or two and then be done with it because we conquered it—we have to commit to the same core activities. There are parts of our jobs that we absolutely love to do, but there are a lot of things inside our world that just aren’t as fun. We have to commit to the monotony of success.

3. Connect with a coach. In order to reconnect with the fundamentals of the snatch lift, I knew that I needed to contact a coach. My coach was not only able to show me the movement but also taught me how to do it as well, showing me where I needed to improve.

The goal in today’s market, the most competitive market we’ve ever seen in the real estate industry, is for agents to recommit to the fundamentals. Take a step back and ask yourselves what you’re doing well and which areas you need to increase your skill set in.

Commit yourself to the monotony of success while knowing what the flow of your day looks like, and you will get better at the monotonous part of your business. You’ll have more time and energy to put into the things that you love doing in your career.

If you’d like the opportunity to connect with the fundamentals, I currently have a webinar series called “Real Estate: The Fundamentals.” It’s free and is held every Monday morning from 8 a.m. to 8:30 a.m. You can join in at any time, and if you’d like to go back and visit topics we’ve discussed previously, visit us at www.savvyagent.biz/fundamental.

For any questions you have, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/April/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Reconnect+Yourself+to+the+Fundamentals+of+Your+Business.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/April/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Reconnect+Yourself+to+the+Fundamentals+of+Your+Business.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In today’s competitive market, agents need to revisit the fundamentals of the business and hone their skills. Here’s how I learned that lesson.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In today’s competitive market, agents need to revisit the fundamentals of the business and hone their skills. Here’s how I learned that lesson.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How the Sears Team Has Continued to Find Success</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-the-sears-team-has-continued-to-find-success.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Interviews</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-13 10:58:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/March/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+the+Sears+Team+Has+Continued+to+Find+Success.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I had a great Q&amp;A recently with Liz and Amanda of the Sears Team. We talked to them a little bit about why they chose Keller Williams and where that decision has brought them to today.

Why did you choose Keller Williams?“When I ran across Keller Williams, I wasn’t even looking for another brokerage. I was very successful at Re/MAX and brought my dad on as a buyer agent. He told me that there had to be a better brokerage out there that offers more support and training to get you to the next level. I sat down with the team leader at KW and the more he talked, the more I was impressed with the way the company was structured. The coaching is phenomenal and the interaction between the management, the training staff, and the agent was something I had never seen before. What I love most about Keller Williams is the support that it has provided me which has allowed me to get to the next level.”

“Our clients are the heart of our business.”

What sets you apart from other real estate agents?“The one thing that really sets us apart from other agents is that we love making sure that our clients know they’re the heart of our business. The one thing they value the very most is excellent communication. What we’ve done is tailored our business and our process so that our clients always understand each step. We like to keep them updated throughout the entire process so that they feel comfortable and never lost. We also invest our time in attending seminars, training, and coaching so that we can continue to provide the very best service along with our communication. Since we are a team, when one of us isn’t available, the other can assist in the meantime. Our goal is not only to created satisfied customers, but also raving fans.”If you have any questions for Liz or Amanda or want to learn more about The Sears Team, head on over to http://www.thesearsteam.com/. If you have any other questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/March/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+the+Sears+Team+Has+Continued+to+Find+Success.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/March/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+the+Sears+Team+Has+Continued+to+Find+Success.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Liz Sears and her team have taken things to another level since joining Keller Williams. Here’s how.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Liz Sears and her team have taken things to another level since joining Keller Williams. Here’s how.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Keller Williams Turned Shea Kopecky’s Career Around</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-keller-williams-turned-shea-kopeckys-career-around.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Interviews</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-13 13:41:38 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/February/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Keller+Williams+Turned+Shea+Kopeckys+Career+Around.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When Shea Kopecky chose Keller Williams when he first got into real estate, he didn’t have much of an idea of what to do. His father had been in the real estate industry for a long time and had talked to him about working in real estate so that he could help him with some of his land and commercial deals.

“I went to work with a small broker for, legitimately, six days,” he says. “They told me nothing; they just sat me down and gave me some paperwork to fill out, gave me some fees that I was supposed to pay, and that’s about it.”

He worked there full-time while his wife stayed at home, taking care of his two children. From there, he went online and searched for the No. 1 real estate company in the United States for new agents.

“Keller Williams popped up, so I looked up KW and Utah on the maps and pulled up the South Ogden location. I called them up and told them that I was an agent trying to move. We met with the team lead and they got me in from that day.”

He had no idea what to do beyond cold calling, door knocking, and marketing himself. He didn’t know about the systems or what one is supposed to say and expect.

“This was the first thing I expressed to them,” Shea says. “I didn’t have the funds to be able to go into all these classes at first. They gave me the chance to get into a class called BOLD, an eight-week course that teaches you to get down and dirty, to do everything that you’re supposed to do to create your business.”

“The whole point of KW is to show agents that real estate doesn’t have to be a self-employed business anymore.”

From then on, KW helped him grow no matter what. He knew right off the bat that he didn’t like paperwork, so he hired a transaction coordinator. From there, his goal was to be present in other states. Then the expansion team came up; KW was one of the only brokerages who were doing that.“The whole point of KW is to show agents that real estate doesn’t have to be a self-employed business anymore. KW gives you tools, free trainings, mastermind events, and support.”Shea learned that instead of always needing his broker to be nearby to answer questions, he could simply walk next door and ask a fellow agent. “They’re more than willing to help you,” he says.

The biggest reason that Shea chose KW was that his goals were to dream big, to get to the biggest point he can. “I know that they are the ones who have shown and proven that you can do it, and they helped me do it.”

What sets Shea apart as an agent now?“I’ve created a team with multiple people who are able to help you no matter what. You don’t have an obligation to call just one person. All of my team is going to be communicating with you, making sure that the whole process is smooth. I also have knowledge of commercial, land development, industrial, and residential. We can help you with anything.”

Shea still has friends in other brokerages, so he hears about the problems they face.“The biggest thing that they’re probably afraid of is change. They’re top-producing agents who have created a business at their brokerage; having to move everything they’ve created scares them, I think,” he says of these other agents outside of KW.KW gives you the tools to get ahead of the market and change when it changes. Quarterly market reports and statistics give the agents the ability to gauge how best to serve their clients in the current market.“Our goal is to give what knowledge we have to our clients so that they can make the best decision for themselves,” says Shea.

If you have any questions or are curious about working with Keller Williams, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/February/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Keller+Williams+Turned+Shea+Kopeckys+Career+Around.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/February/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Keller+Williams+Turned+Shea+Kopeckys+Career+Around.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re an agent who is stagnant in your career, you’ll want to hear this agent’s story of how KW transformed his approach to the real estate industry and why should join the team.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re an agent who is stagnant in your career, you’ll want to hear this agent’s story of how KW transformed his approach to the real estate industry and why should join the team.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Forget FAQs, You Need to Ask the SAQs</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/forget-faqs-you-need-to-ask-the-saqs.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-22 06:50:47 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Forget+FAQs%252C+You+Need+to+Ask+the+SAQs.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’ve all heard of FAQs, but have you heard of SAQs? Today I’m going to talk about why the SAQs are the questions you should really be asking, as they relate to your real estate business.

First off, let me say congrats on your new real estate career. I’m very excited for you. I remember when I started my journey 16 years ago and it was very exciting. You’re probably getting a lot of calls from brokers and other agents that want to tell you about their company and why you should choose to work there. They’re all ready to answer the FAQs because that’s what everybody asks them. However, there are certain questions that you should be asking

“You should be the one doing the interviewing.”

When you’re looking to join a team or brokerage, you should be the one doing the interviewing. Not the other way around. You want to make sure that they have what you need to perform at a high level. I’ve actually put together a list of SAQs for you to ask the next time you meet with a broker.

They include questions like, “How is your company ranked in the marketplace?” and “What technology is available to me for free?”

These kinds of questions are important to ask so that you have clarity on what they are bringing to the table. You need to view this as an investment into a brokerage instead of an expense. If you’re going to invest money in a brokerage, you want to make sure you succeed at a high level.

You obviously got into this business to succeed. If you’d like to succeed and are interested in getting a copy of my SAQs for free, reach out to me and I’ll make sure to send them over.

If you have any other questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Forget+FAQs%252C+You+Need+to+Ask+the+SAQs.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Forget+FAQs%252C+You+Need+to+Ask+the+SAQs.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As you start your real estate career, there are a few things you should know. One of them is the SAQs that you should be asking.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As you start your real estate career, there are a few things you should know. One of them is the SAQs that you should be asking.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Has KW Helped Kaelee Miller’s Career?</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-has-kw-helped-kaelee-millers-career.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Interviews</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-05 04:51:25 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Has+KW+Helped+Kaelee+Millers+Career%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re bringing you another great testimonial from agent Kaelee Miller. Here’s what she had to say about choosing Keller Williams, what makes her stand out as a real estate agent, and how KW has helped her throughout her career.

Why did you choose KW?

Last year, I decided what my goals were going to be. I knew what I wanted them to be, but I didn’t know how to get there. The team leader here at the Legacy office was super amazing—she always wanted to be there regardless of me being at KW or not. She would consistently reach out to me to see if she could help me. We met one night, and everything that KW had to offer helped me get to the next level in my business and double the production I wanted to. They have training, they have statistics—they actually teach you how to run your business like a business, where before I didn’t realize it was a business. It was kind of a hobby at that time. Last year when I set out my goals I really wanted to step it up and have it more serious. When I met with the team leader, she actually had the statistics and the training that would help me, and they taught me to run it like a business.

“Every single person, regardless of how high-level they are or how busy they might seem, is there to help you.”

What makes you stand out as a real estate agent?

I like to hold your hand when needed. If you’re a first-time homebuyer, I like to set aside the time to educate you through the process so it’s not just, “Oh hey, I’m buying a house.” You know the steps of the process. Another one is I like to set it up so I’m building a relationship with you through the process so when we close on the transaction, it’s not a transaction—I’m actually helping you get into the home and I build the relationship with you moving forward. I believe that helps me with building a referral-based business and having me be your lifetime Realtor, as you are my lifetime client.

How has KW helped through the fears that come with being an agent?

From experience, I did the assisting and helped on the back end, and then when I jumped in full time, that’s where I really excelled. I think KW really helps with holding your hand through that and they show you the process and the steps. They also include you in the KW statistics so that when you introduce yourself, you don’t have to say, “Hi, I’m a new agent–I haven’t closed a deal.” You can actually say, “My brokerage,” “Who I am with,” or “We” when discussing your statistics. You get to use those different words where you have them behind you. The other thing I absolutely love about this office specifically but also KW overall is that every single person, regardless of how high-level they are or how busy they might seem, is there to help you. You can go knock on their door. You can go ask questions. I’ve been doing this for several years now, and I still have questions, and it’s super nice to just go knock on the door and be able to have them help me with whatever the question is, as silly as it is or if it’s a more in-depth question. There are always people here to help us.

Thanks to Joe for spending some time with us. If you have any questions for us in the meantime about KW or what it’s like to work here, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Has+KW+Helped+Kaelee+Millers+Career%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2018/January/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Has+KW+Helped+Kaelee+Millers+Career%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We sat down for another great testimonial with agent Kaelee Miller to talk about how KW has helped her career. Here’s what she had to say.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We sat down for another great testimonial with agent Kaelee Miller to talk about how KW has helped her career. Here’s what she had to say.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Q&A With Joe Reardon</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/a-quick-qa-with-joe-reardon.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Interviews</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-14 05:18:57 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/December/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+A+Quick+Q%2526A+With+Joe+Reardon.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We had another opportunity to sit down with a great agent here at Keller Williams, Joe Reardon. Here’s what he had to say about joining KW and how his experience has been so far.

Why did you choose Keller Williams?

I got introduced to KW through some of the classes. I went to a career visioning class and also an expansion class. I ended up talking with the OP here, Marcus, and I decided this was the best platform for building my team. I knew I wanted to build it out further. What’s different about KW is they help you build teams in a way that you grow a business. Many other brokers in other places have so-called teams that are really just lead generation platforms.

What I’ve started doing here is growing a real, solid team that’s a long-term business structure with many different types of good lead generation and many different ways for these agents to be successful. The structures for the agents on our team were more beneficial for them in terms of us retaining them as team members because with KW you have that built-in structure on teams because it’s so team-centric.

“What’s different about KW is they help you build teams in a way that you grow a business.”

What is a common fear of being involved in a brokerage?

For most real estate agents, once they get their license, they have this romantic notion of what that will entail that’s different than what the reality is. However, having said that, there are also many great things about it once you’re able to do it on a level that’s more than just sustaining yourself and putting gas in the car.

I think the fear is people coming into this business and being scared they’re not going to make it, and with good reason—there’s an 80% dropout rate for new agents within the first two years of getting their license. What they need to do is go someplace where they can get training and lay the foundation for being successful. Unfortunately, there are only a handful of places where you can actually get that. KW is a great spot for people to get those foundations, know the business, get business done in a short amount of time, and stay in the business.

What’s unique about your practice?

We have a unique background. I was an investor before I became an agent. Before that, I was a professional musician—my wife and I actually met while we were both playing Beauty and the Beast on Broadway. I’m a trumpet player; she’s a French horn player. Doing something like that requires a ton of discipline.

When we work with our clients, they know we have the discipline, the systems, and the strategies to get them the best outcome. We always make sure we get the best deal for our clients and their families. If that means we have to tell them to walk away from a house because it’s not a good deal, they know we’ll have the integrity to do that. Most agents run their business as if it’s a hobby. We run ours as a business, with the intent that our clients get the best outcome.

What goes into running a real estate business?

We already talked about discipline, so this means we have schedules and meetings. We meet with our agents every morning at eight and review what’s going on. After that, we’re on the phones prospecting and trying to find buyers for our listings and trying to find properties for our buyers. Then we have a team meeting at noon. From there we make sure everything’s going smoothly before focusing on our appointments. It’s a structured, systematic process that allows us to sell a lot of houses and take great care of our clients.

If there a specific agent that you have helped grow and succeed?

This is one of the things that’s really giving me the most joy in this business—not only helping our clients, but helping our agents be successful. We have an agent who’s joined our team within the last five months, and now they’re selling three homes a month. Before joining us, they only did two deals in the past year. I can sell 60 homes a year, but if I can help other people ignite their careers, that’s more satisfying. It’s enabling that person to live their dreams.They now have the skills and knowledge to help people and do this business on a high level with integrity.

Thanks to Joe for spending some time with us. If you have any questions for us in the meantime about KW or what it’s like to work here, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/December/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+A+Quick+Q%2526A+With+Joe+Reardon.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/December/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+A+Quick+Q%2526A+With+Joe+Reardon.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We recently sat down with Joe Reardon to ask him a few questions about his career at KW. Here’s what he had to say.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We recently sat down with Joe Reardon to ask him a few questions about his career at KW. Here’s what he had to say.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Analysis Paralysis Keeping You Stuck in Place?</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/is-analysis-paralysis-keeping-you-stuck-in-place.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-29 07:04:25 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Is+Analysis+Paralysis+Keeping+You+Stuck+in+Place%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do you find yourself caught in analysis paralysis—the feeling of overanalyzing what needs to happen in your business or life? Many of us have felt this way, so today I’d like to talk about how to overcome this feeling. Analysis paralysis is particularly common in our industry. People become so focused on analyzing their next step forward that they’re unable to actually move on.

Having big goals and dreams is great, but it’s important to not let analysis paralysis prevent you from taking immediate action. For example, I was at lunch with a good friend of mine the other day who told me he just couldn’t understand why he wasn’t moving forward. He had a big vision, but hasn’t been able to progress toward that goal.

When he told me about this problem, I was reminded of my own struggle from my past. Years ago, I was undergoing a huge shift in my career. This shift gave me a lot of anxiety. Instead of moving forward, I spent all my time analyzing my next move.

One day, I took some time off and visited an art gallery. As I saw one piece in particular, the image really hit home with me. I still have this piece of art today. The image is of a man walking through the dark with a torch. In the background of the painting, there’s something barely visible that appears to be the man’s goal.

“The only wrong action is inaction.”

I really identified with this painting. Just like the man in the painting, I was able to see my immediate surroundings, but couldn’t quite make out the end goal in the distance. I knew something better was out there, but I would need to cross a chasm of darkness to get there. This fear of the unknown is what holds us back.

Fear can keep us in a state of analysis paralysis. Thankfully, you can overcome it. The first thing you need is to have a sense of clarity around your vision. This doesn’t mean you need to have a perfect sense of the future, but you should have a clear goal.

The next step in overcoming analysis paralysis is to identify what’s “five feet in front of you.” Thinking back to the painting, the man with the torch could only see about five feet ahead of where he was going. You need to know what steps are in your immediate future. Then, you’ll need to move onto the third step: Take massive action.

The only wrong action is inaction. Sitting and overanalyzing your situation instead of taking any action won’t get you anywhere. When you actually take action, you’ll find that the light from your “torch” will cast out to the next “five feet” of your journey, which weren’t visible before you made that action.

At this point, it’s time to recalibrate. Make sure you’re headed in the right direction, then repeat the first three steps. Keep repeating these steps until you reach your goal. What I love about this method is that you are always moving forward. When I first saw this painting and got inspired, I didn’t know what was ahead of me. I chipped away toward my goal a little at a time. The dim light that represented my goal became brighter and brighter as I progressed forward.  Using this method, you can beat your analysis paralysis and move forward, too.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Is+Analysis+Paralysis+Keeping+You+Stuck+in+Place%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Is+Analysis+Paralysis+Keeping+You+Stuck+in+Place%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you suffering from analysis paralysis? Today, I’d like to share the key to reaching your goals in just four steps.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you suffering from analysis paralysis? Today, I’d like to share the key to reaching your goals in just four steps.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet Kaitlyn Norton, Listing Specialist</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/meet-kaitlyn-norton-listing-specialist.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Interviews</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-20 08:55:51 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Meet+Kaitlyn+Norton%252C+Listing+Specialist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We recently had the opportunity to sit down with another great agent here at Keller Williams, Kaitlyn Norton, and ask her a few questions about how she got into real estate and how KW has helped her career.

Kaitlyn had always been involved in sales, so getting into real estate seemed like the next logical step for her career. She heard of Keller Williams through her mother, who worked for KW herself. Once she started doing research between different brokerages and what we offered for training, however, the choice became clear. As she learned, real estate school can get you your license, but it can’t tell you what to with it, and that’s where KW stepped in.

“They have the systems and models and the training where you can hit the ground running,” she says. Though she did consider joining other brokerages besides Keller Williams, they didn’t offer training for new agents.

“They have the systems and models and the training where you can hit the ground running.”

“You do need a mentor, and you need someone who is looking out for you to make sure you know what you’re talking about.”

Many of Kaitlyn’s friends have also gotten into real estate, so it’s been interesting for her to compare different teams and models with them. The biggest thing that surprises her when she talks to people in different brokerages is the scarcity mindset and the inconsistency in their business. Being with KW, she notes, protects agents from experiencing that same kind of inconsistency because of the models and systems we have in place. Furthermore, those same models and systems allow agents to develop their business into something bigger.

Kaitlyn’s current role is a listing specialist with the William Bustos Group, which means she primarily works with sellers and helps market and negotiate their homes. This role, she claims, is well-suited to her strengths, and she credits the mentorship she received and the models and systems her team has in place for allowing her to focus on that.

What makes her and her team unique are the drive they have to do the job every day regardless of the rejection and having the mindset to run everything like a business.

“Sometimes, people don’t see that when they get into real estate,” says Kaitlyn. “You are running a business, and you have to have that same mentality.”

Thanks to Kaitlyn for taking the time to answer some questions for us. If you have any real estate questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Meet+Kaitlyn+Norton%252C+Listing+Specialist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Meet+Kaitlyn+Norton%252C+Listing+Specialist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re sharing another testimonial from listing agent Kaitlyn Norton about why she joined KW and how it helped her in her real estate career.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re sharing another testimonial from listing agent Kaitlyn Norton about why she joined KW and how it helped her in her real estate career.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A True Story of How Keller Williams Can Transform Brokerages</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/a-true-story-of-how-keller-williams-can-transform-brokerages.html</link>
        
          <category>Keller Williams Success Stories</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-06 10:11:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+A+True+Story+of+How+Keller+Williams+Can+Transform+Brokerages.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m excited to share the story of Chris Martindale and how he came to join Keller Williams.

Chris owned a brokerage but was drawn to the training, culture, and environment of Keller Williams. His brokerage only had about 70 agents, so he felt he really needed more support. According to Chris, Keller Williams provided that support while still allowing his agents to brand themselves.

The structure that Keller Willams provides is one key feature Chris believes has had a huge impact. Before working with Keller Williams, he felt his brokerage lacked accountability. Keller Williams’ tracking, mentoring, and training is something Chris says a small brokerage cannot achieve on its own.

“Keller Williams provides support while still allowing agents to brand themselves.”

According to Chris, Marcus Green has been incredibly helpful in assisting him in his adjustment to Keller Williams. Having someone like Marcus to guide him through this transition has been essential.

So, what’s unique about Chris’ practice? He believes his team and business are separated by the level of coaching and leadership he provides them, as well as the online marketing they employ. Rather than just handing out leads and leaving things be, Chris believes in helping to guide his agents through the process.

As an example of this, Chris recalls a story of a young agent who he helped to grow in the industry. This agent had a large network from the beginning but wasn’t sure how to leverage it. This is where Chris came in. Now, this agent has closed eleven deals so far this year. Helping agents grow their business is just one way Chris sets himself apart in the industry.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+A+True+Story+of+How+Keller+Williams+Can+Transform+Brokerages.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/November/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+A+True+Story+of+How+Keller+Williams+Can+Transform+Brokerages.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Chris Martindale was seeking more structure in a brokerage. This was just one reason that he transitioned into working with Keller Williams.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Chris Martindale was seeking more structure in a brokerage. This was just one reason that he transitioned into working with Keller Williams.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching the Importance of Managing Money</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/teaching-the-importance-of-managing-money.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-19 09:21:08 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Teaching+the+Importance+of+Managing+Money.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I read a staggering statistic recently about how people—particularly millennials—are spending their money. The problem is, they haven’t figured out how to manage money.

My 12-year-old daughter Abby “entered” the workforce recently by doing some babysitting, and she’s been asking me a lot of questions since then about how to save and invest money. In response, I invited her to read the very first business book I ever read, “The Richest Man in Babylon.” My grandfather gave me this book when I was 14, and if you haven’t read it, it’s a great read.

At first, she felt a bit timid because it was her first business book and it was a whole different world she was stepping into, but she was surprised and pleased with how it turned out. Here are two key lessons she learned from it:


  Get systematic in how you save your money. In one particular chapter, one of the characters had a regimen of how he spent his money. For every 10 gold pieces he earned, two went to paying off his debts, seven went toward living expenses, and one he set aside for savings. What this teaches is money can either go to work for you and bring back some of its friends, be used toward buying things, or flee. If you make bad investments, you’ll never see that money again.
  Make work your friend, not your enemy. This lesson comes from another chapter where a man who was sold into slavery was told by another slave that he would get his freedom back if he made work his best friend.


In addition to having her read this great book, I also dug up a ledger I made of my work schedule when I was 12 years old. In this ledger, I logged where I was working, how many hours I was working, and what job site I was at. Back then, I was working nine-, 10-, and 12-hour days at construction sites. In this ledger, I also recorded the money I was saving and depositing in the bank.

“I want to stop this epidemic of people creating bad money-spending habits at a young age.”

Even though I had a ledger at age 12 and read “The Richest Man in Babylon” at age 14, I didn’t get serious about following the principles of saving money until I was about 21. To show Abby the power of these principles, I built her her own spreadsheet. In this spreadsheet, her goal is to set aside $20 per week. Down the road, whenever she gets married, if her husband puts aside $20 per week as well and they make an average of 12% interest, that equates to almost $2 million over the course of 40 years. At 15% interest, that would equal $4 million, all from just setting aside $20 per week and starting the habit of saving early.

To help her get excited about instilling this principle, I’ve pledged to match every dollar she saves this year so we can do some investing together. I’m proud to say she already has some pretty good ideas on how to make that money work.

I encourage you to start having conversations with your own kids at a young age about saving money. I want to stop this epidemic of people creating bad money-spending habits at a young age. They’re spending money faster than they earn it, and this will cause big problems for our country if we don’t start having these conversations with our kids, advising them on how to spend money appropriately, and how to save for their future.

If you have any questions about this topic or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in our market, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Teaching+the+Importance+of+Managing+Money.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Teaching+the+Importance+of+Managing+Money.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>It’s important to develop the habit of investing and saving money at a young age. Because I believe in this principle, I’m putting my money where my mouth is.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>It’s important to develop the habit of investing and saving money at a young age. Because I believe in this principle, I’m putting my money where my mouth is.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet Carolyn Chavez</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/meet-carolyn-chavez.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Interviews</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-05 06:44:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Meet+Carolyn+Chavez.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We recently had the opportunity to sit down with another great agent here at Keller Williams, Carolyn Chavez. We sat down and asked her some questions, which she provided some great answers to. Here’s what she had to say:

Why did you choose Keller Williams?

I joined KW in 2007 when the market was a lot different. I was encouraged to come here because of the training, which was an amazing thing to have as a new agent. As a seasoned agent, the continued training has allowed me to grow, expand my business, and take things to the next level.

“Carolyn joined KW in 2007.”

What did you do before you joined KW?

I was a bar manager at a restaurant. In some ways it was similar because both jobs focus on the business of people and relationships, but as a Realtor I feel like I’m bringing more real value to people’s lives by helping their dreams come true.

What is one of your earliest memories at KW?

One of the first things I did as a new agent with KW was meet with a successful, seasoned agent with an incredible business. We went to lunch and I picked her brain about any and every little thing. She didn’t hold back, gave me great advice, and shared with me how she was having success even in a down market. It was really cool to experience the KW culture in that way and be welcomed into the fold so warmly.

What does that particular agent mean to you these days?

They will always be a mentor and someone that I look up to. I know I can always turn to her for advice, whether it’s in my professional life or personal life.

What is unique about your practice?

My tenacity is one thing that sets me apart. People have described me as a dog with a bone. I get after it and don’t let go. I will do whatever it takes to get things done. I’ve also made it a point to really focus on my craft and develop my skill set in a way where I feel confident in pretty much any situation I will encounter.

What is one of your favorite client stories?

I have one client who I ran into at a Tony Robbins seminar a few months back in L.A. We had already established a business relationship and friendship, but it was great to get to see her outside of the business world. Since then, we’ve developed a deeper friendship and continue to keep in touch. I always feel tickled pink knowing that this relationship happened off of a sign call. It’s amazing what can happen in this industry when you’re open and eager to build relationships.

Thanks to Carolyn for spending some time with us. If you have any questions for us in the meantime about KW or what it’s like to work here, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Meet+Carolyn+Chavez.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/October/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Meet+Carolyn+Chavez.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We recently sat down with Carolyn Chavez to ask her a few questions about her career with KW. Here’s what she had to say.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We recently sat down with Carolyn Chavez to ask her a few questions about her career with KW. Here’s what she had to say.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Benchmarks Help You Reach Your Goals</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-benchmarks-help-you-reach-your-goals.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-20 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/September/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Benchmarks+Help+You+Reach+Your+Goals.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m coming to you today from the beautiful Canadian Rockies. I’m excited to be up here with a great group of people.

As you may know, part of my personal mission statement is that the most difficult tasks yield the most valuable lessons. As we’ve been hiking across difficult terrain, I’ve learned a great lesson that I want to share with all of you.

I spent the last several months planning a very specific route for this trip. The day before we left, I got an email from the national park saying that the trail I’d planned to go on was closed.

I had dedicated a lot of time to planning the route, getting camping permits, and studying the trail. Everything was ready and suddenly, I had to come up with a new plan in less than 24 hours.

We went to the source, asked a few questions, and got a map. I put together a few key places that we wanted to go. Then, we figured out where we were going to start and where we were going to end up, which are the two most critical points in any journey.

Once I had a clear idea of our destination, I broke the trip down into smaller benchmarks. I studied all of the landmarks I would need to know to reach the first benchmark. I knew exactly what I was looking for, so I was able to put the map away.

“Celebrate each benchmark and milestone, and then head to the next one.”

Once we got to that first benchmark, we verified that it was where we were supposed to be and looked ahead to the second benchmark.

Benchmarks can also apply to your business and personal goals.

I get to rub shoulders with some of the most phenomenal people in the world, and we’re constantly talking about our end goals but we don’t talk about the next benchmark we need to hit to get there.

My challenge for you today is to figure out what your next benchmark is on your way to success. Once you hit that benchmark, celebrate your progress! Then, figure out where you need to be next in order to stay on track to achieve your goal.

Of course, your ultimate goal is still important, but that path is all built on benchmarks.

If you have any other questions or if there is anything else I can do to help you with your business, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/September/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Benchmarks+Help+You+Reach+Your+Goals.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/September/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Benchmarks+Help+You+Reach+Your+Goals.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We all tend to focus on our ultimate goals, but how do you know if you are on the right path to reach them? I’ll explain today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We all tend to focus on our ultimate goals, but how do you know if you are on the right path to reach them? I’ll explain today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Did This Agent Find Success With Keller Williams?</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/how-did-this-agent-find-success-with-keller-williams.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Interviews</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-05 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/September/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Did+This+Agent+Find+Success+With+Keller+Williams%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Having formally been affiliated with another brokerage that wasn’t the right fit, William Nieves says he chose Keller Williams upon the recommendation of a friend. He decided to give it a shot, so he called and made an appointment.

Since William used to be a police officer, he knew exactly how to interpret information and determine its worth. So when he received an informational packet about Keller Williams, he was happy to discover they had No.1 training, top-notch systems, and a family-oriented culture.

After a discussion with his wife, William made the switch. Switching to Keller Williams, he says, was the best career decision of his life.

At his previous brokerage, everyone was nice enough—but he simply didn’t feel as if he fit into the culture. He considers himself to be a very upfront person. Despite having brief success with working from home, something was missing. When he found Keller Williams, he found what he was missing.

Now William is the team leader of the Nieves Realty Group. He has approximately four people on his team right now, and it’s a great fit. Experience in law enforcement has molded William into a highly-disciplined person—he believes that if you follow the systems and you are a good fit for a culture, there is no reason you can’t succeed.

“When you are consistent, you will master what you do.”

Within his team, it is expected and required that his agents follow the systems. He believes that following systems is the key to success. However, he also has said that with success comes failure. In order to find success, you have to have had failure. William himself has had many hardships in life. He came from poverty and had to work through many struggles. It is this pain and strife, he says, which he has harnessed in motivating himself to do more. He has built upon the pain and loss to help his success blossom.

This focus on consistency and tenacity is something William carries with him through all aspects of his life and career. As a sixth degree in Kempo, he applies his black belt mindset to real estate. He says it’s as important to follow systems and procedures as an expert, or black belt, as it is as a novice, or white belt.

When you are consistent, you will master what you do. Time is the key to developing a skill set.

But, that’s not the only thing that sets William apart from other agents in our area. William comes from the East Coast, where people are more direct. As a result, he isn’t afraid to get down and dirty. He attributes many things to his success, including his upbringing in the Pennsylvania culture, his black belt, his hardships, and his time in law enforcement.

Many agents say that they’re the best, but the bottom line is that none of them have lived the way William has. William treats every client like family—he knows what it’s like to experience the pain of not succeeding. This is one of the reasons he is so successful. In fact, he has a 99% closing rate. As an agent and a person, he is truthful, consistent, and successful.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/September/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Did+This+Agent+Find+Success+With+Keller+Williams%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/VIdeos/2017/September/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Did+This+Agent+Find+Success+With+Keller+Williams%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This is the story of William Nieves. Today, he’s sharing how he found success with Keller Williams.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This is the story of William Nieves. Today, he’s sharing how he found success with Keller Williams.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Successful Communication in Life and Business</title>
        <link>http://blog.savvyagent.biz/the-key-to-successful-communication-in-life-and-business.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Advice</category>
        
        <author>Marcus Green</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-21 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate-.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The two most critical skills to succeed at a high level in both business and in life are communication and problem-solving.

One of my favorite quotes is: “The single greatest problem in communication is the illusion that it has taken place.”

Think about the number of times you’ve been in a conversation where you felt that you really understood each other only to walk away realizing that you each left the table with a very different idea of what was said.

The best way to understand this is to realize that there’s more to communication than talking, alone.

To help walk you through the process of communication I’d like to begin by telling a story.

One Christmas Eve during my teen years, I remember lying awake at night too excited to sleep. Being a little mischievous, I decided to sneak down to my parents’ storage room where I found an old, tattered pair of cowboy boots. I took the boots back upstairs, wrapped them up, and wrote “To: Mason, From: Santa” on them. After that, I put them in my little brother’s pile of presents.

When Mason opened the present the next day he had an absolute look of bewilderment on his face. I thought it was hilarious, but I’m not sure my parents shared that opinion.

My point is that just like with wrapping a present, there is a process to communication starting with encoding, then wrapping, and then delivering.

“We need to deliver messages in a way that the person receiving them would find appealing.”

When we decide that something needs to be communicated, we encode that message in our minds. In other words, we develop a plan. The next step is deciding a form of delivery—or how to “wrap it up.”

After that, we deliver the message. This delivery can be in-person, over the phone, through email, written, or in many other ways as well.

The problem that comes from this process is that after we deliver the message, we feel as if we’re finished with the communication. But, that’s not the case.

The message still needs to be unwrapped and decoded.

You might remember the game “Telephone”—where you stand in a circle and pass along a whispered message. As you may recall, the message was almost never the same once it reached the end of the chain.

A successful communication occurs when the message that we encoded is the same one that ends up being decoded.

To achieve this, we have to realize that not everyone is wired the same way. We need to deliver the message and wrap it up in a way that the person receiving it would find appealing.

Try implementing this process over the next few days in your life and business. See how it can work to help you improve the way you communicate.

If you have any other questions or would like more information feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate-.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.savvyagent.biz" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Marcus+Green/Northern+Utah+Real+Estate-.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Communication is as difficult as it is essential. Thankfully this simple process can help.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Marcus Green</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Communication is as difficult as it is essential. Thankfully this simple process can help.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Marcus Green</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Marcus Green</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Savvy Agent - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
