<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Michael Kaim Team - your professional Northeast Ohio Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Michael Kaim</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-05-25 12:57:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Michael Kaim</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northeast Ohio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>KaimTeam@gmail.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Michael Kaim</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northeast Ohio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Northeast Ohio Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Michael Kaim Team - your professional Northeast Ohio Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interview with Michael Kaim on How He Got Started in Real Estate</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/interview-with-michael-kaim-on-how-he-got-started-in-real-estate.html</link>
        
        <author>Michael Kaim</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-24 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northeast Ohio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Translate Your Schedule Into Success in Your Career</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-translate-your-schedule-into-success-in-your-career.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Michael Kaim</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-21 06:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Real+Estate+Agent+Training+%257C+Whats+your+schedule+like%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

One question that clients, friends, and other professionals in this industry always ask me is, “What does your typical day look like?”

To tell the truth, the answer to this has not remained consistent over the years. My schedule has changed. So before I get into talking about where I am today, I’d like to discuss how I got here.

At the beginning of my career, I was up at 5 a.m. each morning. After spending one hour at the gym, I was in the office six days a week by 7:00 a.m. I had a 7:30 a.m. roleplaying call where I practiced my scripts, and then at 7:45 a.m. I would get on the phones to prospect for three to four hours straight. I was calling my sphere, prospecting FSBOs, reaching out to expired listings, and more. This took me up until about lunch. I then prepared my afternoon schedule.

Then, between 2 p.m. and 4 p.m., I would make phone calls and take care between administrative work. If I had finished with that, I would work on following up with leads, instead. At last, I would end my day by scheduling appointments or doing more prospecting until 8 p.m. or 9 p.m.

My goal every day was to make between 50 and 75 contacts. This was the schedule I had set for years.

Since that time, I’ve had kids, I’ve built a team, and things have changed. Still, while my schedule may have been modified, this is still the same basic set of duties I work through each day.

“Prospecting time is money time.”

Working on the buyers’ side is a little different, though. That’s exactly why I’ve brought on Tina Hivnor to talk about her experience and schedule. One of the first things she emphasized was the importance of taking time off. And, according to her, this is something that holds true for buyer and seller agents alike. Our team likes to approach time off by looking at schedules a month at a time. We decide right away what time people will be taking off so that everyone can “recharge their batteries” from time to time.

After that, our team focuses more narrowly on what each week’s schedule will look like. We look at which days an agent will be in the office and which days will be marked off of their schedule. This way, appointments can be set with certainty and confidence. Our agents block off all the time they are not available so that they can be clear with their clients about when they are available. Our agents’ schedules are really formed around our clients.

And, of course, there’s also the matter of prospecting time. In Tina’s words, “Prospecting time is money time. This is the one block of time that if you ever erase it, you must replace it.” The reason that agents on our team are so successful is that they take the time to follow up and make new contacts each and every day. My father used to say that if you did no prospecting in a day, you didn’t do any work.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Real+Estate+Agent+Training+%257C+Whats+your+schedule+like%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Michael+Kaim/Real+Estate+Agent+Training+%257C+Whats+your+schedule+like%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’ve lived by, essentially, the same schedule as a real estate professional for years. Of course the way I spend a typical work day has evolved slightly since having a family and developing a team, but there are certain things that have remained constant. I still come into the office early and often stay late. To find out how I got to where I am today, what my schedule looks like, and how to use your schedule to be a successful agent, watch this short video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael Kaim</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’ve lived by, essentially, the same schedule as a real estate professional for years. Of course the way I spend a typical work day has evolved slightly since having a family and developing a team, but there are certain things that have remained constant. I still come into the office early and often stay late. To find out how I got to where I am today, what my schedule looks like, and how to use your schedule to be a successful agent, watch this short video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Northeast Ohio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Michael Kaim</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Michael Kaim</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Michael Kaim Team - your professional Northeast Ohio Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
