<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title> Real Estate Podcast with Ulises Vera</title>
    <link>http://theveragroupblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://theveragroupblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Clarity - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Ulises Vera</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-12-12 11:32:06 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Ulises Vera</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>uvera@sbcglobal.net</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Ulises Vera</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://theveragroupblog.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Clarity - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Myths That Are Holding Back Homebuyers</title>
        <link>http://theveragroupblog.com/2-myths-that-are-holding-back-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Ulises Vera</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-06 13:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+2+Myths+That+Are+Holding+Back+Homebuyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m going to debunk a few real estate myths that may have been holding you back from buying a home. Here are two myths that are absolutely false when it comes to home buying:


  Buyers need a 20% down payment. Studies show that 30% of homeowners and 39% of renters believe this is true. However, buyers often overestimate the funds needed in order to qualify for a home loan. In fact, there are many options that include little to no down payment; assistance programs at local, state, and federal levels can help eligible buyers secure an affordable down payment.
  Buyers need a 780 FICO score to qualify for a loan. Similarly to down payment beliefs, many buyers think they can’t purchase a home without a high FICO score. The graph at 1:27 in the video shows this isn’t true—51.7% of approved loans come from applicants with scores between 600 and 749.


“Being aware of your mortgage options helps make the process much easier.”

Whether you’re buying your first home or moving up to your dream home, being aware of your mortgage options helps make the process much easier. With these myths debunked, you may have even found that you’re in reach of buying your home sooner than you believed.

If you have any questions or need information, feel free to reach out to me. If you’re looking to buy your next home, get packing and give me a call. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+2+Myths+That+Are+Holding+Back+Homebuyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+2+Myths+That+Are+Holding+Back+Homebuyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>These myths may have been stopping you from a home purchase, but no more!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>These myths may have been stopping you from a home purchase, but no more!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Come Get Your Free Thanksgiving Pie</title>
        <link>http://theveragroupblog.com/come-get-your-free-thanksgiving-pie.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Ulises Vera</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-13 15:29:26 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Come+Get+Your+Free+Thanksgiving+Pie+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

I am so grateful for all the support my clients, friends, and family have given to The Vera Group. I could not have had such a great year without you. In return, I’d like to offer you a token of my appreciation this Thanksgiving: a free apple or pumpkin pie.

To make sure you get your dessert before the holiday, please make sure to RSVP as soon as you can. We’ll be handing out the pies on Monday, November 19 at 5:30 at our office, 884 Eastlake Parkway #1629 (in the same shopping center as Sprouts/Trader Joes). I can deliver your pie to you personally if you can’t make it, but keep in mind, we’ll have around 15 to 20 bottles of wine to share with those who come to pick up their pies.

“I can deliver your pie to you personally if you can’t make it.”

I look forward to giving you a gift you can share with your family and friends. Once again, I thank you for everything you’ve done for me and wish you a happy Thanksgiving and holiday season! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Come+Get+Your+Free+Thanksgiving+Pie+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Come+Get+Your+Free+Thanksgiving+Pie+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’d like to provide the dessert for your Thanksgiving feast.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’d like to provide the dessert for your Thanksgiving feast.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ensure a Fun and Safe Halloween With These 4 Tips</title>
        <link>http://theveragroupblog.com/ensure-a-fun-and-safe-halloween-with-these-4-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Ulises Vera</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-25 14:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Here are four tips that will help you and your family have a fun, safe Halloween:

1. If you’re a homeowner expecting trick-or-treaters, clear your sidewalks and front yard of all debris and keep everything brightly lit. Also, make sure you use LED candles instead of real candles inside your Jack-o’-lanterns.

2. If you’re a parent with young children who plan on trick-or-treating, make sure you accompany them to every front door they visit. Also, always use crosswalks instead of running across the street, and remember to tell your children to never enter a stranger’s home.

“By following these tips, you and your trick-or-treaters will have a safe and happy Halloween.”

3. If you’re going to be driving on Halloween night, drive slowly, stay off your cell phone, watch out for children crossing the street, and be extra careful when you’re near an intersection or a street corner.

4. Make sure your candy is safe to eat. Watch out for any treats with an unusual or discolored appearance, any unwrapped items, or any items whose wrappers have a tear or a hole in them. As a general rule of thumb: When in doubt, throw it out.

As always, if you have any questions about our San Diego real estate market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Halloween is just around the corner, so here are a few tips to keep things fun and safe for you and your family.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Halloween is just around the corner, so here are a few tips to keep things fun and safe for you and your family.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Your October 2018 Market Update</title>
        <link>http://theveragroupblog.com/your-october-2018-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Ulises Vera</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-02 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+October+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In our market, the homes that are still hot are those in the lower price point—the sweet spot is between $250,00 and $550,00. The reason this price point is still so hot is because of home affordability; this is the range in which most people will qualify for a mortgage.

At higher price points above $750,000, it seems like homes are staying on the market a little longer. The same is true of homes that aren’t yet in market condition, like those that haven’t been decluttered, depersonalized, or staged well. Price and condition both make a huge difference in whether or not buyers will make an offer on your home in this market.

The median home price for San Diego County remains between $585,000 and $630,000. For a 2,000-square-foot home, you’ll end up paying around $575,000, depending on upgrades and the condition of the home.

“Price and condition both make a huge difference in whether or not buyers will make an offer on your home in this market.”

Many buyers and sellers on the fence about entering the market have been asking about whether the market is shifting or not.

My answer is yes, the market is shifting, moving from a complete seller’s market to more of a balanced market. In the end, it’s a win-win for both buyers and sellers. Interest rates are still historically low and you’re getting a lot of bang for your buck.

If you have any questions about the market or about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+October+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+October+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In this October market update, I’ll show you which price point is hottest, what determines a home’s chances of getting offers, and what a shifting market means for buyers and sellers alike.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In this October market update, I’ll show you which price point is hottest, what determines a home’s chances of getting offers, and what a shifting market means for buyers and sellers alike.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6 Mistakes to Avoid When Selling</title>
        <link>http://theveragroupblog.com/6-mistakes-to-avoid-when-selling.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Ulises Vera</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 15:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+6+Mistakes+When+Selling.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In my 14-year career, I have seen many sellers make detrimental mistakes. Today I want to give you six of the biggest ones so you can avoid making them as well:

1. Picking the wrong agent. The right agent will answer your calls or at the very least return them in a timely manner. They will be professionals who know the market from experience and be honest and straightforward with you. You want someone who will tell you the truth, not just what you want to hear. 

2. Overpricing your home. When selling, pricing is everything to potential buyers. Even a home with poor marketing will sell if it is priced right. 

“To help declutter, get boxes to pack up personal items and store them in the garage or a storage pod.”

3. Failing to make repairs to your home.  You need to fix those minor repairs such as the dog-chewed baseboards because buyers can see it when they walk through your home.

4. Neglecting to declutter. Most buyers start their home searches online, so you want your pictures to show off your home, not your stuff. If you leave your home cluttered, there’s a good chance buyers won’t want to look at your home. To help declutter, get boxes to pack up personal items and store them in the garage or a storage pod. 

5. Not allowing adequate access to your home. Make sure your home is show-ready for potential buyers, because I found out that eight out of 10 won’t try to see your home a second time. 

6. Getting too emotional about your house. Sellers are sometimes very attached to their homes because they have a lot of memories there, but when you sell your home, you need to look at it as a property, not your home. If someone gives you a lowball offer or they talk about remodeling the home once they move in, don’t take it personally, especially if you got the money you wanted. 

If you have any additional questions about this, or if you’re interested in speaking with me about buying or selling, please feel free to call or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+6+Mistakes+When+Selling.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+6+Mistakes+When+Selling.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you making any of these six selling mistakes?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you making any of these six selling mistakes?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Make Your Offer Stand Out</title>
        <link>http://theveragroupblog.com/4-tips-to-make-your-offer-stand-out.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Ulises Vera</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-16 16:07:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Making+Your+Offer+Stand+Out.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Buyers searching for a home in the middle of a seller’s market may feel discouraged by the competitive conditions they find themselves up against. When the market is stacked against them, is there anything buyers can do to make their offer stand out from the crowd? Actually, yes. Let’s take a look at a few simple techniques homebuyers can use to set themselves apart: 

“Submitting a high offer with great terms will go a long way in helping you stand out against the crowd.”


  Submit a larger earnest money deposit. Deals don’t always go through to closing, so sellers in a competitive market may be wary of offers that come without any guarantee of the buyer’s intentions. A larger earnest money deposit shows the seller you’re serious. 
  Show sellers that you’re qualified. Many of the buyers you’ll compete against will be pre-qualified, but a significantly smaller percentage will be pre-approved. A pre-approval letter verifies that a lender has reviewed your status and believes you to be a capable and qualified buyer. 
  Give the seller some time to move. Buyer possession is often a sticking point in a transaction. If you’re buying and selling simultaneously, you already know what a difficult a position this is to be in. And this scenario only becomes more complex when you realize the seller you’re appealing to may be in the same boat as you. So, cut them some slack and allow them ample time to settle their own moving process. Sellers are much more likely to accept offers from buyers who are willing to make such concessions without asking for compensation.
  Write your best offer. Don’t hope for the chance to negotiate later on. Have your agent conduct a comparative market analysis so that you can strategize your offer accordingly. Submitting a high offer with great terms will go a long way in helping you stand out against the crowd. 


If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Making+Your+Offer+Stand+Out.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Making+Your+Offer+Stand+Out.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Homebuyers who find themselves competing in a hot sellers market can follow a few simple tips to stand out from the crowd.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Homebuyers who find themselves competing in a hot sellers market can follow a few simple tips to stand out from the crowd.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>You're Invited To Our Ice Cream Social</title>
        <link>http://theveragroupblog.com/youre-invited-to-our-ice-cream-social.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Ulises Vera</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-22 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Come join us on Saturday, July 28th over at Montecito Park for unlimited ice cream for the whole family! We will have a jumper and fun activities for the kids from 11am-1pm. RSVP here and use the code: fun for free tickets for the whole family!

 

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Come join us on Saturday, July 28th over at Montecito Park</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Come join us on Saturday, July 28th over at Montecito Park</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Major Life Changes Impact Your Real Estate Situation</title>
        <link>http://theveragroupblog.com/how-major-life-changes-impact-your-real-estate-situation.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Ulises Vera</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-16 14:33:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Unfortunate+Life+Occurrences.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to share with you a few tips for dealing with your home through major life changes. Try as you might, you can’t plan your life out fully. Sometimes things just happen, which is why I have a few scenarios where life makes a decision for you and how you should respond.

1. Losing your job. If you find yourself in this position and can no longer afford to pay your mortgage, there are some options. The first is finding another job quickly. Even if you don’t, there are multiple avenues that you can pursue. Don’t just list right away or walk away from your home.

“You need time to grieve, but the real estate market isn’t sympathetic to anyone.”

2. Divorce. Unfortunately, this situation is more common than we would like. If you’re in this situation, you have options as well. You can sell the home, or one of the spouses can offer the other a buyout. There isn’t a one-size-fits-all deal here. It’s important to contact a real estate expert before making any irrational decisions, which can be tempting in this situation.

3. Losing a loved one. You need time to grieve, but the real estate market isn’t always so empathetic. If you or someone you know has this happen, we would be happy to help explain your options and help make things just a bit easier at this tough time.

If you have any questions for me about any of these unfortunate situations and what you can do to remedy them, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Unfortunate+Life+Occurrences.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Unfortunate+Life+Occurrences.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re going through an unfortunate life situation like death or divorce, we can help solve your real estate problems. Here’s what we can do.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re going through an unfortunate life situation like death or divorce, we can help solve your real estate problems. Here’s what we can do.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Not Even Zillow Trusts Their Zestimate Feature</title>
        <link>http://theveragroupblog.com/not-even-zillow-trusts-their-zestimate-feature.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Ulises Vera</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-04 11:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Zestimates.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You have probably heard of Zillow’s Zestimate tool, but today I am here to tell you the truth about this well-known online feature. In actuality, you shouldn’t trust Zestimates. And there are a few key reasons why.

If you have not heard of Zestimates already, I will break that down for you before moving onto our main discussion. Zillow’s Zestimate tool is a web-based algorithm that draws on limited data to generate a home value estimate. 

Unfortunately, Zestimates are not very accurate. Zillow freely admits that this tool is just a starting point in determining home value. It is not an appraisal. If it were, it would be called a “Zappraisal.” 

But what exactly is it that makes Zestimates so unreliable? 

Well, the algorithm relies on user-submitted data. This means anyone with access to the website could skew what is displayed. Sellers know that today’s home buyers spend a lot of time online and that many people will see their home (and its supposed value) on Zillow. 

As a result of this, sellers may submit information that falsely inflates their Zestimate. Ultimately, Zestimates are very easily manipulated. 

“You would not trust serious health issues to WebMD, so why would you trust pricing your home to Zillow?”

In fact, Zillow is well aware of the fact that 75% of San Diego County homes have Zestimates that are off by 10% or more. A home worth $700,000, for example, could have a Zestimate that lists its value $70,000 too high, or too low.  

It is for this reason that even Zillow themselves encourage homeowners to get an appraisal or a comparative market analysis when pricing their home. The truth is that Zestimates should be used similarly to WebMD. You would not trust serious health issues to WebMD, so why would you trust pricing your home to Zillow?

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or are curious about your home’s true value, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Zestimates.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+Zestimates.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Zestimates are a popular tool for determining home value, but are they trustworthy? Today we will discuss this important question.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Zestimates are a popular tool for determining home value, but are they trustworthy? Today we will discuss this important question.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is Currently Happening in the San Diego and Chula Vista Markets?</title>
        <link>http://theveragroupblog.com/what-is-currently-happening-in-the-san-diego-and-chula-vista-markets.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Ulises Vera</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-15 12:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+EDIT+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does the market look like in our area for spring 2018? San Diego and Chula Vista are in a seller’s market.

What does that mean, and what is the difference between a seller’s market and a buyer’s market? Basically, the difference boils down to supply and demand. We are experiencing less supply and more demand from buyers in the current market, which creates a seller’s market. Inventory of homes is down about 9%, which is due to our market having more buyers than sellers.

So how does the current inventory affect the home values in our area?

Median prices continue to grow, and they’re up about 8% from this time last year.  But why do median prices continue to rise? This is simply because supply is low. Meanwhile, there are many buyers who want to get into this desirable area and get more bang for their buck.

“If you are a buyer, you need to know your finances and purchase power.”

On another note, let’s talk about interest rates. Interest rates continue to rise in our area. However, they are still historically low. Now is definitely the time to break into the market if you are thinking about it. 

If you are a buyer, make sure you talk to a lender to get all your financing ready so you can start submitting offers. You need to know your finances and purchasing power. You then have to interview to get the right agent who can help you submit competitive offer.

If you are a seller who is still on the fence about selling, now is the time. We are still getting multiple offer situations, and you should take advantage of this situation before the rates really spike up.

If you have any questions about our current market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+EDIT+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://theveragroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ulises+Vera/2018/San+Diego+Real+Estate-+EDIT+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The San Diego and Chula Vista markets remain strong. Today I have some of the recent statistics for our market this spring.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ulises Vera</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The San Diego and Chula Vista markets remain strong. Today I have some of the recent statistics for our market this spring.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Ulises Vera</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Ulises Vera</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Clarity - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
