<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Real Estate Podcast with Kati Spaniak</title>
    <link>http://realestategrit.net</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://realestategrit.net"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Real Estate Grit - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Kati Spaniak</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-06-25 13:22:55 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Kati Spaniak</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Kati@SpaniakTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Kati Spaniak</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://realestategrit.net/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Chicago Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Real Estate Grit - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Build Relationships With Potential Clients</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-to-build-relationships-with-potential-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-14 12:45:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
I find it interesting to watch how people work with their clients. So today I am going to talk about how to build relationships with potential clients. I have found that coming across as a consultant results in people trusting and valuing you. Years ago, I took a sales training class where they talked about how you cannot go into a situation feeling like you need the money. If you go in thinking that you are financially secure, you are going to build a relationship with that potential client. I come from a place of giving back to my clients. When you meet someone, you really want to listen to what they are looking for and decide if you are really able to help them. If you are not able, tell them. You will get much further in life with your client by being honest. Sometimes this means that you must be a little confrontational. I am personally not great at being confrontational, so I try to tone it down. For agents who have a really hard time with needing to be liked by everyone, this can be a little challenging.

“The client needs to understand that they will not necessarily get everything that they want.”An example of this is when you have a client who has specific wants. They want a 3-bedroom, 3-bathroom home within walking distance to downtown and is completely updated for $500,000. This is not possible, but some agents will neglect to tell their clients this and instead tell them they will find it. The client needs to understand that they will not necessarily get everything that they want. When they start their home search and discover that nothing is matching well, that is a problem. It is your job to guide them using your communication skills. You must have those uncomfortable conversations so you don’t end up showing them 20 homes and none of them match. If this happens, they will eventually go to another agent. You really have to understand what a client is looking for and be honest with them. You need to guide them and communicate with them that they may not get exactly what they want. Being honest may lead to you not getting the sale, but the client will view you as trustworthy. So, when I am working with people, I really try and connect with them as a consultant. I provide them information about the real estate industry and be myself. I enjoy hearing their story and deciding if I can help them or not. To find out more about how to build relationships with your clients, please feel free to contact me. I would be happy to speak with you further about this.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Although it may seem like you could lose a potential client, you have to be honest with them so nobody ends up unhappy.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Although it may seem like you could lose a potential client, you have to be honest with them so nobody ends up unhappy.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How I Slowly but Surely Built a Successful Real Estate Business</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/how-i-slowly-but-surely-built-a-successful-real-estate-business.html</link>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-07 12:21:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

People ask me all the time, “How did you get started in real estate?”

Today I would like to tell you the answer to this question. So, let’s take a look back at how I got my start.

I entered this industry back in 2003 when I got my license and began working as part of a real estate team. This chapter in my career lasted until about 2008, when I left the team and took a few years off from this path. 

Ultimately, though, I did come back. I got a new license in 2012 and started up the team that I am still leading today. Since then, I have built my business to be among the top real estate professionals on the North Shore of Chicago and the No. 1 producer in Northbrook. 

And, actually, being in the business prior to founding my current team proved to be a great benefit as I re-entered the industry. It gave me time to really focus on my business plan, as well as my plan for daily activities. Immediately after re-entering real estate, I was very committed to dedicating certain days and times to being in the office working on my business plan. From the very beginning, my goal was to be the No.1 agent in Northbrook. I wanted people in this community to think of me as their go-to real estate professional.

So, once I had developed a plan, I began reaching out to people. I started sending out emails, I took out a little bit of advertising space, and I began providing market evaluations for community members. And I did this because whether people are moving or not, everyone loves real estate.

“I wanted people in this community to think of me as their go-to real estate professional.”

Diving deeper into real estate was a slow-going process, but I kept going. I continued to put my name out there and provide services for the community, knowing that it would eventually pay off. After about six months of doing this, people began to notice. They would say things like, “You’re everywhere!” 

In actuality, I wasn’t everywhere. I was just making sure to stay visible in the places that mattered. I kept my focus small and found my niche. Doing this, in my opinion, is one of the keys to building a business. Being persistent without making people feel as though they are being constantly sold to is what put me on the path to success. If you hope to build a business, you have to show people what kind of value you can provide for them. 

Even if someone has no immediate real estate need, it is good to establish yourself as a resource. That way when the time does come for them to make a move, they know who to reach out to. 

Another way I got my start and established myself within the community was by hosting roundtable discussions about Northbrook. Doing this allowed me to meet a lot of people without spending a lot of money in the process. 

Everything you do as an agent should be done with a certain question in mind: “What do people need and want from you as a real estate agent?”

Being an agent is not about being a salesperson, it is about being someone who the community can turn to for their real estate needs. If you work toward this and do so consistently, you are sure to find success in your business.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I would like to share the story of how I got started in real estate. I hope that this look into my past will help you grow a better future.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I would like to share the story of how I got started in real estate. I hope that this look into my past will help you grow a better future.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Gaining Leads from an Open House</title>
        <link>http://realestategrit.net/the-key-to-gaining-leads-from-an-open-house.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-29 12:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Open houses can go really well or really badly. In any case, there will be a lot of people walking through the house to check things out. 

So, how do you sit an open house to get leads? 

The first thing you need to focus on is having the right mindset. You’ve got to believe that the connections you make at the open house will either translate to a sale or to a new lead. After all, when you sit an open house you’re there for two reasons: To sell the house and to gain leads. 

Beyond simply having the correct mindset, it’s also important to have adequate signage. The more signage you have, the more traffic you’re going to see through the open house. Putting out a lot of signs can be time-consuming, but it will be well worth it in the end. 

Door knocking is another great way to generate interest in the open house. Even though the people you meet this way may not be looking for a home, it’s still good to make connections. They could make a great addition to your database. 

Now that we’ve discussed a few ways to prepare for the open house, let’s move on to what you should be doing the day of. First, make sure you arrive about 15 minutes early. There’s nothing worse than walking up to an open house to find people already waiting in the driveway. 

“The goal of an open house is to make connections and then follow up with them.”

It’s also important to have a sign-in sheet prepared and readily available to everyone who passes through. You can use anything from an iPad to pen and paper. All that matters is that you’re capturing the contact information of the people who attend. This includes their names, phone numbers, and email addresses. They should also provide the name of their agent. 

The goal of the open house is to connect with people on a personal level. Do not be overbearing as people tour the home. You want people to feel at ease. However, people who aren’t willing to fill out the sign in sheet shouldn’t be allowed to view the home. 

Once the open house is over, it’s good to take notes about the connections you made. And don’t forget to enter these people into your database. Of course, you should always keep in mind that you’re also there with the goal of helping to sell the home. If anyone visiting the home comes along with their agent, be sure to let the listing agent know. This creates a great opportunity to get some feedback about the house. 

So, in short, the goal of an open house is to make connections and then follow up with them. Open houses are a great way to get clients. Remember to keep your energy up and be yourself.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://realestategrit.net" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are two goals you should keep in mind when you sit an open house: selling the property and gaining leads.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are two goals you should keep in mind when you sit an open house: selling the property and gaining leads.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>North Shore real estate agent, North Shore real estate career, Northwest Suburban real estate agent, Northwest Suburban real estate career, Lake County real estate agent, Lake County real estate career, Chicago real estate agent, Chicago real estate career, Chicago real estate job, real estate careers, real estate jobs, real estate training</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Kati Spaniak</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Kati Spaniak</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Real Estate Grit - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
