<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Wasatch Front Real Estate Podcast with Doug Cary</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Doug Cary Team - your professional Wasatch Front Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Doug Cary</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-02-20 14:30:27 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Doug Cary</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>doug@dougcary.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Doug Cary</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Wasatch Front Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Doug Cary Team - your professional Wasatch Front Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Ways to Sell Your Home</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-ways-to-sell-your-home.html</link>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-06 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://youtu.be/NE5NMVvQSe8</guid>
        <description>

“Time to move or cash in on your investment property? Now is a great time to sell, the question is, how to go about it? Today we’ll go over the pro’s and con’s of a home owner’s three major options. To learn more, watch this video.”
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://youtu.be/NE5NMVvQSe8" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://youtu.be/NE5NMVvQSe8" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Look for in a Real Estate Agent</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/what-to-look-for-in-a-real-estate-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-03 13:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+Look+for+in+a+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a lot of real estate agents out there, but that doesn’t mean they’re all able to serve your needs effectively. In fact, there are some key differences that set the best agents apart from the rest.

The average real estate agent with the Salt Lake Board of Realtors only sells four homes per year. 50% of agents sold no homes in 2018. It’s very important to make sure the agent you choose isn’t one of these low producers.

“To find out how good of an agent they are, you need to look at their track record.”

To find out how good of an agent they are, you need to look at their track record. Don’t just focus on years of experience—you need to know how many homes they sell in a year. Here are a few questions you can ask in order to gain a better understanding:

1. “How many homes did you sell last year?” This shows how productive and experienced they are.

2. “What is your list-to-sale price ratio?” For example, if they list a $300,000 home and sell it for $300,000, they have a 100% list-to-sale price ratio. However, the average agent only has a 95% ratio, so it’s important to know your agent’s ratio. Mine, for example, is 99.3%.

3. “Do you work alone or with a team?” If they’re a solo agent, they have to manage everything on their own. There’s so much to keep track of, so it’s much better to have an entire real estate team at your service. However, you may not want to work with a very large team that may not give you personalized service.

If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+Look+for+in+a+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+to+Look+for+in+a+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What should you look for in a real estate agent? Here are a few things you need to know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What should you look for in a real estate agent? Here are a few things you need to know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Going on in the Wasatch Front Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-going-on-in-the-wasatch-front-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-18 14:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/April/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Going+on+in+the+Wasatch+Front+Market_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

At the beginning of this year, economists predicted that, along the Wasatch Front, we were going to see a very flat or even a declining market. Interest rates were predicted to go up a couple times this year, as well.

Well, those predictions have been called off. In fact, in February, when interest rates were expected to go up, they actually came down. Due to our economy, interest rates for a 30-year fixed mortgage are currently at 4.25%, which is quite a drop from the 4.75% to 5% range they were in.

Not only can owner-occupied buyers afford more, but investors can also buy now. Doing so makes better sense financially, even with the home prices going up as they are.

That spurred the market on—not only are we seeing far more competitive offers in the market, but we’re also seeing properties in the lower price points sell above list price! Overall, the market for homes under $500,000 has been seeing a lot of traffic.

“If you’re thinking of selling a home, I encourage you to act before June, just in case the market does flatten out.”

Above the $500,000 price point, homes that are properly marketed, fairly priced, and that are in great condition are selling as well.

Right now, inventory along the Wasatch Front is again going down, reaching an all-time low in all price ranges. There are currently 1.5 months of supply, meaning that if no other homes came on the market today, it would take 1.5 months to sell all the homes currently available.

Given that an inventory of four to five months is a balanced market and an inventory of six months or more constitutes a buyer’s market, we can clearly see that this is a fantastic seller’s market.

In the spring of 2018, we noticed these trends occurring, as well. We were in a great seller’s market until June came along, when things flattened out. We can reasonably expect something similar to happen again in 2019, but who really knows what the future will bring?

If you’re thinking of selling a home, I encourage you to act before that time, just in case the market does flatten out. For specific questions related to your property, feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/April/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Going+on+in+the+Wasatch+Front+Market_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/April/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Going+on+in+the+Wasatch+Front+Market_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m bringing you an update about the spring real estate market here along the Wasatch Front.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m bringing you an update about the spring real estate market here along the Wasatch Front.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A New Loan Program for You to Know About</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-new-loan-program-for-you-to-know-about.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-12 12:42:41 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/February/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+New+Loan+Program+for+You+to+Know+About.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re excited to talk about a brand-new loan program that allows buyers to use the rent on an investment property to help them qualify for more home.

“This program lets you buy and invest at the same time.”

Utah Housing has been around for a long time. They have a ton of different loan programs, from the traditional 20% down mortgage loans to zero-down loan programs. Recently, they’ve introduced a new program that allows buyers to purchase different kinds of properties, such as a duplex or a home with a mother-in-law apartment, and use the projected rent from those accessory dwellings to add into their income in order to purchase more real estate.

This is a great opportunity for a buyer to buy a new home while also getting a great asset. If you or someone you know is interested in this brand-new program, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/February/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+New+Loan+Program+for+You+to+Know+About.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/February/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+New+Loan+Program+for+You+to+Know+About.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You can become a homeowner and home investor with one transaction. Take a look at this new program from Utah Housing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You can become a homeowner and home investor with one transaction. Take a look at this new program from Utah Housing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>National Radon Prevention Month</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/national-radon-prevention-month.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-28 00:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/February/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Is+Radon+and+Could+It+Be+in+Your+Home%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Radon is a colorless, odorless gas that rises from the ground, enters our home through the foundation and, right now, is the No. 2 leading cause of lung cancer in the United States.

Between the months of October and March, Davis County actually provides free radon testing for residents. You can file a request for this test here.

Here are some startling numbers: 56% of homes in Centerville, 42% of homes in Bountiful, and 20% of homes in North Salt Lake City tested above the healthy EPA levels for radon.

“Radon is the second leading cause of this kind of lung cancer in the United States.”

When you’re buying a home, I highly recommend having a radon test performed. I also recommend having your home tested whenever you make significant changes or remodels, especially to the lower level.

If your home tests high or positive, you can purchase a radon mitigation system. This system uses a fan to pump air through the house to eliminate radon.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/February/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Is+Radon+and+Could+It+Be+in+Your+Home%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/February/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Is+Radon+and+Could+It+Be+in+Your+Home%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Why is having your home tested for radon so important? Today, let’s find out.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why is having your home tested for radon so important? Today, let’s find out.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Market Recap to Close Out 2018</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-market-recap-to-close-out-2018.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-02 14:15:27 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/January/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Market+Recap+to+Close+Out+2018.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Now that 2018 is in the books, what should buyers and sellers know about this past year’s market? What do the market trends from 2018 tell us about 2019?

The final numbers aren’t out yet, but we estimate that homes appreciated by 8% over the course of the entire year. Most of that increase happened during the first half of the year; after that, prices generally flattened out.

Interest rates started the year at 4%, but now they’re around 4.75%, and we expect them to continue to rise in 2019. Of course, the higher interest rates rise, the more expensive homes become for buyers. For example, getting a $300,000 mortgage would cost $133 per month more at today’s rate than it would have a year ago.

“As inventory levels have risen, homes have stayed on the market longer.”

Building costs are extremely high right now, but that’s not stopping builders from building and buyers from buying. There are some fabulous communities being built right now along the Wasatch Front, so make sure you contact a knowledgeable local agent before you walk into any of these properties so you know what you’re getting into and you get the best deal possible.

Nationwide, we’ve seen a general market slowdown. As interest rates have risen, inventory has increased as well. In many places, inventory is at a five-year high. Here in Utah, we’re starting to see this same trend. As inventory levels have risen, homes have stayed on the market longer. This is good news for buyers, who now have more homes to pick from.

We’re looking forward to a fantastic 2019, so if you have any other questions about our market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/January/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Market+Recap+to+Close+Out+2018.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2019/January/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Market+Recap+to+Close+Out+2018.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>2018 saw home prices increase, interest rates rise, and inventory levels increase as well. This is good news for buyers moving forward in 2019.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>2018 saw home prices increase, interest rates rise, and inventory levels increase as well. This is good news for buyers moving forward in 2019.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Opportunity Zones for Real Estate Investors</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/opportunity-zones-for-real-estate-investors.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-03 16:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/December/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Opportunity+Zones+for+Real+Estate+Investors.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are new and not very well known opportunities in the market called Opportunity Zones.

They were created by Congress last year and put into place beginning this year. There are certain census tracts in every state in the U.S.—46 in Utah, in fact—that are lower income areas in need of redevelopment. Opportunity Zones allow for states to nominate the areas as they would like to see increased investing in real estate.

When you invest in these Opportunity Zones, you are allowed to defer, reduce, or eliminate your capital gains entirely. This includes single-family homes and commercial real estate. If you hold the property for five to seven years, you’ll get a 10% reduction on your federal capital gains; for seven to 10 years, you’ll get a 15% reduction; and if you hold it longer than 10 years, you’ll pay no capital gains tax on the gains of this property.

As I mentioned, there are 46 Opportunity Zones here in Utah right now, including 15 in Salt Lake County, three in Davis County, and five in Weber County.

“When you invest in these Opportunity Zones, you are allowed to defer, reduce, or eliminate entirely your capital gains.”

Here’s how it works: Imagine that you have enough savings to allow you to invest in real estate; maybe you’ll end up selling another investment property of yours specifically so that you can invest in this Opportunity Zone. If there’s a capital gain from that previous sale, you can defer those gains, reinvest into this property, and then look to pay zero capital gains later on.

The big key is that you have to hold it for 10 years or more to be able to eliminate these capital gains altogether. Hypothetically, if you were to normally pay 25% in federal capital gains tax, eliminating the capital gains would allow you to have a 25% gain compared to investing in areas outside of an Opportunity Zone.

If you or someone you know is interested in investing in an Opportunity Zone, I’ve created automated emails that alert me and my clients about opportunities in these areas. Simply reach out to me and let me know in which areas you’re interested in searching.

Mind you, I’m a licensed real estate agent, NOT an accountant or a financial planner, so it is very important to consult those people on your team as you look at these opportunities.

I hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/December/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Opportunity+Zones+for+Real+Estate+Investors.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/December/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Opportunity+Zones+for+Real+Estate+Investors.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’ll tell you how you can legally pay zero capital gains on your investment properties.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’ll tell you how you can legally pay zero capital gains on your investment properties.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Get Rid of Your Mortgage Insurance</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-get-rid-of-your-mortgage-insurance.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-09 14:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/November/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Get+Rid+of+Your+Mortgage+Insurance.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m Doug Cary, Real Estate Agent with Century 21 Everest. I’m going to tell you how to get rid of mortgage insurance.

If you’ve bought a home and put less than a 20% down payment down, you’re familiar with mortgage insurance.  It’s that added amount on your statement every month you wish you could get rid of. The good news is you might be able to.  

Homes with less than 20% equity in it are more risky for lenders and the lender requires that you pay for insurance. This goes to another company that will pay back the lender if you were to foreclose on the home.

If you get a conventional loan, your lender will set up what is called Private mortgage insurance (PMI) and the rates vary by down payment and credit score but are generally cheaper than FHA rates for borrowers with good credit. Private mortgage insurance is typically paid monthly with your principal and interest payment. Once you hit 20% equity in your home you can request an appraisal from your mortgage company and drop this payment altogether. This will naturally drop off when you’ve made enough payments and it get’s to 78% loan-to-value.

“Once you have at least 20% equity on the property, you can also request that your lender drop that mortgage insurance altogether.”

If you get an FHA loan now the mortgage insurance cost is the same no matter your credit score and you are not allowed to drop the mortgage insurance premium when you hit 20% equity. You will either stick with it or refinance to a conventional loan. It wasn’t always this way. If you got your FHA loan before June 2, 2013, you can drop it at 20% just like a conventional loan.

VA loans have the VA guarantee which replaces mortgage insurance and works the same. There is an up-front funding fee that varies based on many things that your lender can go over with you. Sometimes this is all paid up front and sometimes it’s calculated into the monthly payment.

Many people are in a much stronger equity position today with prices having increased so much over the last few years. You might be surprised to find out that you could drop your mortgage insurance and save all that money every month.

I’m offering a free mortgage insurance review to see if you should request from your lender to drop mortgage insurance from your payment. Just call me and have your monthly mortgage statement available.

I’m here to help you with anything regarding real estate. Forward this to others making real estate decisions so they can be the best informed. Thanks for watching, I’m Doug Cary, your Utah Real Estate agent.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/November/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Get+Rid+of+Your+Mortgage+Insurance.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/November/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Get+Rid+of+Your+Mortgage+Insurance.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’ll be talking about mortgage insurance and how you can get rid of it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’ll be talking about mortgage insurance and how you can get rid of it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in our Wasatch Front Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-wasatch-front-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-10 10:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/October/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Happening+in+our+Wasatch+Front+Market%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’ve been paying any attention to the Wasatch Front market lately, you’ve probably noticed that it’s been undergoing some changes.

In comparing this year’s statistics to those from last year, we can see that there has only been an 8% year-over-year rise in the number of homes for sale.

However, while year-over-year changes may not indicate much change, the shift we’ve seen over the past few months has been comparatively quite dramatic. In the time between June of this year and the present moment, there has been a 56% increase in our market’s available inventory.

“Now is the time to sell.”

Meanwhile, the number of homes that have gone under contract in the last 30 days has decreased 20% since this time last year.

So what do these statistics mean, exactly?

Actually, it’s hard to say what the future holds. But while I may not have a crystal ball,  I can tell you that if you or anyone you know of are looking to sell, now is the time.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/October/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Happening+in+our+Wasatch+Front+Market%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/October/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Happening+in+our+Wasatch+Front+Market%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>It’s time to take a look at the latest developments in our Wasatch Front real estate market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>It’s time to take a look at the latest developments in our Wasatch Front real estate market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>You Won’t Want to Miss This Halloween Client Appreciation Event</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/you-wont-want-to-miss-this-halloween-client-appreciation-event.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-26 11:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’m excited to invite you to our Client Appreciation Pumpkin Patch Event coming up on Wednesday, October 10, 4:30-7:30pm. We’ll be transforming the parking lot outside our office into an amazing pumpkin patch featuring a hay maze, face painting, balloon animals, family photos, and free pumpkins for all! We plan on having a lot of fun and making this a great place for you to make some memories with your family. I’ll be dressed up, and if you can find me there, you’ll have the chance to guess which superhero I am. To see my full invite with all the details, watch this short video.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m excited to invite you to our Client Appreciation Pumpkin Patch Event coming up on Wednesday, October 10.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m excited to invite you to our Client Appreciation Pumpkin Patch Event coming up on Wednesday, October 10.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Miss the Deadline to Appeal Your Property Tax</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/dont-miss-the-deadline-to-appeal-your-property-tax.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-11 09:59:20 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I want to share an important reminder about the deadline to appeal your property tax. Salt Lake, Davis, and Weber counties all sent their assessed property value statements out at the end of July, and the deadline to appeal them is September 17. If you haven’t looked at yours yet, we’re seeing more people than ever whose property taxes are inaccurate. I’ve been helping people appeal their taxes for 13 years, and this year I’ve done more appeals than ever. If you’d like to appeal your property tax, I can assist you with that, as well as provide a complimentary tax evaluation. To hear my full message, watch my latest video.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you think your property tax is too high, the deadline to appeal it is coming up, and I can help you with the appeal.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you think your property tax is too high, the deadline to appeal it is coming up, and I can help you with the appeal.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Utah Market Is Shifting</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/our-utah-market-is-shifting.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-24 12:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/August/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+Utah+Market+Is+Shifting.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The market here in Utah is already starting to shift. Today I am going to talk with you about how this affects you as a homeowner, buyer, seller, or investor. You may want to share this with those that you love, especially those looking to make real estate decisions soon.

Nationwide, markets are shifting. In Utah, we are already seeing our inventory increase. We haven’t seen this happen in over five years, so the fact that we saw a 15% increase in the number of homes on the market in just 45 days is pretty significant.

So, what does this mean for you as a homeowner? If you’re happy in your home, absolutely nothing.

However, if you are thinking about selling, now is absolutely the best time to do so.

“The fact that we saw a 15% increase in the number of homes on the market in just 45 days is pretty significant.”

For those of you thinking about buying, it is also a great time for you because there are more homes on the market to look at.

If you think that waiting for the price to increase again is a good idea, you are taking a pretty big gamble. What if interest rates increase like experts predict to happen in the fall?

For investors that have been sitting and waiting patiently for a market change, get your money ready. Things are going to start changing quickly and we are going to start seeing some deals just around the corner.

The reality is that our economy here is strong. Our unemployment rate is only 3.3%, and we are ranked No. 1 in job growth in the nation. But, homes are 15% less affordable than they were this time last year and wages haven’t increased. This means that something has to change.

If you have any questions about this, or if you are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/August/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+Utah+Market+Is+Shifting.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/August/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Our+Utah+Market+Is+Shifting.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our Utah market is shifting, but what does it mean to you? Let's have a look.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our Utah market is shifting, but what does it mean to you? Let's have a look.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Pay for College Tuition With Real Estate</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-pay-for-college-tuition-with-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-10 14:21:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/August/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Paying+tuition+with+real+estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you worried about not being able to pay your child’s college tuition one day? If so, today we’ll discuss one way you can pay for it using real estate.

The average college tuition is $100,000 for a four-year degree. It’s estimated that in 15 years, this number will rise to over $207,000.

Further to that, studies show that the average college graduate earns 89% more than a worker with only a high school diploma. Each year of school adds 5% to 15% on their annual earnings later in life.

“It’s estimated that in 15 years, cost of college tuition will rise to over $207,000.”

With this information in mind, there are four ways people typically pay for college:

1. Parents pay for it with their regular income. Parents are taxed on their income, so the average degree will end up costing more like $130,000.

2. The student works through college to pay for it. This typically extends how long the student is in college and increases the likelihood of them dropping out.

3. Student loans. Students today are burdened with incredible amounts of debt.

4. Owning assets. Through the passive income of owning such assets as real estate, the parent can pay for college in part or in full.

This last method is what I want to discuss in more detail.

Imagine that your child will go to college in 15 years. Suppose also that you bought a rental property for $200,000, with a 20% down payment of $40,000. With the typical mortgage today, you’ll probably be making some cash flow, but suppose you put all of that back into the house for those 15 years. By that time, the house will have been completely paid for.

At that 15-year mark, that house could be worth $300,000 to $400,000. This asset would more than allow you to pay for your child’s education.

There are many ways in which we can work to make this happen for our clients. I know some people who will buy one property for each child, knowing that they will easily pay for tuition.

If this is of interest to you as a parent or grandparent, or if you know of someone who would benefit from this information, please reach out to me anytime. I would be glad to walk you through these concepts in greater detail and give you advice about how real estate investing can improve your or your child’s life.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/August/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Paying+tuition+with+real+estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/August/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Paying+tuition+with+real+estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>College is expensive, and it is on track to become even more so over time. Luckily, real estate investments, if done properly, can more than pay for your child’s education.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>College is expensive, and it is on track to become even more so over time. Luckily, real estate investments, if done properly, can more than pay for your child’s education.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Protest Your Property Taxes?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-you-protest-your-property-taxes.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-27 14:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/July/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Protest+Your+Property+Taxes%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re going to be talking about the property tax statement that you’ve recently received in the mail. It’s in a green and white envelope, and it shows you what the county thinks your property is worth and how much they will tax you based on that.

In Utah, every county assesses properties differently. They will come up with a valuation based on previous sales from the prior year. They do this in lump sums, and they know that with this method they won’t get it perfect. Their goal is to undervalue a property, but 15% to 20% of the time, they will overvalue it instead.

If your taxes are too high, you can petition the county to bring them down. A commonly perpetuated myth says that the value they assess your property for is how much it’s actually worth.

“If you feel your taxes are too high, you can petition the county to bring them down.”

That’s not true at all. I’ve never seen a buyer willing to pay more or less on a home because of how a home is taxed. The most important thing is getting your assessed value as low as possible so you don’t have to pay as much in taxes.

Our assessors know that they’re not perfect and never will claim to be. However, they have given us a way to appeal our property taxes if you believe your property is overvalued.

The first thing they say to do is contact a Realtor, like myself, who is willing to help. I’d be happy to do a market analysis on your property to determine what it’s actually worth. I’ll write up the letter, you’ll submit it to the county assessor’s office, and that’s it. Most of the clients get the reduction on their taxes they are looking for.

The best part is that I do this for free, with one small stipulation. If you, your friends, or family are looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate down the road, I ask that you keep me in mind.

If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/July/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Protest+Your+Property+Taxes%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/July/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Protest+Your+Property+Taxes%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Was your recent property tax assessment a little too high? Here’s how you can bring it down.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Was your recent property tax assessment a little too high? Here’s how you can bring it down.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Going on in the Wasatch Front Real Estate Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-going-on-in-the-wasatch-front-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-22 09:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/June/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Going+on+in+the+Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Market%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re going to talk about the state of the market here along the Wasatch Front. Overall, we’re clearly in a seller’s market right now. Homes that are listed under $500,000 are selling very quickly, usually within a week. Homes over that price are taking a bit longer on average, but it all depends on the area, the age of the home, and its condition.

For the past three years, we’ve had an inventory shortage in all price ranges. Builders are building as fast as they can right now, but they just aren’t able to keep up with the demand out there. This means our market will continue to stay very strong until they are able to catch up.

“Our market will continue to stay strong for sellers until the builders can catch up.”

Over the last two months, our overall inventory has actually increased by 29%. This gives buyers much more opportunities than we’ve had in the past. Below $400,000, however, we’re still in desperate need of inventory.

Short sales and bank-owned properties are virtually gone from our market. This means most homeowners are above water and have positive equity in their homes. Davis County alone has seen an increase of $110,000 in the median price of a home since the market was at its low in 2012.

I’ve got so much more to share with you. If you have any questions about the market or about your specific situation, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/June/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Going+on+in+the+Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Market%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/June/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Going+on+in+the+Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Market%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Builders are building as fast as they can along the Wasatch Front. However, it’s still not enough to keep up with the high demand we’re seeing from this hot seller’s market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Builders are building as fast as they can along the Wasatch Front. However, it’s still not enough to keep up with the high demand we’re seeing from this hot seller’s market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Attract Multiple Offers for Your Listing?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-can-you-attract-multiple-offers-for-your-listing.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-30 11:31:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Attract+Multiple+Offers+for+Your+Listing%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you best position your home to generate multiple offers in our hot seller’s market? I have sold around 65 homes over the past year using a few key tips. These tips have been proven to attract multiple offers, so allow me to share them with you today.

First, take your time getting your home ready for the market. Don’t be in a rush to list your home—make sure everything about it that needs to be touched up is touched up before photos are taken and before any buyers walk into the house.

Second, let your neighbors know about your impending home sale. For every person who hires me to sell their home, I am out door-knocking and calling over 100 people on their behalf. We have found that over 10% of homes sell primarily because of a neighborhood referral.

“When I hear someone say that they sold their house in under an hour, what that really means is they could have gotten more for it.”

There are thousands of homes for sale along the Wasatch Front, so do not assume that all real estate agents will see your home. Call or email the top 50 real estate agents in your area and notify them that you are putting your home on the market. If you sit back and assume they will see your listing, you will miss out on getting top dollar for it.

Lastly, do not just accept the first offer. This is a mistake I see a lot of people making right now. Selling your home is a numbers game. When I hear someone say that they sold their house in under an hour, what that really means is they could have gotten more for it. I market all my sellers’ homes for at least four or five days once they are listed before I start reviewing offers. You want to make sure 100% of the buying pool gets to see your home. That is how you can get as many as three, five, or even 18 offers for your home.

If you have any more questions about how to generate multiple offers for your home sale or you have any other real estate needs, please feel free to reach out to me. I would be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Attract+Multiple+Offers+for+Your+Listing%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Attract+Multiple+Offers+for+Your+Listing%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to generate multiple offers for your home once you put it on the market, I have a few tips to share with you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to generate multiple offers for your home once you put it on the market, I have a few tips to share with you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Ways You Can Buy and Sell at the Same Time</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-ways-you-can-buy-and-sell-at-the-same-time.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-16 12:00:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Ways+You+Can+Buy+and+Sell+at+the+Same+Time.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What happens if you cannot find another home after you sell your current one?

It seems like every week I sit down with a family that asks me this same question. Here are a few ways you can successfully buy and sell a home at the same time.

First, you can buy your next home without selling your current one. This option does not apply to everyone, but you could refinance your current home or pull out an equity line on it in order to buy your next home. A family member could also provide a short-term loan, which would make your home sale more comfortable and put you in a better position to buy your next home.

“You’ll find a house–all my clients have.”

Second, you could negotiate a rent-back agreement with your home’s buyer that will allow you to stay in your home for a short period after it is sold. This will give you time to find a new one. You will have the normal 30-day escrow period and another 30 to 45 days after the home is sold to find and close on your next house.

If you are upgrading from a red-hot price range to one that is not as hot, you can make an offer that’s contingent on your home selling. I just did this for a couple clients of mine. They were selling their home for $300,000 and moving up to a higher price range. During this process, we were able to get the seller to accept their offer before they listed their original home. Once they did, they got 18 offers for it.

Lastly, you could have another place set aside to live in between selling and buying, like a short-term rental or a family member’s basement. This is an option a lot of people prefer to avoid.

My recommendation is to go on faith. You will find a house—all my clients have. On that note, stay tuned for my next video where I’ll talk about how we find homes that aren’t on the market that our clients get the first look at.

In the meantime, if you have any other questions about how to buy and sell at the same time or you have any other real estate needs, please reach out to me. I would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Ways+You+Can+Buy+and+Sell+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Ways+You+Can+Buy+and+Sell+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are four ways you can successfully buy and sell a house at the same time in our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are four ways you can successfully buy and sell a house at the same time in our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Breaking Down the Top 5 Real Estate Myths</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/breaking-down-the-top-5-real-estate-myths.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-03 13:02:01 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Breaking+Down+the+Top+5+Real+Estate+Myths.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I want to talk about the top myths of real estate in a hot seller’s market.

1. All agents are the same. Some of you may have seen me discussing this myth on “Good Things Utah“. Imagine that you had $500,000 to invest in the stock market. Would you go and hire a stockbroker just because you knew them, or would you get out there, investigate, and find the absolute best stockbroker who will protect and increase your money?

Hiring a real estate is just like that. You need to hire the best real estate agent. On average, I get 3% to 4% more on the sale of a home than most other real estate agents, and there are a lot of great agents out there that you’ll want to interview.

2. I can list my home as For Sale By Owner and get the same results as an agent in this market. I don’t doubt that you can sell your home on your own in this seller’s market. However, we often see a For Sale By Owner property sell for less than a property in the same neighborhood that’s represented by an agent. Real estate agents are better able to capitalize on your home’s exposure to buyers. In this market, we’re also seeing a lot of homes sell above list price and above the appraised value. Most people don’t think it’s possible, but it is—especially if you work with an agent.  

“If you overprice your home, it will sit on the market and go through multiple price reductions.”

3. Buyers only come out on the weekends. The hottest buyers are out there all the time. They are taking time off work and taking a whole day during the week to look at homes, so make sure that you open your home up to all buyers possible. Oftentimes, the weekend buyers can really just be looky-loos, which you don’t really want.

4. You can overprice the house and get the right buyer. Even in this market, there is still the idea of the fantasyland buyer who will overpay for your home. However, buyers really aren’t paying more than what everyone else will pay for your home. The value of your home is based on what the buyer and seller will agree upon. Look at where the market is. You may be able to go 2%, 3%, or 5% above recent sales, but if you overprice the home, it will sit on the market and go through a lot of price reductions.

5. You can take advantage of a property that’s gone through multiple price reductions. Sometimes people think, “Hey, this seller is desperate—I’ll be able to get a great deal.” In reality, the seller is just someone who didn’t know where the market was and is just adjusting down to try and find the market.  Oftentimes, they’re not desperate sellers. In some cases, they may be the opposite—these sellers might get so stuck on their price that if they don’t get that price, they won’t sell at all.

I hope you found this information helpful. If you have any other questions about buying or selling in our current market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Breaking+Down+the+Top+5+Real+Estate+Myths.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/May/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Breaking+Down+the+Top+5+Real+Estate+Myths.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you are thinking of buying or selling a home in this hot seller’s market, make sure that you don’t fall for these five real estate myths.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you are thinking of buying or selling a home in this hot seller’s market, make sure that you don’t fall for these five real estate myths.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6 Tips to Make Your Home Dazzle on the Spring Market</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/6-tips-to-make-your-home-dazzle-on-the-spring-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-20 09:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/April/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+6+Tips+to+Make+Your+Home+Dazzle+on+the+Spring+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What do you need to do to get your home ready for the spring market? Here are six tips you can follow:

1. Pressure-wash your home’s exterior. If you don’t have a pressure-washer, you can buy or rent one and spray off the winter grime around the outside of your home.

2. Brighten up the inside. Make sure your light bulbs are working, your windows and screens are as clean as possible, and there aren’t any shrubs or bushes outside that are keeping light from shining inside your house.

3. Get rid of any signs that you have a pet (if you have one). Clean up any winter damage your pet(s) may have caused. If you’re trying to sell your home, you don’t want buyers to know that you keep a pet inside it.

“Small investments can pay big dividends when selling your home.”

4. Depersonalize your home. You’re about to move anyway, so you might as well start packing things up. I would start with the gallery wall of family photos. Your house should look like a model home, so clean up wherever you can so that when a buyer walks through it, they can picture themselves living there.

5. Update your kitchen. A little investment can go a long way, and your kitchen is the most important place to do it. You can try painting the walls a neutral color, adding a shiny new faucet, or installing some new cabinetry.

6. Amp up your home’s curb appeal. Now that the season has changed, there are a few things you can do to make the front of your home more inviting, like spreading some weed killer around your yard, laying down some fresh bark, and planting some flowers. If it’s not warm enough yet to plant flowers in the ground, you can also set out potted flowers. These will add some nice color to your home’s exterior.

If you have any questions about how to prepare your home for the spring market or you’re thinking of buying a home in our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/April/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+6+Tips+to+Make+Your+Home+Dazzle+on+the+Spring+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/April/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+6+Tips+to+Make+Your+Home+Dazzle+on+the+Spring+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re a home seller and you want to put your home on the market this spring, I have six tips that will help you get it prepped and show-ready.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re a home seller and you want to put your home on the market this spring, I have six tips that will help you get it prepped and show-ready.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7 Benefits of Buying Rental Real Estate: Part 2</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/7-benefits-of-buying-rental-real-estate-part-2.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-06 10:58:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/April/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+7+Benefits+of+Buying+Rental+Real+Estate-+Part+2.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’m here with the second and final video in our series about the seven benefits of buying rental real estate. You can find the first installment here.

Last time, we talked about cash flow, appreciation, and depreciation. Now, it’s time to learn about:

4. Leverage. When you purchase rental real estate, you are able to leverage other people’s money to buy the property. For example, if you buy a $200,000 rental property at 20% down, you’re putting $40,000 of your own money into the property. You will gain appreciation in that property and get cash flow while someone else pays down your mortgage.

“With real estate, you always have options.”

5. Write-offs. When you own a rental property, it’s like owning a business, which means you get a lot of write-offs that you can use to your benefit. You can write off things like repairs, HOA fees, and management fees. If you and your family like to travel to Hawaii or St. George, you can buy a rental property there and write off your travel expenses. Talk to your accountant; there are a lot of things you can do with write-offs. There are many ways you can manage your rental property to benefit you and your family and get the lifestyle you want.

6. Real estate is a tangible asset. Unlike stocks and bonds, which can change quickly, real estate will always be there. In 2008, 2009, and 2010, the stock market changed drastically. Real estate was still there. In fact, rental real estate was in even higher demand at the time.

7. Real estate gives you options. You can always sell your rental property, use seller financing, purchase another investment through a 1031 exchange, and defer your capital gains taxes so you can use that profit to buy something bigger. In the worst-case scenario, you can always live in your rental property.

As you can see, real estate is a great investment option.

If you are thinking about starting to invest in real estate or would like to add more properties to your portfolio, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/April/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+7+Benefits+of+Buying+Rental+Real+Estate-+Part+2.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/April/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+7+Benefits+of+Buying+Rental+Real+Estate-+Part+2.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’ll go over the last four benefits of buying a rental property.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’ll go over the last four benefits of buying a rental property.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Great Benefits of Investing in Real Estate</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-great-benefits-of-investing-in-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-22 14:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/March/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Great+Benefits+of+Investing+in+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’m bringing you the first installment in a two-part series on real estate investing. For this part, I’ll be going over some of the advantages of investing in real estate.

The first benefit of investing in real estate is cash flow. But what does this mean? Essentially, your cash flow is the return you get on your property at the end of the year after all expenses have been paid.

When looking at cash flow, it’s important to examine how much you have invested in the property. A lot of my clients ask, “How much should I really make?” My answer is this: If you make less than 6% in the equity off of your property, you should sell immediately. However, most of my clients are making a return of more than 10%.

“Most of my clients are making a return of more than 10% by investing in real estate.”

The second benefit is appreciation.Slow and steady appreciation adds to the benefit of owning rental real estate. Last year, we actually saw an 8% appreciation rate across the Wasatch Front.

The third and final benefit I want to go over is depreciation. Specifically, depreciation will bring advantages in terms of your taxes, since it provides opportunities for write-offs.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/March/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Great+Benefits+of+Investing+in+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/March/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+3+Great+Benefits+of+Investing+in+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What are the advantages of investing in real estate? Today, let’s go over three of the primary benefits.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What are the advantages of investing in real estate? Today, let’s go over three of the primary benefits.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Most Important Part of Buying New Construction</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-most-important-part-of-buying-new-construction.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-08 10:31:08 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/March/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Most+Important+Part+of+Buying+New+Construction.mp4</guid>
        <description>

New construction is booming right now. In fact, if you live anywhere near open farmland, you’re probably seeing big developments being built. If you’re considering buying new construction, you need an agent by your side to guide you through the transaction.

Over the 12 years I’ve been selling real estate, I’ve seen and worked with a lot of great builders, but that doesn’t mean problems don’t usually arise during the new construction process. As long as there are problems to overcome when building new construction, you’ll need an agent to help you work through them.

It’s important to work side by side with an agent who knows your area, knows the schools in your area, and knows the builder so you and your family get what you’re looking for. A good agent will also familiarize you with what’s going on in the market. As market conditions change, what we can negotiate with builders changes as well. I’ve seen many buyers try to buy new construction homes over the years without an agent, mostly because they didn’t understand what could and couldn’t be negotiated.

“As long as there are problems to overcome in the new construction process, you’ll need an agent by your side to help you with them.”

An agent can also walk you through the lengthy contracts builders put together. They work extensively with their own attorneys to draft contracts that work for them, so you need someone with you who’s looking out for your best interests as well.

Work with your agent to make sure you also get a third-party inspector to look at the property. If you’re not already a contractor or you’re not familiar with the new construction process, why not hire someone to check everything out for you? An extra eye will benefit you greatly. In fact, I recently heard a story from a client of mine about someone who bought a new construction home in their neighborhood and flooded their garage the first time they turned on the bathtub in the bathroom on top of it. Nobody noticed this flaw, even after both the builder and the city inspector inspected the property.

Lastly, take your agent with you the first time you look at your new construction home or make sure the agent calls and registers you beforehand so that agent can get paid. If they don’t, they might not be able to represent you.

The best part is, when you work with a builder, you won’t pay anything extra to have an agent there looking out for your best interests.

If you have any further questions about buying new construction or you have any other real estate needs I can help you with, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/March/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Most+Important+Part+of+Buying+New+Construction.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/March/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Most+Important+Part+of+Buying+New+Construction.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re considering buying new construction, you need an agent by your side to guide you through the transaction.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re considering buying new construction, you need an agent by your side to guide you through the transaction.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Buyers and Sellers Take Advantage of Our Current Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-can-buyers-and-sellers-take-advantage-of-our-current-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-12 09:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Matt+%26+Jenn+Freda/Video/2018/February/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+Buyers+and+Sellers+Take+Advantage+of+Our+Current+Market%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There’s no question that this year is different than the rest. Spring is already here. Tulips are already blooming and so is the market.

Interest rates are beginning to creep up, and this trend will likely continue through the spring and summer. In other words, now is the right time to get on the market, whether you are a buyer or a seller.

Homes that couldn’t sell last year are selling now. I just listed a home that sat on the market all year in 2017 and was able to sell it in a matter of just three weeks.

“Now is the right time to get on the market, whether you are a buyer or a seller.”

If you’re considering buying a home this year, watch rates very carefully. If rates rise from their current 4.25% to, say, 5.25%, the increase in cost could run high.

Ultimately, now is the right time to take advantage of the market.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Matt+%26+Jenn+Freda/Video/2018/February/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+Buyers+and+Sellers+Take+Advantage+of+Our+Current+Market%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Matt+%26+Jenn+Freda/Video/2018/February/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+Buyers+and+Sellers+Take+Advantage+of+Our+Current+Market%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our current market presents great opportunities for buyers and sellers alike. Spring has already arrived, so don’t hold off any longer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our current market presents great opportunities for buyers and sellers alike. Spring has already arrived, so don’t hold off any longer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Add a Solar Panel to Your Home?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/should-you-add-a-solar-panel-to-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-17 04:32:08 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/January/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Add+a+Solar+Panel+to+Your+Home%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Lots of people have been asking me lately about whether it’s a good idea to add solar panels to their home.

The answer really depends on how long you plan on living there. If you plan on being in a home for a very long time, adding solar panels is probably a great idea.

However, if you aren’t going to be in your current home for very much time at all, you may want to wait until you’re settled somewhere else.

“The decision on whether to add solar panels really depends on how long you plan on living in a home.”

I personally think solar panels are great. It’s wonderful to be self-reliant. The challenge, though, is that when it comes to selling a home, solar panels are not always appraised for their full value.

Additionally, not all buyers will want solar panels. Sometimes, they’ll even request for them to be removed before they close.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/January/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Add+a+Solar+Panel+to+Your+Home%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/January/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Add+a+Solar+Panel+to+Your+Home%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I often receive questions about whether adding solar panels to a home is a good idea. Today, I’m bringing you the answer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I often receive questions about whether adding solar panels to a home is a good idea. Today, I’m bringing you the answer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Latest Word From Our Wasatch Front Market?</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/whats-the-latest-word-from-our-wasatch-front-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Doug Cary</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-03 07:56:52 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/January/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+Latest+Word+From+Our+Wasatch+Front+Market%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are the current conditions in our real estate market?

We’re still in a very hot market. The inventory level along the Wasatch Front is less than a two-month supply of homes, which means if no new homes came on the market, it would take less than two months to sell everything.

This means prices are going up. Just the other weekend, I sold a listing that had 15 offers on it. This listing sold significantly above its appraised value, too.

“We’re still in a very hot market.”

Interest rates are still around 4%, which still allows buyers to buy a lot of homes in this market. Although prices are high, there are still a lot of great investments out there. I’m seeing properties selling with an 8% to 12% rate of return on their cash. I’m also seeing 6% to 7% cap rates. If you’re looking for investment properties, now is still an excellent time for you.

If you have any further questions about our current market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/January/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+Latest+Word+From+Our+Wasatch+Front+Market%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Doug+Cary/Videos/2018/January/Wasatch+Front+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+Latest+Word+From+Our+Wasatch+Front+Market%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There is good news for both buyers and sellers in our market. Prices are high, but interest rates are still low.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Doug Cary</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There is good news for both buyers and sellers in our market. Prices are high, but interest rates are still low.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Wasatch Front, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Doug Cary</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Doug Cary</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Doug Cary Team - your professional Wasatch Front Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
