<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>San Diego Mortgage Podcast with Abel Tejeda</title>
    <link>http://abeltejeda.blog</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://abeltejeda.blog"/>
    <description>Home loans in San Diego can be complex, but that doesn’t mean you should sign on the dotted line without explanations.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Abel Tejeda</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-12-17 16:14:16 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Abel Tejeda</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>abel@abeltejeda.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Abel Tejeda</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://abeltejeda.blog/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers in the San Diego Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>Home loans in San Diego can be complex, but that doesn’t mean you should sign on the dotted line without explanations.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Fall for These 5 Mortgage Misconceptions</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/dont-fall-for-these-5-mortgage-misconceptions.html</link>
        
          <category>Finance Advice</category>
        
          <category>Home Loans</category>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-05 10:48:15 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+The+Biggest+Mortgage+Misconceptions.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Homebuyers: there are five big mortgage misconceptions that could lead you astray if you believe them. Today I’ll name them and discuss the actual truth behind them:

1. You’ll get the best rate with your current bank. Some banks offer discounts to their clients, but that’s not usually the case. You’re always better off shopping around and talking to different lenders so you can compare both the best rates and overall cost.

2. You can’t get a mortgage loan for less than 20% down. In reality, there are several mortgage loans you can get for less than 20% down. The FHA first-time homebuyer program, for instance, allows you to secure a loan for just 3.5% down. Additionally, conventional loans allow you to put down any amount less than 20%. Keep in mind, though, that if you put down less than 20%, you’ll have to pay mortgage insurance.

3. You can only refinance your home loan once every 12 months. Actually, you can refinance your home loan whenever you want. As a rule of thumb, though, you should only refinance when you can recover the cost of that refinance within two years or you can lower your rate by 1%.

“Credit shouldn’t stop you from buying a house.”

4. You need excellent credit to buy a house. There are programs you can use that allow you to buy a home with a FICO score as low as 580. Remember, the beauty of credit is you can fix it right away. Our team offers free credit counseling, so if your credit score isn’t where you’d like it to be, we’d be happy to sit down with you and talk about what you need to do to raise it.

5. You can’t buy a house if you had a bankruptcy, short sale, or foreclosure. Again, there are several programs that allow you to do just that. An FHA loan, for example, will allow you to buy a home within two years of your bankruptcy discharge, and conventional loans allow you to buy within four years after a foreclosure.

No matter what your situation, your best course of action is to talk to a mortgage professional such as myself so we can go over what you need to do to buy a home.

As always, if you have any other mortgage questions or there’s anything else I can help you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+The+Biggest+Mortgage+Misconceptions.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+The+Biggest+Mortgage+Misconceptions.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are five major mortgage misconceptions that you should know the truth about so they don’t prevent you from buying a home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are five major mortgage misconceptions that you should know the truth about so they don’t prevent you from buying a home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Documents You’ll Need in Order to Get Pre-Qualified</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/the-documents-youll-need-in-order-to-get-pre-qualified.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Loans</category>
        
          <category>Finance Advice</category>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 09:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+The+Documents+Required+for+Pre-Qualification.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to provide you with a list of documents you’ll be required to have in order to get pre-qualified for a home loan if you’re going FHA, VA, or if you’re self-employed.

With both FHA and conventional loans, you’ll need the same documents:


  The two most recent pay stubs for both the main borrower and the co-borrower if there is one
  Tax returns for the past two years
  Two recent bank statements
  A copy of your driver’s license
  A copy of your social security card


If you’re in the military or are a veteran and you qualify for a VA loan, the documents you’ll need are slightly different:


  Your latest Leave and Earnings Statement (if you’re active duty)
  Your certificate of eligibility
  Your tax returns
  Your most recent bank statements


“Remember that the first step in the home buying process to get pre-qualified—don’t start by looking at homes or going to open houses.”

If you’re self-employed, there are two different options:


  Two years of tax returns, which allows us to base your income on how much you declare as profit at the end of the year


Or:


  Bank statements from the last 24 months, which allows us to determine your income based on the deposits you’ve made in the last two years.


Now that you know the documents needed, what do you do with them? Well, we can set up an appointment where we’ll sit down face-to-face, or you can email or fax the documents to me.

Remember that the first step in the home buying process to get pre-qualified—don’t start by looking at homes or going to open houses. You first need to determine what is the maximum amount you’d qualify for, what your options are, and how much your monthly payments would be at different price points. You only want to be looking at houses you can afford, and the only way to do that is to get pre-qualified.

If you have any questions or would like to set up an appointment with me, please feel free to reach out. I’d love to discuss your situation and see how we can help you move forward.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+The+Documents+Required+for+Pre-Qualification.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+The+Documents+Required+for+Pre-Qualification.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What documents do you need in order to get pre-qualified for a home loan? Today I’ll provide you a list.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What documents do you need in order to get pre-qualified for a home loan? Today I’ll provide you a list.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Few Different Ways to Tap Into Your Home’s Equity</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/a-few-different-ways-to-tap-into-your-homes-equity.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Equity</category>
        
          <category>Finance Advice</category>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-28 13:35:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+How+to+Tap+into+the+Equity+of+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are many different ways to tap into the equity of your home. We’re going to break it down for you today, whether you have VA, FHA, or conventional financing. We’ll also tell you how to cash into your equity without having to refinance.

First, let’s talk about cashing out with a VA loan. A huge advantage of having a VA loan is that you are able to cash out up to 100% of your equity without having to pay taxes on it.

If you’re self-employed, it doesn’t matter what type of loan you had in the past. With the new loans we have available, we can use your bank statements to qualify instead of having to use your tax returns. This lets you tap into that equity. You used to have to wait to cash out on that equity until you sell, but today we can help you cash out up to 90% loan-to-value.

“VA homebuyers can cash out up to 100% of their equity.”

There are a lot of things you can do with an FHA loan. Once you start to build equity, you can get rid of mortgage insurance by tapping into it. Even though you are increasing your loan amount by cashing out, you are reducing your payment by removing the mortgage insurance. At the end of the day, even though you’re cashing out, you’ll end up saving money on your payment.

Finally, our bonus tip. How can you tap into the equity of your home and cash out without refinancing? The answer is simple. Take a home equity line of credit, or HELOC, out on your property. If you have a really good rate, you don’t even have to touch that loan. You can get a HELOC for whatever amount you need while keeping your loan payment.

The decision of whether to refinance or get a second mortgage depends on a number of factors, including your rate and your credit, but the best thing for you to do to start the process is message me. If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+How+to+Tap+into+the+Equity+of+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+How+to+Tap+into+the+Equity+of+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you ready to cash in on your home’s equity? Here are all the different ways you can do so.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you ready to cash in on your home’s equity? Here are all the different ways you can do so.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are San Diego and Temecula in a Housing Bubble?</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/are-san-diego-and-temecula-in-a-housing-bubble.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Purchase</category>
        
          <category>Interest Rates</category>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-10 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Are+We+in+a+Housing+Bubble%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I am going to discuss a couple questions that my clients keep asking me: Are we in a housing bubble? Will there be a downturn in home value prices?

The economy is extremely strong in San Diego and Temecula and we are not following the same pattern of oversupply that we did in 2007. In fact, we are two years behind on new home construction and that is actually causing home prices to continue to rise.

If you think you can just wait for home prices to drop, you are in for a rude awakening. The only thing that can stop this rise in prices is interest rates. For the past seven quarters, interest rates have been going up. Every 1% increase in rates decreases your purchasing power by 10%.

What does this mean if you are a buyer or a seller? Well, first of all, while I am not a real estate agent, I see the patterns since I lived through what happened in 2007. If you are looking to buy, go ahead and buy. If interest rates and home prices both continue to increase, you are going to be priced out of the market.

“If you think you that you are just going to wait for home prices to drop, you are in for a rude awakening.”

If you are a seller and you are trying to time the market so you sell at the peak, I would advise that you sell now instead. It is a really good time to sell and you never know what is going to happen to property prices.

So are Temecula and San Diego in a housing bubble? No— not even close. We are not even close to a housing bubble. Especially since we still have the huge problem of a lack of inventory.

If you have any additional questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Are+We+in+a+Housing+Bubble%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Are+We+in+a+Housing+Bubble%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are we in a housing bubble in San Diego or Temecula? I am looking at the current market facts to find out.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are we in a housing bubble in San Diego or Temecula? I am looking at the current market facts to find out.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Our Awesome New Loan Program</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/the-benefits-of-our-awesome-new-loan-program.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-19 12:46:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+The+Benefits+of+Our+Awesome+New+Loan+Program.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re a real estate agent, an insurance agent, self-employed, or own your own business and haven’t been able to buy a house or refinance your current loan because of how much money you declare, then today’s topic is for you.

It seems like there are new programs and guidelines being introduced to the market almost every day, and that’s great news for you. In the past, if you were self-employed, the only way to show your income and be able to qualify for a home purchase (or to be able to refinance your property) was to show your past two years of tax returns. We would then take the average of those 24 months and come up with your income; these are, after all, your expenses.

This created a huge problem. For example, say you’re a trucker who makes $200,000 a year, but after depreciating your truck, paying for gas and meals, you would only end up with, say, $40,000. That means we would only use $40,000 to help you qualify for a home purchase. Now, with the way that the real estate market is—especially here in San Diego—there’s not much you can qualify for. That’s why the new self-employed program, which is based on bank statements, was introduced.

“We don’t take your expenses or business deductions into account, just a percentage of your deposits.”

What’s so special about our self-employed loan?

First and foremost, it’s not based on taxes. We base your qualification on your deposits using your bank statements. Say that you get $20,000 a month—we use the average from 24 months, 12 months, or even just one month, depending on the program you qualify for. We don’t take your expenses or business deductions into account, just a percentage of your deposits.

Another thing about this loan is that you can come in with only 10% down, and you don’t need perfect credit. The loan can also go up to $2 million, and the debt-to-income ratio is higher than traditional loans.

This is just one of our newest home loans that we’ve rolled out, and we’ll have new ones coming out in the the next couple of weeks, to be discussed in future posts.

If you or someone you know someone needs a home loan to purchase a property, needs to refinance, or has any questions, you are absolutely encouraged to reach out to us. I’ll be sure to take care of you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+The+Benefits+of+Our+Awesome+New+Loan+Program.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+The+Benefits+of+Our+Awesome+New+Loan+Program.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We have a new loan that can help the self-employed buy a home or refinance their property. Here’s how it works.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We have a new loan that can help the self-employed buy a home or refinance their property. Here’s how it works.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>All of Your Questions About VA Eligibility, Answered</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/all-of-your-questions-about-va-eligibility-answered.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-27 13:19:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+All+of+Your+Questions+About+VA+Eligibility%252C+Answered.mp4</guid>
        <description>

People have approached me with a number of great questions about VA loan eligibility, so today I would like to highlight and address some of the things I’m most frequently asked.

“How do you get a VA loan?”

 As simple as this question sounds, many people don’t know where to start this process. To get a VA loan, you’ll need to visit a financial institution, like a bank, or a direct lender that is qualified to handle VA loans. We at American Mortgage Group would be happy to assist you in this pursuit.

“What determines how much you can borrow from the VA?”

Your Certificate of Eligibility (COE) will tell you how much you can borrow from the VA. A COE can be obtained directly from the VA or from your lender.

“What qualifies as acceptable proof of military service?”

The answer to this question will actually vary depending on whether you are a veteran or are still active duty. Active duty military personnel will need to present a Statement of Service. Veterans, though, will need to present a DD 214.

“Can you still obtain a VA loan if you are unable to present a Statement of Service or DD 214?”

Actually, yes. Another way to obtain a COE (and a VA loan) is to fill out a VA Form 26-1880. This will allow your lender to gather military records and determine how much you qualify for.

“Can you have a cosigner on a home purchase you’re financing with a VA loan?

Having a cosigner help you purchase a home when using a VA loan is acceptable, but the cosigner must be your legal spouse. You may have other people on the title of the property, but not on the VA loan.

“You can rest assured that when you purchase a home using a VA loan, you will be paying a fair price.”

“If someone already has a VA loan, can they get another one?”

Yes, but the amount you will qualify for depends on how much entitlement you have left after your previous purchase. Your COE will indicate this amount. Also, eligibility can be restored if the previously purchased home has been sold. A lot of people think they can only have one VA loan at a time, but this is not correct.

“Can you get a VA loan if you had a bankruptcy in the past?”

Yes. It will need to be determined whether your bankruptcy was a Chapter 7 or a Chapter 13, though, because these will each be handled differently. More than anything, the most significant thing you will need to do is sit down and have a conversation about your current financial standing. And you will want to pay special attention to your FICO score.

With these common questions out of the way, there is one more common concern I’d like to touch on.

Many people fear that they will overpay for a home when making a purchase with VA loan financing. However, the VA appraisal process won’t allow you to do so. There are certain codes and conditions a property must meet to qualify for VA financing in the first place. You can rest assured that when you purchase a home using a VA loan, you will be paying a fair price.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+All+of+Your+Questions+About+VA+Eligibility%252C+Answered.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+All+of+Your+Questions+About+VA+Eligibility%252C+Answered.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>People have a number of questions about VA eligibility, so today I wanted to address some of the most common inquiries that come up regarding this important subject.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>People have a number of questions about VA eligibility, so today I wanted to address some of the most common inquiries that come up regarding this important subject.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Things First-Time Homebuyers Need When Purchasing a Home</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/3-things-first-time-homebuyers-need-when-purchasing-a-home.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-04 12:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

As a first-time homebuyer, what’s required of you when purchasing a home?

If you’re like most first-time homebuyers, you pretty much have three mortgage loan options to choose from: VA, FHA, and conventional. If you’re not a veteran or currently in the military, a VA loan doesn’t apply to you. As for FHA and conventional loans, there are three requirements that come with qualifying for these.

The first is your credit, and the difference with this factor between an FHA and a conventional loan is huge. With an FHA loan, you can qualify with a score as low as 580. With a conventional loan, it can depend on which program you choose and what payment you come in with. Even if your credit is not where it needs to be in order to purchase a home, that can be fixed. We have credit repair companies we partner with who we can refer you to, and we can also give you in-house credit counseling.

The second requirement is the down payment. As with your credit, there’s a huge difference between an FHA loan and a conventional loan in terms of what you have to put down. With an FHA loan, you can go as low as no money down. There are plenty of down payment assistance programs out there, but you have to determine whether that’s something that’s conducive to your situation.

The FHA program for first-time homebuyers only requires you to put down 3.5% of the purchase price, which translates into $3,500 for every $100,000. Keep in mind, you can tap into your 401(k), IRA, or retirement plan to pay for that down payment—it doesn’t have to be paid for with money you currently have in your bank account.

With a conventional loan, you can go anywhere from 3% down to 30% down. Many people assume that conventional loans require you to put down 20%, but that’s not true. However, if you don’t put at least 20% down, you’ll have to pay private mortgage insurance (or PMI).

“If you meet these three requirements, there’s no reason you shouldn’t get approved for a loan.”

The third and final requirement is your income. When it comes to this factor, you need to be employed within the same industry over at least the last two years. This doesn’t mean you have to be with the same employer, though. This comes into play once we start talking about your debt-to-income ratio (DTI). Again, there’s a big difference here between a conventional loan and an FHA loan, and you need to know your DTI to determine which route to take.

The situation is slightly different if you’re self-employed. If you have a lot of compensating factors, we can potentially take only one year’s worth of taxes. There are several loan programs for self-employed individuals that don’t require two years’ worth of taxes. Your loan can also be done with only bank statements, and that’s important because it means you don’t have to declare huge amounts to be able to qualify, and you only need one month’s worth of bank statements to determine where your income is.

If you meet these three requirements, there’s no reason you shouldn’t get approved for a loan.

If you have any other questions about this topic or you’re thinking about buying a house, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When purchasing a home with a loan, three things are required of you: your credit, income, and a down payment.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When purchasing a home with a loan, three things are required of you: your credit, income, and a down payment.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Ways to Pay Down Your Mortgage Faster</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/4-ways-to-pay-down-your-mortgage-faster.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-17 13:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you are like most people, you have a 30-year mortgage on your home to pay off. That might seem like an eternity, but there are a couple of different strategies that you can use to pay off that mortgage early.

What most people are unaware of is that when you do get a mortgage, most of your interest is charged upfront. Banks are in the business of making money, so they want to make sure they get their money upfront.

For the first 18.5 years of that 30-year term, you’ll be paying more in interest than on the principal loan amount. When the average homeowner sells after seven years, they don’t even get to the portion where they’re actually knocking down the principle. Here are a few ways to pay off your 30-year mortgage a little sooner without a ton of extra effort:

1. Get a 15-year mortgage and a lower interest rate. When you get a 15-year loan as opposed to a 30-year loan, you tend to get a lower rate. You also have less to pay in interest on the loan. At the end of the day, you end up saving thousands in the process.

2. Making bi-weekly payments. Grab your mortgage payment and look at the payment breakdown. Instead of making, one $1,000 payment, for example, you make two $500 payments each month. When you do this, you end up making 26 mortgage payments a year. That equates to 13 monthly payments instead of 12 without you even noticing. This will save you eight years of payments, on average.

“The best strategy is whichever one fits your lifestyle and budget.”

3. Making an additional mortgage payment. If you get a big tax refund or bonus at work, think about making an additional mortgage payment instead of going on a vacation or buying a new car. Make sure you note that the payment “Be applied directly toward the principle.” That will help you knock years off of your loan term.

4. Refinancing for a lower rate or to remove mortgage insurance. If you have a $1500 payment and it goes down to $1,300 with a refinance, that’s $2,400 per year you’re saving. However, If you keep making the same payment of $1,500 after you refinance, you can pay down your mortgage much quicker.

Which strategy is the best? Whichever one fits your lifestyle and budget. What is good for you is not necessarily good for your neighbor.

If you have any questions or want my help with this, please give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Your 30-year mortgage can be paid off much more quickly by utilizing one of these four simple strategies.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Your 30-year mortgage can be paid off much more quickly by utilizing one of these four simple strategies.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 2 Most Popular Loan Programs for First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/the-2-most-popular-loan-programs-for-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-02 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

There are many different loan programs available for first-time-homebuyers (or homebuyers in general), but the two most popular that I want to talk about today are the FHA loan and the conventional loan.

Let’s start with the FHA loan. This loan allows you to purchase a property with a down payment of just 3.5%. That’s equivalent to paying $3,500 for every $100,000 the home is worth. A $400,000 property, for example, would only require a down payment of $14,000. That’s an awesome deal! The FHA loan is also a government-secured loan, but the best thing about it is you can qualify for it with a FICO score as low as 580.

The FHA loan does have its drawbacks, however. Since you’re not putting at least 20% down for it, you have to pay mortgage insurance. At the end of the day, though, the important thing is it allows you to buy a home without a large down payment.

“Remember, these loans aren’t one-size-fits-all.”

The conventional loan is the second-most popular among first-time homebuyers. People with high credit scores and a higher income make up the majority of those who qualify for a conventional loan. Unlike FHA loans, conventional loans are credit-driven. This means the higher your credit score is when applying for it, the lower your interest rate will be. Additionally, conventional loans aren’t as lenient as FHA loans when it comes to a person’s debt-to-income ratio. If you have an excellent credit score and you make good money, this might be a better option for you.

A conventional loan allows a down payment as low as 3%, but as with an FHA loan, you’ll still be stuck having to pay mortgage insurance. The main difference between these two scenarios is that with an FHA loan, you have to pay that mortgage insurance until you refinance your loan. With a conventional loan, once your property appreciates to a 70% loan-to-value ratio, you can do a drive-by appraisal or simply contact your mortgage insurance company and have your mortgage insurance removed.

An FHA loan is a better option if your resources are limited or you have a low credit score, but it’s not designed for you to keep it over a period of 30 years—it’s designed to get you into a house. Once that property appreciates, the smart move would be to refinance out of the FHA loan and into a conventional loan so you can get rid of your mortgage insurance and have a lower payment.

Remember, these loans aren’t one-size-fits-all. If you have any more questions about which one is best for you, give us a call so we can determine where you stand and what you need to do to qualify for either.

As always, if you have any other mortgage questions, don’t hesitate to reach out. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>FHA loans and conventional loans are the two most popular loan options for first-time homebuyers</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>FHA loans and conventional loans are the two most popular loan options for first-time homebuyers</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do VA Loans Work?</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/how-do-va-loans-work.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Loans</category>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-05 11:08:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+How+VA+Loans+Work+and+How+to+Get+One.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I often get questions about how VA loans work and what it takes to obtain one. The very first thing I’ll touch on is the VA lending limit.

The VA only allows you to borrow up to a certain amount. This amount will vary by county. In San Diego County, for example, you can borrow up to $649,750 for a single-family residence.

One important point to be aware of is the fact that there are different lending limits for single-family homes, duplexes, triplexes, and fourplexes. In San Diego County, the VA lending limit is $831,800 for a duplex, $1,005,450 for a triplex, and $1,249,550 for a fourplex.

In Riverside, the VA lending limit is $453,100 for a single-family residence, $580,150 for a duplex, $701,250 for a triplex, and $871,450 for a fourplex.

So, what happens if you want to purchase a home above the VA lending limit? You actually do still have options in this scenario.

You can still purchase a home using a VA loan, even if that home is above the lending limit, so long as you pay 25% of the difference. So if you want to purchase a $700,000 single-family home in San Diego, the $649,750 covered by the VA loan leaves a total difference of $50,250. Of that $50,250, you would only have to come up with $12,562.

Moving on, people also often ask me what kind of incomes qualify for VA loans. Well, if you’re active military, we can use every income source on your LES.

If you are no longer in the military or are retired, you can still use your current income so long as you have continued to do what you did while in the military. If in the military you were a mechanic and you are still working in that field, you can still use your new income to help you qualify.

“Remember that certain lending standards vary depending on county and income.”

Unfortunately, you cannot use your GI bill because that income won’t continue for three years.

VA disability income, however, does qualify. In fact, you can use 120% of VA disability income toward a loan, and if you’re receiving at least 20% disability, you can have your VA funding fee waived.

Some counties even offer property tax exemptions for veterans who are 100% disabled. This varies by county and depends on your income, so consult with your agent and your county recorder’s office for more information.

I hope this has answered some of your questions. Still, nothing compares to speaking with a lender about your specific circumstances. And to all veterans and active duty military members: Thank you for your service.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+How+VA+Loans+Work+and+How+to+Get+One.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+How+VA+Loans+Work+and+How+to+Get+One.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to address some common questions about VA loans.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to address some common questions about VA loans.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Qualify for a VA Loan</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/how-to-qualify-for-a-va-loan.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-19 11:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Whether you are a veteran or active duty, the VA loan is a great option for you. In my opinion, the VA loan is the best loan in the country. I’ll break down everything you need to get a VA loan for your home purchase today.

First, though, I want to explain the three main benefits of the VA loan:

1. The VA loan offers 100% financing, which means there is no down payment involved. There are still closing costs, so talk to your lender and real estate agent. The lender can offer you a credit, and the agent can see if the seller would be willing to help with closing costs.

2. There’s no mortgage insurance with the VA loan, which saves you between $200 and $400 a month compared to an FHA loan.

3. The VA can intercede if you are ever in a situation where you may lose your home. If you have financial problems, the VA can help try to come to an arrangement with your lender so that you can keep your home.

That said, there are two sides to eligibility requirements. One is the individual obtaining the loan, and the second is the property itself.

The property must be VA-approved. This is usually not an issue for a single-family residence. The appraiser will determine if the property is VA-approved. The VA will not allow you to overpay for a property, so the appraised price does have to line up with the purchase price.

“You can have more than one VA loan, just not on properties in the same county.”

If you are buying a condo or townhome, your lender can help you determine whether that property will be VA-approved.

So, what determines if you do or do not qualify for a VA loan? It all comes down to your certificate of eligibility. After we meet with you, we send your DA14 to the VA. The VA then issues a certificate of eligibility that shows how much you qualify for.

The amount you qualify for will be very different in San Diego than in Riverside County. A lot of VA clients are moving to the Riverside area. We are able to help you there as well, but the VA rules do change from one county to the other, so keep that in mind.

You also need to be employed. If you are active duty, we need your latest LES to determine how much you qualify for.

The property must be owner-occupied. You cannot use the VA loan for second homes or investment properties.

Since you can’t use the VA loan for second homes, many people wonder, “Are you able to have multiple VA loans?” You can, but you can’t have two VA loans on two properties in the same county. If you had a VA loan on a property somewhere else and got transferred to San Diego, you can get another VA loan for the San Diego property. We would just have to determine how much entitlement is left.

You need a minimum credit score of 580 to qualify for a VA loan. If your score is not quite there, don’t worry. We offer free credit counseling for VA clients. We want to help you get to the point where you are able to buy a home.

If you are looking to buy a home with a VA loan, just give us a call. We will see what you can qualify for and what your payments will be. Thank you for your service, and I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What do you need in order to qualify for a VA loan? I’ll explain today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What do you need in order to qualify for a VA loan? I’ll explain today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Expert Tips for Refinancing Your Mortgage</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/expert-tips-for-refinancing-your-mortgage.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-02 12:00:59 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Expert+Tips+for+Refinancing+Your+Mortgage.mp4</guid>
        <description>

For the past month, I’ve been meeting with previous clients and doing their yearly loan reviews. When the topic of refinancing comes up, I keep hearing the same things. “Refinancing only means taking money out of your mortgage or your house.”

That’s not necessarily true. When refinancing, you have several options. The most common is refinancing an FHA loan into a conventional loan so that you can remove your mortgage insurance.

Another reason people refinance is to lower their interest rate. Depending on how much you have on your loan, this could save you thousands and thousands. It’s always good to try to lower your interest rate by at least 1% if you refinance.

“There are many reasons to refinance.”

When you refinance, you are able to take money out due to appreciation. Last year, properties in San Diego appreciated by close to 10%, which you can tap into as an owner. Equity is imaginary money until you put it to good use. You can refinance take some of that equity out, and use it to remodel your home to increase your equity even more.

Refinancing also means changing the terms of your loan. For example, if you own a home with an adjustable-rate mortgage, your payments are going to jump dramatically at some point if they haven’t already. Always switch from an adjustable-rate mortgage to a fixed-rate mortgage if you are able to.

Finally, you can refinance to shorten the term on your loan and lower your rate. You can switch from a 30-year loan to a 20- or 15-year loan.

If you have any questions for me or you’re considering refinancing anytime soon, I’d love to sit down with you and go over your options. Don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email anytime.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Expert+Tips+for+Refinancing+Your+Mortgage.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Expert+Tips+for+Refinancing+Your+Mortgage.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Why do homeowners choose to refinance? It could be for any number of reasons.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why do homeowners choose to refinance? It could be for any number of reasons.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8 Questions You Should Always Ask Your Lender</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/8-questions-you-should-always-ask-your-lender.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-09 08:25:39 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+8+Questions+You+Should+Always+Ask+Your+Lender.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When buying a home, there are a few questions that you should make sure to ask your lender.

1. What is my interest rate? This is important because the interest rate determines what the principal and interest portion of your mortgage payment will be. Make sure that you discuss interest rates up front so that you know what your payment will be at the end of escrow. If they don’t disclose the rate right away, you may end up with a higher payment than you thought you were going to get.

2. What is my monthly mortgage payment? Your mortgage payment includes the principal, interest rate, taxes, and insurance (PITI). Some lenders may just tell you the principal and interest payment, but you need to know the total payment. In San Diego, property tax rates are around 1.25%, so take that into consideration, as well as insurance payments.

3. Is my interest rate fixed or adjustable? If you have a fixed interest rate, your payment will be the same for the term of the loan. Adjustable rate mortgages got a lot of people in trouble in 2007 because the rates would change and their mortgage payments would go up. In order to have a consistent mortgage payment, get a fixed rate.

4. What fees are involved in the transaction? Whether you are buying a home or refinancing a home, you should ask if the transaction involves any points being charged to you. Some lenders charge 1% of the loan amount. If you are buying a $400,000 home and they charge you 1% up front, then you are paying $4,000 just to do the loan. If you are buying a house, those fees are included in your closing costs.

“Adjustable-rate mortgages got a lot of people in trouble in 2007.”

5. Does the loan have a prepayment penalty? You will be stuck with that loan for however long the penalty term is. The prepayment penalty can be between 3% to 5%. If you buy a $300,000 property and your mortgage has a prepayment penalty, that will cost you between $9,000 to $15,000 to get out of that loan. Make sure you don’t have any prepayment penalties.

6. What is the minimum required down payment? The down payment amount is dictated by what type of loan you get. Conventional loans require 5% to 20%. FHA loans have a minimum requirement of 3.5%. It’s important that you go into the transaction knowing how much of a down payment you will need.

7. Does the loan have private mortgage insurance? This is an additional payment on top of PITI. Call me if you have any more questions about private mortgage insurance. It’s a bit complicated, and I’ll be able to go more in-depth about this on the phone.

8. Do you have any other products that offer a lower interest rate? Loans are not one size fits all. There are a number of different options available. See what your options are and if you can get a lower mortgage payment.

I hope you found this information helpful. If you have any other questions about buying a home or refinancing, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+8+Questions+You+Should+Always+Ask+Your+Lender.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+8+Questions+You+Should+Always+Ask+Your+Lender.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When you talk to a mortgage lender, there are eight important questions that you should ask if you plan on buying (or refinancing) a home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When you talk to a mortgage lender, there are eight important questions that you should ask if you plan on buying (or refinancing) a home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do Interest Rate Increases Affect Your Pockets?</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/how-do-interest-rate-increases-affect-your-pockets.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-08 06:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+How+Do+Interest+Rate+Increases+Affect+Your+Pockets%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How does the recent interest rate increase affect you? There are a few ways you need to be mindful of.

First, you need to know that when the Federal Reserve moves interest rates, what they’re actually doing is moving the federal funds rate. The federal funds rate is the rate at which banks lend money to each other.

The first way this affects you is through credit cards. Most credit cards have variable interest rates, so as the Fed moves the federal funds rate (or prime rate), more of your monthly payment goes toward interest instead of your principal. Basically, you’re paying more for interest, and it will take you longer to pay off your credit card.

Rising interest rates also affect student loans. If you got your student loans before 1996, then those student loans have a variable interest rate. As the prime rate increases, your student loan payment will increase as well. The only time rising interest rates don’t affect you is when you have fixed interest rates.

Rising interest rates make car payments more expensive as well. If you currently own a car and you have an adjustable rate, your payment will be higher this coming month.

“The only time rising interest rates don’t affect you is when you have fixed interest rates.”

Rising interest rates impact your mortgage payment too. You might say, “Well, I have a fixed interest rate, so I have nothing to worry about.” You have nothing to worry about now during your fixed period, but what happens when you want to refinance, take some cash out to make some improvements, or get a line of credit? Your payment will be higher because you’re subject to that higher interest rate. Even with a fixed rate, you’ll be affected if you decide to refinance or change your terms.

The same applies to people with adjustable-rate mortgages, which is why they’re so dangerous. You have a small payment now while interest rates are low, but according to Freddie Mac, rates are expected to rise from 4% to 4.6% at the end of 2018.

If you’re in the market to buy a house, rising interest rates means your purchasing power diminishes and your house payments increase. If you want to take advantage of the currently low interest rates to either buy a house or refinance your property, give me a call so we can review your situation and see if it’s conducive for you to do so.

If you have any other questions about how rising interest rates might affect you or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+How+Do+Interest+Rate+Increases+Affect+Your+Pockets%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+How+Do+Interest+Rate+Increases+Affect+Your+Pockets%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Rising interest rates affect you in a variety of ways. Here are some things you need to pay attention to over the next year as rates are predicted to increase.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Rising interest rates affect you in a variety of ways. Here are some things you need to pay attention to over the next year as rates are predicted to increase.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Right Now Is the Best Time to Buy</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/why-right-now-is-the-best-time-to-buy.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-22 03:40:14 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Why+Right+Now+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Buy.mp4</guid>
        <description>

One question I hear frequently is, “Is right now the best time to buy a house?”

Well, I’d like to let you be the judge of that. Today I’ll provide you with some facts and figures about our market, so that you can get an idea of what’s really going on. The numbers don’t lie.

When it comes to the time of year, though, right now is undoubtedly a great time to buy. First of all, there’s less competition. Most people aren’t buying near the holidays, so you have an advantage on the market.

Secondly, sellers are worn out. Sellers who listed their property during the summer but haven’t sold yet will likely lower their price, if they haven’t done so already.

Also, because fewer transactions occur at this time of year, you will have the undivided attention of whichever real estate professionals you work with.

Finally, this time of year is great to buy because depending on how you buy your property, some closing costs may be tax deductible.

“Is right now truly the best time to buy? The answer is yes.”

So, now that we’ve established that this time of year is the best time to buy in general, what about right now, specifically? Is this moment in time truly the best time to buy? The answer is yes.

Currently, you could get a 30-year mortgage at an interest rate at 3.5% for a monthly payment of approximately $1,475.35. But this won’t last. Interest rates are going to rise. While your interest rate may not impact your monthly payment much, a higher interest rate would absolutely mean a lower loan amount.

The difference between a loan you obtain now versus one you get later could be tens of thousands of dollars. So, why wait?

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Why+Right+Now+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Buy.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Why+Right+Now+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Buy.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Right now is an amazing time to buy, but don’t take my word for it. Let me show you some numbers that prove this point.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Right now is an amazing time to buy, but don’t take my word for it. Let me show you some numbers that prove this point.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Changes Are Happening in the Lending Industry in 2018?</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/what-changes-are-happening-in-the-lending-industry-in-2018.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-06 07:24:52 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+What+Changes+Are+Happening+in+the+Lending+Industry+in+2018%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are two major changes that will take place in the home lending industry in 2018.

The first is an increase in lending limits, both locally and nationwide. Here in San Diego, the lending limit will increase to $679,500. In Riverside, the lending limit is increasing $453,100. This affects conventional conforming loans, FHA loans, and VA loans. This means you’ll be able to buy a bigger, more expensive house in 2018 than you were this year.

The second change is the introduction of new lending programs. Today, I’ll list three of those programs.

The first is the Bank Statement Program, which is designed for individuals who are self-employed. Instead of having to show two years’ worth of taxes, we take the average of all of your deposits for the past 24 months to calculate your purchasing power.

“You’ll be able to buy a bigger, more expensive house in 2018 than you were in 2017.”

The second is the 90%, one loan, no mortgage insurance program. This loan is perfect if you bought a house last year or two years ago and are waiting for the property to increase 20% in order to remove the mortgage insurance. With this loan, there’s no need to wait that long. If your property has appreciated as much as 10%, we can refinance your loan, switch it from an FHA loan to a conventional loan, lower your interest rate, and remove your mortgage insurance. You’ll save hundreds of dollars each month!

The last program is the Fresh Start Program, which is for those who filed for bankruptcy or had a short or a foreclosure. With this program, you don’t have to wait as long as seven years to buy a house again.

If you have any questions about these changes or you’re looking to buy or refinance a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m here to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+What+Changes+Are+Happening+in+the+Lending+Industry+in+2018%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+What+Changes+Are+Happening+in+the+Lending+Industry+in+2018%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>An increase in lending limits and an introduction of some new lending programs are two important changes in the lending world you need to take note of.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>An increase in lending limits and an introduction of some new lending programs are two important changes in the lending world you need to take note of.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is It Time for You to Refinance Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/is-it-time-for-you-to-refinance-your-home.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-14 03:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+When%2527s+the+Right+Time+to+Refinance+Your+Home+Loan%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

People always ask me why someone should refinance their home. To answer that question, I’ve got a few smart reasons why refinancing your home loan could be a good option for you.


  To lower the term. You could go from a 30-year mortgage to a 20- or even 15-year mortgage. Refinancing to a shorter term will help lower your interest rate and also the amount you’re paying for your home.
  To lower your rate. If you had a high interest rate when you purchased your home, now is the time to refinance. Whether it’s going from a 5.5% rate to a 4.5% rate, or even from a 4.5% rate to a 3.5% rate, you’ll be able to shorten your term and save hundreds every month. “Refinancing could lower your rate and help you save money.”
  To take cash out. If you’ve owned your property for a couple of years and have accumulated equity, you can take some of that equity out and reinvest it into your home. You could also use it to pay off some debt.
  To move to a conventional loan. This is probably the most common reason people refinance. Changing from an FHA loan to a conventional loan, for example, could allow you to get rid of your mortgage insurance.


If you have any other questions, would like more information, or want to know if refinancing is right for you, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+When%2527s+the+Right+Time+to+Refinance+Your+Home+Loan%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+When%2527s+the+Right+Time+to+Refinance+Your+Home+Loan%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’d like to go over four of the main reasons people might choose to refinance their home loan.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’d like to go over four of the main reasons people might choose to refinance their home loan.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the First Step in the Home Buying Process?</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/whats-the-first-step-in-the-home-buying-process.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-27 07:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Whats+the+First+Step+in+the+Home+Buying+Process%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are the steps you must take when buying a home?

Whether you’re a first-time homebuyer, you’re buying your second home, or you’re looking for an investment property, the first step is to get pre-qualified. Everybody typically does the fun stuff like look at properties online, but getting pre-qualified is the first step you must take.

There are three main factors that can affect your qualification.

The first is your credit. Most programs require you to have at least a 580 FICO score to qualify.

The second factor is your income. You need to be employed for at least two years in the same industry. Not the same job—the same industry. For example, if you work in construction and switch companies but you continue working in construction, that’s perfectly fine. If you go from working construction to working at a bank, the clock gets set back two years. Your income determines your debt-to-income ratio, and that determines how much you’ll be able to qualify for.

“Getting pre-qualified is easier than you think.”

The third factor is the down payment. Different programs require different down payment amounts. With the new government down payment assistance programs, you can put as little as 0% down. There are also FHA programs for first-time homebuyers and conventional programs that offer 5%, 10%, or 30% down.

Once you complete the pre-qualification step, then you can start looking at properties and interviewing agents. Getting pre-qualified is easier than you think. It can be done either over the phone or in-person. If you need help, give me a call so we can help you know where you stand.

If you have any other questions about this topic or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Whats+the+First+Step+in+the+Home+Buying+Process%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+Whats+the+First+Step+in+the+Home+Buying+Process%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The very first step you must take when buying a home is to get pre-qualified.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The very first step you must take when buying a home is to get pre-qualified.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips for a Better Credit Score</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/3-tips-for-a-better-credit-score.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-12 04:14:14 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+3+Tips+for+a+Better+Credit+Score.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a mortgage lender, people always ask me which factors will most affect their credit. Today, I’d like to share a list of these key factors.

1. Making your payments on time. You may not realize what a dramatic impact missing even just a single payment can make on your credit score. The effect can actually be between 20 to 60 points, so make sure you are always punctual with your payments

“Always keep your credit card balance 30% below your limit.”

2. The length of your credit history. The longer you have an account open, the more points you’ll rack up over that time. As a side note, if you want to pay off an account and credit card, never cancel that account. If you do, all of the credit history will disappear and cause your score to go down.

3. Your balance against the limit. As a rule of thumb, you should always keep your credit card balance 30% below your limit.

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or are interested in free credit counseling, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+3+Tips+for+a+Better+Credit+Score.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/Abel+Tejeda-+3+Tips+for+a+Better+Credit+Score.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Few people realize how big of an impact some seemingly small factors can have on your credit score. Today, I’ve got a list of key tips.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Few people realize how big of an impact some seemingly small factors can have on your credit score. Today, I’ve got a list of key tips.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Biggest Mortgage Mistakes You Can Make</title>
        <link>http://abeltejeda.blog/3-biggest-mortgage-mistakes-you-can-make.html</link>
        
        <author>Abel Tejeda</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-28 08:05:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/American+Mortgage+Group-+3+Biggest+Mortgage+Mistakes+You+Can+Make.mp4</guid>
        <description>

For most homebuyers, their mortgage is their biggest monthly expense. However, most owners do little to no preparation, negotiation, or shopping in order to get the best deal possible. Here are three of the biggest mortgage mistakes you can make and how to avoid them:

1. Believing the advertised rates are what you’ll actually pay. Unless you have near-perfect credit, most advertised rates are out of your league. To get boasting rights on a good rate, you have to pay part of a point, or even a full point. A “point” in the mortgage world is roughly 1% of your loan amount.

2. Not comparing lenders. Just like everybody knows a real estate agent, everybody knows a loan officer or mortgage banker. However, they aren’t the same thing. A loan officer works for the bank and can only offer packages the bank puts together. A mortgage broker pre-qualifies you like a loan officer, but can shop around to get the best deals for you. Just like you wouldn’t go to buy a car without visiting a few different dealerships, you shouldn’t get a mortgage after talking to just one lender. “Most advertised rates are not what they appear.”

3. Not paying attention to the terms. The true cost of the loan lies in the APR, which includes various fees from the lender. There are so many ways lenders can inch those up, including with loan origination or processing fees that can vary widely. Make sure you know what you’re going to be paying before you sign on the dotted line.

If you have any questions for me or want any more tips about how to get the best possible rate and terms for your mortgage, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/American+Mortgage+Group-+3+Biggest+Mortgage+Mistakes+You+Can+Make.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://abeltejeda.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Abel+Tejeda/American+Mortgage+Group-+3+Biggest+Mortgage+Mistakes+You+Can+Make.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are a few things you should know if you’re trying to get a mortgage. For one, you need to compare different lenders.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Abel Tejeda</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are a few things you should know if you’re trying to get a mortgage. For one, you need to compare different lenders.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Houses for sale in San Diego, mortgage tips, mortgage lender, financing a home, finance, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Abel Tejeda</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Abel Tejeda</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">Home loans in San Diego can be complex, but that doesn’t mean you should sign on the dotted line without explanations.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
