<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Real Estate Podcast with Ashley Carter</title>
    <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carter Property Group - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>The Carter Property Group</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-05-30 14:26:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>The Carter Property Group</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@CarterPropertyGroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>The Carter Property Group</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Chicago Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carter Property Group - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Book That Will Help You Reach Your Real Estate Investing Goals</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/the-book-that-will-help-you-reach-your-real-estate-investing-goals.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-30 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Here at the Carter Property Group, our mission is to create generational wealth through real estate and assist our clients with achieving their goals.

What does this mean for you? Ask yourself these questions:

Are you hoping to retire sooner than you originally thought possible?

Are you worried about your post-retirement financial stability?

Are you worried about how you’ll pay for your children’s college education?

Do you plan on leaving behind a legacy for your friends and family?

“This is the playbook that will take you as far as you want to go with your real estate investing needs.”

By taking the right action steps now, you can put yourself in a position to achieve all of these goals. To that end, we’re offering you a free copy of “The Millionaire Real Estate Investor” by Gary Keller, the founder of Keller Williams Realty.

The information in this book is so valuable that we want to share it with you. It’s the playbook that can take you as high as you want to go with your real estate investing goals. If you’re interested in receiving a copy, click on this link [LINK], share your information with us, and we’d be glad to send one to you.

We’re very passionate about this topic and we want to educate as many people as we can on the right action steps to take in their lives to achieve the same goals, so if you aren’t interested but know someone who might be, don’t hesitate to refer them to us.

If you have any other questions about this offer or there’s anything else we can assist you with, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here at the Carter Property Group, our mission is to create generational wealth through real estate and assist our clients with achieving their goals.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here at the Carter Property Group, our mission is to create generational wealth through real estate and assist our clients with achieving their goals.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Market Shift Is on the Way</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/a-market-shift-is-on-the-way.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-05 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Carter+Property+Group-+A+Market+Shift+Is+on+the+Way.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A question we get asked almost every day in our business is, “When is the best time for me to sell my house?”

With our area being so dense, buying or selling a home can be done at basically any time of year. However, this doesn’t mean there aren’t seasonal factors at play. We live in a cold-weather market, which means our market cycle is different from those located in warmer climates.

When the weather here starts to warm up, then the market tends to heat up too. If you want to know when the best time to sell is, you’ve got to pay attention to current market statistics. Understanding market trends is the key to success in real estate.

“If you or anyone you know is thinking of selling, now is a good time to make your move.”

So far this year, we’ve seen a decrease in the number of contracts being written compared to what we saw this same time last year. Still, there has been a slight increase in inventory after a very long period of decreasing supply.

The market is set up statistically for a shift. With that information in mind, think about anyone you know who is thinking of selling in the next three to 18 months. Conditions are now slowly shifting to benefit buyer’s more, so if you or anyone you know is thinking of selling, now is a good time to make your move.

My team and I watch market statistics on a weekly basis, so we have clear evidence that this shift is on its way.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Carter+Property+Group-+A+Market+Shift+Is+on+the+Way.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Carter+Property+Group-+A+Market+Shift+Is+on+the+Way.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Right now, changes are coming to our local real estate market. Today I’d like to bring you the latest update on this upcoming shift.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Right now, changes are coming to our local real estate market. Today I’d like to bring you the latest update on this upcoming shift.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Top 3 Mistakes Home Sellers Make</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/the-top-3-mistakes-home-sellers-make.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-04 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Carter+Property+Group-+3+Biggest+Seller+Mistakes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re counting down the top three mistakes that home sellers make when they put their home on the market.

3. Not saying “yes” to a showing request. You should always say yes. The buyer and the buyer’s agent have carved out time in their schedules to come and see your home. If we ask them to schedule for another day, ask to move the time, or decline altogether, we may never hear from them again. Even if we follow up and ask them to please reschedule, they will probably go out and find another home.

2. They don’t rise to the occasion and prepare the property to show in the best light possible. It’s so important that your property looks great. Make sure that you declutter, clean, and make repairs and updates. With wide-angle lenses and enhanced photographs, our first sale is online. Your home has to look amazing online, or the buyer may not come into your home to start with.

“You should always say “yes” to a showing request.”

1. They refuse to listen to market data and price the home correctly for the market conditions. You cannot afford to overprice your home. When you are getting your home ready for the market, it’s important to pay attention to market conditions and price your home accordingly.

Those are the three most important things you should keep in mind when preparing to sell your home.

If you are thinking of selling your home and would like to know what your home is worth in the current market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Carter+Property+Group-+3+Biggest+Seller+Mistakes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Carter+Property+Group-+3+Biggest+Seller+Mistakes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to set your property up for a successful home sale, you need to avoid these top three seller mistakes.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to set your property up for a successful home sale, you need to avoid these top three seller mistakes.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening With Interest Rates?</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/whats-happening-with-interest-rates.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-19 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Carter+Property+Group-+Whats+Happening+With+Interest+Rates%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I want to go over what interest rates are doing in the local market and how they impact buyers and sellers.

Since the beginning of 2018, mortgage interest rates have increased from 4.0% to 4.625% for a 30-year mortgage. That might not seem like a significant jump, and, historically speaking, a 4.625% interest rate is still very low.

Here’s the thing—that increase has an impact on a buyer’s ability to borrow money to buy real estate.

“An increase in interest rates means a decrease in buying power.”

If you are a homebuyer and you want a specific monthly mortgage payment based on your income, you’ve lost 7.2% in purchasing power. That means you have the ability to buy 7.2% less home for the same monthly payment.

As a seller, since people who are interested in buying your home have lost some purchasing power, there will be a downward effect on prices and the offers that they might be able to make.

That said, the real estate market in Chicago is still very strong. This is a fairly recent development but it is significant, so I wanted to make sure that everyone was aware of it.

It looks like rates will continue to increase over the course of 2018. If you have any questions about how rising interest rates will impact your 2018 real estate goals, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Carter+Property+Group-+Whats+Happening+With+Interest+Rates%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Carter+Property+Group-+Whats+Happening+With+Interest+Rates%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How do rising interest rates impact homebuyers and sellers in the Chicago area? I’ll explain today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How do rising interest rates impact homebuyers and sellers in the Chicago area? I’ll explain today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is a Buyer’s Agent?</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/what-is-a-buyers-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-22 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/What+Is+a+Buyers+Agent%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to introduce you to Laura Jones, the buyer’s agent for our team here at Carter Property Group, so that you can get to know her and have some of your questions answered by her.

What’s a buyer’s agent?I focus solely on the purchase of our clients’ homes. First-time homebuyers, investors, upsizing, downsizing—I only work on the buy side of the transaction.  Any client we have has to sit down with me for a consultation. I’m able to get an idea of their needs in about 30 to 40 minutes.  Once we do that, we begin searching and going out into the field to look at homes. After that, when we’re ready, I write the contract and negotiate the terms.

So essentially, I do needs-assessment through a consultation, preview homes on the MLS, set up searches for people, take people out into the field to view homes (sometimes as many as 40 properties a week), write offers and negotiate terms once a property is selected, and eventually get it under contract. I’m able to service clients at a very high level.

What does a typical day look like for you?

I wake up in the morning, shake my son awake and take him to school, and then I get to the office. I generally block off my morning for business calls and finding properties that aren’t yet on the market for our clients. I’ll take lunch and maybe make time for a workout, and then for the rest of the afternoon and evening I’ll block out that time period to be able to go out into the field with clients.

So the MLS is only one source that you use to find properties for clients?Absolutely. Sometimes I’ll send out mailers and follow it up with a call. Sometimes the property for our clients isn’t always on the market at the time. That allows me to block a whole morning to find properties and preview them.

What’s your favorite part of your job?As a buyer’s agent, my favorite part of my job is the fact that I do get to know my clients in a really intimate way. I spend a lot of time with them and their families, I get to know personal things about them, and after the transaction, we don’t really fall off. I love checking in with them. They send me photos of remodels, updates, babies, and more. It’s just really rewarding. I don’t take it lightly that buying a home is probably the most money you’re ever going to spend.

“Helping someone get into their new home is pretty powerful. I love it.”

Helping someone get into their new home is pretty powerful. I love it.

If you have any questions about property, taxes, or anything real estate-related, give us a call. We’re always happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/What+Is+a+Buyers+Agent%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/What+Is+a+Buyers+Agent%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Meet Laura Jones, our buyer’s agent, and find out what she does, why it’s important to clients, and why it’s important to her.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Meet Laura Jones, our buyer’s agent, and find out what she does, why it’s important to clients, and why it’s important to her.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Gaining a New Perspective on the Home Buying Process: Part Two</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/gaining-a-new-perspective-on-the-home-buying-process-part-two.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-01 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Gaining+a+New+Perspective+on+the+Home+Buying+Process.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re coming at you with the second part of our two-part series, where we continue to answer the question “What happens when the agent becomes the buyer?” For the first part of this series, click here.

The next step in the home buying process for Paul was the home inspection phase, which always creates moments of apprehension. Going in with a 203(k) loan, Paul is borrowing a little bit more money than the purchase price of the property in order to put some money back into that property.

““We train really hard on stuff like that—how to listen, how to find out where people are, and how to ask a question to dig deeper about emotions.””

Knowing that extra money was there to handle problems created a sense of calmness, but the home’s inspection revealed three relatively big ones: asbestos, residual termite damage, and some fascia on some of the gutters, which is a complicated fix. Moving forward, we’ve uncovered a layering of information and still have some unknowns to decide on in order to proceed.

Paul jokes that he’s almost fired two people so far, but having the experience of feeling like he’s not being heard was invaluable to him because he always wants our clients to feel like they’re being heard, as do I.

What we’ve seen for a long time, and what partially explains this feeling if you’re a homebuyer, is that the further away a person involved in the transaction is from the actual transaction and the core facilitators of that transaction (i.e., the agent), the more you’re just a file to them. They don’t have the first-hand connection to your goals, your situation, and your timeline. We always keep these factors in mind when working with our clients.

“We train really hard on stuff like that—how to listen, how to find out where people are, and how to ask a question to dig deeper about emotions.”

We’ll keep you posted on the next steps of this transaction and relay some more first-hand knowledge on the subject. In the meantime, if you have any questions or are looking to buy or sell a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Gaining+a+New+Perspective+on+the+Home+Buying+Process.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Gaining+a+New+Perspective+on+the+Home+Buying+Process.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>One of our very own agents is in the middle of buying a house, and the experience has left him with a deeper understanding of the home buying process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>One of our very own agents is in the middle of buying a house, and the experience has left him with a deeper understanding of the home buying process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Gaining a New Perspective on the Home Buying Process: Part One</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/gaining-a-new-perspective-on-the-home-buying-process-part-one.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-01 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Gaining+a+New+Perspective+on+the+Home+Buying+Process.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re coming at you with a two-part series, where we answer the question “What happens when the agent becomes the buyer?” For the second part of this series, click here.

So, what exactly happens when the agent becomes the buyer?

Paul Popp, our transaction coordinator and operations manager, is purchasing a property right now, which means he’s going through all the same steps our clients go through when buying a home.

So far, Paul’s been calm where he didn’t expect to be calm and feeling different emotions in situations he thought he’d know how to handle better. Being in the same shoes as you are has helped him understand the process better.

“This experience has been invaluable to Paul as an agent.”

“It’s been unique,” he says. “It’s a constant reminder of where our clients are at different stages of the process and how those stages are being influenced, either by the other agent, the seller in this situation, the home inspector, timeliness of response—all of that stuff is really kind of communicated in a heavy, tangible way what our clients are going through.”

The amount of documentation buyers have to provide to their lenders has stood out as the most vivid part of the process for him. As easy as lenders make that exchange, he’s found that it can still be tense as far as the level of detailed knowledge they have about you. Once he finished getting pre-approved and entered negotiations, keeping his end-goal in mind helped him deal with the emotions of that situation and navigate all the hypothetical scenarios that arose.

“Continually coming back to the goal made it crystal clear what we were trying to accomplish.”

In the next part, we’ll discuss what happens during the home inspection. To watch the second video in this series, click here. In the meantime, if you have any questions or are looking to buy or sell a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Gaining+a+New+Perspective+on+the+Home+Buying+Process.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Gaining+a+New+Perspective+on+the+Home+Buying+Process.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>One of our very own agents is in the middle of buying a house, and the experience has left him with a deeper understanding of the home buying process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>One of our very own agents is in the middle of buying a house, and the experience has left him with a deeper understanding of the home buying process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investing in Short Term Rental Properties: Part Two</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/investing-in-short-term-rental-properties-part-two.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-09 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to Part Two of our series on investing in short-term rentals. Joining me again is Rees , a client of ours who has recently used short-term rentals in her investing strategy.

To watch the first part in this series, click here.

In the first part of this series, Rees explained the return she received on this investment. Initially, returns were in the single digits. From a percentage standpoint, though, short-term rentals produced a 50% higher return than long-term rentals. Her family also decided to outsource the management of these properties, so they hired a company who handles the management of similar internal units, and that 50% was after that management company’s fees.

When it comes to managing the property itself, her workload has decreased because their management company, like most management companies, has a handyman on call for maintenance issues within short-term properties. Many people wonder how much time they’ll have to devote to managing residential rental property, and the answer is usually less than you think.

“Always have a good team in place when investing in short-term rentals”

Rees has two main points of advice for anyone thinking about buying an investment property. The first is to leave a little bit of a buffer from a dollar standpoint, especially with short-term rentals. This is because there is a little bit of upfront capital investment required, and issues can arise that you’ll need money set aside for.

It’s also critical to have a good team in place. Rees had a great real estate attorney and a home inspector working for her, and they advised her against buying a different property that would’ve caused her a lot of headaches.

We want to thank Rees for joining us today to help us explore the topic of short-term rentals. If you have any more questions about investing in short-term rentals, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Welcome to Part Two of our series on investing in short-term rentals, or, more specifically, Airbnb properties. Joining me again is Rees, a client of ours who has recently used short-term rentals in her investing strategy.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Welcome to Part Two of our series on investing in short-term rentals, or, more specifically, Airbnb properties. Joining me again is Rees, a client of ours who has recently used short-term rentals in her investing strategy.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investing in Short Term Rental Properties: Part One</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/investing-in-short-term-rental-properties-part-one.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-09 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/How+Short-Term+Rentals+Can+Boost+Your+Real+Estate+Investment+Strategy.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re coming at you with a two-part series, where we take a much deeper dive into the topic of short-term rentals. For the second part of this series, click here.

To discuss how short-term rentals can make a wise real estate investment strategy, we’ve brought in Rees, a client of ours who’s recently found success investing in short-term rentals.

Rees had a few goals in mind when she got into real estate investing. Though she wasn’t initially thrilled about the idea, after a few conversations with us, it became clear to her that it was a great option to add to the current investments she has from a diversification standpoint. She also considered it important to gain some passive income in addition to her job. On a more personal note, it was important for her to have an investment dedicated to the medical needs of her son.

“From a percentage standpoint, though, short-term rentals produced a 50% higher return than long-term rentals.”

To clarify, whereas “active income” is whatever comes from your primary occupation, “passive income” is typically the category where real estate investing falls, and that’s the way the IRS categorizes it as well.

Rees was initially looking for multi-unit properties (specifically three-unit) with long-term renters, and she was identifying them specifically based on whether they would be a good investment numbers-wise and make sense from their return perspective.

One property in particular came up that was significantly higher in return. That property had one of its three units as a short-term rental. She then realized that short-term rentals could be applied to other three-unit properties with long-term renters. Once she was able to take that idea and apply it to other properties, several more options became available.

Initially, returns were in the single digits. From a percentage standpoint, though, short-term rentals produced a 50% higher return than long-term rentals. Her family also decided to outsource the management of these properties, so they hired a company who handles the management of similar internal units, and that 50% was after that management company’s fees.

We want to thank Rees for joining us today to help us explore the topic of short-term rentals! If you’re considering investing in short term real estate, we encourage you to watch the second part of this series, where we discuss what it takes to manage an investment property, and give advice to those looking to diversify their investments with real estate.

If you have any more questions about investing in short-term rentals, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/How+Short-Term+Rentals+Can+Boost+Your+Real+Estate+Investment+Strategy.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/How+Short-Term+Rentals+Can+Boost+Your+Real+Estate+Investment+Strategy.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we’re coming at you with a two-part series, where we take a much deeper dive into the topic of short-term rentals.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we’re coming at you with a two-part series, where we take a much deeper dive into the topic of short-term rentals.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Carter Property Group's Pumpkin Giveaway!</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/pumpkin-giveaway.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-09 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Oct+1.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Happy fall, everyone!

The Carter Property Group is holding a pumpkin giveaway this year. We’re going to have two pickup locations—one in the city, and one in the suburbs.

“We need to hear from you in order to have a pumpkin ready for you!”

But we need to hear from you in order to have a pumpkin ready for you! RSVP using the instructions in the video above, and you’ll also receive a postcard in the mail. Shoot us a text, give us a call, or send us an email and we’ll have a pumpkin reserved for you.

We look forward to seeing you on pumpkin pickup day!

For pumpkin carving ideas, check out our Pinterest board: https://www.pinterest.com/carterpropgroup/pumpkin-carving-ideas/

If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Oct+1.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Oct+1.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The Carter Property Group is holding a pumpkin giveaway this year. We’re going to have two pickup locations—one in the city, and one in the suburbs.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The Carter Property Group is holding a pumpkin giveaway this year. We’re going to have two pickup locations—one in the city, and one in the suburbs.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Helping Those Impacted by Harvey</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/helping-those-impacted-by-harvey.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-18 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Ashely+Carter.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When Hurricane Harvey made landfall in Houston, it brought with it over two feet of rain and left in its wake tens of thousands of displaced people and hundreds of thousands more without power.

“Overall, this experience has been incredibly rewarding.”

We recently had the opportunity to travel down to the Houston area with my Keller Williams colleagues to lend a hand to homeowners whose homes had flooded due to Hurricane Harvey. One home, in particular, belonged to a couple in their 90s, who needed help getting the drywall cut out, the carpet removed, and baseboards replaced.

Overall, this experience has been incredibly rewarding. We got to help a lot of families, but there are many more people who still need help. Because of this, our Keller Williams Chicago-Lincoln Park office has pledged to contribute $100,000 back to hurricane relief. We want to work together to make the biggest impact possible, so we’ll be hosting a telethon that gives us the opportunity to give back to our communities on a local and national level.

For more information on how you can give back, visit https://www.reliefnow.info/

In the meantime, if you have any questions, don’t hesitate to give us a call or shoot us an email. We’d be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Ashely+Carter.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Ashley+Carter/Ashely+Carter.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When Hurricane Harvey made landfall in Houston, it brought with it over two feet of rain and left in its wake tens of thousands of displaced people and hundreds of thousands more without power. I recently had the opportunity to travel down to the Houston area with my Keller Williams colleagues to lend a hand to homeowners whose homes had flooded due to Hurricane Harvey.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When Hurricane Harvey made landfall in Houston, it brought with it over two feet of rain and left in its wake tens of thousands of displaced people and hundreds of thousands more without power. I recently had the opportunity to travel down to the Houston area with my Keller Williams colleagues to lend a hand to homeowners whose homes had flooded due to Hurricane Harvey.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Does It Take to Manage a Short-Term Rental Property?</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/what-does-it-take-to-manage-a-short-term-rental-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-24 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/What%20Does%20It%20Take%20to%20Manage%20a%20Short-Term%20Rental%20Property%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The residential rental market is being revolutionized.

Airbnb, if you haven’t heard of it, is a short-term rental service that allows landlords and tenants to connect on properties currently for rent.

The amount of money that can be generated in this way is actually much higher than what the landlord could earn from renting out a property on an eight to 12-month basis.

This is largely due to the fact that the rent can be made higher for these properties since they are short-term and are often utilized similarly to a hotel.

“The residential rental market is being revolutionized”

The nightly rental rates of a hotel over a 12-month payment would be much more expensive than a typical 12-month rent.

But not only are short-term rental landlords earning more income, they are also cutting certain costs typically associated with renting out property.

However, there are some added expectations and requirements for a short-term rental property. From a management perspective, you as the landlord must offer the property furnished. Managing bookings and turnover is also different than it would be in a month-to-month rental property.

There are now companies that specialize in the turnover process. They’ll change sheets and help turn properties around for the next resident. So, there are absolutely resources out there that can help.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/What%20Does%20It%20Take%20to%20Manage%20a%20Short-Term%20Rental%20Property%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/What%20Does%20It%20Take%20to%20Manage%20a%20Short-Term%20Rental%20Property%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Short-term rentals have been revolutionizing the market. Today, I wanted to share some information about these kinds of rentals.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Short-term rentals have been revolutionizing the market. Today, I wanted to share some information about these kinds of rentals.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Meet Our Listing Manager</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/meet-our-listing-manager.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-07 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Meet%20Our%20Listing%20Manager.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Get to know the Carter Property Group. Today, we’d like to introduce you to Shannon Kelly, our listing manager.

As listing manager, Shannon gets involved in the process whenever a home seller decides they want to work with us. “I help prepare the home to go on the market,” says Shannon. Shannon lines up a professional photographer, gets all the keys necessary to access the property, and gathers background information on the home or condo.

She also puts together our online and print marketing materials and keeps everyone updated on the process until the seller gets a contract on their home.

“One of my favorite parts of the job is getting to go through the house with the photographer and making sure everything looks its best,” she says. “It’s really fun to get the look and feel of the property. I also enjoy staying on top of our online marketing presence. There are cool things going on with Facebook marketing, and online marketing changes every day, which I get excited about.”

“Shannon keeps everyone updated on the process until you get a contract on your home.”

A typical day for Shannon starts with making sure that everyone on the team has what they need. For example, a selling agent may have questions about how to access a property. She also puts together brochures and marketing materials, and sometimes she gets to go to a photo appointment or make keys for a property.

As for a few fun facts about Shannon: “I like to bike a lot. I’ve really gotten into biking recently; it’s my primary way of getting to work. I also have a dog that I probably talk too much about,” Shannon says, laughing. “Just ask anyone on the team.”

If you have any questions for Shannon or anyone else in the Carter Property Group, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Meet%20Our%20Listing%20Manager.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Meet%20Our%20Listing%20Manager.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Meet our fantastic listing manager, Shannon Kelly.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Meet our fantastic listing manager, Shannon Kelly.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don't Miss This Great Event</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/dont-miss-this-great-event.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-28 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’ve got some exciting news to share with you. You’re invited to our upcoming first-time homebuyers social.

We’d love for you to come out and take advantage of this no cost social, where we’ll have drinks, appetizers, and useful information about the homebuying process.

“You’re invited to our upcoming first-time homebuyers social.”

The event will take place at Old Town Social at 455 North Avenue from 6 p.m. to 8 p.m. on Thursday, August 3rd.

Don’t let this opportunity pass you by. Once you RSVP, which you can do by clicking this link, you’re all set to learn and have fun.

Also, if you know anyone else who might be interested, please feel free to pass along the video or information about this event. We’d love to see you there.

This is a great chance to have fun, have some food and drinks, and learn about the process of buying a home.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learning about buying a home just got more fun. Our upcoming event is going to be a great time with food, drinks, and valuable information about the homebuying process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Learning about buying a home just got more fun. Our upcoming event is going to be a great time with food, drinks, and valuable information about the homebuying process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How the Carter Property Group Is Different</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/how-the-carter-property-group-is-different.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-12 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/How%20Carter%20Property%20Group%20Is%20Different.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Hello, my name is Paul Popp, and I am the transaction coordinator and operations manager for the Carter Property Group.  As a transaction coordinator and operations manager, my job involves handling the benchmarks and communication from the time a property goes under contract all the way through closing.

Between attorneys, other agents, clients, lenders, and appraisers, about six other people enter the transaction once a property goes under contract.

What this means is that I communicate with all of these people to make sure we’re on track with hitting all the dates in the contract, making sure all agreed-upon money is delivered, and to ensure the process goes smoothly overall.

“The opportunities I’ve found here remind me of the reason I got into real estate to begin with.”

Additionally, I make sure that the client is in the know all the way through the process.

After getting my license in 2005, I worked first as an individual agent before meeting Ashley in 2008.

One of the things I found most interesting about my job with the Carter Property Group is that I’ve been put in a position where I’ve done the things I am best at.

There’s a high level of customer service, communication, and organization here. The opportunities I’ve found here remind me of the reason I got into real estate to begin with.

So if you’re interested in working with us or have any other questions, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/How%20Carter%20Property%20Group%20Is%20Different.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/How%20Carter%20Property%20Group%20Is%20Different.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As a real estate professional working with Carter Property Group, my job is to ensure that communication is clear all the way through closing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As a real estate professional working with Carter Property Group, my job is to ensure that communication is clear all the way through closing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why It's Smarter to Buy Than Rent in Chicagoland</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/why-its-smarter-to-buy-than-rent-in-chicagoland.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-05 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/When%20It%2527s%20Smarter%20to%20Buy%20Than%20Rent%20in%20Chicagoland.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In many cases in our market, you can actually buy a property for less money on a monthly basis than it costs to rent. It seems too good to be true, but the math checks out. Here’s why.

Even though prices have gone up steadily over the last five years, the key question is how much it costs to borrow money from a mortgage lender to buy a home. At 4% interest—the prevailing rate we see right now—the principal and interest payment for a $100,000 loan is only $477 a month. It would be just under $1,200 a month for a $250,000 loan, before taking into consideration any association fees or ‘assessments’ if you buy a condominium, as well as a county property tax bill.

“In many cases, your monthly payments to buy a house are cheaper than your rent.”

Rental rates here in the Chicagoland market have been high and increasing over the last five years. If you rent now and you’re getting sick of paying your landlord’s mortgage, you really should consider buying a home. Those low interest rates are what make buying a home so affordable right now.

If you or anyone you know wants to talk about the costs of buying a home and how it compares to renting, give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to sit down with you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/When%20It%2527s%20Smarter%20to%20Buy%20Than%20Rent%20in%20Chicagoland.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/When%20It%2527s%20Smarter%20to%20Buy%20Than%20Rent%20in%20Chicagoland.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>With rental rates rising steadily over the last five years and housing affordability so strong, we've reached a point where buying a home could actually be cheaper than renting.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>With rental rates rising steadily over the last five years and housing affordability so strong, we've reached a point where buying a home could actually be cheaper than renting.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in Our Market?</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/whats-happening-in-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-03 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Whats%20Happening%20in%20Our%20Market%253F%20%281%29.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are four main statistical numbers that we track to understand what the market is doing. Today we’re looking at those numbers from March 2016 to March 2017. 

“The median days on market has gone down 16% compared to this time last year.”

1.) The first is the median increase in sales price. In the last 12 months we’ve seen a 7.6% median increase in sales price across all property types in the entire metro area.

2.) The second number, the median days on market, is decreasing. In fact, we’ve seen the median days on market go down by 16% compared to last year.

3.) The next number is the month’s supply of inventory, which is a measurement of how many months it would take to sell all the inventory currently on the market if no new properties were added, is very helpful in determining if we are in a seller’s, buyer’s, or balanced market. We’ve actually seen a decrease in the months supply of inventory of 16% in the last year and have been hovering in a firm seller’s market.  

4.) That brings me to the final number to look at, the number of properties for sale. There are more than 6,000 fewer properties for sale than this time last year, which means competition is increasing. So what does that mean for you? More competition is great news for sellers because houses are selling faster and for more money. On the buyer’s side, interest rates are still low, so you still have a good amount of purchasing power. 

If you or anyone you know is looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’m happy to help and look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Whats%20Happening%20in%20Our%20Market%253F%20%281%29.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Whats%20Happening%20in%20Our%20Market%253F%20%281%29.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m going over some important numbers to give you an idea of what’s happening in our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m going over some important numbers to give you an idea of what’s happening in our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Things to Tackle If You're Updating</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/things-to-tackle-if-youre-updating.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-30 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Mar%201%20%281%29.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If your property is out of date, you might be wondering what updates you should make before putting it on the market. In our last video, we covered improvements you can make to your surface areas to spruce up your home. Today we’re back with a few more upgrades that will make your home really stand out.

First and foremost, you want to be strategic and economical about the updates you undertake, but keep in mind that upgrades are crucial as buyers are very critical.

The areas you’ll want to focus on are the kitchen and bathrooms.

For the kitchen, you’ll want new countertops, a new sink and faucet, new hardware for the cabinets and drawers, and new appliances. You should also consider adding a backsplash or at the very least, painting. Those things will get you the most bang for your buck in your kitchen.

“The areas you’ll want to focus on are the kitchen and bathrooms.”

As far as the bathroom goes, the first thing you’ll want to look at is the condition of the flooring. Also, make sure you take a look at the area surrounding the tub and/or the shower, as well as the condition of the vanity. The good news is that vanities and sinks are generally inexpensive upgrades. Another inexpensive update to consider is adding a new light fixture as that will really make the bathroom pop.

Updates can bring some pretty significant returns and there are ways to update your home on a budget. On the other hand, if you really believe you don’t have the money to upgrade those rooms, you’ll need to be prepared to sell at a lower price.

One of the things my team and I have successfully done over the years is help navigate sellers to the best upgrades for their homes that will have the best returns. If you’re thinking about selling, we can definitely help you key in on the things that will be the most important to buyers.

If anyone you know is looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate or you have any other questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I’m happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Mar%201%20%281%29.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Mar%201%20%281%29.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re looking to sell your home, what are some great updates you can make before you go on the market? Today I’ll go over what areas you should focus on to ensure the best return.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re looking to sell your home, what are some great updates you can make before you go on the market? Today I’ll go over what areas you should focus on to ensure the best return.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Breaking News: Interest Rates to Increase</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/breaking-news-interest-rates-to-increase.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-15 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Breaking%20News-%20Interest%20Rates%20to%20Increase.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’ve got some breaking news to share with you today. The Federal Reserve has just increased their interest rates by 0.25%.

The media may lead you to believe that it will have a direct relationship to the interest rates on the open market, but that’s not the case. We saw rates creeping up toward the end of last week and throughout this week in anticipation of the announcement.

“We’re still in a strong seller’s market.”

If you’re buying or selling a home in today’s market, what does this mean for you? In Chicagoland, we have a very strong seller’s market for the most part. We’re in the heart of our spring selling season and homeowners are able to sell quickly and at or above list price. Because there are fewer properties available, buyers are competing for limited inventory. That’s driving prices up.

If you’re looking to make a move later this year or early next year, you should take a look at the market now and see if you would have a better advantage with rates where they are now. If rates continue to go up, it makes sense for you to buy now. As they increase, your buying power will decrease. We wouldn’t be shocked to see them go up two more times this year alone, so now is a good time to consider making a move.

If you have any questions for us or you are interested in buying, selling, or investing in real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Breaking%20News-%20Interest%20Rates%20to%20Increase.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/Breaking%20News-%20Interest%20Rates%20to%20Increase.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The Federal Reserve has just increased their interest rates. Here’s what it means for buyers and sellers in Chicagoland.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The Federal Reserve has just increased their interest rates. Here’s what it means for buyers and sellers in Chicagoland.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Home Improvements Give You the Best Return?</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/3-investments-to-make-before-you-list-your-house.html</link>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-15 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/3%20Investments%20to%20Make%20Before%20You%20List%20Your%20House.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are the three areas of your home that need to be in tip-top shape before listing? It really comes down to the big surface areas.

That being said, the first thing you want to spend money on is paint. By the time you are ready to sell your home, your walls probably have accumulated some scratches. A clean coat of paint will make your property shine and you’ll see a great return on that investment.

Next, you want to focus on your floors.If you have carpet and there are signs of wear and tear, replacing it is your best option. Otherwise, make sure to give it a thorough cleaning if the carpet is still in good shape. Hardwood flooring is a favorite among buyers, so if there is damage to the hardwood floors, it might wise to have them professionally buffed and refinished.

It is very important to buyers that a home is move-in ready and all the major surface areas are taken care of, so spending the extra money to make sure the hardwood floors are in great shape will pay off.

Finally, consider investing in some new lighting fixtures. If a room or space is dark and doesn’t produce a lot of light, it will be a huge turnoff for buyers. LED lights have become a new standard in the real estate industry, both for their cost effectiveness and their ability to really brighten up a room.

“It is very important to buyers that a home is move-in ready and all the major surface areas are taken care of.”

Investing in those three things will not only give your home a fantastic, fresh feeling, but will almost always guarantee a great return. If you or anyone you know is looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/3%20Investments%20to%20Make%20Before%20You%20List%20Your%20House.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/3%20Investments%20to%20Make%20Before%20You%20List%20Your%20House.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Making these three investments will make your home shine on the market and almost always offer a great return.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Making these three investments will make your home shine on the market and almost always offer a great return.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's Going On In Our Real Estate Market?</title>
        <link>http://carterpropertygroupblog.com/whats-going-on-in-our-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>The Carter Property Group</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-27 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/What%2527s%20Going%20On%20In%20Our%20Real%20Estate%20Market%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I wanted to take a moment to compare the 2016 Chicago real estate market to that of 2015.

As we left 2016, we found that we’re in a slight seller’s market here in Chicago; homes sold at a faster pace and for more money than in 2015. That’s all good news for sellers.

On the buyer side, you’ll find that you have to be ready to make a decision once you find a property that’s the right fit. That’s because properties are selling faster than they typically would. However, there is good news for buyers. Interest rates are still incredible. Due to low rates, buyers have a lot of buying power.

“Due to low rates, buyers have a lot of buying power.”

Have you been considering getting into the real estate investment market here in Chicago? Are you already the owner of an investment property? It continues to be a really strong market for us here in Chicago. Demand for rentals keeps going up as well. In fact, we’ve seen increases for the last four years in a row. The speed at which units re-rent is very fast.

If you have any questions about the Chicago market or you’re thinking about selling your house or buying an investment property, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email with any questions at all. I’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/What%2527s%20Going%20On%20In%20Our%20Real%20Estate%20Market%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://carterpropertygroupblog.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="http://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ashley%20Carter/What%2527s%20Going%20On%20In%20Our%20Real%20Estate%20Market%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What's going on in the Chicago market? To get an idea of where the market is heading, let's take a look back today at the 2016 and 2015 markets.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>The Carter Property Group</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What's going on in the Chicago market? To get an idea of where the market is heading, let's take a look back today at the 2016 and 2015 markets.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>The Carter Property Group</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">The Carter Property Group</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Carter Property Group - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
