<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Philadelphia Real Estate Podcast with Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</title>
    <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://salasteamrealestate.org"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Salas Team - your professional Philadelphia Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-06-12 10:13:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@SalasTeam.net</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://salasteamrealestate.org/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Philadelphia Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Salas Team - your professional Philadelphia Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Pros and Cons of Renting vs. Buying</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/the-pros-and-cons-of-renting-vs-buying.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-04 12:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I recently read an article that said millennials spend about 45% of their income on rental payments. Over their lifetime, they will spend about $93,000 in rent. So, it gave me the idea to talk about the pros and cons of renting versus owning. Renting does have some obvious benefits. If something in the property breaks and needs to be repaired, for example, it is most likely going to fall on the landlord. Also, when the market depreciates, renters do not own the asset which is decreasing in value. Although we are in a market which is appreciating currently, it goes in cycles. Finally, if you do not have a lot of money saved up, or liquidity is an issue for you, renting can help you save more in your savings account. You can keep that money in savings instead of pulling it out to use it on a mortgage. The cons of renting, meanwhile, are also obvious. You do not own anything. Your rent payment is going to the landlord’s mortgage. Also, we are currently in an appreciating market which has been appreciating at a double-digit clip recently. You won’t see any of that if you’re still renting. Finally, you won’t be getting any deductions on your taxes.

“Millennials will spend over $93,000 on rent during the course of their lifetime.” The pros of owning mirror image the cons of renting. Every payment that you are making now builds equity. Every single time you make a monthly payment, you are lowering your mortgage and recapturing your equity. Plus, with the current market’s appreciation, you now have an asset that appreciates in value over time. Taxes, as previously mentioned, change when you own because you get deductions for interest payments and more. Finally, you can personalize your own house. You can improve the home and make it look the way that you want. If you have any questions about real estate or you are interested in buying or selling a home, please feel free to reach out to me. I would be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You could be spending thousands of dollars on rent or spend it on a home which is entirely your own. Which is the best option for you?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You could be spending thousands of dollars on rent or spend it on a home which is entirely your own. Which is the best option for you?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Things You Should Know as a First-Time Homebuyer</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/5-things-you-should-know-as-a-first-time-homebuyer.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-21 10:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

So, you want to buy your first home and you’re ready to get out there and start looking at properties. I’m excited for you! I love working with first-time homebuyers. It’s a fun experience, but sometimes it can be a little stressful.

Today I want to share five tips that will help you during the process of buying your first home. 1. Pick a great agent. You want to work with somebody who takes the time to understand what it is that you are looking for. It is important for them to know your needs and wants. You need to have a great working relationship since you are going to be working with this person for potentially several months. You will also need that person to be someone who listens to you. While Realtors know what you want, they still need to be willing to listen, so don’t work with someone who is pushing you. 2. Establish a plan. You need to know where you want to be. Other important factors to consider are what kinds of things you want in your home, your commute time to work, or even schools in the area. You should have somebody who understands the areas you’re looking to buy. 3. Determine your financing. How are you going to pay for this house? A Realtor’s job is not to know about your personal financial situation, but a good agent will have great lending firms they can introduce you to and who you can work with directly. The lender can help you understand the different packages and products to help you pick the right product for you. Then the agent will work with the lender to help you find the right place.

“While Realtors know what you want, they still need to be willing to listen.”

4. Get to know the neighborhood. Go out and find what neighborhood you want to be in. While I can give you an idea of the neighborhoods, it is still up to you to decide if you can live in a particular area. I recommend that you walk around at different times of the day and see if a neighborhood is comfortable to you. You should also schedule a visit with the schools, check out the shops, and go to the parks. It will give you a good idea of the community. 5. Understand the pricing and the seller. A good agent is going to know the pricing in different areas. It can vary greatly, especially in cities. So, you want to make sure that you have an agent that understands the differences between the neighborhoods and how to come up with a comp plan on a particular home. Finally, you want them to understand the seller. Once you find a house, you want to make sure your agent understands the seller’s perspective. What do they want from the house to make sure that we are giving you the best negotiating techniques and tips possible to get you the home that you really want? If you have any questions or would like to sit down and go through a buyer’s consultation, please contact me by phone or email. I would be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buying your first home can be a fun, yet stressful, experience. To help relieve some of the stress, I have five things that you should know when going through the purchasing process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buying your first home can be a fun, yet stressful, experience. To help relieve some of the stress, I have five things that you should know when going through the purchasing process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Let a Bad Credit Score Stop You From Buying a Home</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/dont-let-a-bad-credit-score-stop-you-from-buying-a-home.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-07 17:42:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you plan on buying a home but you’re not sure whether your credit score is high enough to qualify for a loan, don’t worry. Here are a few tips that can help you still become a homeowner.

First, try utilizing these credit repair strategies:


  Lower your credit utilization rate
  Request a credit limit increase
  Become an authorized user for someone with good credit history
  Consolidate your debt


There are also several government loan products, such as a VA or FHA loan, that require a FICO score as low as 300.

“Don’t let a bad credit score stop you from buying a home”

If you’re having trouble with your down payment, there are several city and state programs that can help you, including the Homestead Down Payment and Closing Cost Assistance Loan, the Keystone Advantage Assistance Loan Program, the First Front Door Program, and the Settlement Assistance Grant from the Division of Housing and Community Development.

If you have any questions or you’d like to know more about any of these programs, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are several ways you can still buy a home even if your credit score isn’t as high as you’d like it to be.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are several ways you can still buy a home even if your credit score isn’t as high as you’d like it to be.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Upgrade Your Home’s Exterior With These Quick Tips</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/upgrade-your-homes-exterior-with-these-quick-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-09 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team+Upgrading+your+home%E2%80%99s+exterior.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I have a few tips to share with you that will help you upgrade the outside of your home.

&nbsp;

Whether you’re selling your home or making sure it’s well-maintained heading into spring, here are a few tips that will help you upgrade its exterior.

First, replace or clean the siding. Take a look around the outside of your home and search for any damaged siding that needs to be replaced. Also, spray off any dirt or mold or consider hiring a professional to power-wash your home.

Next, keep an eye out for any dry rot, especially around door and window frames. Scrape off any peeling materials, sand, and/or paint to make your home more attractive to buyers.

If you have any roof damage, have it repaired before putting your home on the market. If your concrete is in disrepair, that could become a hazard, so consider having any broken or uneven concrete fixed.

“A fresh coat of stain can go a long way.”

If you have a deck or patio, keep that clear of any debris. A great way to give these areas a great new look is to have them power-washed. If they’re made of wood, a fresh coat of stain can also go a long way.

Fences can sometimes fall into disrepair and give your home a shabby look, so make sure you have any missing boards replaced and painted or stained to match the rest of the fencing. Your gates should also open and close smoothly.

If you haven’t kept up your home’s maintenance or you have doubts about its condition, you can always get a home inspection done before listing to give yourself peace of mind knowing it will sell without any issues.

If you’d like more tips on how to upgrade your home’s exterior or you have any other real estate questions I can help you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to assist you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team+Upgrading+your+home%E2%80%99s+exterior.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team+Upgrading+your+home%E2%80%99s+exterior.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I have a few tips to share with you that will help you upgrade the outside of your home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I have a few tips to share with you that will help you upgrade the outside of your home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Expect From Your First Meeting With Us</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/what-to-expect-from-your-first-meeting-with-us.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-19 12:05:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What’s it like to meet with the Salas Team? Whatever your real estate needs, we are here to help. Today, I’d like to go over what you can expect when you start working with us.

If you are looking to purchase a property, your first meeting with us will be a buyer’s consultation. During this consultation, we’ll discuss your wants and needs. We’ll go over where you’d like to live, what kind of property you’re looking for, and other specifics. Next, we’ll explain the entire process of purchasing a home using what we call our “homebuyer roadmap.”If you are looking to sell a home, the process will also begin with us meeting for a consultation. We will visit your property, discuss your intentions for the sale, and talk about price and value. We’ll also point out any areas in your home that might benefit from repairs or updates.

“Understanding your preferences, needs, and intentions will help us best serve you.”

We want to know what your expectations are for us, and vice versa.

If you’re looking to invest in real estate, we will meet to discuss your intentions. We can’t help you unless we know what it is that you want. Understanding your preferences will help us best serve you.

No matter what your real estate needs, the last step of our meeting will be to explain all of our services to you. Because we’re a team, many different people will be assisting you throughout the process. We really want you to feel that we’re on your side.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s it like to meet with us? Allow me to explain what you can expect.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s it like to meet with us? Allow me to explain what you can expect.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6 Tips to Drive Your Home Sale</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/6-tips-to-drive-your-home-sale.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-05 14:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+6+Tips+to+Drive+Your+Home+Sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are six tips I always share with my clients that can help you drive your home sale to success.

1. Price it right. You don’t want to overprice your home, because you won’t attract enough buyers to actually show up and look at the property. Most buyers have search ranges, and if your home is over their range, they won’t even take a look at it. It will also hurt you in the long run because if you price the home too high initially and you have to keep reducing that price while the home sits on the market, buyers will be suspicious of it and wonder what’s wrong with it.

2. Understand buyer preferences. If your house has multi-colored bedrooms with many different types of furniture, that might not be very popular among the buyers of today. You might be better off switching things to a more neutral color. Your agent can certainly help you with this kind of thing.

3. Stage and declutter. Make sure someone walking into your home can envision it as their home. If you have lots of clutter and personal items lying around, that will make doing that hard for them. Don’t forget to declutter your closets too, because buyers always check those to make sure there’s enough room for their stuff.

“Make sure someone walking into your home can envision it as their home.”

4. Repair any pet damage.Oftentimes, dogs and cats can leave scratch marks around doors and door frames, so make sure that kind of thing is repaired. You also want to check for smells. It’s hard to notice your own house’s pet odor, but buyers will definitely notice if a house has a dog or cat smell. That being said, don’t overpower the house with potpourri, because that can give off the wrong impression as well.

5. Enhance the home’s curb appeal.This can be tougher in wintertime, but you want to make sure anyone approaching your house sees a clean driveway and walkway and a sharp exterior. In springtime, it’s a good idea to plant some flowers.

6. Focus on marketing. Roughly 99% of all buyers today look online when searching for a home, which means the first thing they see are photos. You want to make sure those photos pop and impress them enough to want to see your property in person.

If you have any more questions about how to drive your home sale or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+6+Tips+to+Drive+Your+Home+Sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+6+Tips+to+Drive+Your+Home+Sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to give your home the edge it needs once it hits the market to sell quickly and for top dollar, here are six tips you can follow.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to give your home the edge it needs once it hits the market to sell quickly and for top dollar, here are six tips you can follow.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Questions to Ask a Potential Real Estate Agent</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/4-questions-to-ask-a-potential-real-estate-agent.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-06 04:38:14 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+4+Questions+to+Ask+a+Potential+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You should never ask a magician their secrets, but I don’t feel the same way about real estate. Today, I’m going to clue you into a couple “magician’s secrets” of real estate by providing you with insider questions you should ask a potential listing agent when making your decision about who to work with.

1. What is your average sales-to-list price ratio? When you sell your home, you’ll decide on a price for it. Ultimately, you want your home to sell for at least that price, but it could also sell for less. The market average right now is about 92%, but here at the Salas Team, we actually sell with a 96% sales-to-list price ratio. But not every agent is built the same, and some agents will only sell the home for 80% to 85% of the original list price. Ask this question to make sure that your agent meets the industry standard.

2. What is your marketing strategy? For instance, do they stage the homes they’re trying to sell? You want an agent who is experienced and can tell you what a potential buyer will want to see so that you can prepare your home to sell for top dollar.

Do they use professional photography? Never settle for an agent who uses their iPhone or Android to take pictures of your home. A good agent should have someone on staff with professional equipment and and experience.

“Look for key indicators of success, such as how many houses they’ve sold.”

Do they have a strong social media presence and knowledge of online advertisement? In our social media-driven society, it is so important to be up to date on the latest internet technologies. You can access demographic information to predict who is most likely to be looking for a house. They should have a properly segmented database, and use Facebook and Google advertising to their best advantage.

Do they do circle prospecting? Your agent and their team should be calling around the neighborhood to ask if anyone is thinking of buying a house. This is critically important in a market with tight inventory. You want an agent who will proactively market on your behalf.

3. What is your success rate? Look for key indicators of success, such as how many houses they’ve sold. The average agent sells about three homes a year. The Salas Team, however, has repeatedly sold 150 homes a year. An agent who sells many homes has the experience to be able to advise their client in the best way.

4. Are you part-time or full-time?The popularity of real estate shows like those on HGTV has brought a lot of people into the market thinking that it’s a flexible career. But a part-time agent isn’t good enough for you. This is, in many cases, the biggest financial transaction in your lifetime, and you’ll want someone who knows what they’re doing and can devote their full attention to your needs.

Asking these questions is a great way to get a look at how experienced the agent is and whether or not they have the level of expertise you need in order to satisfy your goals.

If you have any questions for us, we’ll be more than happy to give you answer. Feel free to reach out to us by phone or email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+4+Questions+to+Ask+a+Potential+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+4+Questions+to+Ask+a+Potential+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You know that you want a good agent to represent your real estate interests, but how do you find the best one for you?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You know that you want a good agent to represent your real estate interests, but how do you find the best one for you?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7 Tips for a Successful Home Buying Process</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/7-tips-for-a-successful-home-buying-process.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-23 03:47:19 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+7+Tips+for+a+Successful+Home+Buying+Process.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are the seven habits of highly effective homebuyers? If you’re ready to enter the market and start looking for your new home, here are some great tips to get you started:

1. Get pre-qualified. Be ready to buy as soon as you find the right home. Sellers are going to want to see a pre-qualification letter to know that you are truly capable of purchasing the property. You should become pre-qualified before even beginning your search.

2. Define your “must-haves,” your “like-to-haves,” and your “don’t-wants.” At our buyer’s consultation, my team and I will go over these things with you. It’s important to determine what you’re really looking for in a home. Once you do, you can break down those desires into the categories I mentioned earlier.

3. Be realistic. Today’s market is short on inventory. With that being the case, buyers simply won’t be able to lowball sellers.

4. Be open and flexible. As a buyer, you won’t always get everything you want. It’s certainly good to focus on what you want and don’t want from a property during your search, but try not to expect the perfect house. Remember that you can always change things after you move in. Don’t get caught up in trying to find a home that’s already perfect.

“Don’t get caught up in trying to find a home that’s already perfect.”

5. Understand the home buying process. Our team wants to help you understand what you can expect. When you meet with us for a consultation, we will walk you through every step.

6. Be responsible and maintain your credit. I can’t tell you how many times I’ve had issues with buyers paying off some major debt right before closing. It might sound counterintuitive, but paying off a loan or a credit card right before you close can actually sink your credit. Also, hold off any major purchases until after closing.

7. Have fun with the process. My entire team and I truly want you to have the best home buying experience possible. If you let us help, we will make sure the process is as smooth and as enjoyable as it can be.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+7+Tips+for+a+Successful+Home+Buying+Process.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+7+Tips+for+a+Successful+Home+Buying+Process.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If it’s time for you to find your next home, there are seven key things you can do to better prepare yourself for the process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If it’s time for you to find your next home, there are seven key things you can do to better prepare yourself for the process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Easy Steps for Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/3-easy-steps-for-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-10 07:06:48 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+3+Easy+Steps+for+Selling+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’d like to share three easy steps for selling your home.

The first step I recommend is planning. When it comes to selling, a lot of mistakes can come from a lack of preparation. If you take the time to plan things out, you will be more successful.

This goes for selling a home, as well. One thing to consider is when and where you move. If you have children in school, you may want to think about which point during the school year you want to make your move.

Part of the planning process means having your real estate with you for at least 30 to 60 days before you plan to sell. In this current climate, it could take 30 to 45 days to find the right buyer. And even once you’ve found a buyer, it could take an additional 30, 40, or even 60 days to actually close. You really need to plan for this amount of time in order to be successful with your home sale.

“Taking the time to plan things out will greatly benefit your listing.”

The second step has to do with first impressions. When it comes to selling houses, first impressions matter. The first 30 days of the process are especially important. Some of the ways you can make sure your home gives off the right impression to buyers are by neutralizing and decluttering. Also, be sure to have a professional take the photos for your listing.

The third and final step is to make sure you price it right. I know you probably hear this tip over and over again, but it is so critical in today’s market. The strategy of pricing a home high and waiting to negotiate down simply isn’t a good idea. All that does is lead to more haggling.

In order to price your home right, you should take the time to do a comparative market analysis. My team will perform this for you by sitting down to really examine your home and the competitive landscape around it.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+3+Easy+Steps+for+Selling+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+3+Easy+Steps+for+Selling+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you are planning to put your home on the market, I’ve got three easy steps you can take for better selling success.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you are planning to put your home on the market, I’ve got three easy steps you can take for better selling success.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays From All of Us at the Salas Team</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/happy-holidays-from-all-of-us-at-the-salas-team.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-18 07:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+Happy+Holidays+From+All+of+Us+at+the+Salas+Team.mp4</guid>
        <description>

My team and I wanted to take a moment to thank all of you for the love and support you’ve provided us with over this past year. Our success in 2017 wouldn’t have been possible without you. From our family to yours, happy holidays. May the season be merry and bright for you and your loved ones. To hear our full message, watch this short video.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+Happy+Holidays+From+All+of+Us+at+the+Salas+Team.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+Happy+Holidays+From+All+of+Us+at+the+Salas+Team.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My team and I have a very special message today for the holiday season.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My team and I have a very special message today for the holiday season.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Method of Property Valuation Is Best?</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/which-method-of-property-valuation-is-best.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-08 05:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+Which+Method+of+Property+Valuation+Is+Best%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Have you ever wondered how a real estate agent comes up with the property valuation for your home? Are you thinking of putting your home up for sale, or would you like to get it out on the market? Today, we’re going to talk about the four general ways to obtain a property’s value.

1. Look at the assessed value. The assessed value of a home is the value assigned via the county tax records.Typically, this isn’t a great number to use because it could be an assessed value on the land alone, or it could be based on land and improvements, even though the improvements were made many years ago.

2. Online valuation tools. Everyone asks me if the Zillow valuation tool called the Zestimate is accurate, and my answer is no. Online valuation tools average prices that have sold in your area, but oftentimes they’re looking at county records or MLS records. There’s a lot of skewed data in those records. They also don’t look at apples-to-apples comparisons, meaning that if the home next door with less square footage than yours sold for less than your home, they’ll still compare the two homes, which could negatively affect the valuation. Let’s stay away from those Zestimates.

“Online valuation tools average prices that have sold in your area, but oftentimes they’re looking at skewed data from county records or MLS records.”

3. Obtain an appraisal. This is actually a great start, and I often ask my clients to get an appraisal for their homes. The good thing about them is that they do look at the homes in your neighborhood that have recently sold, the layout of the house, and they also do apples-to-apples comparisons. However, an appraiser is only going to look back six months. They don’t look at market conditions or trends.

4. Obtain a comparative market analysis (CMA). This is the best way to get an accurate analysis of your property. Performed by a real estate agent, a CMA will look at what has recently sold in your neighborhood within the last six months to a year depending on the market today, as well as what’s currently available.

Understanding the market trends is important, and if it’s a hot market in which things are selling quickly, then certainly your home is going to be worth more. What’s more, by pricing your home correctly, you’ll certainly sell it quicker and for more money.

If you have any questions about selling real estate in general, or if you’re thinking about buying or selling a property, feel free to give us a call. We’d be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+Which+Method+of+Property+Valuation+Is+Best%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+Which+Method+of+Property+Valuation+Is+Best%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you ever wonder about how property valuations are determined? There are four ways in general to do this.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you ever wonder about how property valuations are determined? There are four ways in general to do this.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is There a “Right” Time to Put Your Home on the Market?</title>
        <link>http://salasteamrealestate.org/is-there-a-right-time-to-put-your-home-on-the-market.html</link>
        
        <author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-21 06:14:51 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+Is+There+a+Right+Time+to+Put+Your+Home+on+the+Market%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There’s a lot of debate in the real estate world about whether it’s better to list a home during the spring and summer months or during the fall and winter months. For sellers, there are pros and cons for each season.

In the spring and summer months, homes look better and have better curb appeal. The days are also longer, so more buyers will be able to look at your home during longer periods of time. Sellers can also be pickier about which offer they choose during the warmer months because there are more buyers out and about.

One of the downsides of selling during the spring and summer months, though, is there are more sellers to compete against. Because there are more sellers, buyers can afford to be pickier as well.

“Houses sell all year round.”

Selling in the fall and winter months means there aren’t as many buyers, but the ones that are active are far more motivated to buy and will typically come with stronger offers. You’ll also face less competition from other sellers.

Snow and other inclement weather can lessen a home’s curb appeal, however. You might also come across thriftier buyers who will try to lowball you because they assume the fact that you’re listing during the fall and/or winter means you’re more eager to sell.

In my experience, if you price your home correctly and you have the right agent in your corner, you can extract the right value for your home at any time in the market.

Remember—houses sell all year round.

If you have any more questions about our market or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to give us a call. We’d be glad to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+Is+There+a+Right+Time+to+Put+Your+Home+on+the+Market%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://salasteamrealestate.org" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Danielle+Salas/The+Salas+Team-+Is+There+a+Right+Time+to+Put+Your+Home+on+the+Market%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Each selling season comes with its own advantages and disadvantages, but if you price your home correctly and have the right agent in your corner, your home should sell no matter when it’s listed.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Each selling season comes with its own advantages and disadvantages, but if you price your home correctly and have the right agent in your corner, your home should sell no matter when it’s listed.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Philadelphia, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Danielle Py-Salas & Guillermo Salas</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Salas Team - your professional Philadelphia Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
