<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacksonville Real Estate Careers and Training Podcast with Shawn O'Neill</title>
    <link>http://expertadvisornetwork.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://expertadvisornetwork.com"/>
    <description>A Podcast about Jacksonville Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Shawn O'Neill</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-06-08 16:22:55 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Shawn O'Neill</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://expertadvisornetwork.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Jacksonville, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Careers@ExpertHomeAdvisors.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Shawn O'Neill</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Shawn O'Neill</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://expertadvisornetwork.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Jacksonville, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Boost your Career with Veteran Real Estate Agent Shawn O'Neill</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>A Podcast about Jacksonville Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Do 87% of All Real Estate Agents Fail?</title>
        <link>http://expertadvisornetwork.com/why-do-87-of-all-real-estate-agents-fail.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Shawn O'Neill</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-17 13:26:36 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Did you know that 87% of all agents in the real estate business fail? Whether this is something you’ve heard in the past or it’s new information to you, you’re probably wondering how you can avoid becoming part of that statistic. Well, allow me to walk you through a few key steps to success. These steps will ensure that you fall within the 13% of agents that win.

All of the steps we go over today will contribute to helping you develop a business plan. You must have a clear idea of what you do in your business, when you do it, and, perhaps most importantly, why you do it. This will be your first step in the path to success. You must ask yourself, “What is my why?” There’s got to be a reason you got into the business in the first place, and it’s up to you to reflect on what that reason is. You didn’t spend your time and money getting a real estate license for nothing.

Once you’ve established your “why,” the next step is to figure out your cost to live. In other words, how much do you need to make to get by? This refers to your necessities, not your wants. I recommend first calculating your total cost to live per month, and then multiplying that figure by 12 to get an idea of what you need to make in a year.

Chances are, though, that you want to make more than just enough to get by. Many people get into real estate because they’re looking to replace their previous income. Whatever your past job might have been, you probably want to either match or exceed what you earned up until now. Calculating this supplementary money, which you can spend on “wants” instead of “needs,” is the third step. Setting a target for yourself will hold you accountable to your goals.

These first few steps we’ve covered are all part of finding your motivation for being in this business. So now I’d like to move on to the next major question you must ask yourself, which is: “What area do I want to work in?” Think of the location you choose as a sandbox. Whether your sandbox is one subdivision or an entire 30-mile radius, it’s time to delve deeper into understanding how that area’s market typically functions. The average price point and the average commission within your sandbox are two critical figures you’ll need to be aware of.

These statistics are important because you’ve got to multiply the commission by the average price to calculate the commission check—the thing you’re working for. You will then divide this total by the target figure you came up with earlier to determine how many homes you’ll need to sell per month to meet your goal. Most people will find that it will take one, two, or three sales per month to hit their target. That said, it never hurts to be bold and shoot higher. But you’ve got to have a grasp on the minimum activity you need to meet your goals before you can think about surpassing that.

“Success is a long journey of failures—the key is to move on quickly and enthusiastically from your failures, instead of letting them hold you back.”

With everything we’ve discussed so far in mind, it’s time to ask yourself about your standards and time commitments. It’s very hard to make a full-time income by doing part-time work. Not acknowledging this discrepancy is one of the biggest reasons agents fail. If you do only plan to work part-time as an agent, you’ve still got to put in a full-time level of effort. It’s all about making a commitment. If for you that means being a part-time agent with a  full-time commitment three days a week, that’s fine. The important thing is that you hold yourself to a high standard and commit to your goals.

What to do with the time you’ve committed to your goals, however, is where many agents get stuck. The balance of time and money is something all agents will need to grapple with in their career. You need to treat yourself like a business, and businesses have expenses. As an agent, you’ve got many different ways you can approach this balance. One way to address this is by joining a brokerage. At my brokerage, for example, we like to help agents use their time, not their money, to reach their goals.

But whether it’s with the help of a brokerage or of your own volition, you’ve got to understand what your ideal day looks like. And an ideal part of any agent’s day is working toward face-to-face contact with clients—which sounds simple enough, but consider this: Where will those clients come from? This is just one more question to reflect on as you build your plan for success. At the end of the day, asking questions like this is what will drive you forward.

You’ll need to consistently ask yourself the same things we’ve discussed here. Ask yourself about your “why,” your sandbox, your target income, and your plan for meeting that target. The answers you come up with will go into building your business plan. Success is a long journey of failures—the key is to move on quickly and enthusiastically from your failures, instead of letting them hold you back.

A lot of agents stay stuck in their failures because they never alter their strategy. While your goals should stay consistent, you should be re-examining your strategy all the time. Of course, if you find someone to partner with or guide you on your journey, all of this will become even simpler.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://expertadvisornetwork.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Unfortunately, most agents never find success in real estate. If you’ve the drive to be among the few who prevail, though, I’ve got some important tips to share with you today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Shawn O'Neill</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Unfortunately, most agents never find success in real estate. If you’ve the drive to be among the few who prevail, though, I’ve got some important tips to share with you today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Jacksonville, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Shawn O'Neill</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Shawn O'Neill</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">A Podcast about Jacksonville Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
