<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title> Real Estate Podcast with Jim Casbarro</title>
    <link>http://blog.gafinesthomes.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://blog.gafinesthomes.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from GAFinestHomes Group, LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Jim Casbarro</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-09-19 10:57:35 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Jim Casbarro</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.gafinesthomes.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Jim@GAFinestHomes.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Jim Casbarro</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Jim Casbarro</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://blog.gafinesthomes.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from GAFinestHomes Group, LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Overview of the 2 Kinds of Real Estate Investing</title>
        <link>http://blog.gafinesthomes.com/an-overview-of-the-2-kinds-of-real-estate-investing.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Jim Casbarro</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-17 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/Cobb+County+Real+Estate+-+An+Overview+of+the+2+Kinds+of+Real+Estate+Investing.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are two kinds of real estate investing, each of which has its own merits.Today I&rsquo;ll give you the basics of each so that you can better understand how to become an investor yourself.

 

In an effort to help you continue to love where you live, today we’ll be diving into what it takes to become a real estate investor.

There are two genres of investing you can pursue: active investing and passive investing.

As you might assume, active investing involves taking a hands-on approach. Active investors are categorized as either wholesalers or rehabbers (those who fix and flip homes), and they’re out working part- or full-time, finding deals, meeting with sellers, locking in contracts, and possibly doing some physical work (as with rehabbers).

Passive investors, on the other hand, use real estate as a vehicle to grow their portfolio and generate passive income. This might include buying a multifamily property and hiring a property manager to run it, or possibly buying residential homes and renting them out.

If you’re thinking about becoming an investor, the first question I always ask is, “How much time and capital do you have access to?”

“Investing itself is not inherently risky—it’s the investor who is risky.”

The ‘capital’ part shouldn’t scare you—if you follow me on social media, you’ve probably seen ads for becoming an investor with zero money down, and that’s actually possible. I started learning about investing way before I ever became a Realtor, so if you’re curious about starting the process, I’d love to discuss in greater detail the various routes you can take.

We’ve actually been working with a very successful passive investor who identified a niche in our market: he has invested in tiny, modular homes and mobile home parks, and his ROI has been killer.

If you’re someone who doesn’t want to do any hands-on investing, take a look at this video of my interview with a passive investor to learn about some of the real estate benefits of working with our group.

For those more interested in active investing, I highly recommend that you start with educating yourself about real estate. Investing itself is not inherently risky—it’s the investor who is risky. Ignorance is the most expensive currency, so don’t trade in it. You have to know what you’re doing, and we can help guide you into some of the good training and mentoring programs available. Lone wolves don’t make it very long in real estate investing.

No matter which kind of investing you’re most interested in, reach out to us. We can set up a phone consultation and figure out where you are now and what can be done to help you reach your goals of becoming an investor.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/Cobb+County+Real+Estate+-+An+Overview+of+the+2+Kinds+of+Real+Estate+Investing.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.gafinesthomes.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/Cobb+County+Real+Estate+-+An+Overview+of+the+2+Kinds+of+Real+Estate+Investing.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are two kinds of real estate investing, each of which has its own merits. Today I’ll give you the basics of each so that you can better understand how to become an investor yourself.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jim Casbarro</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are two kinds of real estate investing, each of which has its own merits. Today I’ll give you the basics of each so that you can better understand how to become an investor yourself.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Foreclosure Auctions</title>
        <link>http://blog.gafinesthomes.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-foreclosure-auctions.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jim Casbarro</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-18 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Foreclosure+Auctions.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do foreclosure auctions work? The process is actually interesting, and it presents an opportunity for you to help out those in need in your community.

 

Today I’d like to share some of my real estate knowledge with you regarding how foreclosures—specifically, foreclosure auctions—work in your local community.

To begin, the state of Georgia is a non-judicial foreclosure state, meaning that when a home is in the foreclosure process or if a seller is delinquent on their payments, the state and the bank that hold the loan on the property don’t have to go to court to complete the foreclosure process. You simply need to send a notice and market the property in a newspaper or other public article for up to four weeks. Once you do, if the homeowner hasn’t worked it out with the bank by that period, the bank can actually go through with the process.

Assuming the homeowner didn’t remedy any of their delinquent payments, there are steps that you need to follow.

If you have the funds to do so, you can go to the courthouse steps where the property was “cried”—meaning the details of the property were read, the legal description was given, and they put the house up for auction—and bid on it. However, sometimes properties don’t get cried at the country courthouse. Sometimes the bank will buy back the delinquent loan instead of opening the bidding up to the public.

“Sometimes the bank will buy back the delinquent loan instead of opening the bidding up to the public.”

It’s actually a pretty interesting process to see; I’d recommend taking a look in your area and seeing one in person, if possible. In Georgia, on the first Tuesday of every month, the county foreclosures are auctioned off at the county courthouses. If you would like to see a list of counties that are heavy with foreclosure traffic, click here. Fulton County is notably high-traffic in this regard; you’ll see all sorts of investors, hedge fund companies, and other buyers making cash offers on the foreclosure at the county courthouse steps.

We bring you this information today to help you build an area you love to live in. Those who are going through a foreclosure are in a tight spot, so if you notice a property in your area in danger of foreclosing, we have a network of investors who offer a wide array of solutions that genuinely help those struggling in the community.

If you know of properties like those, are interested in real estate investing, or have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. Otherwise, stay tuned for our next episode, in which we delve more into becoming a real estate investor. Hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Foreclosure+Auctions.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.gafinesthomes.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Foreclosure+Auctions.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How do foreclosure auctions work? The process is actually interesting, and it presents an opportunity for you to help out those in need in your community.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jim Casbarro</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How do foreclosure auctions work? The process is actually interesting, and it presents an opportunity for you to help out those in need in your community.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do Short Sales and Foreclosures Work?</title>
        <link>http://blog.gafinesthomes.com/how-do-short-sales-and-foreclosures-work.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Jim Casbarro</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-05 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/How+Do+Short+Sales+and+Foreclosures+Work%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Short sales and foreclosures might sound like good deals for home buyers, but they can be nightmares for homeowners. Here&rsquo;s how the process actually works.

 

Today I’m talking about the difference between a short sale and a foreclosure. Most people believe that these types of properties are good deals and pretty straightforward, but we’re going to debunk that myth.

First, let’s look at the differences between a short sale and a foreclosure. A short sale typically happens when a homeowner owes more on a home than it’s worth and they have a window of time to sell it before the bank seizes the property. During the short sale process, the homeowner can remedy their debt and get caught up to make sure they don’t go into the foreclosure process.

For a valid short sale, there will need to be a significant distress in your life. For example, a spouse passing away, a job loss, or a medical issue. You have to prove that something caused you to be unable to make your payments. If you can prove that you have a hardship and that you’re in distress, you should be able to initiate the short sale process. The bank will then “short” the loan and take a loss on it to get it off the books. Then the seller can initiate the process of selling their home. It’s a tough spot for a seller to be in, but it does open up good opportunities for home buyers who are looking for a deal.

If you know someone who is going through a short sale, we can help them out.

“I’d be happy to refer you to a short sale expert if you need one.”

A short sale is not an easy process. You have to jump through the hoops that the bank will provide. Negotiations and paperwork can be frustrating. However, the short sale will have much less of an impact on your credit than a foreclosure.

Foreclosures are much tougher for homeowners. They will ruin your credit. With a foreclosure, the seller is no longer involved. The bank is the party that initiates this sale. As soon as house payments stop, the home becomes a liability for them, and they’ll take a bit of a loss to dump that property. Legal fees can get pricey during this process for the bank.

I really hope this helped shed some light on the differences between a short sale and a foreclosure. If you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/How+Do+Short+Sales+and+Foreclosures+Work%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.gafinesthomes.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/How+Do+Short+Sales+and+Foreclosures+Work%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Short sales and foreclosures might sound like good deals for home buyers, but they can be nightmares for homeowners. Here’s how the process actually works.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jim Casbarro</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Short sales and foreclosures might sound like good deals for home buyers, but they can be nightmares for homeowners. Here’s how the process actually works.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Pay Your Rent/Mortgage and Get Cash Back</title>
        <link>http://blog.gafinesthomes.com/how-to-pay-your-rentmortgage-and-get-cash-back.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Jim Casbarro</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-07 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/How+to+Earn+Money+From+Paying+Your+Bills+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today let&rsquo;s talk about two great resources that can help you earn rewards for paying your bills.

 

If you’re like most people who pay their mortgage or rent by using a direct deposit, Automated Clearing House (ACH), or writing a check, this tactic could be a great way to help build your credit, pay your major bills like rent and mortgages, all while earning cash back in the process. Let’s dive into how this works!

Firstly, there is a company called Plastiq. This company allows people to use a credit card to pay major bills like a mortgage company, individual, insurance company, etc. Now, they do charge a fee to process your credit card and make the payments. Plastiq charges your credit card 2.5% for every transaction. Now that may make using Plastiq not so appealing to people without knowing the second half of our tactic - using a cash back credit that at least covers the 2.5% fee. Along comes (drumroll please) the Alliant 3% Cash Back Credit Card from VISA.

The Alliant 3% Cash Back Credit Card

To apply for the Alliant VISA card to earn the 3% cash back, there are a few steps to their application process. Firstly, you’ll notice that Alliant is a credit union. If you’re unfamiliar with credit unions that’s ok - just note that they are unlike most bigger banks like Wells Fargo, Bank of America, Chase, etc., in that they are a cooperative of members who pool their money together. Essentially, credit unions are not-for-profit organizations that exist to serve their members. To apply for the Alliant credit card, you have to first be a member of their Alliant Credit Union. If you are like me located here in GA, or another state other than IL (Alliant being based out of Chicago, IL), there is a little step to complete to become an Alliant member. Take a look at their website to see which one you want to pursue, but I personally did the option of paying $10 to donate to the Orphan Foundation of America to start the membership process.

Once you are a member of the Alliant Credit Union, you are now able to complete the credit card application process. I did mine online, and it was straightforward just like most credit card applications. Once completed, you’ll get contacted afterward and voila, you now have a 3% cash back credit card to cover any Plastiq bills you want to pay and make a small 0.5% in cash back.

Going back to Plastiq, it is an awesome service. It’s also important to note that this tactic of using a credit card to pay companies or individuals applies to many other transactions that are a part of our daily lives. Check out Plastiq’s website for further information about all the services, and here is an example of just a handful of other ways to utilize this tactic to pay:



“Using these two resources together is a great way to maximize your earnings.”

A great way to earn even more cash back, or potentially cut back on the cost of using Plastiq’s service could be:


  +.75% Business Tax Deduction


The Plastiq fee can be classified as a business expense on tax returns.


  +2% Early Pay Discount


You can now pay earlier and earn better payment terms.


  4.75% Potential Value Back


Gain additional value with extra cash on hand and Plastiq referrals.

So if you’re a business owner and using Plastiq to run business expenses through your company with this tactic then you can take advantage of the 2.5% fee Plastiq charges as a business write-off (Thanks Uncle Sam!).

And the last item on their website to alleviate their fees are using the referral codes once you sign up and create your own Plastiq account. Please feel free to use my code to get started, which obviously benefits me, but also adds 500 points to your account on signup. The points equate to how many dollars you can waive the 2.5% fee on (with their website showing up to a total 4.75% value back).

USE REFERRAL CODE: 888120

Now that you are armed with a tactic to build up your credit, pay people and vendors without needing cash in your account, and all of which goes a long way to just make you that much more financially savvy! ;)

I hope you found value in this article, and stay tuned for many more nuggets of financial, real estate, and business gold that I’ll be sharing along your journey. 

Cheers to loving where you live!

Joe Riggs

Mortgage Banker

678.226.7846  Office

678.226.7867  Fax

770.335.7705  Cell

jriggs@brandmortgage.com

jriggs.brandmortgage.com

50 Chastain Center Blvd | Kennesaw, GA  30144

NMLS# 75615 | 966672
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/How+to+Earn+Money+From+Paying+Your+Bills+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://blog.gafinesthomes.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Jim+Casbarro/Videos/How+to+Earn+Money+From+Paying+Your+Bills+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today let’s talk about two great resources that can help you earn rewards for paying your bills.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jim Casbarro</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today let’s talk about two great resources that can help you earn rewards for paying your bills.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Jim Casbarro</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Jim Casbarro</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from GAFinestHomes Group, LLC - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
