<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Orlando Real Estate Video Blog with Deepak Gupta</title>
    <link>http://askdeegupta.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://askdeegupta.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dee Team - your professional Orlando Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Deepak Gupta</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-05-17 14:43:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Deepak Gupta</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>dgupta@dgupta.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Deepak Gupta</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Orlando Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dee Team - your professional Orlando Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Be an Effective Homeowner</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/how-to-be-an-effective-homeowner.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-03 08:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/Videos/2018/The+Dee+Team-+Homeowner%252C+Now+What%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

So you’ve recently become a homeowner. Congratulations! Excitement aside, you’re probably starting to wonder, “Now what?”

Owning a home is a great thing. You get to say goodbye to the struggles of rental life. As a homeowner, you’ve embarked on a new chapter in life that comes with as many responsibilities as it does benefits.

Therefore, today I’d like to recommend seven things all new homeowners should do. For a summarized list please click here.

1. Safeguard your investment and get a home warranty. You can’t control when issues may arise. Whether the dishwasher stops working or something worse goes wrong, you will want to be prepared. A home warranty will help give you peace of mind in case the unexpected happens. Make sure you also set aside savings for necessary repairs. Spending a little on a home warranty policy can save you a lot down the line.



2. Get into an inspection habit. Over time, new issues may arise and old issues may become exacerbated. It’s important to keep in-tune with your property’s condition, so I highly recommend getting an inspection done once every year or so. This will hopefully help you to uncover problems before they become serious.



3. Take care of expensive appliances. Don’t defer maintenance on major home appliances. Make sure to regularly replace your air filter, for example. Consistent maintenance will help to extend the lifespan of your appliances.

 

“Homeownership comes with as many responsibilities as it does benefits.”

4. Get to know your appliances. When you move into your home, familiarize yourself with its features and appliances so that you will know how to properly care for them.

 

5.Take advantage of tax benefits. With homeownership comes a number of tax benefits, like deductions. But there are also other credits that may be available to you. So speak to your CPA or reach out to us about your options.

 

6. Keep your records. I highly recommend you keep a folder with all documents related to home improvement or repair projects. This way when you’re ready to move, you’ll be able to verify everything you’ve done to the home.

 

7. Beef up your insurance. Don’t just get a basic policy. Make sure that you are truly well protected. The advantage this can bring you will be well worth the cost of the additional coverage.



If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/Videos/2018/The+Dee+Team-+Homeowner%252C+Now+What%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/Videos/2018/The+Dee+Team-+Homeowner%252C+Now+What%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The journey into homeownership is full of rewards, but it’s also paved with a lot of responsibilities. To fully enjoy the benefits of homeownership, you must be committed to taking care of your property. Today I’d like to offer seven tips all new homeowners should keep in mind as they enter into this new chapter in life. To learn more, watch this short video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The journey into homeownership is full of rewards, but it’s also paved with a lot of responsibilities. To fully enjoy the benefits of homeownership, you must be committed to taking care of your property. Today I’d like to offer seven tips all new homeowners should keep in mind as they enter into this new chapter in life. To learn more, watch this short video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Has Our Central Florida Market Changed Since Last Year?</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/how-has-our-central-florida-market-changed-since-last-year.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-23 16:03:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The%2520Dee%2520Team-%2520How%2520Has%2520Our%2520Central%2520Florida%2520Market%2520Changed%2520Since%2520Last%2520Year%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The numbers for our latest year-over-year market update are hot-off-the-press, so let’s take a look at how things have changed since the first quarter of 2017.

First of all, the average median price for Central Florida has risen by over 5.5% from $218,000 in 2017 to $230,000 now. Also, .04% of that growth occurred in just the period between February and March of this year. As you can see, values are getting better by the month.

A major reason for this growth is our current lack of inventory. Our market has far more buyers than available inventory at the moment.

Moving on, overall sales have also gone up. Since Q1 of 2017, they’ve risen by 38.2%. Current high demand means properties just aren’t sitting on the market for very long. 3,508 homes sold this March alone, versus the 3,393 homes that sold in March of 2017.

“There has never been a better time to buy or sell in our Central Florida market.”

Given the 5,724 pendings on our market right now from March alone, we can expect the coming months to also see a high number of sales. There has never been a better time to buy or sell in our Central Florida market.

We only had about 7,710 homes available for purchase as of March. This is about 700 fewer homes than we had last year. With so little inventory and so many buyers in today’s market, it’s a great time to list.

But today’s market also has a lot to offer buyers. Interest rates are still low, with the current average sitting at just 4.29%. Before the market crash, we used to believe 6% was a great rate. Well, even though rates are climbing from the 3% range we saw a few months ago, rates are still at historic lows.

It’s no wonder why so many people who have been on the fence are starting to make to enter the market.

To review the full details of this market update, Click the icon below.



 

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or would like to know how my team and I can help you buy or sell in today’s market, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The%2520Dee%2520Team-%2520How%2520Has%2520Our%2520Central%2520Florida%2520Market%2520Changed%2520Since%2520Last%2520Year%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The%2520Dee%2520Team-%2520How%2520Has%2520Our%2520Central%2520Florida%2520Market%2520Changed%2520Since%2520Last%2520Year%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A lot has changed in our Central Florida real estate market since the first quarter of last year. Now that 2018’s first quarter has come and gone, it’s time for a year-over-year market update.  First of all, inventory has continued to drop. This has led to a high level of buyer demand and an increased number of sales. To learn more, watch this short video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A lot has changed in our Central Florida real estate market since the first quarter of last year. Now that 2018’s first quarter has come and gone, it’s time for a year-over-year market update.  First of all, inventory has continued to drop. This has led to a high level of buyer demand and an increased number of sales. To learn more, watch this short video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Buyers and Sellers Can Win a Multiple Offer Situation</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/how-buyers-and-sellers-can-win-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-29 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I have tips for both buyers and sellers on how to get the best deal possible out of a multiple offer situation.

&nbsp;

The end of the first quarter is almost here, so today’s topic is a scenario that many buyers and sellers are facing in our current market: a multiple offer situation. I have some tips and advice for both sides of the transaction so no matter which side you’re on, you can get the best deal possible.

If you’re a buyer, here are five tips you can follow that will help you beat out other offers and close on your dream home:

1. Offer more money. It’s that simple—money talks. If you’re pre-approved for $250,000, I suggest looking at homes in the $200,000 to $245,000 range so you have the capacity to raise your offer. At the end of the day, nothing works better than gree.

2. Write a letter to the seller. Money talks, but it’s not always about the money. Buying and selling a home can be an emotional process, and sellers are often emotionally attached to their homes, so they want to make sure whoever buys it will be good to it. Writing them a letter that compliments them, gives a little bit of your background, and shares what you like about the property and what you plan to do with it can help you tremendously.

3. Keep your financing clean. By “clean,” I mean keep your offer simple. For example, if you don’t need closing costs, don’t ask for it. If you can offer cash, of course, there’s nothing better than that. With the way our market’s going, one house listed in a good neighborhood can get 15 offers in a single day.

4. Buy as-is property. This means buying the property in its current condition as you saw it. As-is properties are subject to inspection, so you have seven to 10 days to do that inspection. If you don’t like anything about the home, you can always go back to the negotiating table. As I always tell my clients, get your foot in the door. Be the person who gets their offer accepted on an as-is property so the seller takes that property off the market. That way, if the next seller wants to offer more money for it, that won’t matter unless you decide to walk away from the deal.

5. Have your agent call the seller’s agent. This will fill you in on more details about the home and its seller, including why they’re selling. On our team, we call the seller’s agent once when we submit an offer and once while the offer is under consideration just to see how we can help our client. More often than not, this helps us win the home for them.

To see more information, please click on the icons below to read more!

Buyers click here!



Sellers click here!



“Our market is red-hot, so take advantage of these tips and get the best deal possible for yourself.”

What about sellers? First of all, if you are a seller, congratulations. There are a lot of buyers in our market and not a lot of inventory, so you’re in a unique situation.

My first tip for you is to just make sure you’re being a smart seller. Just because everything else is selling doesn’t mean your home will if it isn’t priced right. That’s why the most important thing you can do to create a multiple offer situation for your home is to price it right. If your property is worth $250,000, I’d suggest putting it on the market at $245,000. Listing it for less than it’s worth will attract more offers and you’ll end up selling the home for more than what it’s worth. You also want to price your home in a way that prevents any appraisal issues.

If you price your property too high just because the market is so good, buyers may not even want to see it because they know the might have to compete against other buyers and pay even more money for it. This is why it’s also important to listen to your Realtor when it comes to pricing your home. Look at your reasons for selling your home and take advantage of the market, but don’t be over-advantageous and miss the boat.

Once you get multiple offers, cash offers are great for a quick sale, but not all offers are created equally. You might get a cash offer that’s $5,000 or $10,000 less than what you expected and then get another offer that has a financing contingency and might take 30 to 45 days to close. If you want a quicker closing, you’re better off taking the cash offer. Otherwise, as long as the financed buyer is completely pre-qualified, you might be better off picking their offer. Again, make a decision based on your needs.

Lastly, look at each offer carefully. Have your agent call the buyer’s agent. Better yet, have them call the mortgage company that pre-approved the buyer so you can verify things like their credit, their bank statement, and their proof of funds. There is nothing wrong with asking for proof of funds because all you’re doing is making sure you have a closing at the end of the day.

Whenever we represent a seller, we make sure all of these factors are checked and verified. We don’t just jump at the first buyer who comes along with a great offer. We understand that moving is a nightmare, so we want an offer that will close. If a deal falls apart for whatever reason, it’s not only disappointing, but it’s also emotionally tiring.

If you have any more questions about how to handle a multiple offer situation whether you’re a buyer or seller, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I have tips for both buyers and sellers on how to get the best deal possible out of a multiple offer situation.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I have tips for both buyers and sellers on how to get the best deal possible out of a multiple offer situation.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Now Is the Time to Buy in Our Market</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/why-now-is-the-time-to-buy-in-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-08 13:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+Is+now+the+time+to+purchase+in+our+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a few very important reasons that make now the time to buy in our market.

&nbsp;

If you’re thinking of buying a home in our market, now might be the time to take action, and there are a few reasons why.

First, there are two main real estate myths that keep people from buying homes in our market in the first place that I want to dispel.

The first is that you need to put down at least 20% for your down payment. Not only is this not true, but there are loan programs out there that require far less than 20%. FHA loans, for instance, only require as little as 3.5% down. Some conventional loans only require 3% down. USDA loans don’t require any money down at all. Some lenders will also loan you money for your closing costs if you’re a first-time homebuyer.

The second myth is that you need a FICO score of at least 750 to qualify for a loan. On the contrary, over half (53.5%) of all loans are given with credit scores between 600 and 750.

To learn more, click here.



If you’re planning on buying a home but you want to wait, you might be in for a surprise. Right now, interest rates are very low and hovering between the high 3% and low 4% range. By the end of this year, however, they’re projected to climb closer to 5%.

What does this mean in terms of dollars and cents? If you’re looking to buy a home for $250,000 and you lock in a loan with a rate of 3.9% right now, your principal and interest payment for that home would only be $1,179 per month. If you waited until the end of the year to purchase that same home, our central Florida market’s 10% rate of appreciation will have increased its price to $261,750. Furthermore, if you have to lock in a loan rate of 4.5% or 4.6% instead of 3.9%, your principal and interest payment would increase to $1,341 per month. That’s a difference of $162 each month. There’s a lot you could probably do with an extra $162 in monthly savings.

“You can’t lock in a low mortgage rate if you don’t have a property.”

As you can see, you don’t have to wait to buy a home if you’re ready now. The fact is, you can’t lock in a low mortgage rate if you don’t have a property.

The cost of renting is another factor to consider. Historically, the percentage of income needed to afford the median cost of rent has been 25.8%. Now, that percentage has increased to 29.2%. The percentage of income needed to afford a median home, on the other hand, has dropped from its historical average of 21% to just 15.8% right now. The reason for this decrease is interest rates are so low.

To learn more, click here.



You owe it to yourself to consider making the leap from renting to homeownership. One way or another, you’re paying someone’s mortgage.

It’s a great market for homebuyers out there, so if you have any questions about what it would take for you to buy a home or you need an agent to help you become a homeowner, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+Is+now+the+time+to+purchase+in+our+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+Is+now+the+time+to+purchase+in+our+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are a few very important reasons that make now the time to buy in our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are a few very important reasons that make now the time to buy in our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Will Rising Rates Impact Our Market?</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/how-will-rising-rates-impact-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-13 16:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+2018+Mortgage+Rates.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is the outlook on mortgage interest rates for 2018?  

If you are a buyer in today’s market, interest rates really matter. Any rise in rates will affect affordability. 

In 2017, the interest rates started around 3.5%. By December of that year, rates were between 4% and 4.1%. 

Now as we enter the first quarter of 2018, rates are still hovering around 4.1%. It’s likely that rates will stay static for another month or so, after which they may rise to 4.4% or 4.5%. Then, rates are expected to continue rising throughout the year. We won’t see a huge jump, but they will certainly rise. 

To learn more click here,



In fact, rates may be at 4.9% by the end of this year. That would mean a significant change in affordability. According to CoreLogic, the value of our Central Florida homes has already increased by 10% recently. In the US as a whole, market values have increased by approximately 7%. 

Due to the speed at which homes are appreciating, homes will become more and more expensive as the year progresses. If you want to buy a house in 2018, I recommend doing so sooner rather than later. For the remainder of the year, we’re expecting a healthy 3.5% increase in home value. 

“If you are ready, willing, and able, now is the time for you to buy.”

When you buy right now, you can take advantage of more affordable prices while also locking in a lower interest rate. If you are ready, willing, and able, now is the time for you to buy.

One more thing I’d like to point out is that the Freddie Mac guidelines have now changed. The rates for a conforming loan have increased from $400,000 to $453,100. 

VA loan financing has also changed its limit to $453,100. If you plan to buy a home for more than this amount, you can still get a VA loan. However, you must be able to pay at least 25% of the difference. Also, the FHA limit is up to $294,015. 

Due to these changes to Freddie Mac guidelines, a lot of lenders are coming up with their own conforming and non-conforming loan limits. Many are even allowing for 3% down on conventional loans with a PMI that is either reduced or is included in the loan itself. 

If you’re looking to take advantage of our market right now, I suggest you call on my team and I. We are among the top 1% of Central Florida when it comes to buying or selling a home.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+2018+Mortgage+Rates.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+2018+Mortgage+Rates.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s happening to mortgage interest rates in today’s market? Let’s go over a few recent changes.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s happening to mortgage interest rates in today’s market? Let’s go over a few recent changes.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Market Review of 2017 and a Forecast for the New Year</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/a-market-review-of-2017-and-a-forecast-for-the-new-year.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-29 07:00:44 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+Jan+2+2017+Overview+-+Charts+Added%2521.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How was the 2017 market and what can we expect for the new year that’s ahead? Let’s take a look at the latest numbers.

First of all, the median price for homes increased by 10% in 2017. So for the Central Florida/Orlando Area, the median price was $220,000.

The annual median price for single-family homes also increased, going up by 8.2%. When it comes to condos, the median price increased in 2017 by 17.7%, at $111,000. Duplexes, townhomes, and villas also increased by 10.8%.

Overall, we saw very healthy gains from 2016 to 2017.

Another area of growth we saw was in average sales price, which increased 3.8%. The average sales price of single-family homes increased by 2.1%, with 37,198 homes sold in 2017. Year over year, the number of homes sold increased by 10.7% in 2017.

Also in 2017, normal sales for the overall market were up by 11.9%. And as another piece of good news, foreclosures went down by 49%. This means that the market has recovered and is on its way up.

In total, 44,343 homes were sold in 2017, compared to the 43,062 that sold in 2016. This is an overall increase of 3%.

Sales increased by 7.2% in Lake County, 2.8% in Orange County, 3.8% in Seminole County, and by 7.9% in Osceola County.

“Right now is a great time for buyers and sellers alike.”

The market is doing really well, so if you’ve given any thought to selling your property this year I definitely recommend you do so. Builders aren’t able to match the demand and inventory is still low. On top of that, the average interest rate is 4.125%. Compared to what we saw a couple of years ago, this is very low.

You can find the full market report here.



In other words, this is a great time to buy or sell. We would love to help you with your transaction.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+Jan+2+2017+Overview+-+Charts+Added%2521.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+Jan+2+2017+Overview+-+Charts+Added%2521.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Let’s take a look back at what we saw from our market in 2017 and, also, glance forward into what we can expect from the new year.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Let’s take a look back at what we saw from our market in 2017 and, also, glance forward into what we can expect from the new year.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Will the New Tax Changes Affect You?</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/how-will-the-new-tax-changes-affect-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-10 06:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+How+Will+the+New+Tax+Changes+Affect+You%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re looking to buy or sell a home in 2018, how will the new tax rules affect our real estate market? There are three main changes you need to be mindful of.

First, a quick disclaimer: The views reflected on this blog are an interpretation of what we understand. We are not an accounting firm, so if you’d like to explore this topic more in-depth, I suggest you contact your accountant. We are not saying these changes are good or bad news—we’re only explaining how they will affect buyers and sellers in 2018.

“We are not saying these changes are good or bad news.”

The first change you need to be aware of is the requirements of the sale of your principal property. The second is the reduction of the limit on mortgage interest. The third is the elimination of state and local taxes.

Regarding the requirements of the sale of your principal property, the original proposal was that if the property was a homestead property, you would have to live in it for five out of the last eight years in order to avoid paying any capital gains taxes when selling it. That’s been changed so you only have to stay in the home for two out of the previous five years to sell the property without having to pay any capital gains taxes.

Click here to learn more.



 

This change doesn’t impact you very much if you’re looking to sell your home. If you’re living in the property as part of a married couple, then you have up to $500,000 in gains that you don’t have to pay taxes on. If you’re single, you have up to $250,000 in gains that you don’t have to pay taxes on.

Regarding the reduction of the limit on mortgage interest, previously you could buy a home for up to $1 million and get the mortgage deduction when doing your taxes. They were proposing reducing that sum from $1 million to $500,000, but they agreed that you could reduce the itemized deduction on your mortgage for up to $750,000.

This change will only affect people who are buying homes in a higher price range—primarily those buying over the $750,000 range. However, if you’re buying a home for $1 million and you’re putting down 20% or more, it may not affect you that much. If you’re buying a home that’s more expensive than that, there will probably be tax implications.

Lastly, regarding the deduction of local and state taxes in relation to your property, the original law was to take that away completely so you weren’t allowed to claim that on your taxes. The new change allows you to do so for up to $10,000. Basically, if your taxes are more than that, it will have an effect on you whether you’re buying or selling.

If you have any other questions about these new tax rules and how they affect the real estate market, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+How+Will+the+New+Tax+Changes+Affect+You%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+How+Will+the+New+Tax+Changes+Affect+You%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>With Congress recently approving the new tax code, there are three changes that will affect our real estate market and possibly your ability to buy or sell in 2018.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>With Congress recently approving the new tax code, there are three changes that will affect our real estate market and possibly your ability to buy or sell in 2018.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Wish You a Happy New Year</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/we-wish-you-a-happy-new-year.html</link>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-18 09:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+We+Wish+You+a+Happy+New+Year.mp4</guid>
        <description>

“We hope your 2017 was a good one.”

As we end 2017 and move toward the new year, we wanted to take a moment to wish you and your family a very happy and prosperous 2018. We hope this next year is a very blessed one for and your family. If there is anything we can do for you, please let us know because we’re always here to provide a helping hand.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+We+Wish+You+a+Happy+New+Year.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+We+Wish+You+a+Happy+New+Year.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As we wind down at the end of 2017, we wanted to be sure to wish you the best in the new year.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As we wind down at the end of 2017, we wanted to be sure to wish you the best in the new year.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Buying Your First Home? These Programs Can Help</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/buying-your-first-home-these-programs-can-help.html</link>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-04 08:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+Buying+Your+First+Home%253F+These+Programs+Can+Help.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’m joined by special guest Rhett Delaney from Movement Mortgage to help me explain how first-time homebuyer programs can help you save.

But, who qualifies as a first-time homebuyer? According to Rhett, a first-time homebuyer is anyone who hasn’t owned a home in the last three years. There are a lot of different programs out there to fit people who fall under this qualification.

These programs include grants, non-interest bearing loans, and also something called Florida’s Hardest Hit Program, which can provide up to $15,000 toward closing costs for first-time homebuyers.

This money comes in the form of a forgivable grant. So if you live in the house for at least five years, you’re not required to pay back the $15,000. Though to qualify for Florida’s Hardest Hit, there are some stipulations.

“Don’t hesitate to take advantage of this program.”

First of all, your credit score must be 640 or above. Also, depending on your county and whether you’re using a conventional or FHA loan, there will be an income requirement ranging from $60,000 to $80,000.

It’s important to note, though, that only one person in a household must qualify to obtain this grant. These funds are available now, but are on a first-come, first-serve basis. Don’t hesitate to take advantage of this program. If you work with Movement Mortgage, the pre-approval process will take just 24 hours and underwriting will take just one or two days.

So, if you are a first-time buyer looking for a home and would like help, have any other questions, or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+Buying+Your+First+Home%253F+These+Programs+Can+Help.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+Buying+Your+First+Home%253F+These+Programs+Can+Help.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you are looking for your first home, there are a few great programs that can help you achieve your goal.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you are looking for your first home, there are a few great programs that can help you achieve your goal.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays From the Dee Team</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/happy-holidays-from-the-dee-team.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-16 04:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+Happy+Holidays+From+the+Dee+Team.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here at The Dee Team, we want to wish you a happy holiday season.

Thank you for giving us a fair opportunity to earn your business. We greatly appreciate that.

We wanted to wish you, your friends, and your family a happy and prosperous holiday season. May God bless you.

“Have a happy and prosperous holiday season.”

As always, we are here and happy to help with any questions you may have.

Happy holidays!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+Happy+Holidays+From+the+Dee+Team.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team-+Happy+Holidays+From+the+Dee+Team.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Happy holidays from The Dee Team! We hope you have an amazing holiday season.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Happy holidays from The Dee Team! We hope you have an amazing holiday season.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons Now Is the Time to Sell Your Home in Central Florida</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/5-reasons-now-is-the-time-to-sell-your-home-in-central-florida.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-16 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+5+great+reasons+to+list+your+home+this+fall.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are the top five reasons you should consider selling your home this fall:

1. Inventory is still low. Within certain price points, there are more buyers than there are properties available. Here is a link to a recent NAR report that explores in further detail the recent buyer activity happening in our market.



2. There is still less competition. Since inventory is still low in most parts of the country and here in Central Florida, there are some price points where there aren’t enough homes and multiple buyers situations happening. Moreover, the buyers that are the most serious about buying are looking now. Click here to see the latest buyers report that shows how strong the demand is.  Why else would they be trying to buy a home during the holiday season?

3.  The process will be quicker. Lenders are very strict now, and they aren’t issuing pre-approval letters unless they know buyers are completely qualified. This means most buyers will have passed all lending hurdles. They will have held their credit pulled, given their bank statements and tax returns, and had their employment verified. When you have a buyer, odds are they will be able to get a loan. Click here to see the latest report from Ellie Mae.

“There has never been a better time to move up or move down.”

4. There has never been a better time to move up or move down. Since interest rates are still low, if you want to move up, you could still buy a bigger house for a lower payment. If you want to move down, you can sell your home at the highest possible price.

5. Isn’t it time for you to be done with it? If you’ve been thinking about selling your property for a while and you’ve been holding off or watching the market, this is a really good time for you to be done with it so your goal of selling your property is accomplished before next year.

For more on why now is a good time to put your home on the market, click on this link.

If you have any questions or you think you want to sell your home, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+5+great+reasons+to+list+your+home+this+fall.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+5+great+reasons+to+list+your+home+this+fall.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are five reasons why fall is a great time to put your home on the market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are five reasons why fall is a great time to put your home on the market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is It a Better Idea to Buy Now or Later?</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/is-it-a-better-idea-to-buy-now-or-later.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-12 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+Is+waiting+worth+it.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve been getting this question a lot: “Should I buy a home now or should I wait until next year?” Here are a few statistics that may help you make your decision if you’re unsure.

Interest rates are sitting right at about 3.83%, according to Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac. However, they are expected to go up to 4.4% in the next year. Let’s say the home you’re interested in is listed at $250,000. If interest rates were to go up to 4.4%, that would increase your monthly mortgage payment from $1,169.17 to $1,314.50.



What do those costs add up to over time? Well, an extra $145.33 per month will eventually equal $1,743.16 per year and an incredible $52,319 over the 30-year term of a typical mortgage.

“The cost of waiting to buy could be high.”

The home you’re looking at now is going to be listed for a higher price as well. With a modest 5% appreciation, a home with a list price of $250,000 this year will have a list price near $262,500 next year.  



 

That’s a lot of money that you’re basically giving to somebody else if you’re choosing to rent and waiting to buy. If you’re ready, willing, and able to buy now, you should probably get in the market while rates are low and the market is healthy. If you wait, it’s certainly going to cost you.

If you have any questions about buying a home or anything else relating to real estate, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+Is+waiting+worth+it.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+Is+waiting+worth+it.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Should you buy a home now or wait? We’re answering the question today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Should you buy a home now or wait? We’re answering the question today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Be Worried About Another Real Estate Bubble?</title>
        <link>http://askdeegupta.com/should-you-be-worried-about-another-real-estate-bubble.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Deepak Gupta</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-30 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+Are+We+Heading+Into+Another+Crash.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The number one question I’ve been getting asked recently is, “Are we heading for another market crash?” 10 years ago, our market crashed. Are we headed toward the same situation now? I have three reasons to believe that no, we are not. I have also included some information from Keeping Current Matters to help explain why we are not in a bubble.

1. Today’s mortgage industry standards. The difference is day and night. It’s much harder for someone to get a loan than it was a decade ago.

2. Builders are being more cautious. When getting a loan was as easy as fogging a mirror, builders were building as much and as fast as they could. From 2003 to 2006, there were 350,000 new homes available for purchase. Right now, there are just 142,000 new homes available.

“30% to 40% of the country is still recovering from the crash.”

3. The nationwide market hasn’t fully recovered. Although our market has recovered from the crash, 30% to 40% of the country is still recovering. This is keeping interest rates low for the time being, which is keeping buyers in the market.

I have attached a slide and a link here from Truila.com for you that shows you the numbers. All signs point to a healthy real estate market without any kind of bubble. If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+Are+We+Heading+Into+Another+Crash.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://askdeegupta.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Deepak+Gupta/The+Dee+Team+Are+We+Heading+Into+Another+Crash.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are we headed for another real estate market crash? In a word, no.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Deepak Gupta</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are we headed for another real estate market crash? In a word, no.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Orlando, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Deepak Gupta</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Deepak Gupta</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Dee Team - your professional Orlando Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
